All right!
I can start my training!
Right now, this is all I can do.
I can't allow myself to fail!
What's up?
Going to all the trouble of coming
to pick me up like this...
You're on your way to Kurenai Sensei's
after this anyway, right...?
Taking the time to converse
once in a while...
that's also part of teamwork.
Let me hear about your mission.
It was pretty incredible...
But you wouldn't understand
even if I explained it to you.
I don't want Akamaru to experience
that kind of thing ever again.
And for that reason, I must polish
my jutsu all the more...
I want to hear about it in detail.
Because that's what teamwork
is about.
Are you sulking...
'cause you were the only one
who was passed up?
You are sulking, aren't you?
I still have a long way to go...
Until I can see his moves...
I can't believe you're doing
that this early in the morning...
Neji, let's take a break.
Okay!
- Let's go, Hinata!
- Okay!
Father, see you later.
Barbecued meat?
This early in the morning, huh?
Just when he was looking good
after losing some weight
after he was released
from the hospital.
He made an amazing rebound,
didn't he?
With that good an appetite,
there aren't any more worries
about his health, are there?
When I'm done eating,
help me with my training, okay?
Asuma Sensei!
Hey, are you an idiot
or something?!
You're recuperating, you know!
L-Lee...Come on,
let's take a short break...
What's the matter, Guy Sensei?
The prime of one's youth waits
for no one, you know.
Maintaining the prime of one's youth
is starting to get tough...
Thank you very much!
Do your best, guys...
I'll master the Shuriken Jutsu by
the next time you're here!
M-Me too...
I want to become a kunoichi
just like you, Temari...
I'm honored.
I apologize for asking you
to teach at the Academy...
since we're so short staffed right now.
You probably would've preferred
to go sightseeing or something.
No problem.
I'm doing this because I enjoy it.
Yeah...And we were
also able to survey
the future potential of
the Leaf's military power...
Well, be careful going home.
Okay...
If something happens,
I'll come to your rescue again.
Just let me know, crybaby.
You always say too much.
That's why girls are...
All right! I'm ready!
I just have to wait
for Pervy Sage to come!
There he is!
But my training...
Don't get so pouty, Naruto.
Some work came in all of a sudden.
It can't be helped.
It's just gonna be doing
an interview
for some obscene magazine
anyway, right?
That kind of thing isn't called work.
It's a mission to gather
information about the Akatsuki...
But if I tell this guy that,
he might ask me to
let him come.
Humph!
I'll make it up to you by...
Huh?
W-What's this?
It's so that you don't get bored
while you're staying at home.
It's a special training menu
I put together!
Wow!
Wait, wait!
My own prized secret training
methods are inscribed here.
Don't read this where
other people might see it!
Okay!
Well, do your best!
I'm gonna use this
to train vigorously!
Thank you, Pervy Sage!
The walls have ears...
paper doors have eyes...
Pervy Sage's secret training methods...
What?!
Pervy Sage!
Huh, it's Lady Tsunade.
Huh? You guys are...
Hey, are you visiting someone
at the hospital too?
Yes.
You too, Lady Tsunade?
Well, I guess...
She just doesn't want to stay
in the executive office...
Shut up!
Hinata, don't faint when
you see Kurenai Sensei.
P-Please let's not talk about that.
Did something happen?
When we were visiting Naruto
in the hospital in the past...
Shino!
This girl fainted when she saw Naruto
all covered with bandages.
Kiba!
I'll...I'll be fine this time!
I finally found you...!
Old Lady Tsunade, I need
to talk to you!
Huh? Hinata!
Naruto...
- Naruto is...so close!
- Hinata? Hinata! What's wrong?
Your face looks a little red...
Do you have a fever or something? Huh?
Hey...
H-Hey, Hinata?!
Hey Hinata!
Are you okay?!
Get a hold of yourself!
Hinata!
Naruto...
Hey, you woke up.
I've asked you numerous times already!
Please let me go in search
of Sasuke!
I've told you numerous times already.
Impossible!
Why!
You have some training to do!
I can't because Pervy Sage
isn't around!
We have zero leads on either
Orochimaru and Sasuke.
So how are you planning
to search for him?
I can figure it out somehow!
If there aren't any leads,
I'll go find some!
So please let me go do it!
You're stubborn, aren't you?
You're stubborn too,
Old Lady Tsunade!
- Please let me go!
- No, you may not!
If I say I'm going, I'm going!
Shut up! No means no!
Byakugan!
All right! Good work, Neji!
Move in another half step
right there!
Yes sir!
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Let's take a break, Neji.
Yes.
Have some tea too.
Thank you...
If Hinata was here,
she should have observed a little.
Hinata prepared this...?
It would supplement her training
by observing...
Byakugan!
Let's take a break.
Yes.
Food! Food!
That was pretty well done.
I would say that you're getting closer
to perfecting the technique.
It's thanks to you both.
You're so kind to join me
in my special training every day...
We're a team.
When a comrade in the team
is in a fix,
one offers a helping hand.
That's only natural...
A comrade...
If a comrade suddenly disappears,
it must be awfully hard.
You're talking about Naruto,
aren't you?
Isn't there some way
we could help him?
I'd like to help him out in
some way too...but...
Lady Hokage was telling Naruto...
that there are no leads at all.
There may be one resource...
Really?!
I'm talking about bikochu.
Bikochu?
Are you talking about
those rare insects?!
I have heard that they had
become extinct some time ago.
Since there was a possibility
that they could become extinct,
the Aburame Clan discontinued
using them,
so a miniscule number of them
should still be alive.
Lady Tsunade, what are bikochu?
Well...it's not surprising that
you don't know about them.
The last time that bikochu
were used
was before the last Great War...
Bikochu are one kind of insect
used by insect handlers.
Larvae which have hatched from eggs
become chrysalises in no time at all,
then emerge and turn
into imagos.
They are then made to
recognize scents...
and they are able to track
even the faintest scent...
to its source.
Their olfactory sense is several thousand
times greater than a Ninja Hound's.
They are insects capable of exhibiting
that skill in an exceptional way.
However, bikochu lay eggs
only once every several years...
This year is actually the year
in which they lay eggs.
And right now is exactly
the time when they hatch.
I see.
There are still some of
Sasuke's belongings left in the village...
Right?
If one makes the bikochu,
recognize that scent...
We may be able to locate
Sasuke's whereabouts, right?
What is the probability
of finding a bikochu?
Frankly speaking, not very high.
Perhaps 10%.
10% huh...
As you guys know,
the situation in the village
is currently very grave...
We don't have the leeway of allowing
even genin to sit around and play.
However, fortunately or unfortunately,
Kurenai has been hospitalized,
so you guys, Squad Eight,
no longer have a mission.
Rather than just letting
you sit around and play,
I'd rather place my bet
on that 10% possibility.
Huh...you mean...
Shino Aburame. Kiba Inuzuka.
Hinata Hyuga.
I order you to search for
the bikochu!
- All right!
I designate Shino
as the leader this time.
And...that spy up there!
Oww...!
Naruto...
You're going to go even if
I try to stop you, right?
Yup!
In that case, I have no choice
but to let you go...
However...
This is your last chance.
If you don't find the bikochu...
you must give up on Sasuke!
Wha?
You understand?!
It'll be fine...
I'll find it without fail.
All right. You won't go back
on your word, right?
Yeah! Leave it to me!
You're easily pleased, aren't you?
Owww!
Naruto...
Sasuke...
Hinata.
Good morning.
Neji will be here soon
for his training...
Please prepare tea as always.
W-Well...
Huh? What's the matter?
I need to go...
on a mission starting now...
A mission, huh...
In that case, it can't be helped...
I'm heading out...
Don't be a burden to the others.
Yes, sir!
I'm...I'm sorry! I'm in a hurry...
The way she handled
her physical response just now...
Hinata...
You're late, Hinata!
I'm sorry!
All right then! Let's head out!
Let's go!
Huh?
Why are you walking at
such a leisurely pace?!
It takes a shinobi two days on foot
to get to the habitat of
the bikochu...
There's no need to make haste
from the very start.
But what if the eggs hatch
before we get there?
The eggs of bikochu only hatch
on the day after it's rained...
There's no sign of it
raining any time soon...
But...if by some remote chance...
Naruto.
Wh-What is it?
I am the leader of this team.
While we are on this mission,
you will obey the orders of your leader.
Kiba, I can't believe you're able
to work with that kind of guy...
Well, I've gotten used to it...
I'm sure you'll bond with him too, Naruto.
I wonder about that...
Naruto and the others
left a while ago.
I see.
Didn't you want to go too?
When it comes to searching
for insects,
Shino, who's an insect handler,
is number one...
And then Hinata who has Byakugan...
and Kiba and Akamaru who have
sensitive noses are there too...
So there's really no role that
I could play!
What I must do right now...
is to become a Medical Ninja
as soon as I possibly can!
What's the matter, Shino?!
The sun's going down.
We're setting up camp.
Got it.
- Huh?
- Okay.
Huh? What?!
We're gonna set up
camp already?!
I'm not tired at all yet!
Let's go further!
Naruto, the leader of
this team is me.
I-I understand!
Okay then...let's sleep.
Huh...we're gonna sleep already?!
Many animals and plants
go to sleep at sunset
and are awake at sunrise.
In order to search for insects,
we must understand the rhythm
of living creatures with our own bodies...
But...the sun's just set...
Naruto, I am the leader of this team...
Okay, okay. I got it!
There's no way
I can sleep so early...
Yeah, right...
All that complaining and guess
who's the first one to fall asleep?
I have to pee...
Huh?
What's that?
It's a waterfall...
Hey...Is somebody there?
S-Say...
Damn it...!
S-Sorry.
Did I scare you?
Huh?
There's nobody there...
Huh, Naruto...
Did you catch a cold?
Yeah...a little...
After sleeping so much
you're still tired?
Well, uh...
When I woke up last night to pee,
I saw something awesome...
Did you catch a cold too, Hinata?
No, I'm okay...
And...what was that awesome thing?
It was a beautiful woman
in the middle of the waterfall!
Huh?
When that person moved her arms,
the water would suddenly move too!
It was awesome!
And what happened then...
When I tried to speak to her,
she suddenly vanished.
You must have been dreaming
or something.
It's starting to feel that way...
You idiot!
Your face is red, Hinata.
You might have really
caught a cold.
Huh...really, I'm fine...
This fruit is edible.
This will be our meal today.
Got it.
We can save on
our food supplies too.
There's one thing
I need to warn you about.
On rare occasions, this fruit grows
to the size of a human being.
However, those fruits
are damaged inside.
Don't tamper with them
under any circumstance.
There's nobody who would
eat something that huge.
N-Naruto...!
He's eating it...
Naruto...We're going on ahead...
I'll...I'll be right behind you!
Sorry to keep you waiting!
Wait just a second!
Hey...aren't we there yet?
Yes.
We're here!
What...?
Wow!
I've never seen anything
like this before.
This certainly isn't a place
where humans could inhabit.
That's right...
That's why it's paradise for insects.
D-Don't tell me...
Could it be that...over there...?
You mean that's where
the bikochu are?
No problem.
It's better than the Chunin Exam.
Damn...The foothold crumbles easily...
- Naruto...
- What?
As the leader, I'm warning you...
At a time like this,
what is it?!
Don't fall.
I already know that
without your telling me!
Naruto!
No way...!
That was close...
Those were insects, huh...
That's why I warned you.
When this mission is over,
I'm definitely gonna kick
that guy's butt!
This is...the bikochu forest.
Let's go.
There's no mistake.
Those are Leaf shinobi.
The fact that those guys came to
a place like this
means their objective is...
Yeah...it's the same as ours...
the bikochu.
We're not gonna let them
take any bikochu.
The bikochu...
belong to us, the Kamizuru Clan!
It's so quiet, isn't it?
Peace is a wonderful thing, isn't it?
Being able to...
drink sake tranquilly like this...
Please, this isn't the time
to be drinking sake!
Especially at a time when
the village is enjoying peace...
you should hurry up and
finish up your work!
Why is it that work
never seems to cease?
That's because you never complete
a single thing, Lady Tsunade!
There's disquiet among
the Kamizuru Clan?
That's a communiqué from
the ANBU unit
stationed in the Land of the Earth,
isn't it?
I don't think I'm
familiar with the name...
The Kamizuru Clan are the insect handlers
of the Hidden Stone Village.
Long ago, they were so famous
as to be extolled
as equals of the Aburame Clan...
But they've died out and hardly anyone
remembers their name...
I see...
It says there's been some disquiet,
but there can't be many of them left.
It's really nothing to worry about...
Wow...There are so many insects...
This is truly a paradise for insects...
We won't get stung, will we?
Almost none of these insects will
cause bodily harm to humans.
I do have some of the Aburame Clan's
secret recipe insect repellant...
but I would prefer not to use it,
if at all possible.
Because it would also repel
the bikochu.
Then you shouldn't have
brought it out in the first place.
There's no mistake...
That kid in the lead...
he's a member of the Abarame Clan,
after all.
I never imagined that
we'd bump into them in a place like this.
Is their objective the bikochu, Jibachi?
Anyone who wants to get their hands
on a bikochu
has to come to this place
during this particular period.
The restoration of the Kamizuru Clan
rests on the outcome of this mission...
We need to get our hands on
a bikochu, no matter what!
This is a female bikochu.
Pound its characteristics into your heads.
Okay!
Got it.
Hey, I've seen this thing before...
Hey, really?!
Where did you see it, Naruto?
That was...
When I inadvertently leave some food out,
they start coming out of nowhere.
A whole deluge of them...
So those were bikochu...
If it's those things,
they should be easy to catch.
Hey...
Naruto...
Those are called...cockroaches.
Huh? Cockroaches?
You're comparing apples to oranges.
This thing is completely different!
They look exactly identical to me...
- They're not!
Depending on how you look at it,
this could be an opportunity.
What do you mean, Suzumebachi?
It's been ten days since we came here...
we haven't been able to get
any leads on the bikochu.
However, that kid from
the Abarame Clan might...
That makes sense!
You mean they might be able
to catch a bikochu...
From their appearance,
it seems they're all genin.
If they're able to catch
a bikochu...
we'll just take it from them.
All insects look alike.
Insect Summoning Jutsu!
There aren't any...here...
This thing here
is different too, huh...
Huh?
This mission
is something that I suggested...
so I will find it without fail!
Byakugan!
Just as I thought...
it's difficult to perceive things
as small as insects.
Huh?!
Shino! Kiba!
Hinata...Did you notice too?
So...you did too?
I guess...they think they're hiding...
Unfortunately for them,
we have a whole array of specialists
in detecting enemies.
What should we do, Shino?
You're the leader of this mission.
If we end up in a battle, there's
the danger of involving the insects...
and injuring the bikochu.
As long as they don't make a move,
we'll just watch them closely.
Got it.
I wonder if...Naruto noticed.
If he had noticed,
he would have raised a big clamor.
I don't want to stir things up.
So don't tell him.
Okay...
Hey, Shino! Shino!
I found it! I found it!
I'm telling you,
I found a bikochu!
He found it already?!
That's impossible!
When we spent ten days searching
and couldn't find one!
Awesome, Naruto...
Are you sure, Naruto?
Let me see it.
See...this is it, right?
It's exactly like the photo, right?
I might be an insect hunting genius.
Huh?
Does it look the same to you?
That's called a goliath beetle...
Huh?! It's not the same thing
Unless I control my chakra
more precisely,
I won't be able to find something
as small as an insect!
To come all this way and
continue training...
That's quite admirable...
The air pressure has changed.
That's a sure sign that
the weather will change.
Yeah, I realize that.
A wind charged with moisture
has started blowing...
This means
there's gonna be rainfall.
When it's such good weather?
But I can see clouds
off in the distance...
Hinata...
We need to hurry.
Because it's said that the bikochu
only lays an egg when it rains.
And larva emerges from the egg
the following morning.
In other words,
if it rains today, it'll become
a mature larva tomorrow morning.
In view of the season,
this may well be our last chance.
If this chance slips by,
it will become impossible to search
for Sasuke using a bikochu...
Sasuke...
It'll be fine.
I'll find it without fail!
Don't rain...Don't rain yet!
Damn! Where is it?!
Please come on out
before it rains!
Naruto...
What are we gonna do...
if those guys don't find
a bikochu, Suzumebachi?
It was the Aburame Clan
who was the catalyst in
the downfall of the Kamizuru Clan...
In order to avenge our clan's
longstanding grudge...
we will finish them off!
Those guys...
They haven't made a move yet.
They must know that we're searching
for the bikochu.
Which means that they must be waiting
for us to find one.
I see...So their plan is to steal it
from us once we've found one...
What cheapskates...
Rain...
Not this one either!
Damn! When I told it not to rain!
There's no more time...
Don't be a burden to everyone...
So ultimately...
I contributed nothing.
There's still plenty of time!
Naruto...
I will not go back on my word...
That's my Ninja Way!
Naruto, I won't give up either!
Byakugan!
I have to...
I have to concentrate more...
I need to...I need to...
control my chakra!
I can see them!
So those are insects!
That insect...is wrong...
This insect is wrong too.
That's...!
There it is!
Naruto! On the side of that tree!
There's a bikochu there!
I caught it!
We did it...!
I did it! I caught it!
There's no mistake.
It's a female bikochu.
- Yes! I did it!
- Cripes...
Your tenacity amazes me, Naruto!
That's so great, Naruto!
Hinata! It's thanks to you!
Naruto...is...hugging me!
What's the matter, Akamaru?
All right! It's an egg!
It laid an egg, huh...
Really?
It will emerge by tomorrow...
So then we should make it
recognize Sasuke's scent, right?!
It looks like they finally found one...
The time has come, hasn't it?
Yeah...
That Naruto...He suddenly...
pressed his face so close to mine...
So...you were able
to dodge that one just now.
That was pretty well done
for a genin.
They're the ones who've
been trailing us all this time...
However, I wonder if you'll be able
to escape from this attack?
Ninja Art: Honey Jutsu!
Bees?!
No...that's!
It looks like you've noticed, huh.
That's honey.
Honey that adheres like a bonding agent!
I used up all my chakra earlier...
That thing is a real bee.
Naruto...
What do you think, Akamaru?
I see...
I was convinced that those guys
would make some kind of move.
There hasn't been any sign
of them since earlier...
There's a possibility that
we've overlooked something.
Hey, Naruto!
Huh?
Where's Hinata?
She said she was gonna
go wash her face.
Hmm...
But it's been quite some time.
I wonder what she's doing?
Could it be that...?!
Huh? What?
- Naruto!
- Wha?!
A letter on a kunai?
Huh?!
"We are holding the kunoichi
brat hostage.
If you want to get her back,
it'll be in exchange for
the bikochu.
Come to the top of
the eastern hill later tonight."
Damn! So that was their move!
Hinata...!
What the heck is happening...?
Why does Hinata have
to be kidnapped?!
Why are there guys who know
that we're searching for bikochu?!
We were being watched all this time.
Ever since we arrived...
You were aware of that?!
You're the only one who didn't know.
Why didn't you tell me?!
Because if we told you,
you'd have raised a big fuss!
And the insects would flee!
All the insects!
Including the bikochu!
If they tried to steal the bikochu
from us with force,
the insects would be in danger
of getting hurt.
So they captured Hinata and
decided to go with a hostage exchange.
That's very smart of them.
Something smells sweet...
It's the smell of honey.
Bee's honey...
Bees...?
Hinata's scent ends here...
In that case...
Those guys waited for a moment when
Hinata was alone
and attacked her using bees.
I heard that in the Hidden Stone Village
in the Land of Earth,
there's a clan of insect handlers
who primarily use bees.
The name of that clan is...
the Kamizuru Clan.
Kamizuru? That's a name
that isn't heard very often.
Seems they were once hailed as being
at a level equal to the Aburame Clan...
But they aren't anymore?
This is a story from
the times of my grandfather...
There was a time when the shinobi
of the Hidden Stone Village
were going to invade the Leaf Village...
The Kamizuru Clan was designated
to spearhead the operation...
The plan was to create
a disruption by releasing
a large swarm of bees into the village
followed by an invading main unit...
However, the Aburame Clan
wised up to that
and prepared to engage the enemy
in the forest to the west!
This battle between insect handlers
which had no precedent in history...
ended in the Aburame's victory...
With this battle as the turning point,
the Aburame Clan rose to
unchallenged status
in the Hidden Leaf Village...
On the other hand, the Kamizuru Clan
was subjected to cold treatment
even in their own village.
I've heard that only a few of them
remain now...
So those people came here
to capture bikochu, huh?
What the heck are those guys
planning to do with the bikochu?
If my insects come back
we might be able to learn something...
I see...I've been captured...
The Hidden Leaf Village is
in a difficult situation right now...
Because of that incident
at the recent Chunin Exam?
The Hokage was assassinated,
and I hear they lost many shinobi too.
Times are about to change dramatically...
This is a chance for us,
the Kamizuru Clan,
to distinguish ourselves.
But to do that...
The founder's Book of Secrets, huh?
A broad range of Forbidden Jutsu
for Insect Handlers
are apparently inscribed therein
among other things...
If we possessed that at the time of
the battle with the Aburame Clan,
we wouldn't have lost...
However, Clan members have continued
to search for it for many years,
but couldn't find it.
Do you really think
we can find it after all this time?
That's why we need the bikochu...
I brought the keepsakes
of the founder, my grandfather, with me...
When the bikochu emerges,
it will pursue the scent it recognizes.
And we should be able
to locate the Book of Secrets
that grandfather hid just
as he was dying.
This strand of his hair
will surely lead us to it.
If we get our hands on
the Book of Secrets
and if we engage in some big action...
I am certain that...the people of
the village will also acknowledge us.
Those people are also desperately
seeking recognition.
Naruto...
Did you find out anything?
How about Hinata's whereabouts?
No...The other insects were probably
also done in by those guys.
Damn! Then our only choice
is to do what they want?
When I went to all that
trouble of finding it...
So you want to desert Hinata?
H-How could anyone possibly do that?!
I won't desert her no matter
what might happen!
Anybody who deserts a comrade is trash!
Exactly.
But then we'd be able to locate Sasuke
if we have this guy here...
Well, I guess we'll have to think of
some other method of finding Sasuke.
Yeah...Right now, the first thing
we need to do is rescue Hinata.
But, do you think Hinata
would be satisfied with that?
The person who originally
thought up this plan was Hinata.
Huh? But...
It's true that I told her about
the existence of bikochu...
However...
The odds of finding
a bikochu are extremely low...
We thought that she should aspire
to an important mission
with an assured outcome for the village,
rather than a mission with such low odds.
But Hinata didn't give up.
She argued persistently that
if there was even a small possibility,
one should take on the challenge.
Th-That Hinata did...?
She was extremely forceful and
Shino and I had no choice but to agree.
It's the first time Hinata
ever volunteered for a mission.
For that reason too,
I want to make this a success.
Yeah.
But when we don't know
where Hinata is, how are we...?
There is one place where Hinata
will definitely make an appearance.
I see! The place where...
...the exchange with
the bikochu takes place!
We will definitely have
a chance at that time.
All right!
We will recover Hinata without fail...
and we will also protect
the bikochu to the very end!
We brought the bikochu!
Return Hinata!
Place the insect cage
on that rock over there!
Hinata!
Release Hinata!
I must verify it first!
What's...the meaning of this?!
Are you trying to make a mockery
of our Clan? Of insect handlers?!
A goliath beetle...
You gotta be kidding!
Now, Shino!
What?!
Parasitic Insects!
Heh! Recovery successful!
Naruto!
All right, resign yourselves!
Your time's up!
What's this?
This one doesn't smell like Hinata!
Huh?!
Just as I thought...
Beeswax?
There they come!
Damn! You jerk! You jerk!
Damn! All these things are honey?!
Sorry, Naruto...
But these damn bees!
There's no end to them!
Do we need to slash them
if they're honey?!
You two don't move from there!
Huh?
This is the genuine thing!
Furthermore, it contains deadly poison.
It appears that genuine ones
are mixed in...
But they're indistinguishable
from each other!
Back me up for a little!
Wall of Insects Jutsu!
A-Awesome...
Amazing power for a genin...
As might be expected from
the Aburame Clan...I guess.
The Kamizuru Clan...
Huh...? So you were aware
of that fact.
Return Hinata!
Of course, our intention was
to return her...
But only if you calmly hand over
the bikochu.
However...
It looks like you have
no intention of doing that!
In that case,
what do you plan on doing?
If you're an insect handler,
you wouldn't bring a delicate insect
like the bikochu
to a dangerous place
like a battleground...
We'll finish you off right here...
and take our time afterwards
to search for the bikochu!
Wall of Insects Jutsu!
That one doesn't have
any other tricks, huh!
Shino! Paper bombs!
Take this!
1000 Bee Stingers Jutsu!
Insect Clones...?
Up to your annoying tricks, huh...
Shino! What are we gonna do now?!
Don't you think we should
go back there for a moment?
Those guys
might find the bikochu!
No...that location
will definitely be safe.
More importantly, the first thing
we need to do is search for Hinata!
There's no mistake.
Inside here.
Hinata! Where are you?!
Hey! Be careful!
There's no sign of those guys,
but it might be a trap...
Is she there?!
Hinata?
Hinata!
Are you all right, Hinata?
I'll rescue you in a moment!
Just a little more!
All right...I got it off!
Naruto...
Thank you!
H-Hinata?!
H-Hinata...stop that!
What do you think you're doing,
out of the blue like that?!
Who...are you?
What are you talking about, Shino?
That's Hinata.
If you're really Hinata,
you'd get red in the face
and faint if you hugged Naruto.
- Huh?
- Oh!
I see...
But Akamaru's nose wouldn't fail...
What? The smell of two people
is mingled?
You're not Hinata?
Naruto...It's me...
I'm Hinata, believe me.
In that case...
show us what you tried to stick
on Naruto's back right now!
A paper bomb?
So you were intending
to blow up Naruto!
I thought that would work...
You are...
I see, the one on the hill
was a clone, huh...
Wearing Hinata's clothes...
That's how she was able
to compromise the smell.
Where is the real Hinata?!
I wonder where she could be?
I see...
Suzumebachi lured
the Aburame Clan, huh?
Well, it appears that your comrades...
place more value on the bikochu
than on you.
There's nobody else coming
to rescue you.
Jibachi, Let's search for
the bikochu that those guys hid!
There's not much time until sunrise!
Right!
Don't even try to escape.
If you make even the smallest movement
out of the ordinary,
those bees will cut the string.
Up ahead is the entrance to
an underground water vein...
If you fall in, you'll pass into
the afterlife in an instant.
We don't wish to kill
anyone unnecessarily.
If you want to live,
I suggest you just stay quiet.
How mortifying...I ended up being
a burden to everyone, after all.
You guys are just like summer insects
who fly right into the fire!
If you're lucky, we'll meet again...
That place isn't just an ordinary cave.
Hey! Let go! Shino! Naruto!
There's nothing else to grab onto.
Be patient until I've checked
the surroundings!
No!
A huge number of bee larvae!
Bee larvae, huh?
But what's with their unusual huge size?
If you tell me where you hid the bikochu,
I'll spare your life.
I refuse!
Searching for the bikochu is
the mission that we were given!
Then die!
Paper bombs!
Damn! Let's go, Akamaru!
Fang Over Fang!
That sound is...
I see...They're still continuing to fight
without giving up.
This is not the time to be crying...
There's no way that I can give up.
I suggested this whole thing!
Byakugan!
There are 13 bees...
attached to the string.
If I can take them all down at once...
I'll be saved.
But, to take down bees that small...
Impossible! This guy...
I told you before...
I don't know...when to give up.
Naruto...
Yes...I won't give up either!
I need to concentrate and
control my chakra...
Fang Over Fang!
How many of them are there?!
Kiba!
I-I can't muster any strength...
Somehow my body is...
No way!
The larvae in this hive's favorite food
is chakra!
What?!
As long as you're in there,
they'll go through the wall
to suck up the chakra...
What's the matter?
So have you decided
to tell me the location?
Now!
Four...
Five, six...ten...
Eleven, twelve, thirteen...
Damn!
Summoning Jutsu!
Would you like to be the feed
for the larvae...
or would you like to get out of here
and become the prey of this girl here?
Choose whichever you like!
Kiba!
Naruto!
This isn't good.
Oh my, what's wrong?
So you'll just stay there
and become larvae food?
Queen Bee...
That kind of stuff shouldn't
be effective, should it?!
Chakra...!
Byakugan!
It's no good...There's no way
I can make it in time!
Naruto...
I don't know when to give up!
That's right...
I know that Naruto would never give up,
no matter what the situation is!
Hey, did you catch them?
What a foolish group!
They made this creature mad...
And they all got bound in wax!
Bees make wax...
You're an insect handler
and you don't know that?
He's right!
C'mon, are you really an insect handler?
What about the bikochu?
Nothing.
We did an all out mobilization
and searched,
but we haven't found it.
Aren't these guys carrying it?
That's unthinkable.
So that means...
So we're going to have to
ask one of these guys, after all.
Who's gonna talk?!
We can tell you.
Shino!
However...
It's in exchange for Hinata.
That's stupid, isn't it? To bargain...
Do you not understand your position?
You guys definitely will not
find the bikochu.
And you're pressed for time.
You are the ones...who will regret it.
What should we do?
If things stay like this,
the bikochu won't be of any help
even if it hatches.
In that case, our mission is also...
But...
If we can get rid of even one
of the Aburame family...
Hinata...
Are you worried?
Of course!
She's strong.
Huh?
Much more...than you think.
I concede. We have a deal.
First of all, we need our friend.
What happened?
The brat...isn't here.
The wax she was trapped in isn't there...
She may have been swept out
to the waterfall.
Jibachi!
It can't be helped! I warned her not
to make a bad move or she'd die.
You!
What did you do to Hinata?!
What happened to Hinata! Hey!
Shut up, kid.
The kid's probably in
the depths of hell about now.
Damn you!
Aha, the girl's your girlfriend?
You...! I absolutely will not forgive you!
You're kidding me.
What can you do looking like that?
Without Hinata you'll never get
your hands on the bikochu either.
You are right...
That girl's death was not part
of the plan,
but in the end, it's a good thing.
Because...
we'll take your lives in return.
From the very beginning,
the Hidden Leaf and Stone
have been sworn enemies.
It's natural that we kill
each other, isn't it?
What're ya gonna do, little guy?
Die like this?
If you tell me where the bikochu is,
I could save you for now.
- All right.
- Don't you dare tell them!
Those jerks,
I'm going to blow them away!
Shut up, brat!
- Jibachi?
- Hey!
Shut up, I've got to kill him!
It's a paper bomb!
Y-You're...!
...still alive!
That was really close.
But I didn't give up, just like Naruto...
Did she escape from the wax?
It can't be!
These are not ordinary kids.
Leave it to me!
Hinata!
I've never used that in an actual fight...
But I have to do it here, now!
Bee Bombs Jutsu!
1000 Bee Stingers Jutsu!
Bee Swarm Jutsu!
Naruto...
Naruto...Watch me.
Protective 8 Trigrams 64 palms!
- What?!
You're kidding, right?
Hinata can do
such an amazing jutsu?
The Hinata that you know, Naruto,
is from when?
What do you mean?
You've learned new jutsu
since the Chunin Exams, haven't you?
Hinata has been steadily developing, too.
She always has been concerned...
Take aim.
That's nice, the three of you,
all have something you're good at
and something you like.
Hinata, you should find something, too...
You're right.
By the way, what is it?
You had some business with me,
didn't you?
Yeah...
I want you to join me
in my training.
Hinata was fretting over
what she could do...
What she should do...
Hinata!
Hey, I don't think that we should...
No...Don't go easy on me!
If you're doing it for me...
Do it seriously!
I've got it!
During the harsh training,
Hinata discovered her own styles...
and her own special jutsu.
That's the result of her training.
Huh? You, why!?
I'll tell you something...
Angering the Queen Bee,
getting encased in wax,
it was all part of the strategy.
With our chakra being sucked
and being immobilized,
it was the only way to protect ourselves
from the larvae...
And, do you think I was doing nothing
while I was captured?
I was ordering my bugs.
The wax we're wrapped in is very weak.
Shino!
Because of her hard training,
Hinata's chakra control
has dramatically improved.
That jutsu is what she developed
from the training...
Protective 8 Trigrams 64 palms!
Hinata's already flexible body combined
with fine-tuned chakra control
could completely defend
an attack from every direction...
Truly, it's an ultimate defense jutsu.
Yet it's different from
Neji's 8 Trigrams Palms Rotation.
It's Hinata's own jutsu...
She finally worked that out on her own.
She probably did it because she wanted
to be acknowledged by her father.
To be acknowledged by everyone...
And to be acknowledged by you.
Our jutsu isn't effective at all?!
What the hell is going on?
What a girl!
Hey, what happened to those guys?!
When did they?!
Summoning Jutsu!
Blow them away!
Hinata!
Shino!
Believe...in her.
Make the chakra...
sharper, stronger...
bigger, more flexible...
more...more...more...
more...more...more...more!
Hinata!
Naruto...
Hinata, that's an awesome jutsu!
You're really awesome!
Naruto!
Let's hurry. It'll be dawn soon.
- Okay!
- Yeah!
It seems that they succeeded
at protecting the bikochu,
but failed at getting it to smell
the scent of Sasuke Uchiha.
I see...Hinata must be depressed.
This strategy was her idea, wasn't it?
Well...Looks like that's not the case.
Hinata...
I heard that your mission failed.
Yes. It didn't work at all.
I have to train more and more...
and work harder next time!
I-I see...Good luck.
More...
More!