It could be that way...
Sure enough, Ichiraku ramen is
the best for getting energized!
One more, Pops!
Coming right up!
Huh?
One more, you said, eh...?
Just when I thought you'd
snuck out of your hospital room
and were doing some training...
You guys want some, too?
Pop, here's the tab.
Thanks for your business!
Jeez, I'm fine!
Naruto, even if it looks like
you've healed, you're still battered.
It's not like that!
I have to train and get stronger!
Yeah yeah,
after you've healed completely.
Damn it! I have to keep my promise
to Sakura without further delay!
Sakura...You're so pathetic.
All I did...was cry...
All I did was totally rely on Naruto.
I didn't do anything myself.
Naruto tried to bring back Sasuke
even if it meant his life...
What can I do for Sasuke now...?
I just have to put my
life on the line and do it!
It's futile. The ropes are made
of a maiden's black hair.
And the knot is a shinobi
reverse butterfly knot.
It won't be easily untied.
Give me a break.
I have to start training as soon
as possible and get stronger.
Then do as the Medical Corps says
and rest quietly.
Come in.
Oh...
Sorry, Sakura...
I'd like to get moving immediately
if possible, but...
He has astonishing recuperative power,
but overdoing it is a big no no.
I'm okay!
Be a little more patient!
Just wait a little longer!
I'll keep my promise, no matter what!
No...
It's okay...
Up until now,
I was totally reliant on you...
and I did nothing, so...
What's the matter, Sakura...?
Did something happen?!
No...I'm relieved
to see you doing well.
This time, I'll do my best.
Sakura...?
I heard you snuck out of the hospital.
Do you want to train that badly?
Pervy Sage...? My...apple!
Well well, things look
like they're going smoothly.
Don't you worry.
I'll train you hard right away.
Umm...about the training.
I was wondering if you could
wait a little while longer.
Hmm?
I'm not saying
I don't want to train.
But I remembered some odds
and ends I need to take care of.
Oh?
Odds and ends, huh?
Come on. Please?
Come in!
Oh, I've been spotted, huh?
I'm guessing, you want to peep?
No matter how long you wait,
I won't show anything.
Who'd peep at an old lady?!
N-No, I take that back!
Actually, I've come to make an
earnest request to you as the Hokage.
Talk.
It couldn't be
that Sakura's going to...
This might be...my last look...
Sakura...
How did you?
I know what you're thinking!
That there'd be nothing
I could do even if I were to go...!
But I hate that I'm
just standing here doing nothing!
Always being a hindrance to
and taking advantage of everyone...
Not being able to do
one single thing respectably...
It's useless to stop me!
I won't stop you...
You should do it
until you're satisfied.
But...I'm going, too.
But...
It's become just the two of us...
But we're a three-man squad, right?
Yeah.
You guys...
Oops! Pervy Sage?
This person...is Jiraiya,
one of the legendary Sannin?
If you, without permission,
go out past the border of
the Village Hidden in the Leaves...
you know that you'll be sent
to prison as rogue ninja, right?
It's no use stopping us!
I won't stop you.
You've been given a mission
by Lady Hokage.
You're to investigate and report
on the Land of Rice Paddies
where the Village Hidden in Sound is,
and where Sasuke has been taken to.
The mission is set to be carried out
in a group of three.
As of now, you will work under me.
You got a problem?!
It seems they're the biggest of fools.
They won't stop even if you tried.
At this rate,
we'll lose two important subordinates!
You'll recognize it as a special mission
with the goal of investigating
the Hidden Sound Village, right?
I have no choice, huh...?
But I have a condition.
Bring the two back alive. Got it?
Sure, even if it costs my life.
It's too dangerous of a mission,
even with Jiraiya going with them...
Sasuke...
That's the Land of Rice Paddies where
the Hidden Sound Village is.
It's Orochimaru's headquarters.
Take sufficient caution and proceed.
It's kind of anticlimactic...
I thought a bunch of Orochimaru's
followers would be here to greet us!
Is this really the Hidden Sound Village?
It seems to be a peaceful,
quiet and nice land, but...
No, we still haven't entered
the Hidden Sound Village.
This is the Land of Rice Paddies.
Land of Rice Paddies?
It's a small land that's nothing special.
The feudal lord was a foolish lord who
hungered for powerful military strength
in order to make the land
disproportionately larger.
Orochimaru probably won his favor
with some fast talking...
Of course, Orochimaru himself wasn't
thinking about making the land stronger.
He just had an ambition to make himself
stronger and to carry out revenge...
That's why there's nothing in this area
that points to his presence.
Really? So, Pervy Sage...
Don't call me Pervy Sage!
That's right...
He's one of the legendary Sannin, so...
He's just a lady loving
perverted Pervy Sage!
What?!
More importantly,
where's the Hidden Sound Village?
Beats me...I don't know...
What?!
We don't know where it is,
so we're going to investigate, right?
You've got a point, but...
But how do we find it?
There can't be a place where
people are without food and ladies.
People gather where
there's food and girls!
- Where people gather, there's news.
- There goes Pervy Sage's bad habit.
He's planning to sow his wild oats
under the guise of a special mission.
First off, finding a traveler's town with
lots of hot ladies is the top priority!
Every land should have a traveler's town.
This is a traveler's town...right?
Looks like nobody's living here anymore.
No, I feel the presence of people...
And the smell of face powder!
- Naruto, take it out.
- Take what out?
Don't act like you don't know!
In anything one does,
a war chest is necessary, right?
What! Are you after my wallet? Man!
What?! This shouldn't be it!
Try jumping!
Huh?!
No! Stop!
One, two, three...Is this all you got?
That's all of it, really!
- Here...
- Huh?
It's not much, but please use it.
No! Sakura, there's no need for
you to give that to him!
But, it's money for
gathering information, right?
Right, right. This should be enough.
You guys go on ahead to the outskirts
of the post station and wait!
Wh-Why?
It's too dangerous ahead from here.
It's a mission for adults.
Hmm, the smell of
face powder's from here.
Welcome...
Along came a sucker just begging
to be parted from his money.
We should be able to pulverize him.
Food and drink! And young women!
Even if you give the Pervy Sage money,
he's just going to sow his oats without
gathering any information, anyway.
Sow his oats...?
Y-Yeah...
I don't really know about it, but...
You know, make out blah blah blah...
It's fine!
If I can be of at least some help...
I'm always a hindrance
who can't do anything, so...
It's not like that!
In the first place,
if you hadn't taken action...
I'd still be tied to the bed!
Even in different lands,
there are young women everywhere.
So? Why don't we move to
the room in the back?
I want to talk more relaxed.
Nice, nice.
Then first, settle up the tab
for here, okay?
What, am I already drunk
on this cheap drink...?
Aren't there like three too many zeros?
You like to joke, do you?
If you value your life,
leave everything you've got here.
I see how it is.
Master Jiraiya's late.
I'm sick of waiting.
Naruto!
Who's there?!
Who're you?!
Are you one of Orochimaru's followers?!
What? Was I wrong?!
Damn it.
That kid had erased his presence
until he'd gotten that close.
I won't let him get away!
Don't move!
Wh-Why?!
Makibishi spikes!
Naruto!
Wh-What?!
- Hold it! You jerk!
- We won't let you get away!
Naruto, what's that?!
Pervy Sage? What did you do?!
I'll tell you later!
Let's get out of here!
Why?!
Companions of that person just now?
If they're Orochimaru's followers,
then I'll use my Shadow Clone Jutsu and...
No, no! Don't get the wrong idea!
They're just bodyguards
from a rip off bar!
R-Rip off bar?!
First and foremost, this mission has
to be carried out in strict secrecy!
There'd be no point if you were
to use ninjutsu and stand out!
You! Carry the bags!
The one who's totally standing out
is you, Pervy Sage!
You have a point.
This is wrong!
Will we really reach Sasuke like this?!
It seems that the most bustling traveler's
town in the Land of Rice Paddies
is at the bottom of these mountains.
You're going to weird places again
in the name of investigation,
aren't you, Pervy Sage?!
Please stop it already!
We had a rough time shaking
off the bodyguards from the rip off bar.
I understand your point,
but there's no other way to find
the Hidden Sound Village.
Gee, I don't like it either, but...
This is truly a problem...
But we have to do things
we don't like...Right?!
Okay, let's go!
Naruto, Sakura,
don't drag your feet!
Investigation, investigation!
What a pain.
He looks like he's having fun.
He hasn't learned at all.
- Oww!
- That's my line!
This is even rougher than
the last traveler's town.
Let's just take a pass on this place
and find the Hidden Sound Village.
Say...
I don't have any more money.
I don't have any more money either!
Here!
You guys go get some food with that
and wait in the temple
on the outskirts of town.
Information accumulates
in this kind of place,
but it's not good for you guys to see.
I'll sacrifice myself and check it out.
He's a surprisingly nice person...
Sakura...You're still so naive.
Where should I investigate first?
Gee, how rough...
Investigations are painful.
Let's leave the Pervy Sage be
and check somewhere else.
What's the matter, Sakura?
I don't think...
Sasuke's in this land anymore.
What's the matter?!
We won't know that if
we don't investigate!
Yeah, but...
Our opponent is Orochimaru.
Of course, things might not go easily.
But you know...
But I'm sure we'll find him!
Right.
Naruto!
You're...the one from before?!
This kid's...hurt...
You...?
Naruto!
Substitution, huh...?
We let them get away.
Don't worry...
My cute children
are making a silver trail for us.
They can't escape from us now...
It seems those two are
petty ninja from somewhere else.
But getting involved with us
has sealed their fate.
It's unfortunate for them...
The objective of those who sneak into
this land is Lord Orochimaru, anyway.
Sure enough, the skin of
a young woman is supple.
You're mean!
Eh? Oh, sorry sorry.
By the way, have you guys heard
rumors about the Sound Village?
The Sound Village?
I've never heard the name
of such a village.
I'll tip you handsomely if you tell me.
But I really don't know.
I've never heard of it.
I've heard of it!
One of my regulars knows
a lot about it.
Wanna come?
Yeah.
His home is in the back of this alley.
Trapped like a rat.
What, it's a seedy old man!
Hey! He's got money, right?
Yeah. I saw it with my own eyes.
You punks! Stop the idle chatter
and take care of him now!
Right, boss!
Getting infatuated with girls has sealed
your fate! Rest in peace!
Ninja Art: Needle Jizo.
You punk...
I'm in a hurry...
I think it'd be best if you
answer compliantly
whether or not you know
about the Hidden Sound Village.
You're a fool if I look like
a compliant person to you!
You a ninja?
If so?
Interesting!
We've reduced ourselves to
being thieves,
but we're a somewhat
famous shinobi clan around here!
Instead of taking your life,
I could hire you if you want!
A ninja, huh...
Then I don't need to go easy on you.
Don't be acting like a big shot, old man!
Shut up, you squirt!
"Ninja" refers to one who endures.
Those who couldn't endure
their hunger pangs
and resort to use their diligently
studied jutsu for stealing
are not called ninja!
I won't let that pass!
Thinking we're fellow shinobi,
we took pity on you.
Acting all conceited!
You'll regret it
after being sliced in two!
Fuma Ninja Blade Zanbato!
Rasengan!
You punk! How dare you
do that to the boss!
We won't let you do
any more than that!
Oh?
Hold it, you guys!
I didn't know you were so good!
That jutsu just now...
I sense you must be
a person of stature!
If it's all right,
may I ask you your name?
If you don't know, then I shall tell you!
Women become infatuated
with his sex appeal.
He's strong against shinobi,
but has a soft spot for women!
He exists in the
Village Hidden in the Leaves...
And made his name known...
Master Jiraiya, that's me!
What?!
You guys bow your heads
and beg for your lives!
We'll all be killed!
- Yes, sir!
Although we didn't know,
being so rude to Master Jiraiya,
reputed as one of the legendary
Sannin of the Leaf Village!
We beg for your forgiveness!
So my name's known
in this land, too...
Well, it's okay.
So is it true that you know about
the Hidden Sound Village?
Yes! There were many ninja clans
in the Land of Rice Paddies,
including us Fuma.
We divided up the roles
amongst ourselves
and the ninja of this land
were doing well in their own way.
Until that man appeared...
Who was that man?
It's regrettable to even speak
of his name...
It was Orochimaru!
It's okay! Rest easy!
If germs get into the wound
and you get tetanus,
you won't be saved.
But fortunately, I have medicine,
so let me treat you.
They're not coming.
Just show us your wound.
Well, huh?
Naruto, go wait outside
till my treatment is done.
Huh?
Why do I have to be
the only one chased out?!
Jeez!
I guess it can't be helped.
Don't peek!
I know.
Okay, show me your wound.
How mean...
To hit me out of the blue...?
Whoa, interesting.
Naruto! You can come in!
What?!
A cute girl?
Sakura! This girl!
Who the heck is this girl?!
How dense. It's the ninja
from a moment ago.
Come to think of it...
Why...?
I am Sasame Fuma.
Sasame...Why were you being
chased by those guys?
If you like, try talking about it.
We might be able to help.
They were Sound Ninja protecting
Orochimaru's residence.
What?!
I'm sorry for mistaking you guys as
one of them the other day.
That doesn't matter!
We're also looking for Orochimaru!
Would you please give us the details?
Okay...
It all started with the Feudal Lord
of the Land of Rice Paddies
launching an attack on
a neighboring land
in an attempt to expand the territory.
The Land of Rice Paddies
is a small land...
And there aren't that many shinobi.
It was a foolhardy attack.
Losing was expected...
And the shinobi clans of this land
who participated in
the losing battle went to ruin...
Including us, the Fuma Clan.
I hear that among
the surviving shinobi,
there are those who have left this land
and those who have
stooped to becoming thieves.
Even so, we've lived believing
in a restoration of the clan
and continued to live hiding
in the shadows.
Back then, an emissary of the Hidden
Sound Village appeared before us
offering to create a full scale shinobi
village in the Land of Rice Paddies.
The emissary of
the Sound Village said...
My master, Orochimaru, is
gathering all sorts of jutsu!
He has taken an interest
in your jutsu well.
Depending on your work,
you might be given the chance
to serve the Feudal Lord!
My cousin, Arashi...
was an up and coming star
in the restoration of the clan...
Arashi,
as a representative of the clan
headed to the Hidden Sound Village
together with the emissary.
But...
And then...?
We waited for a notice from Arashi, but...
There's been no word from him, huh?
Damn it!
He was tricked by that Orochimaru!
Naruto!
Oh...!
Uh, even so, your cousin Arashi
might be safe...
We don't know, right?
And so...and so...
Idiot...!
I'm going to save Arashi!
I have a small body and
my power is weak.
So no matter what I did...
I did nothing but become a hindrance
even in ninjutsu training...
But Arashi always saved me!
Everyone in the village has
already given up, but...
I'll find the
Hidden Sound Village on my own...
And so, you were chased by
the Sound ninja, right?
This time, it's my turn to save Arashi!
Sasame!
I...I want to be of help to Arashi!
Naruto!
Yeah...I know!
We have to go to the Sound Village
to bring back Sasuke anyway, so!
Now, instead of one,
there are two guys
for us to bring back.
I'll save your cousin, Sasame!
Right!
Eew! A spider...
What's this?!
Naruto!
Wha! What's this?!
Ninja Art: Wind Spiders!
My cute children made a path
for me out of silver thread
and told me where you guys
were going.
Now all three of you will descend
into hell while bearing this secret!
Naruto! It's the Ventriloquism Jutsu!
He's scattering his voice
in multiple directions
to cover up his location!
I get it!
I'll leave the girl to you, Sakura!
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Okay! Bring it on from anywhere!
There's a lot of them,
but it's just the Clone jutsu.
No. Look closely, Jigumo!
The threads are getting tangled.
The clones are tangible?!
Shadow clones?!
If so...Kagero!
Understood...
Come out!
Born to be born, lived to live,
one sunrise and one sunset...
The life of a mayfly lasts but one day.
Thinking that such a fleeting life
is pitiable is, in fact, pitiable...
Know that I'm at my best
when living in the dark and
deep in the ground!
Ninja Art:
Ant Lion Jutsu!
Summoning Jutsu!
Naruto! Grab on!
Okay, pull him up!
There, eh?!
Damn! It was a clone?!
Over here!
Time for our counterattack!
Rasengan!
What?!
You little...!
Yes!
Be careful, Naruto!
There are two others hiding!
Hey, there they are!
Kagero!
Let's retreat for now!
Hold it!
Th-They're totally quick
at running away!
Naruto, why're you spacing out?!
Where's Sakura?
Oh! Oh, no!
Sakura!
Oh! Naruto...
Thank goodness!
You're okay, Sasame.
Yes...Sasame's okay.
Sasame's totally okay.
What're you mad about?
Let's take a break here.
Sakura...Who's the cute girl?
Okay! That's close enough...
What's the deal...Sakura?
Don't come any closer!
Wh-What...I'm only interested
in adult women!
You have me all wrong...!
Don't misunderstand!
It's not a misunderstanding.
It seems Sakura's finally figured out
Pervy Sage's true nature!
I told you to stop calling me
"Pervy Sage"!
Then you're the Lewd Sage!
Both of you stop it! Sasame's scared!
- Okay.
Jeez...
This girl is Sasame...
She's a ninja from
the Land of Rice Paddies...
A member of the Fuma Clan.
She had her cousin taken away
by Orochimaru
and was looking for his hideout.
Right. And those ninja just now
were after Sasame
in order to protect the secret
of the hideout!
Oh...the Fuma Clan, huh?
Huh?! You know?
I had contact with ninja in the town
who'd left the Fuma Clan.
What! So you were actually doing
some serious investigating, Pervy Sage?!
I-I can't believe it...!
Well you see, when I went to
this nice looking bar,
it just so happened to be their hideout.
What! So you were just hanging out
with some girls after all, right?
You mustn't talk in a way that'll
lead to a misunderstanding!
Even Sakura who respects me will...
I've long since stopped respecting you!
I...I see...
Members of the Fuma Clan...?
Yeah. The boss was called Hanzaki
or something...
Hanzaki and the others are traitors
who abandoned the clan.
Oh...
Did those people do something?
They were after my travel money,
so I taught them a lesson.
While I was at it, I attempted to
ask them about Orochimaru's hideout...
but they didn't know anything.
I can show you the way to
Orochimaru's hideout.
For real?!
Yes...
All right!
Your wound hasn't healed yet.
Don't push yourself.
Yes...but...
This is the entrance to
the Hidden Sound Village.
Orochimaru's hideout is deep
in those mountains...
I bet Sasuke is
somewhere in those mountains...
Okay, at last!
Let's hurry!
Well, hold on...
Why?!
If we don't hurry, night will fall before
we arrive at Orochimaru's hideout...
That's right!
Sasuke is just a stone's throw away!
Pervy Sage!
If we're going to save him,
we should do it as soon as possible!
Why do we have to wait?!
Huh?
What?
Gee...
Well...I'm hungry, you see...
You know...All shinobi must...
I can't fight if I'm hungry!
We'll be entering full blown
enemy territory.
We won't have time to
have relaxed meals, so...
Okay, you guys eat too!
Mm, this is good...
You prepared this especially for us?
No. It seems the prettiest girl
in the bar fell to my charm, you see.
She made these with tender loving care.
I'll go make some tea.
Oh...thanks...
Tastes pretty good.
Tea is ready.
Here you go!
Here you go.
Thanks...
Thank you, Sasame...
Sasame, you should eat with us too.
Okay...
Pervy Sage...What's wrong...?!
Naruto!
Sasame did it...
Since it's come to this, they're ours.
Your wound still hasn't healed.
Kagero, you wait here.
No mistake...They're Leaf ninja.
If we take care of the Leaf pursuers...
Lord Orochimaru will surely acknowledge
the power of the Fuma Clan.
Yeah...
Let's go back with good news.
And with the heads of
the Leaf ninja as souvenirs!
I finally found it!
At first, I thought it was someone
from the Hidden Leaf Village.
But it's Sasame, believe it or not...
Kamikiri, Jigumo, Kagero...
This is an odd reunion.
Where's Arashi?!
He wasn't with all you guys?!
Arashi is serving near Lord Orochimaru
and is spending his days training.
Can I see Arashi?!
If you're also going to work together
with us for Lord Orochimaru,
I'm sure you'll be able to see him.
How'd it go?
You've done well.
Now I'll be able to see Arashi, right?
After we've finished them off!
Why?! Weren't we just supposed to
take them to Lord Orochimaru
for examination after capturing them?!
We only need the heads
for the examination.
No!
These people...for my sake...!
Move it!
- Wha?!
- Huh?!
What?!
The Fuma numbing medicine
didn't work!
We knew about it all along
from the beginning!
Sakura!
Substitution...?!
I leave Sasame to you!
Right!
Sasame...Hang in there!
Why? Why does Sasame have
to do something like this?!
No, it's not that she's doing it
against her will...
It's something she wanted to do!
Liar!
It's true...
What...
What should I do to be able
to see Arashi again?
It's not a difficult thing.
You just have to bring us the ones
who infiltrated the Land of Rice Paddies.
We have to kill them...?!
We'll take them back to Lord Orochimaru
for examination.
So we're not going to kill, right?
If we carry that out,
Lord Orochimaru will acknowledge us.
Hanzaki says that Arashi and everyone
are being tricked by Orochimaru.
He says that you'll just be used
and thrown away...
Hanzaki's a traitor
who abandoned the village.
Will you believe what we say?
Or will you believe what a traitor says?
Lord Orochimaru will surely restore
our Fuma Clan...
Sasame, although you're still young,
you're also one of the Fuma.
Assist us in the restoration
of our Clan...
So you guys did trick Sasame!
It's all for the restoration
of the Fuma Clan!
You little!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Here I go!
Wha!
U-zu-ma-ki...!
Naruto Barrage!
This is bad...!
Rasengan!
This is for Sasame.
Prepare yourselves!
Naruto!
You're...from before?!
This is the Earth Style user, huh?
However, there's no point to
using it in this rocky area.
Indeed, the Ant Lion appears from
inside the ground
and the spreading of its wings under
the sunlight is
but a momentary gleam.
That's when I die as Kagero!
Be careful!
What's this...?
Look! Naruto...
Wha?!
U-Unbelievable!
You were a woman...?!
The clan will once again be
in a place lit by the sunlight...
Lord Orochimaru promised that...
I'll use this once in a lifetime jutsu
if it's for the sake of that.
Kagero's Ninja Art: Ephemera!
Naruto! Come with me!
Naruto!
I-I feel like...
I've seen this before...
It's the Toad Mouth Trap Jutsu.
I summoned the extraordinarily
sturdy stomach of
Mount Myoboku's
Iwajuku Giant Toad.
Stomach...?
Yikes!
It's melting...
If I didn't do this,
we wouldn't have been able to
defend ourselves from her chakra.
I believed...that the clan
would someday...
I believed in that.
Sh-She vanished.
I've got to hand it to her.
She put her life on the line
and attempted to save her comrades...
It's unforgivable!
Those guys...
the Fuma ninja...
Their feelings toward their clan
are the same as our feelings!
Manipulating the Fuma's desire
to restore their clan...
I'll kick Orochimaru's butt,
no matter what!
Wh-Where are we?
Kagero!
You risked your life to save us?
You idiot...
Please...
Please use your Medical Ninjutsu
to save her.
Our comrade doesn't have
long to live!
Put your hands to your chests and think.
Think about what you weren't
able to accomplish...okay?
We risked our lives working for you...
to help you, Lord Orochimaru.
In order to restore the Fuma Clan!
Please recognize our work!
You'll just have to atone for
your failure with your bodies.
Lord Orochimaru!
I'm sorry for the betrayal!
How did the Pervy Sage,
who was once so easily defeated by
Old Lady Tsunade's numbing medicine
detect Sasame's medicine this time?
Isn't it strange that
Master Jiraiya's that sharp?
Hey, hey...
Remember when Sasame talked
about Hanzaki and said he's a traitor?
That's how I knew...
Hanzaki told me everything...
When Orochimaru came to this land,
there were those among us
who wanted to use his strength
to revive the clan
and those that saw his evil intent
and said we should not join him.
Hmm...so that's why you guys
were chased out of your village.
Yes. It was probably Orochimaru's idea
to chase us out of the village
as traitors who were getting
in the way of reviving the clan.
When Sasame called Hanzaki a traitor,
I knew that Sasame had ties to a group
that was on Orochimaru's side.
Fool!
Hey, Pervy Sage!
Just wait a minute!
I'm prepared!
Sasame, you did it so that
you could meet Arashi...Isn't that right?
I'm sorry...
that was the only thing I could do.
Master Jiraiya!
Sasame did it only because
she wanted to see her cousin.
Please forgive her!
I'm asking you to forgive her too!
The law of the shinobi
is a strict thing...
I can't just acquit her like this.
Then punish me first!
I promised I'd help Sasame
see her cousin Arashi!
If I don't fulfill that I'll have
twisted my Ninja Way!
Master Jiraiya, me too!
Now now, wait a minute!
It's not as if I'm gonna eat her alive.
- Huh?!
- Oh?
Sasame, Hanzaki was worried that
you might leave your village to
look for Arashi...
After you escort us to
Orochimaru's hideout,
you'll immediately head to
the inn where Hanzaki is
and wait there for our return.
That is the punishment given to you.
Master Jiraiya...
Pervy Sage,
I've gotta give you more credit!
Thank you, Master Jiraiya!
Well, Hanzaki treated me to
a lot of special service at the Fuma Bar
and asked me to look after Sasame...
I thought it was something
like that anyway!
I feel cheated that
I gave you more credit!
He, hey...
It's all right once in a while, right?
There's something called
socializing for adults...
There it is...
Leave the rest to us.
Sasame, be careful going back
to the inn.
Don't worry!
I will absolutely bring Arashi back!
Please take care of Arashi!
Leave it to me!
Just wait, and rest assured that
I'll do everything I can!
Stop getting so carried away Naruto,
you idiot!
Oww!
That's where...
Sasuke is...!
So this is the only entrance...
If they're lying in wait,
we'll be picked off.
There's nothing we can do but go!
Well, don't panic.
If three large rats go, we'll stand out.
First, let's send out one
that won't stand out.
Summoning Jutsu!
Hey!
Th-The frog spoke!
Hey, it's been a while!
Sakura, this is Gamakichi.
Gamakichi?!
I wanted to ask you to do
some reconnaissance.
All right! That's a simple task.
Leave it to me!
I can't help it,
frogs give me the creeps...
There doesn't seem
to be anything fishy...
There doesn't seem to be
a trap at the entrance.
Arashi...
There's nothing to it around here.
Hmm...
What shall we do?
It seems there's no choice
but to split up into three.
My instinct tells me
it's the middle one!
Wait!
What the heck?!
At times like this, it's especially
important to move carefully...
All right, I'll go this way!
That's it?!
So what's so different from
my instinct and that, Pervy Sage?
Well, it's a question of feeling...
If you haven't found anything
after 30 minutes, come back.
Got it?
Yeah...
Naruto, Sakura, the two of you
should proceed together.
Listen, from this point forward,
it's the first avenue of hell.
A demon might appear,
or a snake might appear.
Take them on mindfully!
Yup!
I understand!
We're going down the middle!
Then I'm going this way...
See ya...
Hmm...the smell of face powder.
I'm being invited in...
In that case, it might be good fun
to accept the invitation.
What...?
Because guests would be
arriving from far away,
I was directed by Lord Orochimaru
to entertain.
I'm guessing
it's a type of fox raccoon ghost...
If you're saying
I'm some raccoon or fox,
you ought to come over here
and check to see if I have a tail or not.
Oh, this path was right on...
How about yours, Naruto?
Sakura, be careful!
There's no telling what sort
of traps there might be...
Yeah...
- Oh?!
- Naruto?!
And you were the one who
said to be careful!
It was an ingenious trap floor!
Oh!
What the hell is next!
Sakura!
Naruto!
It's my fault...
What the hell...
I can't get out...
What're you doing?!
You screamed in such
a misleading way, I totally thought...
Give me a hand!
You're really a handful!
Ya saved me...
Really! I'll go first!
Naruto...
It's all right now.
Here!
Huh?!
Naruto!
Sakura...
Naruto?! Are you all right?
Don't worry about me.
You need to hurry and
get out of this trap hallway!
But...
I said go! I'll follow behind for sure!
Really?
Yeah...I'll catch up in no time!
You'd better come, no matter what.
It's a promise, you know...
The sake doesn't seem
tampered with.
So what kind of plot has she prepared...?
Just as I'd expect from
the Hidden Sound...
Are you planning to use ninjutsu
on me with music?
The music isn't only for guests.
It's for myself...
I see...
What do you play for your heart?
Music for my own funeral...
Trying to seduce me...
You've underestimated this Jiraiya!
Escorting the guest to
the underworld is my last mission.
A suspended ceiling?!
I need to hurry up
and get out of this place!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
This is torture!
What the hell?!
Give me a hand!
We need to build up our chakra
and create the Rasengan!
Don't be absurd!
We can't stretch
our bodies beyond this!
My muscles are cramping up!
Man! I've gotta do something...
- What!
- Huh?!
What?!
- Water?!
- Water!
Looks like I've been saved.
Hey, get outta my way!
Oh, it's you, Naruto.
Gamakichi, is there
a way out somewhere?
Don't know!
I was flushed down here too.
So it's no good...
Hey, are you all right?
How could I be all right!
Naruto's taking a long time.
Maybe I should go back...
It's admirable that
you made it this far, Sakura.
Is that Kabuto's voice?!
Isn't it ironic?
During the Chunin Exam
in the Hidden Leaf Village,
you were the only one
that dragged the team down,
and yet you're the one
to make it this far.
I'm not by myself!
Naruto and Master Jiraiya
will be here right away!
Where's Sasuke?
He's all right, isn't he?
Shouldn't you be worried about
Naruto and Master Jiraiya,
and not Sasuke?
Well, it may very well be that those two
are no longer in this world anymore.
No way...
There's no way Master Jiraiya and Naruto
would be taken down that easily!
I wonder if that's so?
Maybe you dragged Naruto
down like you always do?
So I'm right...
Naruto...
If you're worried
you should go and see...
Or perhaps you're afraid
of me attacking
and you can't come out
from behind the pillar.
If someone like you were
on my team,
I don't know how many lives
I would need.
I can too...
I can too!
Substitution Jutsu?!
Substitution again?!
I can too...
When I fight, I fight!
As I thought, this is all you've got...
It's about time I put an end to this.
I can't keep Lord Orochimaru waiting
any longer, you see.
Orochimaru?!
No! I'm different from how
I was...back then!
I wonder if that's true...
It can't be...
Even if you put up a bluff,
I can foresee...
You are already...finished.
Poor thing.
This child is trembling
like a puppy
Now, Kabuto...
Get rid of her,
but don't make her suffer.
I understand.
Wait!
Hmm?
Did you...say something?
Wait!
Where's Sasuke!
Where is Sasuke?
It couldn't be that...
your body is already Sasuke's...?
There's no need to keep it
a secret any longer.
It's all right, Kabuto,
go on and tell her.
He was a little late
in getting here.
Lord Orochimaru wasn't able to
wait for Sasuke,
and already had been reincarnated
into another vessel.
So Sasuke is all right?!
Somewhere in this building...
Lord Orochimaru gave Sasuke
the Curse Mark,
so he could wait for
the next opportunity to reincarnate.
But...
Not all humans can
tolerate Curse Marks.
No way, there's no way
that Sasuke could be...
That's right, Sasuke wasn't able
to tolerate the Curse Mark
and so he died.
That's a lie.
It has to be a lie!
What would telling a lie
like that accomplish?
To someone that's going to die,
that is...
If you want to see him that badly
I'll let you see him.
When you die, you can see him
in the afterlife.
Sasuke...
Sakura!
Sakura, don't you believe...
what a guy like him says!
Naruto!
So it's Naruto, I thought you'd drowned
and died a long time ago but...
When I make a promise
I don't give up.
That's my Ninja Way!
I ain't gonna die,
until I get Sasuke back!
This is interesting!
Sakura, go hide!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
I'm over here!
Hey stupid, over here!
Over here, over here!
Where're you looking?
I'm over here! Over here!
What're you doing? Hey!
So you've used up all
your kunai knives...
I'm gonna...completely blow you away!
How annoying!
Fire Style:
Misty Flames Dance Jutsu!
- Ouch!
- That's hot!
- Yikes!
- Oww!
You're too slow!
Rasengan!
Naruto!
Since you and Orochimaru are here,
it means Sasuke is probably here too!
Tell us the truth right now!
Wh-What the heck?
My body won't move...
Have a good look at yourself.
Wh-What's this?
Those are chakra threads.
Chakra threads?
While you were attacking earlier,
I wrapped the thread around you.
Take a good look at where
that thread is connected.
That's right.
Those chakra threads are...
connected to my heart's
chakra network.
And Naruto, the thread that's
wrapped around you
is connected through my chakra network
to your organs and to your heart.
See, can you hear that?
My heart and your heart will
eventually become connected as one!
- Damn!
- Naruto!
It's no use. That thread is formulated
and spun with chakra...
It absolutely will not break.
Now our hearts are
completely synchronized...
The chakra which passes
through this thread
via the chakra network from my heart
is controlling your heart, you see.
It's no use, even though
it's my heart...
If my heart beat gets faster,
your heart will get faster too...
And when my heart stops beating...
You will die too!
Don't! If you stop your heart,
you'll die too!
That's right.
But that doesn't mean much.
Since I've already promised
my body to Lord Orochimaru...
Wh-What the heck are
you gonna do?!
If I crush this heart...
you will die too!
Now, together we will...
Naruto!
How's it feel to have
your heart seized?
It'll be all right...
You'll be out of your misery
right away!
Stop it!
How foolish, if you kill me
Naruto will die too.
What I'm gonna cut...
is this!
There's no use you know,
It's impossible to cut thread formulated
and made from chakra.
Even Lady Tsunade's great strength
wouldn't be able to break it.
What should I...
What should I do?!
Naruto is suffering right
in front of my eyes and yet...
I can't do anything!
Sakura...!
I...absolutely will not lose!
Until I've fulfilled my promise!
Your bravado ends there.
Now, shall we die together?
And go to the place where
Sasuke is waiting?
Naruto!
Sakura!
- Sasame?!
- Sakura...
Stick this tag on a kunai knife!
Naruto!
Naruto?!
Hey, are you okay? Naruto!
No way...
It can't be...
No way!
Naruto!
Ahh...My chest right now
is beating with joy.
Idiot! It was a waste for me
to have worried!
Sorry, Sakura...
You're so worthless!
That's right, Sasame!
Why are you here?
Well, it's...
I was saved by Sasame,
you know.
Me too.
What do you mean?
Water came rushing into that
trap pit we were in earlier...
That's it! The lid to the pit!
Damn!
When the water reached
the ceiling,
I desperately tried to open the lid,
but wasn't able to escape...
I was told by Master Jiraiya
to go to where Hanzaki is.
But I got concerned about Arashi,
so I came...
Naruto!
Hey! Thanks!
Th-The frog spoke...!
Well, come to think of it,
there's no way you could open the lid
of the trap by pushing on it.
Geez!
But how come the thread that
I couldn't cut before,
was cut when I wrapped it
with Sasame's tag?
That's because those
chakra threads
are a secret technique
of the Fuma Clan...
The Fuma?!
I see...
So who the heck is this?!
Oh!
She's...from earlier!
Mistress Kagero...
She's a Fuma jonin.
Sasame!
Sasame...
I was resurrected
by Lord Orochimaru...
You! You're being tricked
by Orochimaru!
Where is Sasuke?
And Arashi?
Where's Sasame's cousin!
Lord Orochimaru is...
going to raise our Fuma clan...
to the center stage
of shinobi again.
You're still talking about
that stuff?!
At least tell Sasame the truth!
So...He's in there!
Sasame and Arashi...
You two were so close...
It'd be better
if you didn't see him.
Mistress Kagero...
What do you want to do, Sasame?
Do you want to wait here?
I will see him!
No matter what's in store for me!
I came all the way here
to see Arashi!
Yeah! You've got guts!
All right! Let's go together!
Yeah! Let's go!
Sasame...
There might be some sort of trap...
Leave it to me!
Orochimaru?!
Good of you to come, Sasame...
Why...?
Arashi...!
Arashi!
Arashi?
I'm no longer...
Arashi...
Wh-What the heck is going on?!
The skills and bodies of the Fuma jonin
were combined into one...
and I've been reborn as
the ultimate ninja you see...
Now, I'll show you
my ultimate ninjutsu...Sasame!
No...Arashi...
Damn, Orochimaru!
Where's Sasuke!
Where did you put him?!
Heh! You're Naruto, right?
You wouldn't believe anything
I said anyway, would you...?
That's right! I won't believe
that Sasuke's dead!
Naruto...
That's right. Sasuke is alive.
I'll bring Sasuke back!
I made that promise!
Naruto...
In that case, take me down!
If I were the wimp I was in the past,
I would probably have
told you the truth.
Arashi!
No! The old Arashi is dead!
The person you see here
is just a block of flesh
kept alive by
Ninja Art: Cadaver Puppets!
Sakura, please look after Sasame!
Stop it, Naruto!
Don't fight with Arashi!
No!
This guy isn't the same gentle Arashi
you once knew, Sasame!
Jigumo! Go!
No!
Sasame! I'm sorry!
Over here!
Naruto!
Don't, Sakura!
Kamikiri...!
Finish him!
Naruto!
You're...next...!
Sakura!
That was close...
I almost let my guard down.
Just when you had a chance
to launch a sneak attack.
You blew it, didn't you, Naruto?
Naruto!
All because of that ball and chain...!
Ball and chain?!
Naruto...I'm sorry!
That's not true at all!
This kind of injury...
is nothing...at all!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
If there's three on your side...
I'll go with five on mine!
Kamikiri!
Naruto!
Are you all right?!
You're badly hurt...
Sakura...This injury is nothing!
"Sakura...This injury is nothing!"
Stop it! If you say more than that...!
I won't say more!
I'll bring this to an end.
Kamikiri! Jigumo!
Give me your chakra...
Boar, Dog, Rat,
Rat, Snake, Rooster, Dog,
Dog, Monkey, Dragon,
Boar, Boar, Rat, Boar, Dragon...
Why does Arashi know that technique?
It's a Hidden Jutsu that only the past
chiefs of the Fuma clan could use...
What was that?!
Fuma Ninja Art:
Spell of the Mandala!
This ain't good!
Naruto!
What the heck is this?!
This is the end!
What?!
Naruto!
The chakra cage gradually shrinks...
And the human enclosed therein
is crushed to the size of a tiny nugget.
You can't break it.
As long as I myself do not
dissolve the jutsu.
Naruto!
I'm incapable of doing anything...
There's nothing I'm capable of doing...
The person I am now isn't...
capable of doing anything!
Arashi!
Sasame...
You!
Sasame!
Please...come to your senses...
Become the old Arashi again!
I told you, already!
The old Arashi is dead.
Arashi...
I'm sorry, Sasame...
I wanted power...
I wanted the Fuma Clan to find
a place in the sun once again...
Yes! I understand that!
I understand that!
But, enough now...
Let's go home.
Let's go back to the village.
But, I'm just a mere monster now...
That's not true!
This is agony...
Sasame...
Please...kill me...
Please...
How dare you try to kill me!
Arashi!
You'll...die!
Sakura!
Sakura?
You wanna be...the first to die?
Sasame taught me that...
dying isn't anything to be scared of!
I see...
But what's scary is to live one's life
without having been able to do anything...
I'm not afraid to die in the service
of someone who is important to me!
Don't!
I'm telling you...
Whatever happens, you mustn't die...
No matter what! Sakura!
Naruto!
Give it up!
What is it you think you're capable
of doing the way you are now?!
You're so useless!
Vanish from this world!
Get crushed into nothing!
Sasame!
Stop that, Arashi!
Sasame...you!
Naruto!
Hey! Let go!
No!
Arashi?!
I'm sorry, Sasame...
I caused you so much hardship...
No, you haven't!
The person who experienced
the greatest hardship is you, Arashi!
Is there anything I can do for you?
What should I do for you?!
You've already helped me
more than enough...
See...Thanks to you, Sasame,
I was able to return to being
the person I was in the past...
Naruto!
Sakura...
Even if it's to be of service
to someone...
There's no life that
should be lost for that!
Yeah!
Run! Sakura!
Pervy Sage!
Sorry to be late!
I was faced with a number of obstacles
on my end too!
Gimme a break...
Now then...
Climb on, climb on!
Hurry! Let's get back above ground!
Oops!
Sasame!
She's fine...She just fainted.
Naruto!
Orochimaru assigned us a mission...
We were to make sure
nobody took Sasuke back
to the Hidden Leaf
under any circumstances!
Then, Sasuke is...?!
Yeah...He's alive!
Orochimaru had to protect Sasuke
because he is his vital vessel which
he will possess in three years!
Arashi...
Arashi...This place is gonna collapse!
Hurry up and come over here!
I'm already just a puppet...
I cannot live my life anywhere
except here.
Arashi...
All right!
No! Arashi!
Sasame...
Thank you.
Including Arashi,
we've paid an extraordinary price but...
The Fuma Clan has been
able to cut itself free
from Orochimaru's spell...
You can start again anew.
I will rebuild the
Clan again without fail!
With this life...
that Arashi protected.
Yeah!
I am truly indebted to you.
Sasame...
Hanzaki, I'm leaving these two
in your hands!
Yes, sir!
Please take care along the road!
I will.
- Thank you!
- We thank you!
- Take care!
- See you again!
Hey! Hang in there!
Well, we weren't able
to find Sasuke,
but at least we now know
that he's alive somewhere...
We'll have to settle for the fact
that we were able to ascertain
the new information that we still have
a grace period of three years
before he becomes a vessel
to be possessed by Orochimaru.
Yes...
Sasame knew what she needed
to do for her clan...
But this time again all I did was cry.
All I did was depend on Naruto...
Sakura!
You gave your best effort too!
No, I was just a ball and chain
to everyone...
I wasn't capable of doing
anything alone...
That's not true!
Seeing you give your best effort
gave me a lot of courage, Sakura.
If you hadn't been there, Sakura,
I'd have been crushed just like that.
It's thanks to you, Sakura!
Naruto...
Wow, you've grown into someone
who can say that sort of thing!
Oww! I'm an injured man!
Treat me with a little more care!
Oh yeah, that's right!
What I'm capable of
doing right now...
I was thinking...
What?
There are many variables such
as mission level,
or platoon's member structure...
But no matter how small
a platoon might be,
I think it's important to assign
one Medical Ninja to it...
I know that already...
I wrote exactly the same thing
in a report long ago
regarding the survival rate and mission
achievement rate of small platoons.
But it's not that easy to
nurture Medical Ninja.
They require a different set of skills
than that of fighting ninja...
The minute perfection
of chakra control,
the ability to assimilate a huge volume
of specialized knowledge,
the brains to apply that in a broad way...
patience...
And the most important thing
for shinobi who are to develop
into a Medical Ninja...
Well, I'm busy right now, so...
The most important thing...huh?
I'm all wrapped up in bandages again...
This way I can't even
hold chopsticks...
Sakura, when it's time for
my meal, feed me, okay?
I'll open up my mouth
just like this and...
Huh? Sakura?
I'm sorry! I was just joking!
I'm sorry...Naruto...
Huh?
This is gonna mean that
I'll keep you waiting a little but...
Next time, I definitely won't...
be a ball and chain to you!
Huh?
Enter!
I came here with a request!
What is it?
Please make me your apprentice!
You're very desperate, aren't you?
Sakura Haruno,
I heard from Kakashi that you have
a brilliant mind as well as will power!
All right.
But in exchange,
I'm not gonna be easy on you!
Yes, ma'am!
This recent mission...
looks like it wasn't wasted
on her, after all.