Summoning Jutsu!
Oh, long time no see.
We don't have much time
to get nostalgic.
We've got a mission.
That's the
Village of Artisans, isn't it?
Yeah. It's a village of professionals
who develop ninja tools.
The exceptional ninja tools
they develop are also
supplied to us
in the Five Great Nations...
But there's been
a strange rumor recently.
A strange rumor?
Something about them developing
an ultimate weapon
and attempting to antagonize
the Five Great Nations.
In other words, we should
search the village and
verify whether or not
there is such a weapon, right?
That's about the size of it.
Piece of cake.
Hey! Something strange is going on.
What is it?!
There's not a soul in the village!
I also found something terrible
on top of that.
What?!
It's that.
The coffin of Seimei, the founder of
the Village of Artisans.
Even his body is...
This is serious.
The artisans abandoned their village.
Where in the world did they go?
I'm hungry, I'm hungry!
Maybe I'll treat myself and have
two eggs in my ramen today.
Huh?
What's going on there?!
Did I keep you waiting by any chance?
Not really. I just got here.
That's good...Then, here.
I made sure to hand deliver it to you.
Yeah, yeah. What a pain.
Just a minute!
What're you guys doing...
all in secret in a place like this
without even asking me?!
- Naruto?
- Huh?
You're terrible, just terrible, Sakura!
Here you won't even go out
on a date with me at all!
Why're you talking gibberish
all of a sudden?
Ouch ouch ouch ouch...
An errand for the Old Lady?
Yes. It seems a new poison
was discovered or something.
I delivered a list of
research medicinal substance
for Shikamaru's father to prepare.
Oh, that's it?!
Jeez, you jump to conclusions.
Oh, come to think of it,
an update report from Temari
has been delivered to Lady Tsunade.
An update report?
So? What exactly?
I heard that the Hidden Sand Village
started ninja education,
imitating the curriculum program
of the Leaf's.
It seems that Temari and her brothers
are working as instructors.
Instructors?!
Is that harsh woman fit to be
something like an instructor...?
Really? Gaara, huh?
This is hands on training.
Choose a ninja tool that suits you
from this selection.
What is it?
Do we absolutely have to choose?!
What do you mean?
We'll end up hurting each other
if we use a weapon.
We might kill them.
A weapon is...
No, never mind...
A mission isn't a game.
If you were to enter a field of battle
with that frame of mind, you'd die.
I-I'm sorry.
You got Gaara angry because
you ask stupid questions.
You're in trouble.
The three of us will conduct
hands on training.
Gather in the respective class
of your choice.
Gaara, put on a smile!
They'll get scared and nobody will
choose you with that sulky look.
My dad said that Gaara
was the Sand's ultimate weapon.
Yeah. He's so powerful that the village
would be destroyed if he got mad.
He's scary, so let's not bother.
All right, I'm with Temari.
I'll be with Kankuro!
- Me too!
Please be my teacher.
Earlier, he was trying to
teach me something...
Excuse me...Please be my teacher.
Are you okay with me?
Please teach me!
This is cool.
That's too big!
I'll take this.
What's your name?
I'm Matsuri.
Matsuri, choose a weapon.
What's the matter?
Come at me with that weapon
with the intent to kill me.
Yes, sir...
They say an ogre with an iron club
is invincible. But you are no ogre.
Yes, sir. Please tell me
what I should choose.
The weapon called the rope javelin.
Rope javelin...
The sharp blade on the end of the rope
is to keep an enemy out of one's reach,
rather than for attack.
And you seal off an enemy's movement
with the rope.
Practice until you can control it
as a part of your body.
Yes, sir!
Damn. Who are you guys?!
Is this all
the Sand Village shinobi can do?
Wait.
Leave this guy alive.
We can use him to draw that one out.
Hang in there! What is it?!
What happened?
Take me to Gaara...Quickly.
What's the matter?
My mother and father were hit with
countless weapons right in front of me.
So I...
For what purpose
do you hold a weapon?
He...
What are...
...these two to you?!
Th-These guys are...
...my friends!
Try laying so much as
another finger on them!
I'll clobber you!
He said that to me.
That's what we're after: Gaara.
Gaara, we were
just coming to get you.
The patrol ninja were
attacked by somebody.
Guys calling themselves
the Four Celestials,
brandishing strange weapons,
said to tell Gaara that...
"We declare a challenger to you,
the ultimate weapon.
If you don't accept the challenge,
we will take one person
close to you every day...
and they shall
pay the price for you."
You there.
Are you Gaara's student?
You shall be the first sacrifice.
What's this rope javelin?!
Wait!
The enemy went northeast...
Matsuri has become the first sacrifice...
But the real target of that group is...
you, Gaara.
Yeah...
This must be brought to
a jonin council at once...
The Four Celestials left
towards the northeast.
The Hidden Leaf Village
is in that direction,
with the Land of Rivers
sandwiched between.
Therefore, we will be requesting
the assistance of the Leaf...
Temari, Kankuro, Gaara.
Form a unit and prepare for
pursuit immediately.
Hold it.
The enemy is after Gaara.
We might be walking
right into a trap.
That's right.
Why won't you send a party?!
It might be a diversionary tactic
by the enemy.
The village will become shorthanded
if we send out pursuers.
Then you at least could
come with us, right, Baki?!
Hey, how about it?!
I've been given
a different mission, you see...
Go. She's your student, right?
Let's go, Kankuro.
Will it be okay with her?!
She's just a kid.
Will he come?!
If he doesn't come, we'll just sacrifice
those close to him one after another.
That is...?
It's a message from the Sand Village!
Gaara? Why?
Who knows?
The goal is a challenge to Gaara.
The hostage is a
ninja school student.
The enemy is escaping in the direction of
the Land of Fire from the Land of Rivers.
Gaara, Temari and Kankuro are
chasing after them.
At this point, that's all we know.
You want me to set up an operation
to stop the overconfident jerks
who challenged Gaara
just with that information?
Yeah. We're on friendly terms
with the Sand Village, so.
Just a minute.
They came during the Sasuke incident
with much less information than this.
Things are more bothersome
than that time!
Our range would widen significantly
if we ambushed them
instead of pursuing them.
There's also the incident in question
in the Village of Artisans,
and the jonin and chunin
are all away...
- Shizune...
- Yes, ma'am!
Those are the only genin
we can use now.
Take the genin you want to use
and leave the village
within thirty minutes!
Sakura's name isn't on here.
Yeah. She's doing
Medical Ninjutsu training now, so.
I'll accept the mission.
But I have one condition.
Please let me borrow Sakura.
Sakura?
It's almost time!
Is this everyone, Shikamaru?!
One person still hasn't come.
Could that be...?
Sorry to keep you waiting!
I can't do a mission hungry.
So I stopped by Ichiraku for a bit.
What?! That's not fair just you
getting to eat! I'll also...
All right! Now we've got
all our members together! We're off!
Huh? What? This is it?!
I'd heard this was an operation
with a mobilization
of the genin
remaining in the village!
That's right, this is everyone!
That's messed up!
Setting aside Sakura, who's training,
there should still be
Shino, Neji and Hinata!
No mistake. It's weird that
Akamaru and I are the only ninja
with tracking abilities.
So is this team
a go for it super attack type?
Yeah. I name us
Team Return the Favor.
What lame naming!
The guys from the Sand Village
helped us during the Sasuke incident!
In a manner, this operation will be
returning the favor from that time!
All right! Guys, let's make sure to
return the favor from that time.
You're not the leader!
Shikamaru, the chunin, is the leader
of this platoon, right?!
That's right...
Jeez, then let's settle on a strategy
and get going as soon as possible.
Are we going in one line
as we did for the Sasuke incident?
There's no doubting that the conditions
are similar to the Sasuke incident.
However, the strategies for pursuit
and ambush are completely different!
We can't follow them with Byakugan
or by using Akamaru's nose.
No mistake about that.
It's unconventional, but since these are
all the people we've got,
we'll act in groups of two basis
as Two Man Cells.
Solo action is prohibited
no matter what the case!
We owe a debt to the ninja in
the Sand Village.
However, although this is to repay a debt,
no way will we produce casualties!
Yeah, I got it.
- Follow me, Ino.
- Right!
Choji, you go with Kiba...
I'm counting on you, Choji, Akamaru.
Right...
Lee, you're with Naruto...
Right. Please refrain
from selfish actions.
You don't need to tell
me something like that.
Also, the four people Naruto mentioned
earlier have left before us.
Four people? Do you mean
Shino, Neji, Hinata and Sakura?
Yeah. Those four will be
going their separate ways
and won't take part in future battles!
Why not?!
Isn't that an incredible waste
of battle strength?!
In place of that, we get a wider range
of search action...
And we'll have them focus on
medical aid if we engage in battle.
I have been entrusted with your lives
and this is my strategy!
All right, just wait, Gaara!
I'll make sure to return the favor!
So, Kujaku? What's going on
with our pursuers?
Yeah, we went to the trouble of
leaving footprints as we go.
We need them to follow.
It'll be okay. They'll be within
firing range in no time!
There are three pursuers.
One of them is Gaara!
As for the extra two, we'll leave one
behind
and deal with them with
them one on one...
I'll isolate Gaara and drive him into
the Reverse Scale Position.
I'll take the first person.
All right, go.
Hey, Shikamaru.
What's the matter?
We'll stand by here for a while.
Stand by?
We don't have time fooling around
in a place like this!
Be quiet for a second, Naruto.
That's right.
Shikamaru's got a proper plan.
Right, right. Naruto, you have to
be sure to obey the leader.
Fine.
Shino, I'm counting on you.
It's not necessary to drive him
into the Reverse Scale Position.
There are only three of them.
I can handle them by myself.
Flying Kujaku Double Edge Sword:
Whirlwind!
What?!
What is this?
A wind user, huh?
Interesting!
- Splendid.
- Not bad, Temari.
Naturally.
Not half bad.
To think you'd blow away my Whirlwind.
What, you're still just a kid?
- You guys go on ahead.
- What?
Hey, Temari. You okay with this?
Will you be okay?
Well, we're fellow wind users.
I should be able to handle her alone.
Hurry, Gaara.
She's your student, right?
Thanks.
- I'm counting on you.
- Be careful.
Right.
You won't get away.
I'm your opponent.
Cyclone Scythe Jutsu!
Wind Slash!
This wind is...
These double swords alter the wind
at my will to suit the attacks
and amplify the power to the extreme.
It's too late to regret.
I only need a little bit of chakra
as long as I have these swords.
How long can you persevere with
the limited chakra you have?
How about testing that out?
Matsuri.
We caught up.
Where are we?
So you're awake?
Heh. You're like prey plunged on
a branch by a shrike.
You're the bait to lure him out.
What?
Gaara Sensei.
Dragon Eye: Fang Release: Dark Sword.
What?
Damn it.
Did you see that? This is the Dragon Eye:
Fang Release: Dark Sword.
It can look like a living snake
depending on how it's controlled.
But there's no point
once it's been identified.
We both use puppets but,
compared to mine, his is just a kid's toy.
Go, Gaara.
Can I leave it to you?
Yeah. I don't need your help for this.
I'll catch up right away.
I'm counting on you.
Now, bring it on. I'll play with you.
What're you doing acting tough?
You'll die if you take me lightly!
That goes for you too!
Then die, Kabuki makeup jerk!
Here I go.
That's no good.
Come on, that was too easy.
Too bad. This sword
isn't just an adjustable sword.
The sword itself amplifies chakra
in response to my chakra
and changes into the form of a dragon.
Gaara, I'm sorry.
This might take a little time.
Suiko, you ambush him here.
Draw him into
the Reverse Scale Position. Got it?
Yeah...
You won't get through here.
Gaara, fight me.
Very well.
Bring it.
Hey, Shikamaru. How long are we
going to stay like this?
Shut up. There are many difficulties
with ambushes.
Right now, Shino, Neji and Hinata
are taking on those difficulties for us.
What? They are?
Did you find them?
Byakugan!
In that direction, right?
Got it. There are three battle areas.
It's the scent bag of
the female Parasitic Insects.
With this, the insects will find you
no matter where you go.
Right. I'm counting on you, Shino.
Then, we'll be going on ahead.
Be careful!
Oh, information has arrived.
I was getting sick of waiting!
All right, I'm counting on you guys.
This is bad.
It's already begun.
All right, Kiba and Choji,
you take the western forest.
Ino and I will
take the northeastern hills.
Naruto and Lee, you take
the northwestern forest.
We'll take on back up
in two man cells.
Now then, let's begin
the favor-returning operation.
- Right.
I was waiting for this time!
Scatter.
What is it?
Hold up.
If these guys are taking them
on one on one,
and the battle area isn't
a straight line, then...
Could it be a barrier?
What?
Just to be safe.
That should do it. Let's go.
Right.
Now, there's nowhere left to hide.
What will you do?
To think she'd evade all of my attacks.
Since it's come to this, I've just got to
use that technique!
Wind Style: Sea Dragon!
What's that? Nothing's happening.
How pitiful. It seems the wind
doesn't like you.
I don't know about that.
The wind is my friend.
This battle is just starting.
Wind Reversal!
Die!
Damn it! Hey, let go!
Done already? I thought
we could play a little more...
That's the spirit!
What kind of toy is it this time?
That's funny. You think you can
defeat me with junk like this?
The junk is your sword.
What?! A three headed dragon!
You're just quick to escape, eh?
Damn it...
Sure enough,
Crow is at a disadvantage
unless teamed up with Black Ant.
Not bad, Gaara of the desert.
How much chakra is built up
in that sand?
You want to find out?
However...
It'll be in exchange for your life.
Sand Coffin!
Impossible.
That's a nice sand bath.
You, the sand's chakra...
Exactly. This armor sucks up chakra.
Aw, is this good night?
That's it, keep sleeping...
For all eternity!
What?!
That was a close shave,
but Shadow Possession
was a success!
Die already!
Uh, oh!
What?
You guys.
Who are you?
Who are you guys?
- An ally of the Sand.
Guys, fight as much as you want.
I don't see any chakra
abnormalities in the basin...
There's no barrier.
Good luck, guys.
I'll protect you.
Gaara Sensei.
I'll take care of all of you at once!
Here it comes!
To think you'd ask
the Leaf Village for help...
I guess the Sand has lost the edge
they used to have, huh?
Why are you here?
You know, dogs...
They're not satisfied until a favor
has been properly returned.
Especially Akamaru!
A dog retuning a favor doesn't
have much of a ring to it!
Help is on the way to
the other two as well.
You concentrate on this fight!
You're giving me lip!
So you flies are gonna gang up
on me, huh?
But you're no match for my Dragon Eye:
Fang Release: Dark Sword.
Eat this!
If your chakra isn't built up,
your sand is no big deal at all!
It'll only be useful for
blinding me at best!
It's futile!
I feel it.
Your chakra is being sucked up.
What?! He was setting the sand
in the gourd aside?!
I was being cautious,
but he is just too strong.
Just what I'd expect from
Gaara of the Sand.
He's not called the ultimate weapon
for nothing...
The ultimate...weapon?
However, he cannot exceed
our ninja tools,
forged in the Village of the Artisans!
Gaara!
Hey, he's totally got the edge!
Do we have a chance to
return the favor?
That's incredible wind.
What an amount of chakra...
No, it seems that sword is
amplifying her chakra.
So she's relying on that sword for
all of her attack and defense, huh?
We've got to slip within
firing range for our jutsu
and stop her movements!
Right.
Let's go at once!
Annoying!
She's attempting to maintain
her distance just from Temari.
I see.
So she just wants to pay attention
to the long range type Temari and
blow us mid range jutsu users
away with wind
before we can get close, huh...?
Now then, what should we do?
Man Beast Clone!
Partial Expansion Jutsu!
Crow!
- Arms!
- Fang Over Fang!
Did you guys come to
get in my way?!
We made sure to send you
a signal, right?!
How could I tell?!
We don't click at all?
Are you guys...messing around?!
Be more serious and die!
Talking nonsense!
Although I reduced the damage
with my Infinite Kujaku Armor, still...
Just what I'd expect of Gaara,
the Sand's ultimate weapon,
host to the Shukaku...
But you're already in our hands.
What should I do?
She's beyond the range of my jutsu...
and I don't see anything around here
that could be used to extend my shadow.
Hey!
What're you whispering about?
What're you thinking?!
For crying out loud. I'll explain later.
Can you do it or not?
I suppose I could try, but...
What the...?
What's he doing?
Behold the terror of the ninja tools
our village created.
What's this chakra?
This is a water vein!
I get it!
The lines connecting the point
in the center isn't a barrier...
It's a water vein!
Ninja Tool Barrier:
Reverse Scale Formation - Activate!
Oh no!
The aim of the Reverse Scale Formation
was always a single point, Gaara!
Our swords accurately pierce
a water vein
and summon the water dragon.
Sand has sucked up
a large amount of water
and has become as heavy as lead...
Now Gaara can no longer use sand.
Gaara!
- Gaara!
- Calm down!
Lee and Naruto are heading for Gaara!
They are?!
They'll save Gaara,
no matter what.
We need to concentrate on
the enemy in front of us.
To think you'd choose
a sandy area to fall on...
Just what I'd expect of Gaara
of the desert...
However!
That's as far as
your useless resistance goes!
Leaf Hurricane!
A hero always comes late!
That's right!
Sorry to keep you waiting, Gaara!
Naruto!
It seems you rushed to everyone
during the Sasuke incident...
This time we've come to return
the favor from back then.
So we'll take that guy on!
You hurry to your student up ahead!
To think he'd corner you like this...
- Lee!
- Sakura!
Leave Gaara's treatment to me!
Lee, you go with Naruto!
- Sakura!
- Got it!
Then I'll be going first!
Be careful. His armor sucks up chakra!
I'll suck up all of your chakra!
I see. So this means we can't
release our regular abilities?
That doesn't matter!
Even without chakra,
we've got fighting spirit!
Yes! We'll go with that
plus willpower!
Just as I thought.
The fact they haven't launched any
attacks during the fight means
the two reinforcements don't
have long range jutsu.
In that case...
I'll maintain this distance and...
You'll die getting torn up by the wind!
While she's distracted by Shikamaru
and the others,
I'll just go for it!
Mind Destruction...!
Ino!
Foolish girl. It's useless to attempt
to exploit an opening!
You little!
You won't get close to me!
I've read your range as well!
I don't know about that...!
Ino! You stay right there!
I'm counting on you...
Shino! Sakura!
There's one wounded
at the waterfall.
Tunneling Fang!
Now!
Partial Expansion Jutsu!
Oh...!
What're you doing?!
Are you guys...mocking me?
After sucking up all of your chakra,
I'll be returning the favor plenty!
The contusion treatment is complete.
But, the depletion of chakra
is overwhelming.
Contact from your friends?
- Ino's hurt?!
- Go!
Wha?! But in your condition...
I'm okay now. Help your friend!
Okay. Don't push yourself.
Yeah...
What're you doing?!
Hurry up and go after your comrade!
I'll help my comrade.
I'll settle this in a moment.
But...
Bushy Brow!
Damn it. It's no good
just shot gunning it!
It's just him?
A part of Black Ant...
Could it be...a signal?
Fang Over Fang once more!
Back me up with Crow!
I'm counting on you
for back up too, Choji!
Got it!
Heh! Bossing me around.
Our counterattack starts now!
It's futile.
Your jutsu won't reach me!
You never know
until you try, right?
Here we go!
Wind Style: Cyclone Scythe!
Huh?!
What're you aiming at?!
Totally misguided...
Say what?
What's the meaning of this?
I'm sure I read your range already!
I'll show you!
I can create a shadow with
this thick a current
even if the water's clear.
My jutsu's range has infinitely
improved by lifting the waterfall!
Shadow Possession
is a success!
Summoning...
Blade Dance!
This one's done!
Good grief...
I...couldn't do anything.
Everyone's doing their best...
Only I...
Ino?
Gaara.
You don't have any sand
left you can use.
What's this?!
He smashed the Sand Armor.
No way! But the sand's
heavy with water...
If I just suck up your chakra, then...
This is my weapon!
You okay, Gaara?!
This is the finishing blow...
Gaara Sensei!
Hurry! Leave the rest to us!
Man Beast Clone!
Fang Over Fang!
Partial Expansion Jutsu!
Annoying buzzing flies!
Dragon Eye: Fang Release: Dark Sword!
What?!
Oh, no!
Puppet Show...
Secret Black Move Iron Maiden!
The show's over!
- We did it!
- Yeah!
Matsuri.
Gaara and...
A shinobi carrying a child on his back.
He's heading for the valley.
The last one...
Gaara is chasing him!
What?!
You okay, Bushy Brow?
Sakura will be right back.
Thanks.
Well, I'm going after Gaara!
Got it! I'll meet up with you later!
This is as far as you go.
Give Matsuri back.
You think you've got me cornered now?
Don't get the wrong idea.
You're the one who's been cornered!
What?
Byakugan!
He has the final enemy cornered
in a dead end valley.
The area around the valley
is eerily calm.
I don't see his comrades.
Is Shikamaru's final move finished?
No.
We can't state definitively that
they've reached a deadlock.
It's possible that
the battles thus far were diversions...
Just a little more, Lee.
It'll be over once I connect
two or three more muscles.
Sakura's Medical Ninja technique
is really becoming...
And yet I...
The treatment is over for now.
How do keep ending up like this?
I'm sorry.
You saved me.
Thank you, Sakura.
You're welcome.
Oh, you can't, yet.
As a Medical Team member,
I prohibit you from fighting any further.
No, please let me go.
I can't just leave Gaara like this...
We're Team Return the Favor, after all.
Gaara, you may very well be
called the ultimate weapon,
but have you not used up all of
your sand in the fight earlier?
This is my weapon.
Indeed, I have used up almost all
of the sand with chakra built up inside.
But...
No matter what jutsu you use,
I can't lose in a one on one battle.
There's nothing scary about
a shinobi with no weapon!
Come, Infinite Kujaku Armor!
Fang Release: Dark Sword!
Flying Double Edge Sword!
You'll realize that the likes
of a mere ninja
is no match for the ninja tools
created by us artisans.
Fang Release: Dark Sword!
It seems your own body's chakra
has run out.
You're carrying
a monster inside you, right?
Now, isn't it about time
you used the power of the Shukaku?
You okay?
Gaara Sensei is...
Yeah, I know.
Listen up.
You go hide somehwere safe.
Right.
Although Gaara received
Sakura's treatment, he's still...
That's as far as you go,
ultimate weapon of the Sand Village!
Damn it.
Use the power of the Shukaku already.
Hey!
Hold it!
Who are you?
I'll be your opponent from here on.
You're in the way, boy.
Kujaku Hurricane!
Damn it!
Just watch, Leaf shinobi.
The era of control by
the Five Great Nations will end.
No, it won't be just that.
If the ultimate ninja tool created by
the Artisan Village is completed,
the existence of the ninja
will no longer be necessary.
What're you talking about?!
We are people from the Village
of Artisans who for many years
have equally shared
exceptional ninja tools
with you in the Five Great Nations.
However, each time relations
worsened between fellow villages,
the Village of Artisans would be attacked
over fear of ninja tools crossing
over to the other village.
You ninja of the Five Great Nations
have forgotten
that you are kept alive by our power,
and have returned the favor
with vengeance time and again.
Although we have advanced skills,
we have had to survive by currying favor
from the Five Great Nations!
However, that era will now end!
First, I will take out the Leaf Village.
Fang Release Dark Sword!
How long can you run away for?
I'll stake you like a shrike!
What?!
You!
That dome's created with hard minerals
in the ground mixed with sand...
It can't be smashed by such junk.
I'll protect him until the end...
with my power!
Don't make me laugh!
You, who are called the greatest creation
of the Sand, a terrifying weapon,
are going to protect someone else?
And you're going to use
what little chakra you have left
for the sake of a comrade?
That will be your death!
With this,
all preparations are complete.
Damn it!
Oh!
We were contacted by someone
from the Village of Artisans.
It seems ones calling themselves
the Four Celestials,
bearing long withstanding hostilities
against the Five Great Nations...
have completed forbidden research and
are attempting to resurrect
the ultimate weapon of folklore
in their village...
It seems the villagers caught
wind of the crisis
and have evacuated to
a different location.
I see. So that's why the village
was completely empty.
So what exactly is this ultimate weapon?
The resurrection of Seimei,
the founder of the Village of Artisans.
Seimei?!
Are you saying
they're trying to raise the dead?!
I see. That explains why
the mausoleum was violated.
As for us, we must prevent
the resurrection
of the ultimate weapon at all costs.
I understand. I'll be off.
Oh, hold on.
Yes?
I'll be having one more person
accompany you on this mission.
What? Who would that be?
What we wanted was
the Shukaku's chakra.
What did you say?
How we've waited for this...
Now Gaara, release the Shukaku now!
And infuse me with that power.
Gaara!
I'll save you now.
Naruto!
Matsuri, take this.
My rope javelin.
The optic nerves have connected...
Open...
third eye!
Hey, you.
What the heck do you intend to do?
Create the ultimate ninja tool
with Lord Seimei,
the founder of our Village of Artisans.
Ultimate ninja tool?
Now is the time of its completion.
Gaara!
Oh, Lord Seimei.
Please take possession of my flesh
and complete your resurrection!
Oh!
What's going on? He vanished.
The dead body came back to life!
I am Seimei.
The founder of the Village of Artisans.
A hundred years have passed and
I have now been resurrected
as the ultimate ninja tool
of the Village of Artisans!
What in the world is happening?!
My long awaited wish has at last
come to fruition.
With this, my Village of Artisans
will reign over the shinobi apex!
I see...
So the monster from the Sand Village
became the source of my power.
Say what?
Hoko said this.
There is a monster lying
within the body
of the one called Gaara
from the Sand Village.
Once that person is in a cage,
soon he will become
a complete monster, the Shukaku.
I will take away what you could
consider infinite chakra from the Shukaku.
I won't let you do that!
Damn it!
Just wait, Gaara.
I'll get you out now.
What a waste...
Vortex Wind.
I'm just getting started!
What a fool!
I'll get you out now!
Damn it, damn it!
Gaara! Can you hear my voice?!
Gaara, answer me!
What's going on in there?!
Gaara!
N-Naruto...
Shikamaru!
What?
Where are Gaara and Naruto?
Neji, Hinata, tell me the situation.
There's a cage behind an area
surrounded by rocks...
There's a massive amount of chakra
being extracted from there.
Gaara must be inside.
Hey, Shikamaru!
What?
You know there's a terrifying power
lying dormant inside Gaara, right?
Yeah, generally.
Something terrible will happen...
if Gaara has chakra extracted like this
and he loses himself!
The Shukaku that had been kept
under control will go out of control.
Once it starts going berserk,
there will be no way to stop Gaara.
For real?
I must not waste any more time.
This entertainment ends here.
Hot-hot-hot-hot.
Damn it! Just wait, Gaara!
I'll get you out now!
You're a pest!
Give it up already!
I'm just getting started!
Solid Blanks!
Oh, how I have waited for this.
Now, Shukaku! Give me power!
I feel it. This is an amazing power!
Cut out the futile resistance.
The power of the Shukaku
is already mine!
I declare war on the Five Great Nations!
The shinobi in the Five Great Nations
who made light of the Artisan shinobi
will fully realize the 100 year grudge
of the Artisan ninja.
And they will inevitably
become our sacrifices.
Knock it off!
What?!
We won't hand over our power
to the likes of you.
I won't let you take away any more
of Gaara's chakra.
You got that?!
Why do you go this far, kid?
What is the monster of
the Sand Village to you?
Gaara...
Gaara is an important comrade to me!
He said he fights for
those important to him.
Very well. Then die!
What're you doing, little girl?
I finally figured out what
Gaara Sensei taught me.
Weapons took away the lives
of my mother and father.
But I can also protect those important
to me with a weapon!
Foolishness.
Damn it!
It has finally begun, huh...?
Gaara Sensei...
Gaara!
Gaara.
So this is the Shukaku?
It's the first time I've seen
the real thing...
It's dangerous here!
We have to get away!
But! Gaara Sensei...
Shut up.
Gaara is trying...to protect you!
So hurry!
R-Right.
Hey! Could that be?!
Yeah...
The Shukaku transformation
is starting.
Gaara...
Naruto!
Hinata, Sakura.
Matsuri, you okay?
Y-Yes. But Gaara Sensei...
I leave her to you...
Hold it! You're badly hurt!
But...
You'll become unable
to move as soon as you start!
I'll give you some first aid treatment!
R-Right...
What's the meaning of this?
What is it, Neji?
That guy wearing the armor is
releasing chakra stronger than Gaara...
who's half transformed into a beast.
That person called himself Seimei,
the creator of the Village of Artisans.
He said something about being reborn
as the ultimate ninja tool.
That jerk!
He's taking away Gaara's chakra!
Come to think of it, the enemy
we fought wore similar armor...
and took away a great deal
of my chakra.
Armor that sucks up chakra...
And that alarming form...
It doesn't look like
we can just carelessly get close.
Great...What do we do?
I didn't plan on fighting
against the Shukaku...
However, this is quite fun.
As great as the Shukaku may be,
this way, I can prove that
it's no match for the ultimate ninja tool
of the Village of Artisans.
Why is this guy so strong?
I won't allow my friends...
to get hurt!
I will stop you,
even if that means that
I have to kill you!
Why...?
How is it that you can fight
so much for other people...?
They saved me from
the hell of being all alone.
They accepted me for
who I was...
that's why...
they are important to me!
Love is a heart that desires to serve
a precious person who is close to oneself,
and to love and watch over that person...
Love...
That is why he is so strong?
Gaara!
What's that?
Gaara Sensei is returning to normal?
What happened to him?!
Gaara might be suppressing
Shukaku of his own volition.
Why? Wouldn't he end up weakening
his own battle strength?
Even so, he chose to fight
with his own strength and will,
not Shukaku's power,
which he can't control.
So you couldn't maintain
the Shukaku body with that chakra?
I'll...help the friends important
to me with my own power...
How absurd.
A shinobi doesn't need emotion.
It is those who suppress their emotions
who can obtain great power.
Great power.
That power is the only justice.
You're finished now.
Eat this!
That's as far as you go,
monster of the Sand Village.
Acting tough, huh?
You shouldn't have
any chakra left to fight with.
Indeed, I only have a little bit
of chakra left...
But do you think I just sat around
in that cage doing nothing at all?
What?!
Sand Tsunami!
You shouldn't have
any sand you can control!
I'm Gaara of the desert!
It's simple for me to crush rocks
and turn them into sand.
Kujaku: Hurricane Formation!
So you still had
that much power left, huh?
Then I'll just suck up
all of that power!
Gaara's chakra is being sucked out!
- Wha?!
- Gaara Sensei!
- Damn it!
- Wait! Naruto!
What, Shikamaru? Don't stop me!
You'll just get in the way if you go!
Besides, Gaara is strong!
Gaara...
Extreme Tempered Ultimate Attack:
Shukaku's Pike!
Wh-Why...Why can you...?
Someone who gave up on being human
and was reborn as a ninja tool
could never understand anyway.
I don't understand. Why?
Why?!
Giant Sand Burial!
He did it!
Gaara Sensei won!
Yeah! Gaara!
- Gaara!
He's okay...
He's just extremely fatigued
on account of using
his chakra all at once.
Gaara completely suppressed
the Shukaku on his own volition.
Yeah...
We came to the trouble
of rushing here.
To think it'd be over...
It seems
the inexperienced knuckleheads
have grown a teeny weeny bit...
You are very strict.
Pervy Sage!
Oh, long time no see, Naruto.
Don't give me that "long time no see"
garbage, you jerk Sage!
You were talking all big about
watching my training,
making me into your protege
and stuff!
Where were you traipsing
around until now?!
Well, how can I put this?
I was gathering information.
It was probably just information
on naked ladies anyway, right?
You idiot!
Even I come through when it counts...
I was mainly after information
on the Akatsuki.
Akatsuki...
With this I've been able
to verify their actions.
And now as promised,
I believe they'll begin to move
in two years. So...
Before that happens,
I will thoroughly train you.
I wonder if you're ready?
I've been tired of waiting!
I owe you one.
No. I just repaid the debt
from last time.
Next time, I'll settle things
more properly.
Well, at least
this time you didn't cry.
Not that again.
Just like a woman...
What about him?
Huh?
Naruto?
I hear he's leaving today on
a training journey with Jiraiya.
Jiraiya?
One of the Legendary Sannin?
Yeah.
It's such a pain.
He's going to come back
having gotten stronger again.
See you around.
- Farewell...
- See ya.
Please tell Naruto...
Thanks to him,
I figured out what the words
Gaara Sensei spoke of meant.
I'll dedicate myself under
Gaara Sensei from now on...
What did he do?
Well, I guess that's about it.
I read the Village of Artisans report
from the other day.
Although it wasn't a perfect 100,
I'll give you a passing grade.
No! I'm still very much lacking
in experience.
Of course!
I'll have you carry out
several missions
and get you to build up
lots of experience,
so make sure to dedicate yourself!
What?! Does that mean
I'm totally going to get overworked?
Ah, there you are!
Pervy sage!
When are we going to start training?
Hang on a minute...
Just let me finish this paragraph.
What are you writing?
Oh! Well, uh...
I'm writing about my life.
It's called,
"The Tale of Jiraiya the Gallant"!
Your life?
The meetings, farewells,
and various other happenings.
I'm bringing them together in ink,
along with what I've learned
and the paths I've taken.
This will be the ultimate novel!
I'm pouring my soul into it.
And you're still not finished with it?
When I'm finished with this,
everything will be finished.
When I find someone to inherit my will...
and I feel I've properly passed it on...
Well...heh.
I guess I'm not
even close to finishing it.
All this, "inherit your will" talk...
It's just making me confused.
One to inherit my will...
Perhaps that would be...
Hm? What?
Hmph!
At any rate, I suppose
that's enough writing for now.
Next up...
Time to start training, huh?
Time to get to the
mixed bathing hot spring
to find some material for the
next installment of my Make-Out series!
Hey!
I thought you'd say "training"!
You're still hung up on this
mushy "Make-Out" material!
Watch your tongue, boy! This sacred
writing is nothing to make light of!
How about some training already!
Enough! I am in charge, and I
will spar with you some other time!
That's what you said last time!
And the time before that!
So long sucker!
Making me wait again?!
Umm, Sakura. Got a minute?
Ino?
Sure. What's up?
As, as it happens,
I've been thinking about things...
And it became totally clear to me
on this mission.
Clear that I'm be no good at all
at this rate!
Ino.
It's frustrating,
and I was envious of you.
You, who everyone depended on.
So, please.
I also want to become a Medical Ninja.
I know it'll be hard.
But I've got guts and I'll manage
the studying, no matter what.
So could you ask Lady Tsunade for me?
- Sure.
- Really?!
But prepare yourself.
Once that happens,
you'll be my little sister protege.
What's that...?
Naturally!
After all, I'll be your
Medical Ninja superior, you know.
Man, I can't wait.
You'll be my lovable
little sister protege.
I'll train you nice and hard.
Just you watch!
I'll pass you up right away!
Ha! Try it if you can!
Ino pig!
I'll do it! Billboard Brow!
Why?! Why is it?!
What are you talking about?!
Why was I the only one left out
of the mission the other day?!
But you were with
a different team then, right?
But everyone had taken part!
She's kind of in a rage.
It's hard being the only one left out
of a mission.
Come to think of it,
it seems Naruto's finally leaving
for training.
I heard. It seems that Jiraiya
is going to be his mentor.
Damn it! That guy's going
to get stronger again.
It looks like the village will
get quiet for a while.
When you put it that way,
it's a little bit sad, isn't it?
No! This isn't the time
to be getting sad!
I must work hard!
Several times more,
several times more.
If I don't work hard hundreds
of times harder than Naruto,
I won't be able to face him
the next time we meet.
Your guard is off!
We also must grow by that time.
It's because trying to improve
by learning from others,
that is what's called friendship.
Good grief,
we'd better not lose, Akamaru.
Same here!
Hey, you okay, Lee?!
I'm fine, I'm fine.
Lady Hinata, let's call it a day.
What? I'm still...
It's about time for his departure.
Oh!
You won't be able to
see him for a while.
I see...It looks like you'll be
on a long journey...
Yeah!
Listen up.
Be sure to train and don't goof off.
Right! You can count on me!
It's about time to go, Naruto.
Right!
Okay! I'm off, Iruka Sensei!
I'll pay you back for the ramen
once I've become a success.
Jeez...
Good luck, Naruto.
Keep your eyes on me.
What're you doing?!
I'll leave you behind, Naruto.
Hey. H-Hey, wait up!
I also have to work hard in order
to catch up with Naruto.
I just have to work hard and
carve out a future for myself.
And I must not run away
from my path of solitude.
If I do that, someday...
I can be like him.
So as a shinobi
who belongs to the Sand,
I will aim to become the Kazekage.
In order to connect with
this village and live in it.
Gaara...
Watching Naruto Uzumaki
makes me feel this way.
A connection with others...
Until now, that only meant hatred
and a desire to kill.
So just what is this connection
that he keeps talking about?
After all this time, I understand
a little bit about something...
Suffering and sadness...
even happiness...
can be shared with someone.
Naruto Uzumaki...
He has known
the same suffering I have...
And he has taught me
that it is possible to
change one's path in life...
I, too, want to become the kind of man
that everyone looks up to...
Instead of just being
a weapon to be fearful of.
As the Kazekage of the Hidden Sand.