Hey, Kakashi!
Come join us for
some sweet dumplings!
Me? A jonin leader
in charge of genin?
Minato Sensei...
You're late, Obito!
You're finally here...
You must be Obito.
We've been waiting for you.
Barely made it...
You're really late.
We've already introduced ourselves.
You're the only one left!
I'm going to be the Hokage!
My name's Obito Uchiha!
For my Great Stone Face,
make sure my trademark goggles and
Sharingan are nicely carved out!
So I can glare over
the neighboring lands!
I'll scare the hell out of them
with my Sharingan stare...
and no one will
dare attack our village!
Rattle off your instructions
after you become the Hokage
and activate your Sharingan.
Besides, how can they carve the Sharingan
if you're wearing goggles?
They can carve it out over my goggles!
Then it will look like your eyeballs
are popping out.
Anyway...I'm happy that someone on
this team shares my dream.
I'm Minato.
From today, I'll be your superior.
I'm glad to meet you!
Yeah!
All right, let's have
our first practice together.
Y-Yes!
In this training session,
I want to see your teamwork.
Teamwork?
Take these two bells away from me,
and practice will be over.
Simple, right?
Two bells mean...
Exactly.
Huh? What does it mean?
One of us will be dropped
from the team.
What?!
Good observation.
Okay...Let's start.
I'm your jonin leader, Hatake...
Kakashi Sensei, right?
Never mind the formalities...
Let's just get started!
What you're going to do...
has a failure rate of 66%.
During that practice,
I wasn't even thinking of teamwork.
And Minato Sensei
didn't even notice it.
You all pass!
Let's strengthen
our teamwork even more!
– Right!
– Yes!
In other words, one of you will definitely
be sent back to the Academy.
It's no wonder Minato Sensei
didn't notice.
I pretended to work with the team
and used the other two.
I know he's giving us a break...
But Minato Sensei is way too skilled.
There's no way I can do it alone.
Close!
Whoa...
You'll never get it
at the rate you're going.
I knew it.
Minato Sensei is making
an allowance for our skill levels!
Compared to how he is
against Obito and Rin...
With me,
he doesn't ease up as much.
At this rate,
I'm definitely not getting a bell.
In order to complete this mission...
Obito! Rin!
The first formation we learned
at the academy!
Huh?
I doubt if a simple formation like that
would work against Minato Sensei.
Just do it!
I guess it's worth a try.
It's better than doing nothing...
Okay, I'm in!
Here we go!
– Yeah!
– Right!
I see only one opening
with Minato Sensei.
If I use these two to trap him,
we have a chance!
Okay, let's start
That wasn't teamwork.
Back then, if only
Minato Sensei had seen
that something was missing
in our teamwork...
Thanks for letting me get the bell first!
Looks like you're going
to be left behind!
No...
That wasn't...Minato Sensei's fault!
I'm just trying to pass the buck,
and running away from the truth...
That's why...
with these guys...
I'm going to make sure
their teamwork is solid.
You're so clumsy...
You're a disgrace.
Huh?! Speak for yourself!
Damn it...Of all the luck...
To be lumped together
with guys like you.
Say that again!
This is hilarious.
You guys are so ridiculous!
Say, I just had a great idea.
What a coincidence. Me too.
Me too!
We don't want to give Sensei
a hard time...
I agree! So I...
– will...
– decide...
- ...who drops out!
You guys.
Huh?
You all fail!
You're going back to the academy.
That frozen gaze...
It's darkness itself...
His darkness hasn't been dispelled yet.
More time is necessary...
Rin...Obito...
I know.
I have no intention of making people
who don't work as a team into shinobi...
No matter what anyone says...
Now then...
How will this year turn out...?
Keep it up and you'll end up back
at the academy!
I'm in the spring of youth
at full power!
No wonder he's a jonin.
He dodges my taijutsu
with such ease.
I thought graduating from
the academy made us genin.
Failing now is too embarrassing!
Severe Leaf Hurricane!
Giving up already?
I'm not giving up!
My dream is to become a great shinobi
through taijutsu alone!
I cannot...abandon my dream!
That's ridiculous...
But...
I'm not throwing in the towel either!
That's right!
I'm that close to becoming
the kunoichi I've always admired!
No way am I calling it quits!
Now you're talking, guys!
That's how youth should be!
Even if you've used up
every ounce of your energy...
suck it up and push through it!
Hit me with all your might!
– Here we come!
The three of you...
...all pass!
Yes! I did it!
I did it!
I-I can't breathe...!
I'm so happy we all made it!
I wasn't about to fail
after coming this far.
But...
Thank goodness we didn't get
the sensei everyone talks about.
You mean that jonin who sent the three
before us back to the academy?
Uh-huh.
Luck has nothing to do
with real strength.
Those guys just weren't
good enough.
That's not what I heard.
It was about what's even more important
than a shinobi's strength or something...
And what is that?
Is it some kind of
super-lethal-one-hit technique?
But who does he think he is
to make up his own criteria?
Kakashi...
Are you sure about this,
big brother?
Maybe we shouldn't eat
the bento lunches...
Look, have I ever been wrong?
But Kakashi Sensei's not here.
Quit nitpicking!
You two, just listen and follow the rules!
Kakashi Sensei...!
I've failed, but my kid brothers
followed the rules!
The three of you...
Each of you obeyed my orders.
You stuck to the rules.
But you didn't follow what
is most important to a shinobi...
What is that?!
You grey-haired...!
You're all going back to
the academy to figure it out.
Passed on the Chunin Exams?
That's unusually cautious of you, Guy.
Yeah...
Huh? The Chunin Exams?
Yes.
The way the system works is,
if you complete over eight missions...
you qualify to participate
in the Chunin Exams.
There haven't been rookies
in the Chunin Exams lately...
Would you like to go for it?
Uh...!
Huh? What's wrong, Lee?
Well...I'd like to test myself
to see how strong I am...
I do have that desire...
But...
But what?
I don't deserve to take the test
at my present level.
I know my own ability best!
What about you, Neji?
I'll pass on it too.
Huh?
Neji, you'd make it to chunin
in no time!
That's why there's no point
in rushing.
I see. And you, Tenten?
Then I'll pass too!
Let's train hard and take
the next exams together!
You guys!
You guys...
Having students like you
makes me very happy!
Dumplings! Another order
of dumplings, please!
Coming right up!
I don't get it...
But this is so like you.
By the way, what's it like to be
in charge of fresh academy graduates?
That's right. This is your first time.
Hmm?
Hey, Kakashi!
Come join us for some
sweet dumplings!
What's with him?
His eyes are as cold as ever...
like he never left the ANBU.
He failed every one of them again.
That's not such a big deal.
No, but the darkness in
Kakashi's heart is a problem.
He's still carrying that around...
They were my classmates too.
And I grieved as well, but...
You've got to get over it...
I know...
I knew that the depressing atmosphere of
the ANBU would turn him more sullen.
Lord Third!
The ANBU isn't for someone
like Kakashi!
I know it isn't my place
to say this, Lord Third!
But...
We've lost too many of our friends...!
Watching Kakashi...
It's as though he's in a hurry to die...
That's why...we came up with this idea
to put him in charge of the genin...
If he has subordinates to look after,
we're sure he'll change...
Hmm...You think so too?
So then...?!
Maybe we shouldn't have interfered...
We each thought that rather
than being in the ANBU,
being in charge of young future shinobi
held more promise for him, but...
Lord Third!
Lord Third?
Lord Third?!
At ease, finish your tea.
In fact, I'll have a cup too.
I see...
What's so funny?
You always treat us like we're kids...
Asuma!
Oh...Forgive me for laughing.
I must admit that I do treat you
like children.
Minato Sensei...
Is my way wrong...?
– Kakashi Sensei!
Y-Yes?
– Good morning, sir!
Kakashi Sensei!
We're in charge of
academy discipline now!
We realized everything starts
with a proper greeting!
That greeting was spot on!
Keep it up!
– Yes!
Please excuse us!
– Excuse us!
Who cares about greetings?
Let's get started.
Those guys, huh...
It's Kakashi Sensei!
It's you!
– Thank you very much!
W-What?!
Thank you for failing
us in that practice...
we were able to change!
Huh?
We always depended
on our big brother...
and never stood up for ourselves...
Actually, that time, we wanted to
share our lunch with him!
After the practice, we realized
that we should've spoken up
and told you how we felt. Right?
Yeah...
I thought I was helping them,
but I was stifling them instead.
I learned a lesson too.
– And so...!
– We're so grateful to you, Kakashi Sensei!
Grateful...to me...?
A teacher trains his students...
and at the same time,
learns from them.
Only through mutual respect
and growth...
can you foster
a true teacher-pupil relationship.
It is my hope that you will nurture
such a relationship with your pupils.
Of course, I wish it for Kakashi as well.
Lord Third!
Is that...
Oh...it's still very secret.
But this is the list of
academy graduates
who will be under Kakashi's tutelage.
I'm sure it's a group of
highly individualistic kids.
Regarding the next group of genin
that you'll be in charge of...
Me? Again?
Now don't look so upset.
Guy has already formed his squad
and has gone out on missions
with them.
Aren't you eager to set out with
your own apprentices?
Well...
I'm sure this new batch of genin
will hold your interest.
Where are we?
This is Naruto Uzumaki's house.
Lord Fourth's orphan.
So that child is a genin.
Are you a little interested now?
So this is where Naruto lives.
Yes.
This milk is way past
its expiration date.
Minato Sensei was so meticulous.
I can't believe this is his son.
He's a bit of a fool,
but it would be best if
you looked after him.
You have good instincts.
That Uchiha boy, Sasuke, is
also on your squad.
I wish you the best of luck.
Understood.
What have I gotten myself into?
Next up is a kunoichi...
Welcome, Lord Third!
And Kakashi Sensei as well!
Our Sakura, will be under
your supervision!
Come in and have some tea!
I'll hurry and get it rea-tea!
I couldn't resist saying that!
Oh, stop! You're so silly!
I'm here unofficially.
So if I accept an invitation for tea
at a student's home,
other parents might frown upon it.
Oh, please don't be so formal.
Yes! Thanks to you,
we live in peace and have nothing
to worry about, Lord Hokage!
No one would dare complain.
Please, you too, Kakashi Sensei!
After all, you're going to be
our daughter's sensei.
So please come in!
This is really not looking good...
The last up one is...
Sasuke Uchiha's house.
At one time, the Uchiha lived in
a special autonomous district.
Now, only Sasuke remains...
Sasuke's father Fugaku Uchiha
was very strict.
Seems the boy is very disciplined.
His older brother Itachi was
very meticulous as well.
Yes, I remember.
I assigned him under you.
Look after the younger one as well
I'm asking in place of
their father, Fugaku.
I didn't have to teach Itachi a thing.
His Sharingan was far
more effective than mine.
Regardless, you are the only Leaf shinobi
who possesses a Sharingan now.
We don't know yet if Sasuke
will be able to activate his...
but if he does,
you must be there for him.
Yes...
Obito, you—!
This is where...
I'll protect my friends!
Obito...
Kakashi...
Rin...
The shadow of tragedy
trails this eye.
It might be best not to activate
the Sharingan at all.
But...
But for better or for worse,
this eye holds a key into how
I feel about my comrades.
If one thinks that there is a downside
to having these kinds of feelings...
that it attracts tragedy...
then I must see to it that
they treasure their comrades,
in order to prevent that
from happening.
It seems your judging criteria
remains unchanged this year.
Still...
This room is quite a contrast
from Naruto's.
We've been waiting for you.
It should not have taken you this long
to designate team leaders.
I was showing Naruto's apartment
to Kakashi.
About that...
Naruto Uzumaki and Sasuke Uchiha
are on the same team?!
Furthermore, I hear that you've placed
Kakashi Hatake in charge of them.
Yes. I think he's right for the job.
It doesn't matter if
he's right for the job!
What do you plan to do if
Naruto is on a mission
and that thing inside of him goes wild?
That's not all.
There is the danger that he might
be the target of outsiders as well.
Shouldn't we confine Naruto
within the village?
Furthermore, you teamed Naruto up
with Sasuke.
Are you plotting to give the Uchiha
control over the Nine-Tails?
Good idea, Hiruzen.
Next is Team 7. Sakura Haruno.
Naruto Uzumaki!
All right!
And Sasuke Uchiha.
Cha!
Iruka Sensei!
I'm totally brilliant! So why am I
on the same team as him?!
Sasuke graduated with
the best scores of all 27 graduates.
Naruto, you were the worst!
This is just the result of our effort
to balance the teams.
Try not to get in the way, loser!
What was that?!
Jeez, Naruto!
Cut it out!
Ouch! Ow ow ow!
Ouch, stop Sakura! Stop!
So that one was Naruto.
Sakura, there's something
I want to ask you.
Huh?
Oh! Well...What do you think of Naruto?
Naruto?
He's always interfering with my love life.
He enjoys making me suffer.
Naruto doesn't understand
anything about me.
He's just annoying.
I just...want you to accept me.
I'm desperate.
I'd do anything for you to accept me.
That's because I love you, Sasuke.
S-Sakura...I...
Sasuke?
I-I'll be right back.
That look on his face...
I'll bet he drank it.
I won't be able to make it!
That was close.
Oh!
Honestly! You're so shy, Sasuke.
Are you ready now? I'm all ready!
It's almost time.
Where is Naruto?
Oh there you go again,
changing the subject like that.
Never mind Naruto!
He's always picking fights with you!
It's probably because
he's never been raised properly!
He doesn't have any parents, you know!
That's why he always gets
to do whatever he wants!
If I tried to do that,
my parents would get mad at me!
It's so nice to be alone!
You don't have parents to pester you.
That's why he gets to be
as selfish as he is.
Loneliness...
Huh?
It's far worse than feeling sad
because your parents scolded you!
Wh-What's wrong?
What's this about?
You're annoying.
Hey!
Why are you here?!
We ninja have something called
an Escape Jutsu.
Remember that, loser.
Why...you...
Sakura?
Sasuke's words seem to have
hurt her pretty badly.
I wonder if this is what Naruto felt like.
Sakura's really depressed.
Sasuke!
Naruto...He doesn't understand at all.
Hey, Sasuke!
You said something mean
to Sakura, didn't you?!
Not really.
Liar! If you didn't, there's no way
that she'd get that depressed!
I hate to admit it, but Sakura's desperate
to be accepted by you!
Like I'd care.
Wh-What?!
Bastard!
Oh, my...There they go.
What are you doing?
I'm going to hit you
for Sakura's sake.
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
What's wrong?
Aren't you going to come at me?
What?! Shoot! Let go!
All right! You fell for it!
Take this!
You've got the wrong one!
Hey, don't you think that was
a little too much?
I got hasty.
Wait a minute,
how did you get there?!
Hey! Get back here!
You're annoying too.
Damn it...I've got to do something
about Sasuke's quick movements.
In that case,
I'll use my trump card!
That sign...
Another Shadow Clone Jutsu?
Sexy Jutsu!
Sasuke!
Sasuke is so shocked he's speechless!
I've got you!
That hurts!
Ow ow ow...ow!
Hey, Sasuke! We're not finished yet!
Naruto!
Huh? Sakura...
We're meeting in the classroom.
Oh...Wait up.
They're amusing,
but they lack teamwork.
I don't think they can pass my test.
Why?
Why what?
Why did you put me in charge
of those three?
Well, there's a hopeless fool,
a skilled protégé and a clever kunoichi...
I'd say it's much like
Minato's old team.
S-So you chose me on purpose?!
Listen Kakashi, I am the Hokage.
I would never base
my personnel decisions
on personal preference!
It's all about the right man
for the right job...
I carefully consider each of
these assignments...
Separately from what the teachers
at the Academy believe.
Sasuke and Naruto will be
on the same squad?
That's brilliant!
Sasuke graduated at the top of
his class out of 27 students...
Whereas Naruto was last in class.
It seems you did that to keep
the squad balanced!
These are times when
a squad's composition greatly affects
shinobi and their actions,
and subsequently, their success rate.
It is the duty of those who govern
to maintain special teams that
possess a variety of skills.
For example, Guy's team that
was formed last year.
It certainly doesn't
have the kind of balance
the instructors at
the Academy recommend.
It's a squad that specializes largely
in taijutsu.
You're right.
This year, they have really
come into their own.
I also intend to organize
specialty military squads
that utilize Secret ninjutsu.
From that perspective,
Naruto is the Jinchuriki
of the Nine-Tails...
and Sasuke has the potential
to activate the Sharingan...
As I mentioned earlier,
you are the only one who can
advise Sasuke with his Sharingan.
Looking ahead, it is imperative
that Sasuke awaken his Sharingan
that can control the Nine-Tails...
That night's tragedy
must never happen again.
I understand that those two are special.
But what about the girl Sakura?
Well, I believe she has
the potential to be a good kunoichi.
Right now, she's average. However...
Shuriken Shadow Clone Jutsu!
He's already picked up
one of my jutsu!
Good one, Orochimaru!
I can do that too!
What? You too, Jiraiya?
Shu...Shuriken...
Whatever Jutsu...!
Talent attracts people...
Men notice women...
And rivalry matures both...
So they say.
Go get 'em!
Do it!
So you've even considered how
the squad will develop?
That's right.
Without a doubt...
Obito was desperate for Rin
to acknowledge him.
But...
I understand your logic
behind this Lord Third.
But...I failed twice with squads
that you organized.
I don't think I'm cut out
to be a jonin leader.
Did you fail them because of
your own personal feelings?
No...
It was unfortunate for them.
But this is the strict world of shinobi.
It's better that they learn this
when they're young.
Ultimately, this will prove to be
a valuable lesson for them.
But it wasn't planned.
It just happened to work out.
Perhaps.
But I had faith that
it would work out.
I trusted you.
Lord Hiruzen...
It was the same with Minato too.
Minato Sensei?
Judging from only
the practice reports,
it would seem that
Kakashi acted arbitrarily.
Kakashi is leagues ahead
of the other graduates
in terms of skill and intelligence.
It's exciting just thinking about
this genin's development.
Perhaps due to the incident
with Sakumo, he's very headstrong.
But I have faith that he'll realize
the importance of teamwork.
Faith, huh?
Yes, you're right.
I shall have faith in your faith.
Minato Sensei knew all along
about my selfish and
shallow strategy.
But he had faith that one day,
I would realize it...
To believe in one's student
and to watch over them...
is also part of being a teacher.
Father...I spent my life denying you...
I believe that the White Fang
was a true hero.
Sure, in the world of ninja,
one who breaks the rules and
regulations is regarded as trash.
But...those who abandon their comrades
are worse than trash!
But...
I can't repeat that tragedy again
with a new generation.
Are you going to be our Sensei?
I'm Naruto Uzumaki!
And I'm going to be the Hokage!
Shikamaru Nara, Choji Akimichi,
Ino Yamanaka!
- Yes, sir!
I'm the jonin leader of
your squad, Asuma Sarutobi.
We're going to have a meeting now.
Follow me.
See ya!
So long!
See you again, Sasuke!
Get lost, Ino Pig!
What? He's their sensei?
Well, the next one will be ours!
Nope, it'll be our sensei next!
Right, Akamaru?
Kiba Inuzuka, Shino Aburame,
Hinata Hyuga...
I'm Yuhi Kurenai and
I'll be your leader.
Nice to meet you all.
The loser squad gets
a loser sensei too!
- He's late!
Have you been waiting for me, Tenzo?
Stop calling me "Tenzo," Senpai.
Then drop the "senpai."
You'll always be my senpai.
That will never change,
even if you're no longer ANBU.
So what do you want?
I've heard the rumors
that it's been very difficult
trying find my replacement.
Or did you come all this way
to laugh at me, the genin babysitter?
Not at all!
But that was such a long time ago.
You haven't changed a bit, Senpai.
Sorry, but I'm busy today.
I can't stand around and chat.
It's way past the time you were
supposed to meet your genin.
Well, see you later.
"See you later," huh?
Maybe he did change a little.
For someone who was fixated
on the past and present...
to hear him say,
"see you later..."
A silly prank...
Still, if this prank was
the result of teamwork...
He fell for it!
So Naruto's the perp.
I'm so sorry, Sensei.
I tried to stop him, but Naruto...
Sakura makes excuses and
tries to protect herself...
Sasuke minds his own business...
He probably doesn't consider them
as comrades.
There's not even a shred of teamwork...
There are two bells here.
Your task is to take these bells away
from me by noon.
The one who fails to take
a bell gets no lunch.
This exercise is to try
to split the team.
I hope you figure it out.
And failing the exercise means
failing the mission.
In order words, at the very least,
one of you will be returning
to the Academy.
Let's get started.
Ready...Start!
Considering the prank
in the classroom...
I doubt that they'll work
as a team to attack me.
I knew it.
Well, guys!
I'm going to give you
one more chance.
However, the afternoon scramble
for the bells will be much more difficult.
If you accept the challenge,
eat your lunch.
However, don't let Naruto eat.
Huh?
That's your punishment
for breaking the rules
and attempting to eat lunch alone.
If you give Naruto any food,
you will be
immediately disqualified.
I am the law here.
Understand?
Minato Sensei had faith in me...
So should I have faith in them too?
But what if I'm wrong
to begin with?
Don't you have any kindness
in your heart?
All you ever think about are
rules, rules, rules! It's annoying!
That's right.
I'm still trying to stick to my rules...
Come on, let's go, Captain.
Obito...
For the sake of the team,
you walked over to me that day...
If only I had accepted
the friendship you extended...
If I had embraced
that little sign you gave me...
Here.
Obito, did you see that?
I'll never forget you or Rin.
Kakashi.
You!
Pass.
But I think I'm going to move forward
with some new comrades.
Naruto, Sasuke, Sakura...
I'm going to believe in you.
And Obito, Rin...
I'll make a promise.
I'll believe in my comrades
and I'll never let them die!
That ends the survival exercise.
You all pass.
Squad Seven will start
its mission tomorrow!
Huh?! Hey, untie me!