Obito!
Rin is here to pick you up.
Sorry, sorry, Rin!
I can't wait to see
my great-grandchild's face, Obito.
Grandma, I'm only five years old.
Come on, hurry,
it's going to start!
Wow! This is the kunai prize!
It's so cool!
Okay, thank you very much!
I wonder what kind of
ninjutsu is next?
If these are the opponents,
this is going to be a piece of cake.
Number seven, Obito Uchiha!
That's me!
Go for it, Obito!
What are you going
to show us, Obito?
I'm going to be doing
the Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
Wow, impressive!
All right, let's get right to it!
Here I go!
Fire Style:
Fireball Jutsu!
Six points! Seven points!
Seven points!
These are great numbers!
Obito Uchiha is in
the lead right now!
That was great, Obito!
I wasn't in top form today,
but I think it's a sure win for me.
All right, here's our final challenger!
Kakashi Hatake!
What are you doing to do
for us, Kakashi?
Well, how about
the Earth Style: Mud Wave?
Really? That jutsu requires
a considerable amount of chakra.
Are you sure about this?
Mud Wave? At our age?
Earth Style: Mud Wave Jutsu!
The judges all agree!
Perfect 10s!
The winner is Kakashi Hatake!
Too bad, Obito.
Kakashi...Hatake!
You're late, Obito!
Everyone's been waiting!
Sorry, sorry! On the way,
an old man was...
Kakashi!
Kakashi's joining us from today!
Let's play kick-the-can today!
Sure! Let's play!
Kakashi's the only one left.
Obito's such a fast runner.
Save us, Kakashi!
I'll catch him instantly!
What—?!
Saving my friends, no matter what...
That's my Ninja Way.
Want me to be "it"?
As if!
Obito was "it" the whole time.
But he couldn't catch Kakashi,
not even once...
Kakashi is amazing.
Oh, Mom!
Obito, I have to leave.
Me too! Mom!
I won again.
But I'll praise you for one thing...
You're the only one until now
who never chickened out.
You show off!
Hey, I was praising you.
There's my dad! So long!
Yeah...See you!
Say, Grandma...
Am I like my dad? Or my mom?
Well, let's see...
I think both of them.
You are alive because
of your parents.
So you must honor them both
and work for the sake of others.
Oh man, oh man, oh man!
This is the one day I can't be late!
It's the entrance ceremony
and you're already late.
Someone like you has no business
being in the Academy.
You'll never make it.
It's okay.
I got this for you.
For me?
Yes! Just submit this and
you'll be able to enroll.
Thank you! You're a lifesaver!
Keep pampering him and
he'll never be cured of his tardiness.
Shut up! Do you wanna fight?
Say that again!
– What?
– It's your fault!
What did you say,
stupid Kakashi?
Kakashi Hatake!
I'll take him down and become
the Hokage, no matter what!
That's the spirit!
Kakashi is different from us, isn't he?
What a dummy!
He challenged Kakashi again
and got his butt kicked.
As if the class loser can beat
the head of the class!
Rin?!
Someday, I'll awaken my Sharingan,
and I won't lose to him...
Kakashi hasn't been coming
to class at all lately.
I heard something unfortunate
happened to his father.
You broke the rules
for your friends' sake, right?
I've made friends too.
But I'll never be like you, Dad.
I'll obey the rules.
I'll see you later, Dad.
I wish he'd stop messing around!
Who wants to be together with him?!
Don't be so upset.
Kakashi is already leaving the team.
Still...
Um, excuse me.
By "Kakashi," are you talking
about Kakashi Hatake?
Who are you?
Kakashi and I were at
the Academy together.
Oh, so you're friends?
No, I wouldn't call us "friends."
He's pretty nasty, right?
We can't complete a mission
with a guy like that.
Mission?
Oh, right...Kakashi is already
going on missions.
Did something happen?
That guy always prioritizes
the mission over everything.
Even if his teammate is hurt,
or is left behind in enemy territory.
There's no way
we can work with him.
If you ever have to
team up with him, be careful.
Prioritizes...the mission?
I'll save my friends,
no matter what.
That's my Ninja Way.
Him? He'd do that?
Say, Rin...
Do you see Kakashi these days?
No, I only catch glimpses
of him in town.
I think he's away on missions
most of the time.
Why?
I heard some rumors
about Kakashi yesterday.
They weren't good rumors.
Last time I saw him,
he seemed to have changed a lot too.
Could it be something to do
with his father?
Do you know something?
Well, no...
Oh, I see.
Okay, Obito. See you tomorrow!
Yeah.
Kakashi...
Hey, Kakashi!
How's it going?
I've been hearing a lot about you.
Looks like you've been
seeing a lot of action.
Hey, did something happen?
If something's on your mind...
I'm not so desperate that
I need you to worry about me.
Hey...you...
Leave me alone.
Kakashi...
I found you, Obito!
Rin!
Are you all right?!
I just slipped.
I'm okay. I'm okay.
You're training in this rain?
Yeah...I figured I have to try harder
if I'm going to catch up to that guy.
"That guy"?
I mean, Kakashi.
One day, I'll surprise him.
Otherwise, I can't become
the Hokage.
Besides, he's already going
on missions.
I have to work harder or the gap
between us will get bigger!
That's the spirit!
Go for it, Obito!
Yeah!
Excuse me.
You wanted to see me?
I want to ask you a favor.
Kakashi Hatake is
an extremely talented shinobi.
However, he fusses too much
about sticking to the rules
and clashes with his superiors
and teammates.
He may excel in technique,
but as a human, he has much to learn.
His father broke the rules
to protect his comrades,
and then took his own life...
His death has cast
a shadow over Kakashi.
And you want to place him
under my supervision...
Oh no, oh no!
I can't believe you were late
for both your entrance and
graduation ceremonies!
Graduation is over!
But there was this old lady...
You have an awfully high rate
of encounters with old people, don't you?
Lately...I've been getting ambushed
by a lot of them.
That sounds premeditated!
Really...
Come on...
This way!
Here is the graduation certificate
for Obito Uchiha!
"This certifies that
you have graduated
from the Hidden Leaf Ninja Academy.
You are commended
for persevering
through the rain and wind
to reach this milestone!"
Here! Congratulations!
Rin...
Thank you, Rin.
No one's here to watch...
But this makes me happier than
receiving it from that old-man Hokage!
We're genin now,
so you have shape up.
Yeah, I know.
We'll now be part of a 3-man squad
and go on missions, right?
Have the teams already
been announced?
Yes, they have.
So, are you and me...
Well...
Don't tell me...
we're on different...
Unfortunately,
we're on the same team!
No way!
Yup. I'm stuck looking
after you again...
Yes! Yes!
And who's the third member?
About that...
You're late, Obito!
You're finally here.
You must be Obito.
We've been waiting for you.
Barely made it...
You're really late.
I'm Minato, your leader from today.
Glad to meet you.
Yeah!
Anyway, let's have
our first training session together.
R-Right!
In this session,
I want to see your teamwork.
Teamwork?
And the exercise will be...this.
You all pass!
All right...
We'll start our first mission tomorrow.
That's more like it!
I'll show what I've got
in a real battle!
Actually, this first mission
is inside the village.
Like finding a lost pet
or a lost item.
Those are just odd jobs!
A mission is a mission.
If you succeed, then I'll assign
more important missions.
Kakashi, you've been on
many missions already
and this may seem boring,
but do your best anyway.
Okay! Kakashi, I challenge you!
Let's see who can
complete more missions.
That's stupid. Do as you please.
You chicken?
What did you say?
It's not here.
Found it?
No.
It's not here either.
Looking for a lost pet
isn't easy, is it?
But if we can't succeed
at something like this,
our team will never be sent
on real missions.
By the way, where's Obito?
He was determined to
do everything alone,
and went off somewhere.
Is he serious about beating me?
Oh, Obito...
That cat was on the rooftop
up ahead basking in the sun.
Obito, I saw that thing
on a park bench.
Oh right, by the way,
I have some yummy sweets
you can take with you.
Finding a lost pet, and a lost item!
Solved them both,
thanks to the grannies.
And I even got treats!
You're so popular
with the old ladies, Obito.
You really weren't lying
all those times were you late.
"One good deed deserves another."
This time, Obito's kindness
was returned.
How's that, Kakashi?!
All the odd jobs in the village
were taken care of in one day.
Right? It's because I'm the man
who will become the Hokage!
This is nothing!
Lord Hokage, I believe this team
is far more skilled than we thought.
You're right. Kakashi already
has lots of field experience.
Perhaps I shall send them along
with you on your mission tomorrow.
On Minato Sensei's mission?!
Is this a real mission?!
Yes. And the client specifically
requested Minato.
It's a C-rank mission.
Although the risk is low,
I'd be lying if I said
there's absolutely none.
I was planning to assign you
to more odd jobs in the village
while Minato was away.
But there are no more requests.
And, I can't let you just
wait around.
Yes!
This means we're going
on our first real mission.
Okay then...
I'm counting on you all from tomorrow.
– Yes, sir!
Well, Kakashi?!
You should be grateful to me.
I'm the only reason why
there are no more odd jobs to do.
Kakashi, don't get upset with Obito.
Obito's been worried about you
for a long time.
He thinks you've changed...
W-What're you saying, Rin?!
Well, it's true.
And you always said that
Kakashi was better than you...
So you trained hard to catch up!
Did not! I never said that!
You're imagining things!
Come on, let's all shake hands.
We're on the same team now.
I'm not shaking hands with this guy!
Really...
You're both hopeless!
Then...
I'll connect the both of you.
Okay guys, for this mission,
we will be escorting shinobi
from another village.
One of them is carrying
a secret missive.
Namely, that's what we are guarding.
There will also be three other escorts
from the requesting village.
If fighting breaks out...
First and foremost, I want you three
to make sure you're safe.
Understood?
All right!
I'm gonna show my stuff big-time
and make it to Hokage!
It's not going to be that easy.
Obito, were you even listening
to Minato Sensei?
We are not to engage in
any kind of battle.
Besides, we'd only get
in Minato Sensei's way.
Is he really that amazing?
Haven't you ever heard of
the Yellow Flash of the Leaf?
I have.
He's an incredible shinobi whose fame
has spread to other villages too.
And he's our teacher,
Minato Namikaze,
the man touted to become
the next Hokage.
Seriously?! Someone that great
is teaching us?
I feel my blood rushing!
Man, I wish someone
would attack us.
Jeez...
Hey, I wonder who's stronger,
the Yellow Flash of the Leaf
or the White Fang of the Leaf?
O-Obito!
The Hidden Leaf had a hero
named the White Fang.
But I heard he died
protecting the village.
Haven't you heard of him?
No, I haven't.
Kakashi?
What's with him?
This is strange.
We're surrounded...
There are quite a few of them.
What's going on?
This is far more dangerous than
the rank assigned to this mission.
I have to stop them here
before I'm completely surrounded.
Bringing along the team
might have been a mistake.
Who can I depend on?
He can guard one person.
I'll have to guard the other one.
Everyone, listen up.
What is it, Sensei?
Looks like the enemy is on our tail.
Seriously?! We're gonna fight?!
Obito! This is not a game!
Uh, yes sir...
There are quite a few of them.
Obito and I will track back
to confront them.
In the meantime, Kakashi
and Rin will complete the mission.
It's imperative that you two escape.
– Yes, sir!
All right...Let's go, Obito!
Roger!
Oh man, Minato Sensei!
To have you pick me
instead of Kakashi...
This just means you depend on me!
Obito, we're going to lure
the enemy without a fight
and separate them
from the main group.
I know that!
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
Oh, not bad.
I wasn't kidding about
practicing every day!
I'll take down
every single one of them!
Don't get carried away!
I said no fighting!
Obito!
You're in the way!
He's strong!
You're just a kid!
You can't beat me with that!
Damn it!
I'm not going to lose here!
I'm...
...gonna become the Hokage!
I did it!
A shadow clone?!
You're mine!
Not good!
Are you all right?
Minato Sensei!
This is not good...
They're here.
Rin! Go on ahead!
Got it.
Damn—!
Kakashi! We have to save him!
Minato Sensei is still
nearby right now!
If we turn back and let him know...
No! A shinobi's duty is to
carry out his mission!
Kakashi...
Run! Getting away is imperative!
Once we're in the forest,
the village will be near!
They won't pursue us that far!
Understood!
We've come this far.
We should be safe.
What about Obito?
Sensei is with him.
I'm sure they're fine.
Thank you.
I must hand it to
the Yellow Flash's team.
Thanks to you, the secret missive
will be delivered safely.
Don't mention it.
Unfortunately, one man had
to be sacrificed.
That could not be helped.
However...he won't be...
the only sacrifice!
What the—?!
What's going on?
S-So you're...the traitors!
Since you were just so focused
on completing the mission,
you made our mission easy.
Even someone like the Yellow Flash
can't span this distance quickly.
Sorry, but you're going
to have to die too.
No way...
Rin, get out of here!
But...!
You're going to get in my way!
Earth Style:
Mud Wall!
Damn, they got away!
Wha—?!
From inside the Earth Style?!
Rin!
I'll start treatment immediately!
What happened, Kakashi?!
Minato Sensei!
Obito...
Kakashi? Rin?
What am I doing here?
I'll explain later.
First, Kakashi...
What happened here?
We escorted them safely to this point,
but the other two were traitors...
Two of them?
Please, I'm not going to make it.
The contents of the secret missive...
But we can't look at its contents...
Don't worry about it.
Please, just confirm that
it's the real one.
What does this mean?
My superior told me that
another teammate and I would
both be handed secret missives.
And only one of them would
be the real one.
Why?!
There was intel that there could be
a traitor among us.
So who has the real missive?
If the traitor had it,
he wouldn't have attacked me.
So...
It was him.
Kakashi, where's the other guy?
Well, on our way here...
Please, you must get
the secret missive!
There's nothing I can do.
Damn it, did they hear us?
Kakashi.
You didn't leave someone
to die, did you?
I only prioritized the mission.
I followed the rules.
The rules?
Those who don't follow
the rules are scum.
But look at the result!
If you hadn't turned your back
on your comrade,
this wouldn't have happened!
Stop, Obito!
This was an unexpected incident.
Kakashi is not to blame.
Damn it!
I'm going!
Go where?
Isn't it obvious?!
I'm going to save that guy!
But he's right in
the unexpected incident.
He's right. It's too dangerous.
I'm not about to fail
my first mission!
We didn't fail.
This was an unforeseen occurrence!
Kakashi, for an honor student,
you're pretty dumb.
What did you say?
Think about it.
The four guys we were supposed
to guard have all disappeared.
Who's gonna support our claim
that this was all unexpected?
If the village who requested
this mission
pretends to not have known
about the traitors...
Minato Sensei will be forced
to take responsibility!
Never mind me.
Our mission is over, Obito.
All I want to say is...
Sensei, you can keep dragging me
back to the village,
but I won't give up searching
for the guy.
I never turn my back
on a comrade!
– Obito!
Damn it.
I guess it's useless to try
and stop you.
Then I'll go back to where he fell.
Kakashi, you check downstream.
And Obito, check beyond that.
Rin, you go with Kakashi.
Right!
Listen up. Report to me
the minute you find him.
He's here!
We found him.
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
There are too many enemies.
Rin! Take care of him!
Got it!
Let's get away from here.
Wait!
The scroll!
Withdraw!
Obito! Rin!
Guard him!
What about you, Kakashi?!
I'm getting the scroll back!
That's reckless!
You saw how many there were!
I won't let you complain!
If saving him is your Ninja Way,
completing the mission is mine.
Kakashi!
Obito, we have to contact
Minato Sensei!
Yeah!
Obito!
You bastard, do think you can
take us all on by yourself?
I will complete my mission.
Kill him.
Obito! Did you find him?
Kakashi went after the enemy
to get the scroll back!
Kakashi did what?
I hope I make it in time!
Come on!
Don't let him...get away!
Rasen-Flash Super-Circle
Dance Howl Stage Three!
Minato Sensei.
So, were you able to uphold
the principles you believe in?
This completes the mission.
Yes...
Thank you for saving my life.
The Yellow Flash of the Leaf...
I hope we meet again someday.
All right then, let's go everyone.
Sensei, missions are
really difficult, aren't they?
You're right.
Things don't always go
the way you envision them.
But I'm glad the secret missive
was delivered safely.
Yes...
So we successfully
completed the mission.
Probably.
"Probably"? What do you mean?
Back there, he said...
Thank you for saving my life.
If the mission was successful,
he would be more concerned
about the secret missive
and not his life.
What do you mean?!
The missive he had
was also a fake.
We were probably decoys.
Another team delivered
the real missive.
That's the real reason
they requested Minato Sensei
for a C-rank mission.
With Minato Sensei as the escort,
it would seem that we were
really guarding the real thing.
When did you figure that out?
I thought it was a possibility
when we discovered
the first missive was a fake.
And you risked your life
to go after a missive
that could have been a fake?
That was the mission.
That's my Ninja Way.
Good, you actually hit me.
Hitting sensei, that's amazing Kakashi!
It was just one hit.
It isn't all that praiseworthy.
I can do it too, you know!
Nice timing, right?
Kushina!
Yay!
You all doing your best?
They're doing great. We
were just about to take a break.
Great!
Here, lunch.
Here's your order!
It's the Kushina Special.
Alright!
I love the food
you make, Kushina! Thanks!
You're just so cute!
You're such a good girl, Rin, you know?
I took the time to bring lunch all
the way out here to you guys,
and that's the kind
of thanks I get from you?
Hey, I didn't ask you to do that!
I'm not even hungry!
Trying to be tough is okay,
but go ahead and eat something first.
I mean, you can't fight
on an empty stomach, can you?
I-I don't want it!
I won't take anyone's handouts!
I can fight without food!
Hey...you're pretty manly!
Yeah right...like I'd ever
say something like that to you!
Now no more out of you! Eat!
Being healthy is part of being a ninja!
What you just said proves
that you're nothing but a kid!
Well...you know what!
There they go again...
Let's just eat, okay you two?
Just who do you think
you're calling violent?
You know, Kakashi really
is getting a lot better.
Yeah, for his age
he's really something else.
Rin is growing well too.
They're becoming a good team.
And Obito?
He's hardly more than a
bragging little half-pint.
He's always tripping
over himself,
he can't throw shuriken straight,
and his jutsu setup is just...
He'll need some work...
Well, it's like you said...
Obito does have a lot
of things he needs to work on.
But still,
his bright and outgoing
attitude is really important.
Obito being there deepens the
bond between everyone on the team.
That's just a fact.
Well, I don't need
to tell you that.
I mean, he is
your favorite isn't he?
Oh? You sure about that?
Here you go.
Thanks.
By the way,
is the location of your next
mission going to be decided soon?
Yeah. I'll find out for sure
within the next few days, but...
I think it's going
to be at Kannabi Bridge.
Kannabi Bridge...
I hope the war ends soon...
This is bad!
At this rate, I'll be killed!
Can I make it?!
Did I make it?
No, Obito, you're late!
What time did you think
we were supposed to meet?!
If you're a full-fledged ninja
you're expected to follow the rules!
Well...I was on the way,
but an old lady carrying a load
asked me for directions...
And I got something in my eye...
Okay! That's a lie, isn't it?!
That's enough, Kakashi.
Obito showed the old lady the way...
Isn't that right?
I carried her bag too!
You're too lenient, Sensei.
Besides, there's no way that
some needy person appears
before Obito each and every time!
Those who break the rules and
regulations are regarded as scum!
Isn't that so?!
Don't you have a shred of kindness
in your heart?!
All you ever talk about are
rules and regulations!
The main thing is
your own self-control.
Now stop it, both of you.
We're all on the same team.
You're too easy on Obito, Rin.
This is an important day for me too.
Y-You're right...
What was it again?
As of today, Kakashi is a jonin like me.
And in order to increase
our efficiency,
we'll be splitting into two teams.
After all, the Leaf Village is
is currently low on military strength.
Splitting up? Then...
Yes, that's right.
Kakashi will be captain of
a three-man squad with Obito and Rin.
And I'll be working alone.
Remember, we talked about
this the other day, Obito...
About getting Kakashi a gift.
Sorry...I wasn't listening.
This is my gift.
A custom-made kunai knife.
It's sort of heavy and odd-shaped,
but once you get accustomed to it,
it's easy to use.
Thank you.
And this is from me.
Here! A personalized special medkit...
I adjusted things a little,
to make it easier to use.
Thanks.
Wh-What's with that hand?
I don't have anything to give you!
Well...I don't mind.
It wouldn't have been anything
worthwhile anyway.
Getting something useless
would only get in the way.
I still can't figure out
why you became a jonin!
You should talk.
I'm Obito Uchiha of the Uchiha clan!
I'll surpass you some day!
The minute my Sharingan awakens!
Everyone in the Uchiha clan
is elite, right?
So you shouldn't have to rely
on something like that.
What...?!
Stop it, you two!
Can I start to explain the mission
to you?
We're close to the border.
Got it? It's this line.
It shows where the Land of Earth
is currently invading
the Hidden Grass Village.
Our enemies are
the Hidden Stone ninja...
We have received word that
1000 ninja already make up the front line.
They've advanced considerably
since the last time.
The Land of Fire shares borders
with the Hidden Grass.
We should have stepped
in long ago.
Judging by the size of this advance...
they must have an efficient system
for reinforcement.
Hence, our mission is here...
at Kannabi Bridge.
To crush one's enemy at
the battlefront requires
an immense number of ninja.
So ninja like us,
who focus on sabotage missions,
are forced to work in small, select teams.
The bridge...you say?
Then it's an infiltration mission?
Right! Team Kakashi...
Your mission is to infiltrate
the enemy's rear territory.
You will destroy this bridge, which is used
to transport supplies and reinforcements.
And when this is done,
withdraw immediately.
- Yes sir!
And you, Sensei?
I will face the enemy directly
on the battlefront.
I'll create a diversion for you.
In any case,
Kakashi is your captain today.
We'll travel together to the border,
but after that your mission commences!
- Yes sir!
Nice...Kakashi.
They noticed...
They're pretty good.
He's...
No, that can't be...
I'll just watch the situation.
One...
No! Be on guard, everyone.
There are twenty of them.
Although it's probably
a shadow clone.
I think you're right. Sensei...
I'll attack.
Can you cover me?
Don't be hasty, Kakashi.
I think you should back me up.
Sensei...I'm the captain today!
I want to test a new jutsu
I've been working on.
He's coming...
Chidori!
What is that jutsu?!
Wh-What an incredible chakra...
Here I go!
No matter what their numbers are,
with this jutsu,
I can take them down in a flash.
It's just like your nickname.
Besides...
Sensei...You said it yourself.
Right now, I'm the captain.
The rule says that the team must obey
its captain's orders, Sensei!
To think he'd attack head on...
Your kunai attacks helped me
pinpoint your location.
Here I go!
He's fast!
Damn! It's a shadow clone...!
Then on to the next!
Don't let your guard down!
Yes sir!
That's number 18!
Don't get cocky, brat!
Kakashi!
I was barely able to counter
that brat.
But that yellow-haired guy's moves are...
I marked him...
Sensei's Transportation Technique is
so fast!
N-No way...are you the
"Yellow Flash of the Leaf"?!
Those of us from the Land of Earth...
have been taught by our commanders
to run when we see you.
I finally understand what they meant.
Kakashi's wound is serious...
We'll retreat and regroup.
I'm all right!
No, you're not!
All because you ignored Sensei's warnings
and charged ahead!
I don't need to listen to that.
Not from the "Uchiha elite"
who was whining in fear back there!
I-I got some dust in my eye and
started tearing up, that's all!
Do you know the 25th rule
of Shinobi Conduct?
The rule says a ninja must not
show tears!
Hey...Stop it, you two...
That's enough, both of you!
Kakashi, rules and regulations
are indeed important.
But that isn't everything.
Didn't I teach you...?
There are times when
the situation requires
impromptu responses against the enemy.
There, you see?!
Obito, you too!
There's no way dust can get into
your eyes when you have goggles on.
If you're going to advocate self-control,
don't just mouth the words.
Act strong too.
And one other thing...
Kakashi...You shouldn't use
that jutsu anymore.
From what I could see,
your focal point concentrated attack
undoubtedly has power and speed...
But it makes you move too fast to
ascertain the opponent's counterattack.
It's still an imperfect jutsu.
Before we part...
I'll tell you one more thing.
For a ninja, the most important thing
is teamwork.
Sensei...
What's the matter?
I know...
that teamwork is important.
But...
Kakashi always criticizes me about
how I lack discipline, so...
I mean...I know that I'm the black sheep
of the elite Uchiha Clan...
And I admit that Kakashi is
an awesome guy...
Kakashi is the son of the genius ninja,
Sakumo Hatake,
feared as the "White Fang" of the Leaf.
Even the legendary names of
the Leaf's Three Great Ninja paled
before his father's.
His childhood years were spent
under the shadow of such a genius...
So I guess it can't be helped if,
at times, he finds you lacking.
White Fang...
That's right...
I've heard of him too.
The hero who died protecting the village.
Kakashi never said a word about that...
He was a great man...
Someone respected by everyone
in the village,
and naturally, by Kakashi himself.
That is, until that incident...
Incident?
Perhaps, I shouldn't be telling you
something like this...
But since you're on the same team
as Kakashi,
I want you to know.
What happened...?
Kakashi's father, Sakumo,
took his own life
after being slandered.
Five years ago, he was the leader
of an extremely difficult mission
and infiltrated enemy territory.
He was forced to make a choice.
The mission or his comrades' lives...
Of course, according to
the rules of the village,
completing the mission was
the right thing to do.
However, in order to save
his comrades,
he suspended the mission.
That resulted in grave losses to
the Land of Fire and the village,
and he was blamed for it.
What's more, the very comrades
he saved also criticized him.
The whole ordeal took its toll
on Sakumo's health,
physically and mentally.
And finally, he took his life.
Since then, Kakashi has never
uttered a word about his father,
and he has strictly adhered to
to every rule and regulation.
Obito...
Try to understand,
even if it's just a little.
Kakashi means well.
It's healing well.
But don't over-exert yourself
or you'll open up the wound.
Yeah.
Let's start heading out.
- Yes sir!
We'll be splitting up from this point.
Good luck to you all.
The enemy the other day was
doing surveillance alone.
But from here on out,
we'll be fighting teams.
Be careful...
Let's get going...
Captain.
All right...Let's go!
- Yes sir!
Scatter!
Hey...Mahiru went out for surveillance
and hasn't come back.
You don't think those young brats
killed him, do you?
Well then, let's ask them.
Camouflage Jutsu
Fire Style: Fire Ball Jutsu!
We're taking this one.
Wait!
Damn it!!
Obito! Don't go after them!
What?!
Do you realize what you just said?!
Yeah...
The two of us will continue this mission.
And Rin? What about Rin?!
Rin comes later.
The enemy wants to find out
what we're up to.
They won't kill her right away.
And luckily, Rin is a Medical Ninja.
So even if she ends up a prisoner of war,
she'll probably be treated cordially...
On the condition that she treat
the wounded on their side.
The problem is if the enemy learns
about our strategy.
If they obtain that information,
no doubt,
they'll immediately increase
the security on the bridge.
That will make our mission
much more difficult.
You're assuming Rin's safety
under baseless assumptions!
What if those guys just now are lackeys
who don't give a damn?!
Right now, saving Rin takes priority
over the mission!
A ninja...
must sacrifice a comrade in order
to carry out a mission.
That's the rule.
If we fail in this mission,
it is possible that the war
will be prolonged
and many more lives will
be sacrificed.
That's just an assumption!
And for something like that,
you're willing to simply abandon
a comrade
who's been through life and death
with you?!
When you and I were wounded,
Rin saved our lives with
her medical ninjutsu!
If she hadn't been there,
we'd both be dead by now!
That was Rin's duty.
I don't like you, after all!
I don't care. I'm the captain.
You will obey me.
Whatever the situation,
in order to keep the team together,
one person gives the orders.
That is why we have the rule
that states
that members must obey
the team captain.
Obito, you're not strong.
That is why I was chosen
as captain of this team.
Then why won't you try to save Rin?!
As captain, you're strong.
Strong enough to save
your comrades, right?!
If you give in to your emotions
even for a moment
and fail your mission,
you will regret it later.
That is why our code of conduct
forbids any emotional feelings.
You should know that.
Rin...
Rin was concerned about
your well-being.
That's why she gave you that medkit.
She even sewed on
a protective amulet inside it!
The medkit and medical ninjutsu
are superb systems
developed by the Hidden Leaf
in order to increase
the success rate of our missions.
But I told you yesterday, didn't I?
"Getting something useless would
only get in the way."
Something useless?
To carry out his mission,
useful tools are essential to a ninja.
Something like emotions are useless.
Are you serious...?!
Do you seriously believe that?!
Yeah...I do...
Forget it.
You and I have been like water
and oil from the start.
I'm going to rescue Rin!
You don't understand anything...!
Not about what happens if
you break the rules...
I believe that the White Fang
was a true hero...
Sure in the world of ninja,
those who break the rules and
regulations are regarded as scum...
But...
those who abandon their comrades...
are worse than scum!
I'm gonna be trash anyway,
so I choose to break the rules.
And if that doesn't make me
a true ninja...
Then I'll destroy all
these so-called "ninja"!
You finally came.
What is the situation?
I'd say there are about fifty
of the enemy.
Compared to that,
there are just four of us left alive.
It'll all be over soon.
We will all attack at once.
Everyone, please direct these kunai knives
towards the enemy all at once.
I will do the rest...
That's crazy! Not even you could...
Shut up and do as he says.
We're about to see
the Yellow Flash of the Leaf in battle.
It'll happen in a flash. Don't miss it.
I found them...
Calm down...I can do this!
I'll take care of it.
In the meantime, use your genjutsu
and get the information from her.
Camouflage Jutsu
All right...Here I go!
Go where?
K-Kakashi...How come you're...?!
Well, I can't leave this up to
a crybaby ninja like you, can I?
Kakashi...
That silver-white hair and
white chakra blade...!
Don't tell me you're...
the "White Fang" of the Leaf?!
This is my father's keepsake.
To carry out his mission,
useful tools are essential to a ninja.
Something like emotions are useless.
Kakashi...you...
I see...You're the White Fang's kid...
Then there's no need to
be afraid of you.
I thought so.
The scent has been completely erased.
We'll have to locate him
by the slightest movement
and noise he makes.
Wh-Where is he?
Obito, behind you!
My eye...!
Kakashi!
Hey Kakashi! Are you all right?!
Even if he's just a kid,
it doesn't hurt to be cautious...
I'll take it nice and slow.
Our enemy...He's good...
He threw away the kunai knife stained
with the smell of my blood.
Don't tell me you got dust
in your eye again?
A ninja shouldn't cry...
I'm not dead yet.
Stay focused!
There's no way dust can
get into your eyes
when you have goggles on.
If you're going to advocate self-control,
don't just mouth the words.
Act strong too.
I'm just talk...
Always being saved by others...
Just a big-mouthed loser...
But...
I believe that the White Fang
was a true hero...
Those who abandon their comrades...
are worse than scum!
I don't want those words
to be just empty talk!
Die!
Wh-Why...?
There's no way you can see...
Obito...You...!
Wh-What is...that eye...?
This time...I'll protect my comrade!
Obito...That eye of yours...
Yeah...I guess this is the Sharingan.
I can now see the movement
and flow of chakra.
Are you all right, Kakashi?!
Yeah...
Looks like I lost my left eye,
but I have the kit Rin gave me.
I can use it for emergency first-aid.
We're going to save Rin immediately!
Okay!
You're surprisingly stubborn.
Hmm...They're all so pathetic.
The flow of Rin's chakra is disturbed...
It's different from your chakra
or mine.
She's probably under a genjutsu...
They didn't waste any time trying
to get the information out of her.
It seems they're not mere kids.
We fought him earlier.
He's fast...Stay alert!
Right!
Release!
Kakashi...Obito...!
We've come to save you, Rin!
You'll be all right now.
All right, now let's get out of here!
I see...
You two made a good team,
but you're still just kids.
Right now, you're in enemy hands.
Earth Style: Rock Breaker!
This is bad!!
Run for the exit!
Kakashi!
Too bad, I lost a good source
of information...
Oh well, it can't be helped.
Are you all right?
Rin...? Kakashi...?
Obito!
Don't...It's okay, Kakashi.
I don't think...I'm gonna make it...
My right side is totally crushed.
I can't even feel anything...
Dammit!!
No...This can't be...Why...?
Obito...!
Dammit!
Dammit!!
If...If only I had listened to you..
And we had come to rescue Rin
in the first place...
This never would've happened!
So what if I'm a captain?!
So what if I made jonin?!
Oh yeah...I almost forgot...
I was the only one who...
didn't give you a gift...
for becoming a jonin, Kakashi.
I didn't...know what to get you...
but...I think I know now.
Don't worry...
It's not some useless, extra baggage...
I'm giving you...my Sharingan.
Whatever the village may say...
you are...a great jonin.
That's how I really feel...
So please accept it.
Rin...Use your medical ninjutsu...
Take the entire eye and transplant...
my Sharingan...
into Kakashi's left eye.
Kakashi, come over here...
I'll start it right away.
I'm about to...die...
But...I'll become your eye and...
see the future...with you.
How stubborn...
You're still alive, huh?
But...you're just a kid, after all.
What's a ninja crying for?
Come on, crybaby! Let's settle this.
That kid...
He seems different than before...
Kakashi...take care of...Rin.
Yeah...
Don't panic...Rin.
Kakashi...Take Rin...
Take Rin and...get out...of here.
Enemy reinforcements...
will be coming.
Obito...
It's okay...Just go...
Rin!
Earth Style: Earthquake Slam!
Rin, hurry, take my hand!
Rin!
Obito!!
Just when Kakashi and I were...
starting to get along...
I couldn't tell Rin that I...
loved her...
I wish...I could've spent more time...
with everyone.
Obito!
Damn it...!
Obito...This is the jutsu
you helped me perfect!
Hmm...You still have the will to fight,
even in this situation?
No wonder you were able to sneak
so deep into enemy territory.
You are a determined one.
Rin! I'll hold them off!
Get out now!
But...!
I promised Obito I'd look after you...
I'll protect you with my life!
Kakashi...
Rin...Obito cared about you.
He loved you...
You were everything to him.
That's why he gave his life
to protect you.
Then, Kakashi! You should know
my feelings for you...
I...
I tried to abandon you...
I'm nothing but scum.
Rin, go!
Am I...dead?
Where am I?
Looks like
you've regained consciousness.
Huh?!
Sensei! But how...?
The writing on this kunai knife...
acts as a marker that I leap to
using the Transportation Technique.
Then...the enemy?
I took them all down...
Rin...
Where is Rin?!
I'm sorry
I couldn't make it in time, Kakashi...
Rin told me everything.
The Third Great Ninja War.
With the sacrifice of
many nameless ninja,
this long war finally came to a close.
In its wake, it also left legends...
The stories of great heroes,
to be told and retold
for generations to come.
The Battle of Kannabi Bridge...
That day, two heroes were born
in the Hidden Leaf Village,
each with his own Sharingan.
One found his name engraved
on the memorial stone.
The other came to be known
as "Kakashi of the Sharingan."
In time, the tales of his bravery spanned
all borders, and beyond.