Kakashi...
It won't wash off!
Accept this from the Hokage!
Deliver it to Lord Tsuchikage
and relay to him that we desire
an immediate response!
There's no need to deliver
anything to him.
We'll give you your answer
right here!
Sometimes it's best not
to be so hasty.
What?!
The Fourth Kazekage?
Why is the Hidden Sand here?
This is Hidden Sand territory.
It would be unwise to have
an incident occur here.
We'll put out any sparks
that rain down over us.
The Sand will move accordingly,
as the Sand.
Remember that,
whatever you decide to do.
Scatter!
What about the request to enter into
the peace treaty?
Naturally, it will be turned down.
Whatever the Hidden Leaf negotiates
with the Hidden Sand,
nothing will challenge
the unity of the Stone.
– Right!
– Exactly!
Silence!
Naturally, I am proud of
the unity of the Stone.
However...
With our pride on the line,
we sent 1000 of our shinobi.
And I hear that it took just one of them,
the Yellow Flash, to stop the invasion.
And that's the reality of it.
I hear they're going to enter
into a peace treaty
with the Hidden Stone.
How much faith can we put
in a single piece of paper?
That's for sure.
You guys, think about
the burden on Lord Third!
In any case, the long, great war
will be over for now.
Let's toast with some dumplings!
Hey, Kakashi!
Want to join us for some dumplings?
He's not too sociable these days.
Is something bothering him?
Well, you can't expect him
to be jumping for joy.
Are you talking about
Obito and Rin?
Yeah.
That would definitely leave
a hole in your heart...
Kakashi...
Rin...
Well done!
We can breathe
a sigh of relief for a while.
Are you satisfied with
an agreement like this?
To forgive
the Hidden Stone's actions
and drop our demands
for compensation...
It's as though we lost the war!
What do you think, Hiruzen?
Continuing the war
any further would be disastrous
for the already
exhausted Hidden Leaf.
It's a step toward finding
common ground...
Many of my friends gave
their lives for this great war!
It's like they died in vain!
And I assume full responsibility
for that.
How will you take responsibility?
I intend to step down as the Third Hokage,
and have the Fourth Hokage installed.
How regrettable...
The Third Hokage was
doing a fine job...
Hmm...
Truth be told, the Third Hokage
was too soft...
and he allowed the village
to be pushed into a corner.
We need a Hokage
who will change things,
and enforce the laws of the shinobi.
We need someone like that.
And? Is there such a person?
I recommend Orochimaru,
one of the Legendary Sannin.
– Oh...
– Him?
What do you think, Lord Third?
Orochimaru is truly a genius
in this age of war.
However...
A sinister will and greed lurk
deep behind those eyes.
Such a person cannot be given
the duties of a Hokage.
Lord Third!
I recommend Minato Namikaze.
A pupil of Jiraiya...
In other words,
a disciple of your disciple.
A man so skilled,
he's nicknamed the Yellow Flash.
Oh!
Minato is still too young.
He emerged victorious
at the Battle of Kannabi Bridge,
and distinguished himself
by leading the way to end
the Third Great Shinobi War.
I am opposed!
What about the rest of you?
I believe that you will carry on
the Will of Fire.
So I want to entrust you with
the future of the Hidden Leaf...
and the shinobi world.
You will accept, won't you?
I shall do my best to deserve
your trust, Lord Third.
I wish I could have passed this on
under better circumstances...
What lies ahead is not peaceful.
I'm prepared for it.
Good.
I know you can do it.
What are you doing there?
What did Lord Third want with you?
Well...
Did you get scolded?
So what?
Don't worry about it, ya know!
Well, it wasn't that...
Then what?
Well...
He wants me to be
the Fourth Hokage.
Oh really?
Don't mind the Hokage...
What?! What did you just say?
I've been named the Fourth Hokage.
Congratulations, ya know!
Hey, hey...
Thank you very much for
all your hard work.
Thank you.
It's all going Hiruzen's way.
The Third Hokage intends to
use Minato as a puppet
and keep ruling the Hidden Leaf.
At this rate, the Hidden Leaf
has no future.
Don't give up yet.
If my research is successful,
it will be easy to grasp
the power of the Hidden Leaf.
To grasp power...
stronger measures must be prepared.
When the time comes,
we won't be choosing measures.
But, it's not time yet.
Generally, if he's popular at all,
he should...
Let's go, Kinoe, Kinoto, Hinoe!
– Sir!
What's going on?!
Hey, Kakashi!
"How a Shinobi Should Die"?!
What is this?
Give it back.
What's going on?
Oh yeah!
The Fourth Hokage
was just announced!
Don't be shocked!
Minato Sensei will be
the Fourth Hokage!
Rin...
It seems like Minato Sensei
is going to be Hokage!
Minato Sensei will be
the Professor's successor
and change the Hidden Leaf...
and the shinobi world.
There won't be any more sacrifices
like you guys...
I'm counting on you...
Fourth Hokage.
I shall dedicate my life to it.
Enter.
There's a mission?
Yes, I want you to retrieve the documents
relating to the peace treaty.
Yes.
There are still some shinobi
who desire war.
And there are rumors that they are trying
to steal the documents to create discord.
Please do your best on this mission.
Yes, sir.
I'll wrap this up!
Chidori!
Kakashi...
Kakashi!
Die!
Severe Leaf Hurricane!
Another one?
This isn't like you!
Why are you spaced out?
S-Sorry...
Kakashi?
Get a hold of yourself!
I see...
Yes...
I've never seen Kakashi like that.
I'm glad I secretly sent you.
To help him at a time like this...
That's what an eternal rival is for!
That's what I believe, but...
You've already done a lot.
Will you leave the rest to me?
Minato Sensei! I mean...Lord Fourth...
Address me as you always have.
Some in the village think I'm not qualified
for the position and oppose me.
I came here today...
to assign you to the ANBU
under my direct control.
Why me?
I want you to be my right-hand man...
Here's a set of gear for you.
Thank you.
Many shinobi from small villages
that survived
by taking advantage
of the turbulent situation,
have no wish to be controlled by
the nations of Fire, Wind and Earth.
There's no doubt they will continue
to cause disruptions.
But we must maintain peace,
which was attained through
the sacrifice of many.
I'm counting on all of you.
– Yes, sir!
Chidori!
Huh?
Five shinobi,
all approaching rapidly!
What does their headband show?
The Hidden Stone.
We have a peace treaty
with them, don't we?
Maybe they have urgent business?
What?!
Why are you breaking the treaty?!
We're the Leaf Village!
You must be making a mistake!
Reinforcements! Withdraw!
Thanks for saving us!
The Hidden Stone betrayed us!
This isn't a Hidden Stone shuriken.
So they were fakes? But why?
They want to cause a rift between
the Stone and the Leaf.
H-Hey!
Don't chase them too far!
Chidori!
Hey! How have you been?
Are you ignoring me?!
It's only been a short while since
Kakashi transferred into the ANBU,
but some of his actions
are quite astonishing.
One...
Four!
Sharingan!
You're the cold-blooded Kakashi
that everyone talks about!
Wait, Kakashi!
Help me!
Five!
All five were killed with a single blow
to their vital points.
If you kept at least one alive,
we could've gotten intel...
Lord Hokage, regarding the issue
that you were concerned about...
We have not seen any evidence of
psychological trauma in Kakashi
associated with taking Rin's life.
Is something on your mind?
No...
Congratulations.
What?
Your due date is...let's see...
October 10.
Really?!
Huh? A baby...?
I'm going to be a mother, ya know!
And I'm going be a father...
A mother, ya know!
I'm going to be a father!
Imagine that,
A mother, ya know!
Kakashi, I want you to leave
your current mission
and take on a special mission.
Was there an issue?
It's nothing like that.
It's more like a top-secret errand.
Kushina's pregnant!
Oh...Congratulations.
Thank you.
And so...it will be roughly
nine months until she gives birth.
I want you to guard Kushina
against any incidents.
Yes, sir!
Thank you for protecting Kushina.
But...
It's standard for the ANBU
directly under Lord Third
to take over the guard
during the birthing period.
Then I'll be returning to
my duties in ANBU.
There's no need to be so hasty.
Why don't you take
a break for a while?
I'm sorry I haven't been by.
It's not that I've forgotten...
I've been...sworn to secrecy...
but Minato Sensei is going
to be a father.
This generation won't know war.
If only we were born a little later...
I should tell Obito too.
So I'll be going, Rin.
Thank you!
Thanks, I'll come again.
Hey! Watch where you're walking.
Why don't we just do
Rock-Paper-Scissors again tonight?
Not that again!
Think of something more exciting!
How can you call yourself my rival?!
We have an early start tomorrow.
So let's pass for tonight.
Don't use a mission
as an excuse!
I have all this hot pent-up
energy inside me!
Now is the time for
diligent training!
Honest-to-goodness discipline
and hard work
lead to success in future missions!
Are you listening to me?!
You've gotten awfully cold
since joining the ANBU.
I've heard the gossip.
They're calling you cold-blooded.
Well, I know that
I'm not supposed to talk
about your being in the ANBU.
Still, that's no reason to forget
about our friendship!
Youth is short!
Say, Guy...
Do you sense anything weird?
There's been a chill in the air...
It's your attitude that's causing it!
There's nothing like
the present for youth!
That's...!
N-No way...
The Nine-Tails!
– Run! Help!
– It's the Nine-Tails!
Lord Third! The Nine-Tails!
The Nine-Tails has suddenly
appeared in the Village!
I'm aware of that!
I will suppress it.
You and the others,
protect the civilians!
Yes, sir!
You should have ordered the Uchiha
Police Force to guard the civilians
and kept them in the rear.
We can use the visual prowess of
the Uchiha to suppress the Nine-Tails!
They can also manipulate
the Nine-Tails!
If they take control of the Nine-Tails,
and use it to their advantage,
it will be like the second coming
of Madara Uchiha.
I will leave you to
protect the civilians.
Order the ANBU and
security units as you wish.
Guard the village youth as well.
Understood.
Damn you, Nine-Tails!
This is the moment I release
my fiery pent-up power!
Don't be hasty, Guy!
Come on! I'll be your opponent!
Wait!
Huh?
Gather immediately in the guardroom!
Why?
It's the Third Hokage's orders!
Lord Hiruzen?
You heard him. Let's go, Guy!
Now listen up.
You young shinobi are to
stay away from the Nine-Tails.
What do you mean by that?
This is not a battle between villages...
This is a domestic issue.
There is no reason for you
all to risk your lives.
Speak for yourself!
Calm down, Kurenai!
You're a shinobi too.
We are not guaranteed
to live a long life.
But, my daughter,
you are a woman.
At least, pass on the Will of Fire
to my grandchild.
Make that your oath to your father...
For I do believe in you.
This is no time for a family argument!
I can't take not being able to do
anything at a time like this!
The barrier has disappeared!
Lord Fourth!
Lady Kushina!
Take her to Leaf Hospital immediately!
Summon the Medical Ninja!
Lord Third...
Kushina...!
Please take care...
of the child.
Of course, you don't need to worry.
His name is...
Naruto...
Minato and I...
picked it from...
Jiraiya Sensei's novel...
Naruto, you say?
Fine. I take full responsibility.
So, for the child's sake,
you must rest!
Kushina! I promise...
Minato...
Kushina...
You both gave your lives...
to protect the Hidden Leaf Village...
and its future.
Minato Sensei...
We repelled the Nine-Tails,
but the sacrifice was much too great.
This is no time to lament.
The Hokage's seat is empty.
We must decide on someone quickly.
Perhaps someone from
the age group below Minato?
We have nurtured fine jonin,
but they all lack the experience
to rule over a village.
Is there anyone else?
Well...
It cannot be helped.
This is a critical time.
I shall take over.
Oh, will you do that?
If you are willing...
You stepped down once...
Are you up to the task?
Truth be told, even though
you went after the Nine-Tails,
you failed to save the Fourth Hokage...
That remark is uncalled for.
And where were you
at that time, Danzo?
Just indulge this old man.
Let me fill in as Hokage until
we can groom the next one.
Kakashi Hatake, correct?
Lord Danzo...
Come and work under me.
What do you say?
But...I was Minato Sensei's...
Lord Fourth, the one
who recruited you into the ANBU
is no longer with us.
If you stay where you are,
you will end up working
directly under the Third
who will reassume his position.
It was his foolhardy ideals of peace
that dragged the war on
and drove Obito and Rin
to their deaths.
But...
Furthermore, on the night
of the Nine-Tails' rampage,
you were not able to join the fight
because of Lord Third's orders...
Isn't that why Lord Fourth
lost his life?
I don't want to believe that
he planned this to return to power...
but the future of the Hidden Leaf
cannot be entrusted to someone like him.
A few ANBU will be selected to
guard the Feudal Lord's procession
back to his prefecture.
– Yes, sir!
This is the plan.
Wood Style?!
Wood Style: Giant Forest Jutsu!
Halt!
I called him.
Yes, sir!
Thank you for coming.
Here...
The time has come.
Good work, Kakashi.
Wood Style: Giant Forest Jutsu!
Who was the boy
that uses the Wood Style?
Maybe I'll find some information there.
Found it.
Hashirama Senju...The leader of
the Senju Clan of the Forest,
brought peace and stability to
this bloody, war-torn world.
He and he alone mastered
the Wood Style ninjutsu...
No, there's one more.
What does this mean?
How is he able to use
the Wood Style?
Top secret?
Where are the contents?
Is this what you are looking for?
Professor!
It's all right. I give you permission.
Read it.
Yes, sir!
Long ago, the First Hokage,
Lord Hashirama...
after a death match with Madara...
used the Wood Style to
suppress the Nine-Tails.
After that, there was no one to
take over the Wood Style Jutsu...
Either the Sharingan or
Wood Style are necessary
to suppress the Tailed-Beasts.
In the Hidden Leaf Village,
there was a time when
they researched
and tried to revive
the First's Wood Style Jutsu.
However...
despite the dedicated
efforts of many...
the tests to transplant Lord Hashirama's
cells failed one after another...
and the lives that were sacrificed
continued to grow.
And so...
unfortunately, that jutsu...
was deemed a Forbidden Jutsu
and sealed away.
But recently, genin and chunin,
and even members of the ANBU
have gone missing.
Furthermore, what's more disturbing
are incidents
where newborn infants
have been kidnapped
from hamlets surrounding
the Hidden Leaf Village.
Infants?!
Of those confirmed,
there have been 60 kidnappings.
Who could have...?!
What I'm about to tell you is hearsay...
Someone is continuing
the experiments
and trying to implant the cells
of Lord Hashirama.
Even if they're rumors,
why would anyone...?
There are those who want to obtain
every jutsu that exists.
Even I have wondered sometimes,
if there were only someone
who knows the Wood Style...
Had that been the case,
the Fourth Hokage need not
have sacrificed his life.
Isn't that why Lord Fourth lost his life?
Mind you, this is just hearsay.
If...
If Lord Hashirama's cells had
really been implanted into infants...
Implanting cells into infants
is forbidden...
And even if someone was doing so,
the possibility of it succeeding
would be very low.
However...
If...just if...the first infant who
was kidnapped survived...
He or she would be
ten years old already.
Ten years old...
Are you all here?
Yes, sir!
Tomorrow morning at
the hour of the tiger,
the Third Hokage and five ANBU
under his direct command
will depart for
the Feudal Lord's prefecture.
His purpose is to reassume
the Hokage post
left empty by Lord Fourth's demise.
If we allow this,
the Hidden Leaf Village will once again
be forced to accept
a weak and indecisive leader.
For the sake of the village,
we must prevent this at all cost.
Hence, your mission is...
somewhere along the route...
to take the life of the Lord Third
quickly and discreetly.
Remember, no one must know of this.
It must appear that it was
the work of itinerant shinobi.
Understood?
– Yes, sir!
Lord Third, are you ready?
Yes, let's depart!
Enemy attack!
Wood Style Jutsu!
What?!
A Substitution?!
Wood Style: Giant Forest Jutsu!
Chidori!
You...
Where did you learn the Wood Style?
I didn't expect an answer anyway...
Leave.
Go quickly!
That jutsu of yours will be critical for
the Hidden Leaf Village one day.
They were only after Lord Third.
It seems their purpose was
to separate us from Lord Third.
They scattered off somewhere.
Were you all right here?
Yes...
Did you recognize the enemy?
I don't know who it was.
Well, that's all right.
I'm sure Lord Third will take care
of the rest.
I regret to inform you...
that I won't be giving up
that seat just yet...
It seems like you want to ask me
why I'm still alive...
It's nothing like that!
I understood that
you left this morning
for the Feudal Lord's prefecture.
A certain fellow betrayed me...
Rather, he came back to me...
and warned us
that we would be targeted
on the way to the prefecture.
I can easily investigate and
find out who is behind this...
And that person will be executed.
That is as clear as day...
But it's against my principles
to cause any more death.
If I could meet that person,
I would tell him...
That I will overlook his actions
this time...
But in exchange,
he must do all that is in his power...
for the sake of Hidden Leaf Village.
You and your ideals of peace...
One day, that naiveté will be
the death of you, Hiruzen.
Hmm...perhaps you're right.
We've always been this way.
You are the light and
I am the darkness.
Wherever there is light,
there is darkness.
But losing either one causes
disruptions in the world.
Professor...
I'm unqualified to be in the ANBU.
Why? Thanks to you, I'm still alive.
Still, I nearly betrayed you once.
I couldn't protect the Fourth Hokage...
I can't blame you if
you hate me for that.
Actually, when Minato was alive,
he came to speak to me about you.
I wanted him to forget the pain
in his heart, even just a little...
That's why I assigned him
to the ANBU.
But from the rumors I hear lately...
I think I might have made
the pain go even deeper.
Right now, I regret it.
No one can heal a wounded heart...
Only time can heal all wounds.
Yes...
Well, there is one solution.
Why don't you assign him
to guard Kushina?
If he leaves his duties with ANBU
to watch over
a woman who is about to
give birth to a new life,
perhaps it will trigger
a change in him.
You're right!
When Minato died...
I considered releasing you
from the ANBU, for a moment.
But I am in need your strength
at this time.
Yes, sir!
Will you continue on as an ANBU
who reports directly to me?
Yes!
I hope that Minato will
forgive me as well...
Lord Third...
There's something I need to tell you.
Hmm?
There's someone in the Foundation
who uses the Wood Style...
Just as I thought...
I have an idea who it is.
Let me handle this.
Yes, sir.
I see...
So you will be filling
the post again, Lord Third!
You have the knowledge
and experience already...
I am very relieved.
Is that man not here today?
The fierce-looking one
with that scary eye...
Do you mean Danzo?
Oh yes, he's the one.
He had an urgent matter to attend to,
so he is absent today.
Oh...I see.
I don't feel very comfortable
around him.
We must cease direct contact
between us for the time being.
Did something happen?
Kakashi betrayed me,
and there's a possibility
that Hiruzen knows about us.
That's not good.
In time, he might even learn
about this place and its secrets.
Well, we're dealing with Lord Third.
He'll be on to us eventually.
No...He probably has already guessed.
Kakashi...
It won't wash off...
Lord Third is reassuming
the title of Hokage...
I thought the changing of
the guard would mean a new era...
I know what you mean, Genma...
It's not going to be easy
for Lord Third, you know!
Especially at his age!
We just have to do our best
for the village, that's all.
Let's celebrate the return of
Lord Third with some dumplings!
– Yeah!
I-It's me! It's me, Kakashi!
You were seriously out
to get me just now!
I thought I was going to get killed!
I should say the same.
What the hell were you thinking?
I was just...
I just wanted to lure you into
continuing our rivalry showdowns.
Sorry...
Is that you, Kinoto?
Lord Danzo,
there's an urgent matter...
Hiruzen himself is leading them?
Damn him, he's gone too far.
Kinoe, are you here?
Are you going to kill me?
Are you up to the task...
Sarutobi Sensei?
And even with that...
No...it's because of that.
Hiruzen will not be able to
kill his student Orochimaru.
Sarutobi, you have to—!
Just for times like this, we have
another secret meeting place.
Kinoe, go on ahead
and wait for Orochimaru.
Lightning Blade!
You...
I like the look in your eye.
However...I don't need a fake.
So cute...
Do you want to see his blood too?
Lord Third...
So you set this up.
Don't move!
So that's Orochimaru...
This emergency summons was called
regarding the capture of Orochimaru
who escaped during
the previous mission.
According to intel reports,
Orochimaru is seriously wounded.
Considering his condition,
he will not be able to leave
the Land of Fire easily.
Listen carefully.
The knowledge, data and jutsu
that Orochimaru possesses
are a valuable asset
to the Hidden Leaf.
If possible, bring him back alive.
If he leaves the Land of Fire...
...it will be a fatal blow
to the Leaf!
And so...
This must be settled before
he crosses the nation's borders.
Everyone, do your best.
Scatter!
You must love your pupil very much.
It's hard to believe that you
of all people would fail...
I will be happy to cooperate.
For the sake of the Hidden Leaf,
I shall do everything I can.
Thank you. I'd appreciate that...
Whose grave is it?
The friend he killed.
Kakashi Senpai...
Lord Hokage is calling.
All right.
Stop calling me "Senpai."
This isn't the academy.
You're still my senior in the ANBU.
Besides, you're my role model.
Find someone more suitable.
Hey...
Rin Nohara...
You are aware that Orochimaru
has secret research facilities
scattered throughout the country,
aren't you?
Yes.
After he deserted the village,
he destroyed some and
kept some intact.
Including ones that
we have no knowledge of.
It seems that way.
A small battalion on a mission came
upon such a facility by accident.
According to their report
upon their return,
it seems to be a research facility
that was abandoned by Orochimaru.
Did they go inside and investigate?
Fortunately, not yet.
Right, since we don't know
what's inside.
I do not want members
of our village
to learn about his repulsive
research activities...
Of what happened to
their missing kin and friends.
However, an investigation is necessary.
So, you want me to go?
It's been three years since
Orochimaru left the village.
But he still remains
a thorn in our side.
I hate to ask you,
but please take care of this.
Yes, sir.
I understand Orochimaru's hideout
was found.
It's one of his research facilities.
I've dispatched someone
to investigate.
I see...
Is something troubling you?
He could have set some kind
of trap before abandoning it.
Are you sure it's safe
to investigate?
I sent an experienced and
qualified ANBU agent.
I hope nothing goes amiss.
Is that you, Kinoe?!
It's been awhile, Kakashi.
What are you doing here?
I'm on a mission.
As my back-up?
No, that isn't it.
Did Lord Danzo dispatch
a Foundation shinobi,
because he's interested in
Orochimaru's research facility?
Foundation shinobi never discuss
their mission...Is that it?
No matter.
You did help me out there.
We can't have you burned
to a crisp.
Do you want to investigate
what's inside together?
Whatever we find,
we'll share the intel with each other.
What's wrong?
We may work in different divisions,
but we're Leaf shinobi.
Let's cooperate.
Yes...
Who knows if a demon or
a snake will appear?
Let's go together.
Right.
The only trap seems to have been
that one by the entrance.
Orochimaru was pressed
for time in his rush to escape.
You're right.
Still, we must be careful.
Yeah...
Let's go.
Right.
There's nothing in here.
What was Orochimaru
experimenting on in here?
Probably doing what
he does best.
Experimenting on
human test subjects...
Human test subjects...
This one's no good.
This one as well.
That one too...
They're all no good...
This human experiment is a failure.
I thought that an adolescent
would adjust far better
in propagating Hashirama's cells, but...
But it's just the opposite.
A child doesn't have the strength
or stamina to endure it.
I guess I'll have to
shut this place down.
Wait!
But not to worry.
There are many more ways
of cell implantation.
I'll start the next test right away.
Wait, wait...
Wait!
Ki...noe.
Hey, Kinoe.
Let's go.
Right.
This one's locked.
Leave it to me.
It's open.
Are you aware that
the Wood Style Jutsu
is extremely important to
the Hidden Leaf?
I didn't know that.
Your Wood Style jutsu isn't just
for the Foundation...
It is a power meant to serve
all of Hidden Leaf Village.
Lord Danzo wants to
keep you at his side.
But you are more suited
to working directly under the Hokage.
Don't you want to leave
the Foundation
and come out of the shadows?
No...no...I'm still alive!
N-No...
There's a survivor?!
What is this?
What's going on, Kinoe?!
Kinoe!
Are you serious?!
Yes, I'm serious!
I have the advantage.
All that's left is...
He knows how to fight
against my Sharingan.
This was his intent
from the very beginning...
Kinoe!
If you're serious about killing me,
then I won't hold back!
It will be a death match,
friend against friend!
I'm serious.
I'm dead serious!
Why do you want to kill me?
It's my mission.
What kind of mission sends
a friend after a friend?!
You're one to talk.
You're the one who killed a friend.
A substitute?!
Wood Style Substitute...
You've gotten better
since the last time...
Yes. So don't hold back, Kakashi.
I won't kill a friend!
No need to hold back!
Stop, Kinoe! Abandon this mission!
A shinobi's mission is absolute!
Kinoe!
A mission is not absolute!
If your orders are to kill a friend...
that order is wrong!
The one who gave you
such an order is wrong.
Is Lord Danzo wrong?
Can you walk?
What's the matter?
You don't seem to remember
who you are...
but have you forgotten
how to talk as well?
Uh, no...
Follow me.
Orochimaru is greedy.
It's good to have the desire
to test out new things,
but he gives up too quickly.
However, you're lucky
he gave up on you.
If you had stayed
with Orochimaru,
you would have ended up
another test subject.
My organization takes in shinobi
who have nowhere to go.
From now on, you will be
a shinobi of the Foundation.
The Foundation?
Yes. We are the tenacious Foundation.
We support the great tree known
as the Village Hidden in the Leaves.
Without strong roots,
a large tree cannot grow.
That's why the Foundation...
You will be called Kinoe.
Henceforth, you are one of us.
You were one of 60.
Huh?
In order to produce a Wood Style user,
59 other children have been lost...
Kinoe, cherish your life.
Yes.
I'm leaving.
He said I'm going to be one of
the Foundation of the Hidden Leaf.
Water Style!
You're able to infuse chakra
quite nicely now.
Yes!
All right. I shall train you myself.
Lord Danzo is? Directly?
Personally?
I once saw the First Hokage
in battle.
Deep Forest Emergence:
Deep Forest Bloom...
Such formidable
Wood Style ninjutsu.
If you have inherited his cells,
I put all my hopes in you...
Manipulate the Earth Style
and Water Style
Change in Chakra Nature
simultaneously!
Not quite yet.
I'm sorry.
It can't be helped.
You are not an exact copy
of the First Hokage.
Here is the Ninjutsu Scroll left
by the First Hokage.
It's full of jutsu that I can't use,
but you should be able
to learn them.
Me? Learn jutsu that you cannot,
Lord Danzo?
The world of the shinobi is filled
with a myriad of jutsu.
You cannot compete
with just one power.
We must master various jutsu
and use those powers
to unite the shinobi world.
I have high hopes
for your Wood Style jutsu.
Lord Danzo is not wrong!
I will fulfill my mission!
Why you...!
To hell with your mission!
I'll say it again!
Killing a friend is not a mission!
Then why did you kill her?!
What?!
Why did you kill Rin Nohara?!
Why did you kill her?
Why did you kill her?!
You killed her because
it was your mission!
Don't speak about Rin!
As part of my ANBU missions,
I've had to deal with Rogue ninja
and traitors of the Hidden Leaf.
So I can't help it if
I'm called Friend-Killer Kakashi...
But...
Rin was...
Why you...!
I didn't want to kill her!
I couldn't protect my friend.
That's why Rin died...
from this Chidori...
Couldn't protect her...?
Couldn't protect her...
Are you going to...kill me?
Are you a friend
of the Hidden Leaf?
Or are you a traitor?
I'm not a traitor.
Then what are you?
I am...Kinoe of the Foundation.
Then Kinoe...renounce your duty
to the Foundation.
I cannot.
Then I'll take you into custody
and turn you over to Lord Hokage.
Do whatever...you please.
Stand up!
We're leaving.
What about the mission, Kakashi?
Our mission is to search this location.
It's suspended, because of you.
Don't let me stop you.
You're trying to kill me,
so stop joking around.
I'm not joking around.
Move!
I hear Foundation agents
are all trained
to discard their emotions.
Does the same go for you?
Not just our emotions.
Shinobi of the Foundation
have no names, no past, no future.
We have only our missions.
Well, you failed your mission.
This is...
Don't inhale! It's poisonous! Run!
R-Right!
Kakashi!
Kinoe, where's Kakashi?
You did it?
Yes.
So you didn't need me.
Where's his body?
I made it appear like he was killed
by Orochimaru's trap.
Lord Hokage's ANBU
will probably find him.
Good. Let's return before
they get wind of us.
Kinoe?
To Kakashi...
I've become confused
about this mission,
where I'm supposed to kill a friend.
So I'm going to abandon
this mission,
and I will report to Lord Danzo
that I failed.
Please take care.
Kinoe...!
Kakashi Senpai, we have to
tend to your wounds.
I must report in first!
Hmm?
What's the matter?
Lord Third...
Regarding the Foundation's
Wood Style user...
He targeted me.
Lord Danzo ordered it.
But he dropped his mission midway
and saved my life.
He then returned to the village.
But who knows what's happened
to him by now.
W-What is the meaning of this, Kinoe!
I beg your pardon.
I failed my mission.
If Kakashi beat you,
then it's my fault
for underestimating Kakashi's strength.
However, you abandoned
your mission
and did a poor job of faking his death,
and then returned here...
And I sent two men to do the job!
What was your intention?
Answer me.
Why did you do this?
Please go to Lord Danzo
and save Kinoe.
Lord Third!
It's agreed upon that
I don't interfere with the Foundation.
However, that is not possible
in this case.
Yugao.
Sir!
Take this missive
to Foundation headquarters.
It's an order from the Hokage.
Summon Danzo here immediately.
Yes, sir!
I'm counting on you, Yugao.
Please rest assured, my lord.
Kakashi...
Sir.
Go to the infirmary and
tend to your wounds.
Yes, sir.
Senpai?!
I'm coming with you.
Kakashi is a shinobi of the Leaf.
He is a Leaf comrade.
Is it right to kill a friend?
Consider only those in
the Foundation your friends.
Isn't the Foundation
a friend of the Hidden Leaf?
The Foundation is
a unique organization that supports
the large tree known as the Leaf,
from deep underground.
Just as a tree is divided into
what is above and below ground,
the Foundation has its own existence.
Kinoto...What is a Foundation shinobi?
Shinobi of the Foundation
have no names.
No emotion. No past. No future.
We have only our missions.
As the leader of the Foundation,
my missions are absolute!
No future...
No past...No emotion?
No name?
Welcome back, Tenzo!
Are you listening, Kinoe?!
No! My name is not Kinoe!
What are you saying?
You are Kinoe of the Foundation.
What other name could you have
besides that temporary one?
I am a shinobi of the Leaf!
Not just of the Foundation!
A shinobi of the Hidden Leaf,
which has a trunk and branches!
Everyone is my comrade!
Damn you...
What made you turn on us?!
Take him to the treatment room.
Bind him with a Curse Mark.
Sir!
Lord Third has summoned Lord Danzo.
Notify him that he is
to appear immediately.
Lord Danzo is not here.
What?
We will let him know
as soon as he returns.
Where is he now?
We do not know.
We aren't privy to Lord Danzo's schedule.
Go back and report this to Lord Third.
What about you?
I'll stay here and wait for him. Go.
Right.
Stop!
You are under Foundation jurisdiction!
Where is Kinoe?
Damn Kinoe...
What crazy thoughts did
Kakashi put in his head?
Lord Danzo, we're ready.
Release!
Let's get out of here!
Kakashi?!
Kinoe!
Wood Style!
Hey, wait!
Found him! Over there!
Wind Style:
Vacuum Bullets!
Wood Style: Domed Wall!
How good of you to come over
from your side, Kakashi.
You entered Foundation jurisdiction
without authorization
and tried to take one of our own.
Don't think you'll get off so easily.
Lord Danzo, Kakashi is...
Silence!
And you won't get away with this either.
Neither shall you...
Hiruzen...
I know that you bear
a grudge against Kakashi.
But that's no cause to target
one of our best shinobi.
What are you talking about, Hiruzen?
I could care less about Kakashi.
However, he trespassed
by his own accord,
into Foundation territory
and that is serious.
"By his own accord"?
No, I dispatched him with
a summons from me.
Then he went looking for you.
On my orders.
There must've been
a communication mix-up.
I'm hearing that for the first time.
Well then, that settles it
with Kakashi.
It's regarding this next issue
that I sent for you.
It's regarding another
superior shinobi of this village.
You know that the Wood Style user
has long been desired
in Hidden Leaf Village.
There even was a period when
we conducted tests to acquire that power.
Now I understand there
is such a Wood Style user.
Why would you keep him hidden
within the Foundation?
I found him.
And I protected and raised him.
It's not like I was hiding him.
I just felt there was no need
to report it to you.
Listen, Danzo.
The Jinchuriki child is
now four years old.
The Wood Style Sealing Jutsu
is becoming
more and more crucial to the village.
So...
Will you entrust this user to me?
I'll assign him to the ANBU
under my direct control.
But...
Please, Danzo.
I know he is a valuable
subordinate to you.
But for the sake of the Hidden Leaf,
transfer him to me.
Then all will be settled amicably...
Members of the Foundation
have a Curse Mark,
so they do not
reveal top-secret intel.
I will not remove the Curse Mark.
That is fine.
All right then...
I now receive him into my care.
Henceforth, you will be an ANBU
under my direct orders.
Umm...
Thank you for everything.
H-Hello...
I just transferred here from
the Foundation. I'm Kinoe.
Hey, Tenzo!
Tenzo?
Kinoe was your codename
in the Foundation.
In the ANBU,
you should call yourself Tenzo.
But that name is...
Didn't you call yourself Tenzo
in the past?
All right, everyone!
This is Tenzo, the newbie!
I can vouch for his skill.
Nice to meet you!
Welcome!
– Nice to meet you, Tenzo!
– I expect good things from you!
Tenzo...huh?
Tenzo, you're on my team. Team Ro!
I'm counting on you.
Okay, Senpai!
Damn it!
As usual, your Lightning Blade
is as brilliant as ever, Senpai.
Brilliant?
There's no such thing as brilliant
or unsightly in assassination...
A kill is a kill, that's all.
By the way, what happened
to the replacement?
Our team is short a member.
There's no rush.
We're not in the middle
of a war or anything.
Sooner or later,
someone will show up.
Hey, Kakashi.
What's up? You look tired.
Did you just get off a mission?
You're such an idiot, Guy.
Members of the ANBU can't
discuss details of their work!
That's how it goes.
We're going out for
some sweet dumplings.
- Care to join us?
- Sorry, I don't really like sweets...
He's gotten so antisocial lately.
Maybe it's because of
all the secrecy in the ANBU...
No! No way!
Kakashi is my lifelong rival.
He's got a heart that's filled
with burning passion.
All right, since it's come to this,
it's up to me to do something!
You?
Please let me join the ANBU!
It's the best thing to do
for Kakashi's sake!
Now, now, Guy.
I understand your concern
for Kakashi.
But the saying "the right person
for the right job"
applies to this situation...
Your skills will not be optimized
in the ANBU.
It's not about what's
good for me, Lord Third!
As Kakashi's partner, I...
Silence! You are not suited
for the ANBU.
Not...suited...
L-Lord Danzo...
What is it?
Please accept me
as one of your ANBU!
You lack it.
Lack what?
Darkness.
Darkness?
A new member will be
joining your team.
Is it the one
we previously discussed?
Yes, he's extremely capable.
But he's young.
Danzo recommended that
he gain more experience.
Here's your equipment.
Thank you very much.
I've been assigned to
the ANBU from today.
My name is Itachi Uchiha.
I'd appreciate your guidance.
I see. So you're the one.
Use the locker that's
the farthest one in the back.
Yes, sir.
Is that him?
They say he's eleven years old.
Doesn't that make him
the youngest ANBU ever?
Team Ro is to assemble at
the Third Training Ground
in five minutes.
Yes, sir.
What are you doing?
Explain yourselves!
We wanted to make sure he had
the skills to be one of us.
Since he's too young.
Do you have a problem with
the decision of your superiors?
No, it's not like that...
Haven't you already sensed
that he isn't ordinary?
I'm Kakashi, captain of Team Ro.
You're new,
but I want you to learn the ANBU
rules and formations quickly.
Yes, sir.
He's good.
He is talented,
but making an exception
for someone so young is
rather unusual for the ANBU.
Lord Danzo recommended him.
No kidding?
He doesn't fit the mold though.
What do you mean?
Lord Danzo has
his own personal set of criteria
for ANBU and Foundation agents.
And?
I just can't see him...
Are you getting used to the job?
Not yet.
That's unlike you.
I haven't gone out
on a mission yet.
Protecting the Lord Hokage
is a mission in and of itself.
Isn't the ANBU an assassination
and special tactical unit?
Well, we're not at war right now.
- Kakashi...
- Sir?
As the Hokage, every deployment
I order is an official one.
However, I cannot
ignore Danzo's view
that there is an underside
to this mission.
Hence, a separate unofficial team
will be dispatched.
One that the Hokage didn't order?
You will work under Danzo.
On the surface,
this is a diplomatic mission.
We will be exchanging intel
with the Hannya Black Ops
of the Land of Woods
at the border.
However...
I believe this is an enemy trap.
Lord Third agrees with me on this.
The ANBU will guard the team
on the official mission.
When the enemy turns on
the team and attacks, kill them.
Leave no survivors.
Total annihilation?
We must show them
that the Hidden Leaf
does not tolerate betrayal.
I'd like to be in
a two-man squad with Itachi.
Fine.
If I may take my leave...
Kakashi...
I recognize your worth
as an ANBU...
I'm even tempted to pull you away
into my Foundation.
Surely, you jest...
I'm serious.
You have the right qualities.
A quality called darkness.
You will conduct a secret exchange
with the Hannya Black Ops
of the Land of Woods.
The Hidden Leaf will
hand over this scroll.
And you will accept
a scroll from them.
Do we verify the contents?
This is a test of mutual trust.
If they hand over a fake scroll,
it will prove that
the Land of Woods has no interest
in an alliance
with the Hidden Leaf.
So if nothing happens,
we just bring back the scroll?
Yes. Presently, we have no
hostility with the Land of Woods,
but we cannot be certain.
Be very careful.
Leave it to us!
Hey, Itachi.
So it's your first ANBU mission.
Right.
I heard it's just Captain Kakashi
and you in a two-man squad.
Watch your back.
Why?
If it's for the sake of a mission,
the Captain won't hesitate
to kill a comrade.
He's a shinobi
of the highest degree.
Okay, everyone!
Fire up your youthful passion
and...let's go!
Please wait, Captain!
I'm way past my youthful days...
So they weren't told of
the true nature of this mission?
No. The only ones who know
are the top ranks of the Leaf
and the two of us.
You're with the Hannya Black Ops
of the Land of Woods, correct?
Indeed we are.
Now hand over the scroll!
- All right then at the same time...
- You first.
Fine then.
There's no mistake.
And your scroll?
Here it is.
Huh?!
We're supposed to
exchange scrolls, not fire!
The Hidden Leaf reneged on
our agreement and attacked us.
We shall seek retribution.
What a bold-faced lie.
You're the one who broke
the agreement!
Captain?!
They planned on betraying us
from the beginning!
We'll take over from here.
- You guys get away from here.
- You guys?!
- ANBU?!
- Reinforcements!
- Earth Style:
- Rock Collapse!
Run!
Earth Style: Mud Wall!
Your mission's complete.
Return to the village.
Hey, what are you doing?!
This is the mission
we were assigned.
Even still. Stop, Kakashi!
Hey!
Don't use my real name
while I'm on an ANBU mission!
You!
Not to worry, Captain.
No enemy survivors remain.
I'm going to report back
to Lord Danzo.
Your part of the mission
is complete.
Captain...
That Sharingan wasn't
originally yours, was it?
No...
Aren't you uncomfortable
about possessing a power
that wasn't your own?
You're not an Uchiha.
But you possess the Sharingan,
so you wield the same power
as the Uchiha.
Whose side are you on?
I've never thought about it
in that way.
A friend entrusted
this Sharingan to me...
He made me promise never to
forget what's important.
A friend?
Yeah.
To never let a friend get killed.
I see, well done.
Lord Third...
I understand why you said that
the ANBU is not suited for me.
I see...
But I don't think that Kakashi is
suited to be in the ANBU either.
Is that so?
How did the newbie do?
He passed with flying colors.
He'll be a better ANBU than me.
No, you're an exceptional ANBU,
Senpai...
There's a darkness associated
with ANBU missions.
Why are you saying this
all of a sudden?
All of a sudden? You're right.
Deception and killing is
all part of the mission...
Big brother!
Let's go home together, Sasuke!
Okay! So you're done
with your mission?
Big brother! Guess what?
My Sensei praised me
at the Academy today.
Hey, Kakashi...
Sorry about what happened
during the mission.
No...I'm sorry too.
You're part of the ANBU now and
this is one mission
you cannot avoid.
What kind of mission is this?
When the Nine-Tails incident
occurred six years ago,
the higher-ups suspected
the Uchiha Clan was behind it.
Since then, the Uchiha district has been
under 24-hour surveillance.
Time to switch.
Nothing to report.
This is...
This isn't the only
surveillance center around.
Lord Danzo's ANBU are
also watching them.
Now what'll you do?
Notify your clan about this?
What is my job here?
Just keep watching through that.
Okay, Captain. We're going.
Stay alert, Itachi.
This is part of our job as ANBU.
It's not assassination
but it's still dirty work.
A mission is a mission.
You'll be spying on your friends
and family. It's even dirtier.
I can take this shift,
if you want.
No, that's not necessary.
Besides...
Besides?
The Uchiha Clan is aware
that they're under suspicion.
I guess you would be.
Go to hell!
What the hell was that for?!
You're the one that...
It's your fault.
- It wasn't me!
- Sure, it was!
Hey, stop that!
Hey, what's going on?!
Calm down!
Why you...!
Who needs the Police Force?!
Just go and hide like you did
with the Nine-Tails!
What did you say?
Ow ow ow!
We're taking you both into custody!
Let me go!
Be quiet and walk!
It was just a drunken argument...
Couldn't they just
stop the fighting?
Complaints about harsh treatment
by the Police Force are on the rise.
People have started
to distrust them.
The Uchiha are growing impudent.
No, it's backlash.
The negativity from the Nine-Tails' incident
six years ago still hangs over them.
The Uchiha didn't suffer
any damage that time.
That is the cause of suspicion...
Furthermore, the Uchiha viewed
our distancing them from the Nine-Tails
as a sign of
the Hidden Leaf's distrust.
Our strategy of isolating the Uchiha
is a fundamental policy of the Leaf
put in place by Lord Second.
Why are they raising a fuss
after all this time?
The Lord Second's intention
wasn't isolation.
He was just concerned for each clan.
Have you forgotten about
our friend Kagami Uchiha?
I haven't forgotten.
He saved me many times
with his visual jutsu.
The Uchiha Clan is
a friend of the Hidden Leaf.
We must ensure
they stay that way.
If we can...
Move out!
My team will go to the Hidden Leaf
Police Force Headquarters!
My team will go to Uchiha District!
This is horrible!
What the hell?
Rescue anyone who is still alive!
There's a survivor!
Take him to the Medical Unit!
Everyone else is dead.
Take away the corpses.
I mean, every single one.
Check inside the buildings as well.
Who could have done such a thing?
Itachi Uchiha.
Itachi?!
Itachi Uchiha despised his clan.
Enough talking. Get to work!
What's up with him?
Hey!
The entire clan was annihilated...
Not everyone.
I hear one child survived.
What's the difference?
The Uchiha Clan is extinct.
All except one.
I never imagined that Itachi Uchiha
would be placed in the Bingo Book.
In the S-class right from the start.
Well, he slaughtered so many of his clan...
What's wrong, Senpai?
It just goes to show
I knew nothing about him.
I understood nothing.
By the way, I hear Uchiha District
will be razed to the ground.
Razed?
A terrible incident took place there.
No one would want to go near it.
Obito...
What have I been doing...
since that day?
I'm considering a complete makeover
of Danzo's Foundation
and my ANBU.
Plus we need a new Police Force.
Instead of sticking to one clan,
let's have an open recruitment
for the Police Force.
We must think about
the Leaf Village's future,
and find the right person
for the right job.
You wanted to see me?
Tell me, Kakashi.
How many years have you been
in the ANBU?
I joined during the Fourth Hokage's tenure,
so...about ten years.
Minato's original purpose in making you
a member of the ANBU
was to help you deal with
the sadness in your heart.
He wanted to keep you close to him.
I kind of figured that.
Then Minato died, and I resumed
the position of Hokage,
and took Minato's ANBU
under my command.
But keeping you by my side
isn't going to help you.
In fact, it will only darken your heart.
Take off your mask.
Ten years...
Perhaps I have asked
too much of you.
You are hereby relieved of
your duties as an ANBU,
and will assume a new position.
Yes, sir!
You will be a jonin leader!
Huh?!