I treated your wounds.
You won.
But you've sustained quite
a bit of damage as well.
Try not to force yourself up.
We've met once before.
The last time, it was as enemies.
Don't worry about Deidara's death...
I am not your enemy.
I brought you here in order to
tell you something.
You're not interested at all, I see...
Maybe if I put it another way,
you'll want to listen?
It is about Itachi Uchiha.
Yes...You think you know
about your brother,
but you know nothing.
Oh, all right...
Let's start with introductions.
Like you, I am a survivor
of the Uchiha Clan...
And the one who knows
the truth about Itachi Uchiha.
It can't be!
What was that just now?
The Amaterasu,
which Itachi implanted inside you.
How like Itachi. He surprises you
even after he's dead.
To think he planned things this far...
What are you talking about?
In order to kill me,
he placed a jutsu into you...
Or rather should I say;
in order to keep me away from you...
He probably set his Amaterasu
to self-activate
when you look into my Sharingan.
Even Itachi didn't know
everything about me...
Otherwise I would be dead right now.
So this was his fail-safe plan...
Although it didn't work on me.
So...what's this all about?
Before he died, Itachi must've done
something to you.
At the end...for your sake,
he transferred his own
ocular powers to you.
What are you saying?
Just...what are you trying to say?
Why would Itachi do
something like that?!
Don't you get it?
In order to...protect you.
Protect?
Did you say protect?!
I'll say it once more...
You think you know about your brother,
but you know nothing.
If you continue speaking
such nonsense, I'll kill you!
You're not making this easy, are you?
I suppose that's natural though...
Suddenly being told such a story
by a stranger like me.
But what I tell you is the truth.
Itachi did mention it, did he not?
About his accomplice that night.
I am that Madara Uchiha.
I know everything about Itachi.
I suppose Itachi died
without realizing that.
Shut up!
Such things don't matter anymore!
Just get out of my sight!
No, you will listen.
You need to hear this.
It's your obligation!
For the sake of the ninja world...
For the sake of
the Hidden Leaf Village...
And for your sake...
Your brother risked everything.
You will know how Itachi Uchiha lived!
Do you know why?
Why Itachi implanted Amaterasu
into your eye?
Itachi was determined to make sure
that you and I would not meet.
You will understand why,
as well as everything else,
when you hear me out.
Those who knew the truth about Itachi
were Danzo of the Hidden Leaf,
the Third Hokage,
and his advisors Homura and Koharu.
Just those four.
The Third Hokage died...
and now, there are only three aging folk.
Still, those three will probably
never reveal the abominable truth.
The truth about Itachi will fade
into darkness forever.
And that is what Itachi wished.
However, I know the truth
about Itachi too.
As I said earlier...
Itachi died without realizing that.
However, he wanted to
make doubly sure.
It seems Itachi did not trust me.
So just in case I did know the truth,
he planned to silence me
with the Amaterasu.
He probably anticipated I would show
my Sharingan
in order to speak to you.
What is this?
What is this guy saying?
Protect me?
Protect?!
The truth?
Think back.
Think carefully and
remember about Itachi.
About your kind brother.
No, he...
He tried to kill me!
He tried to take my eyes...
Who would do such a thing?!
Foolish little brother...
Mangekyo Sharingan!
Calm down!
Breathe slowly.
Don't touch me!
Even if you do hate me...
That's what big brothers are for.
Sorry, Sasuke...Another time.
You're awake...
Sorry, but I took the liberty
of tying you up.
Since you weren't gonna stay still
and listen to me.
He...Itachi was my enemy.
He killed our parents...
He killed everyone in the clan.
He was a rogue ninja...
A member of the Akatsuki...
He was despicable.
He was my target.
It's true...
that he annihilated
the Uchiha clan that night.
And he deserted the Hidden Leaf.
Then...
And that is what he was ordered
to do by the Hidden Leaf.
That is the beginning of
the truth about Itachi.
It was his mission?
Yes.
That night, Itachi killed his personal
feelings and fulfilled his mission.
It seems you've calmed down a bit.
What are you talking about?!
In order to talk about Itachi,
I must take you back to the early days
when Hidden Leaf Village was founded.
Itachi sacrificed himself.
This is fate that has continued
since ages past.
He was sacrificed for it.
A huge problem rooted since the time
Hidden Leaf Village was founded.
That is what determined Itachi's life.
It's a long story,
but everything I tell you is the truth.
On what basis should I believe you?
You're untrustworthy.
There's nothing I can show you
as proof.
And it's up to you whether
you believe me or not.
But you will hear me out until I finish.
Fine...So talk.
It all started more
than 80 years ago.
The world was in turmoil.
It was the age of war.
Nations battled for power and
to increase their territories.
During this age of war,
ninja consisted of individual clans
serving as armed units.
They were hired by various nations
to participate in the fighting.
And among the many ninja clans,
two were feared as the strongest.
One was us, the Uchiha clan.
And the other was known
as the Forest's Senju Clan.
We of the Uchiha clan possessed
exceptional chakra and the Sharingan.
Excelling in all types of warfare,
we became known as a battle clan.
And I was born into the Uchiha clan,
possessing chakra that
was especially powerful.
Perhaps the fact that I've lived
this long is proof of that.
Back in those days,
all I did was battle.
In an age defined by power,
I sought to become ever stronger
and killed my friends and
even my younger brother.
Why you...!
As a result, I came into possession
of the perfect Mangekyo Sharingan,
and became the leader of the Uchiha.
And using that power,
I fought the Senju clan countless times.
It was inevitable that I face Hashirama,
the leader of the Senju clan.
"Wood Style" Hashirama Senju,
the future first Hokage.
The one who stood at
the top of the ninja world...
And the one I respected most.
If the Senju moved,
so did the Uchiha.
Our clan was probably the only clan
able to compete with them.
If a nation hired the Senju, the
opposing nation would hire the Uchiha.
We were like rivals.
The more I went up against Hashirama,
the more my name became known
as well.
To heighten your reputation...
You took your younger brother's eyes
just for that?!
I did take them.
But I needed power in order
to protect the Uchiha.
Protect?
Yes. As the Uchiha name spread,
its enemies increased.
It was a necessary sacrifice
to protect the clan
during the fierce fighting with the Senju,
and the other clans.
It was not for my fame.
My younger brother was
in total agreement
and offered his eyes to me.
But one day,
the Senju clan offered a truce.
And the Uchiha accepted it.
Everyone, in both clans,
had grown weary of the fighting
that had dragged on for so long.
They had enough.
But I...
I was the only one who opposed it.
Where has all the hate gone?!
For what purpose had my brother
sacrificed himself?!
The Uchiha and Senju are
like oil and water.
I couldn't help fearing that in time,
the Uchiha clan would come to
be oppressed by the Senju clan.
However...everyone in the Uchiha clan
wanted a truce.
As their leader, I had no choice
but to go along with their wishes.
Shortly thereafter, the ninja alliance
signed a pact with the Land of Fire,
which had sought dominion
over the territories.
The secure one nation, one village system
was formed
and became the Land of Fire and
the Village Hidden in the Leaves.
Other countries adopted
the one nation, one village system.
And subsequently,
the fires of war were extinguished.
Momentary peace.
But due to a certain incident,
the Hidden Leaf Village quickly
descended into turmoil.
A certain incident?
A fight...for the First Hokage's seat.
As you know, the first to occupy
that seat was Hashirama Senju.
The Land of Fire and
the entire clan chose Hashirama.
It was inevitable that the Uchiha's
hold on the reins of power would loosen.
I decided that the Uchiha
should take leadership...
That we should confront Hashirama...
But no one, not even from
the Uchiha clan, supported me.
My subordinates, who did not wish
to light the fires of war,
were unsympathetic and betrayed me.
I was accused of acting
out of greed and self-interest.
Not only that...
They scorned me as
a selfish brother
who stole his younger brother's eyes
in order to save his own.
What brother would willfully
hurt his younger brother?!
I just...I just wanted to
protect the Uchiha!
I left the village.
Everyone betrayed me.
I became an avenger and declared
war on the Hidden Leaf Village.
And I lost...
At that place which became known
as the Final Valley.
I was said...to have died there.
Even Hashirama believed it.
And everyone forgot about me...
History forgot about me.
Hashirama's younger brother
who became the Second Hokage
was determined that there would
never be a traitor like me again.
So, as proof of his trust, he granted
the Uchiha a special position...
And he created
the Hidden Leaf Police Force.
But the truth is...
This was to further distance the Uchiha
from the reins of government.
Furthermore, it was a way to keep
a close eye on the entire clan.
There were Uchiha members
who realized this...
Members who wanted to carry
on my rebellion.
But...it was too late.
Time passed...
The Senju clan solidified
its hold on power
and the Uchiha fell to
becoming Senju dogs.
And what I predicted came to pass.
A certain other incident sealed
Uchiha's figurative demise.
Yes...
The attack of the Nine-Tailed Fox Demon
16 years ago.
What do you mean?
The Nine-Tails can only be tamed
and controlled
by the ocular powers of the Uchiha.
The higher-ups of Hidden Leaf Village
perceived the Uchiha
to be behind this attack.
That was a natural occurrence,
a natural calamity.
The Uchiha had nothing to do with it.
Yet suspicion fell on them...
That the Uchiha had revolted
and sought to take power.
As a result,
the Uchiha was put under
the strict surveillance of
the ANBU Black Ops,
and they were forced to relocate
to the outskirts of the village.
They became totally estranged.
The Third Hokage was the only one
to voice opposition to our treatment.
But Danzo of the ANBU Black Ops
and the rest of the councilors
would not listen.
In the end,
the Uchiha clan was not trusted.
And the discrimination began...
Their distrust bred hatred and eventually,
their suspicions became reality.
The Uchiha clan plotted
a coup d'état to take over the village...
The higher-ups in Hidden Leaf Village
planted a spy within the Uchiha clan.
That spy was your older brother...
From that moment,
Itachi's suffering began.
Despite being an Uchiha,
you were kept in the dark.
Because you were still young.
But it's all true...
Your father, Fugaku,
was the mastermind behind the plot.
And your brother, Itachi,
was ordered by your father
to spy on the ANBU Black Ops.
Itachi...You also serve as
the Uchiha clan's pipeline
to the Village nerve center.
You know that, don't you?
However...it was actually the opposite.
Itachi was working for the village,
feeding them information about the Uchiha.
He was what they call
a double agent.
You can't even imagine
what a heavy burden that is to bear.
Why?! Why did Itachi betray the Uchiha?
It may be hard for you
to understand,
not having witnessed the horrors of war.
The Third Great Ninja War...
When Itachi was merely
four years old,
he witnessed the deaths
of many people.
He was too young to experience war.
War is hell...
That trauma made Itachi
a pacifist who hated war.
He was a man who put
the village's safety first,
and who strove to preserve peace.
Instead of being bound
by obligation to his clan,
he was a ninja who loved his village.
And the village higher-ups
preyed on that trait.
They assigned him to
a top-secret mission.
An eye for an eye...
For them to oppose the Uchiha,
they would need the Sharingan.
Yes.
The mission was...
The total annihilation of
the Uchiha clan.
I can't even begin to imagine
what he went through emotionally.
Itachi was forced to make
a terrible choice.
The impossible choice of killing
one's own brethren.
But a civil war started by the likes
of the Uchiha would shake
the very foundations of Hidden Leaf Village
and the Land of Fire.
Other nations would waste no time
in seizing the opportunity to attack.
It could even trigger
a Fourth Great Ninja War...
The Uchiha clan's self-interest would
involve innocent people
who had nothing to do with
the ninja world.
And countless people would die
once again.
If you were Itachi,
what would you have done?
So Itachi made up his mind.
He himself would bring
the curtain down on his clan.
He did not hate the Uchiha
nor did he betray them.
It was inevitable.
The discrimination by the village...
and the object of their antagonism...
He shouldered the blame all by himself.
No one can ever question Itachi's decision
and the sacrifice he made.
To be truthful, back then,
even I anticipated war.
I was bitter towards Senju's
Hidden Leaf Village as well as the Uchiha.
But Itachi was even aware of that.
He alone was aware
of my existence.
Itachi sought to contact me
and made certain conditions.
In exchange for guiding me
in my vendetta against the Uchiha,
I was not to lay a hand on the village.
He would help me kill our brethren...
But the Third Hokage tried
a different hand.
He tried to approach the Uchiha
for a compromise.
But time ran out,
and his efforts failed.
Leading to that night.
It was a mission.
To be the sole perpetrator
of his clan's slaughter
and become a rogue ninja
with his reputation in tatters.
All of that was his mission.
And Itachi completely fulfilled
his duty...
With one exception...
He could not bring himself...
to kill his younger brother.
After that, Itachi appealed
to the Third Hokage
to protect you from Danzo
and the higher-ups.
Then he threatened Danzo
and left the village.
If he laid a hand on Sasuke,
he would leak every detail about
the village to unallied nations.
Above all else,
he was concerned about you.
And yet he couldn't tell you
the full truth.
He had no choice
but to say the things he did.
By making revenge your goal,
he hoped to make you strong.
The Uchiha is a proud clan
of the Hidden Leaf.
He wanted you to keep
believing that.
He beseeched the Hokage that
you never learn the truth.
And from the moment
he left the village,
he was resolved to fighting you,
and dying.
So that he could instill in you
a new power.
That is Itachi's truth.
No, you're lying.
They must be lies.
That's nonsense...
He almost killed me several times!
If Itachi wished it, he would have.
Without a doubt.
He even used the Mangekyo Sharingan
to try to kill me!
Your battle was part of his plan.
Itachi needed to pressure you
in that fight.
The reason for that...
Well, you probably realized it too,
haven't you?
He freed you of the curse mark.
And the death of someone
closest to you...
It was a battle to awaken
your Mangekyo.
It was a battle that Itachi planned
entirely for your sake.
He pretended to be after
your eyes until the very end.
It's starting to sink in, I see...
You are lying.
The one who made the Nine-Tails attack
the village was you, Madara!
Itachi said so.
You framed the Uchiha!
And you teamed up with Itachi
to toy with the clan!
Itachi was lying
when he told you that.
Itachi feared that you would
somehow learn the truth.
He wanted to make absolutely certain
there was no chance of that.
He lied to make sure
you would not trust me...
Not only that,
he implanted Amaterasu in your eyes.
As if I'd believe you!
He...Itachi was evil!
He's a criminal who killed his clan
and joined Akatsuki!
Itachi took sole responsibility for
an unspeakable crime
and left the village.
Then he found a way to join Akatsuki
and watched over
an organization that was dangerous
to the village from the inside.
He was always thinking
about Hidden Leaf Village.
And he thought of you...
When the Third Hokage,
who had promised to protect you, died...
Itachi made an appearance
in Hidden Leaf Village.
It was to tell Danzo and
the other superiors that "I am alive."
You were foremost in his thoughts--
Stop! Lies! They're all lies...
You're still alive, aren't you?
Your eyes did not perceive
a single thing about Itachi.
You were not able to see through
the illusion Itachi created at all.
Itachi killed his friends, his superiors...
He killed his lover,
his father and his mother.
But he could not
kill...his little brother.
He cried tears of blood and
killed every shred of feeling
he had inside him,
then he killed his brethren
for the sake of his village.
But he just couldn't kill you.
Do you understand what that means?
To him, your life...
was more precious than the village.
Until the moment of his death...
No, even in death, it was all for you.
To pass on a new power...
By making you defeat him,
he had avenged the Uchiha clan.
In order to raise and make you
the hero of Hidden Leaf Village.
His body was ravaged by illness
and he knew he was near death.
Even if he had to rely on drugs
to prolong his life...
For the sake of
his beloved little brother...
He had to fight you...
and die in your presence.
For the peace of Hidden Leaf Village,
and most of all, for Sasuke Uchiha.
He wanted to die
as a criminal and a traitor.
He accepted disgrace
in the place of honor,
and hate in the place of love.
And despite that, Itachi died
with a smile on his face.
He entrusted the Uchiha name to you,
his younger brother,
deceiving you to the very end.
I'm home.
Welcome home, Big Brother!
Play with me, Big Brother!
Huh? What'll we play?!
Sasuke!
Your brother has
Academy homework to do.
You can play after he's done.
Huh?
That's okay.
I can do my homework later.
It's easy anyway.
Goodness...
Where could Big Brother be hiding?
Found you, Big Brother.
You're pretty sharp, Sasuke.
However...too bad.
Ah! No fair!
Say, Father...
Hmm?
Brother and I were playing
hide-and-seek today,
but Big Brother used Clone Jutsu
to run away.
That's not fair, is it?
Hmm... You're able to do
the Clone Jutsu already?
Big Brother, teach me
the Clone Jutsu too, after dinner!
Homework!
Sorry, Sasuke.
Let's do it some other time.
Sasuke. It's time to go.
You said that you would teach me
a new shuriken jutsu.
I have an important mission tomorrow
that I must prepare for.
You're a liar...
Sorry, Sasuke.
Maybe some other time.
Big Brother, watch this!
Hey! Don't be reckless...
Big Brother...
Will you train with me again?
Yeah...
But I'm assigned to missions
and starting tomorrow,
you will be attending
the Ninja Academy.
We won't have much time
to spend together.
That's okay.
As long as you can stay with me
once in a while.
But, we only have each other
as siblings.
Even if it's only as an obstacle
for you to overcome.
Big Brother...
Can you help me with
shuriken training today?
I'm busy.
You should ask Father to teach you.
But you're better than Father
when it comes to shuriken jutsu.
Even a kid like me can see that.
Oww.
Sorry, Sasuke...Some other time.
Even if it's only as an obstacle
for you to overcome...
I'm always going to be there for you.
Even if you do hate me...
That's what big brothers are for.
Sorry, Sasuke...
This is it.
We are no longer "Hebi."
From this day on,
our team will be "Taka."
Taka has only one goal.
We...
will destroy the Hidden Leaf.
What are you doing?
The preparations are already complete.
When I look upon the full moon,
it takes me back to that night.
As well as...
the memories I've been trying to forget.
Now I can finally recall things
about Itachi...
He was crying at that moment.
I thought I had imagined it.
I didn't realize...
It seems what you told me was true.
So what will you do?
Are you going to transplant Itachi's eyes?
No...
What Itachi wanted to see,
and what I will see hereafter,
will be completely different.
I can't do as Itachi wished me to do.
I will restore the Uchiha clan
in my own way.
Umm...I need to talk to you,
Kisame Senpai.
First Zetsu,
now you come bothering me?
I actually thought you were dead.
It turns out that you will be
the last to know.
I'm sorry that I had to deceive you,
the person closest to me.
Hmm?
So that's how it was.
I never would have guessed
that Tobi was you.
But I'm relieved...
If you're the one pulling the strings,
that makes it easier for me...
Former Lord Mizukage...
I mean, Madara.
I shall continue to count on you, Kisame.
The same goes for me.
Itachi is out...
And now, his little brother joins.
What an interesting turn of events.
We, Taka, will destroy the Hidden Leaf.
You say that, but how do you intend
to go about it?
We're going to kill the Elders.
The others are not
our immediate concern.
If you aim high,
the ones below will shield them.
It won't be that easy.
You so-called "Taka" don't have
enough strength for that.
Kisame Senpai...
You shouldn't underestimate us.
We still haven't settled that
last game of ours.
Sasuke! You haven't trained them well.
He stopped it with just his arm...!
Suigetsu! Are you stupid?
This isn't the place to...
My objective is his Shark Skin Sword!
I've been hanging with Sasuke only
so I could get that!
Sasuke...What'll you do?
All right...
Go for it if you want to, Suigetsu.
You probably can't beat him
yet anyway.
Yet, huh?
Oh...thanks a lot, Sasuke.
Just hold tight.
I'll treat you to some tasty shark's fin
soon enough.
The Akatsuki is also low on manpower.
I'd like to avoid unnecessary skirmishes.
Humph. Then you shouldn't
criticize others, you guys.
We share common interests.
From here on, Taka will work together
with the Akatsuki.
And what's in it for us?
We'll give you a Tailed Beast.
Tailed Beast?
You don't know about them?
I know! It's like the Nine-Tails,
with chakra physically manifesting
as tails, they're mon-
In other words?
They're chakra monsters.
Originally, the First Hokage collected
several of them
and kept them under his control.
Each time a Great Ninja War threatened,
the Hokage Hashirama used them
to maintain the power balance
and distributed them to other lands,
starting with the five great nations,
as proof of alliances or agreements.
You could call them
the ultimate chakra weapons.
It's not a bad preposition.
That's quite generous.
However, if you betray the Akatsuki,
you will die accordingly.
Humph...
There are nine Tailed Beasts
in this world.
The Akatsuki has collected six so far...
so there are three left.
The Akatsuki and Taka will split up
to hunt the remaining three.
That is our immediate goal.
You don't have the Nine-Tails yet, right?
Taka will capture the Eight-Tails.
The Akatsuki will hunt the rest.
Which includes Naruto...
How did it go?
It went well...
That's good.
Itachi is dead...
So our eyesore's finally gone.
And now,
we need no longer keep our pact
to stay away from the Hidden Leaf.
We've waited so long...
All so we could proceed
according to plan.
This is fine.
But Itachi had placed insurance
in Sasuke.
The Amaterasu.
Itachi believed that no one knew
the truth about him.
So why go so far...?
True intentions aside,
he probably feared I would try
to recruit Sasuke.
But...who would have thought
that the Akatsuki would lose so
many members to get to this point.
We had problems at every turn...
But everyone made a valuable contribution
in their own way.
Deidara...Sasori...Hidan...Kakuzu...
Without them,
we could not have gotten this far.
Thanks to them, the scenario is
playing out just as I planned.
Most importantly...
I've won Sasuke over.
So? Where is this thing called
"the Eight-Tails"?
Don't take us lightly...
We have no intention
of telling you a thing.
We, the Yotsuki clan,
never betray our comrades.
That is-
Doubt exists...in a fearful heart.
Suigetsu, enough.
He's under Sasuke's genjutsu.
Shucks...I was just getting
to the fun part.
Tell me where the Eight-Tails is.
He is training...at Unraikyo,
Storm Cloud Ravine.
Any distinguishing features?
He...wields eight blades...
And has bull horns tattooed on his...
left cheek.
Sheesh...
Those eyes of his have improved.
Now he's even more difficult
to deal with.
Oh wow...
Sasuke's gotten even cooler.
This is a nice place...
I think I could control
my impulses here.
It's calming...
You make my eyes hurt...
Light...
Noon already?
Damn it, bastard! Screw you, man!
Training from mornin',
stomach so starvin'
I'm just a rap-lovin' guy
and just decided on sukiyaki for lunch!
Yay!
Hm...?!
Are you the Jinchuriki host
of the Eight-Tails?
No, it's Lord Eight-Tails. Okay?
Say, "Are you Lord Jinchuriki?" Okay?
I'm here to capture you.
No. You have to say,
"Please allow me to capture you, sir."
Okay? Right?
Suigetsu, you take the right.
Jugo, you take the left.
Karin, get behind me.
Hmm...Let's see.
Right in the middle of our conversation...
Here's some serious advice!
You're fools!
Fools.
We can't kill the Jinchuriki.
Isn't that what the Akatsuki
told us, Suigetsu?
It's all right.
I can feel his chakra.
Geez, talk about a showy diversion.
Why you...!
The only one who gets
to dig me is me...
So scram, you fools, or I'll blast y'all!
You fools...Yeah!
Suigetsu, get back.
I'm peeking through...
And see you alive...
But y'all are so brainless!
Stop joking around!
My thirst for blood is my courage...
Making me so optimistic.
My blades are swirlin',
but my store's a closin'.
Making for a blow-out sale
for my performance!
Yeah...
I've got spare power and
my appeal is glowing,
Eight-Tails the bridge.
Killer Bee, that's me! Ah! Yay!
Start fighting and
you're gonna be embarrassed.
'Cuz you'll be torn apart...
Bit my tongue...
Wh-What's with this guy?
He's totally crazy, but that Jugo...
He keeps dodging
my Executioner's blade...
What is this guy?!
You made me bite my tongue...Fools!
Are you all right?!
Yeah...
I'll go.
Who the heck are you all?
Fools...You fools!
This guy's getting on my nerves!
Who are you?
Why would you capture me? Huh?
We don't owe you an explanation.
A guy who talks in weird verses...
is such a pain to deal with.
It's to obtain power
as quickly as possible.
If you don't like it, leave.
Tsk...
That's your prerogative...
I also want to confirm whether
the Akatsuki's verbal promise is
true or false and get it over with.
Either way, we're the ones who
are going to use the Akatsuki.
Keep that in mind.
The Akatsuki?
That goes without question.
Y-You are so cool, Sasuke!
I knew he wouldn't let himself
be used as a pawn.
Well then, let's get to it and
silence this irritating rapper.
I intend to.
It's not irritating...
It's cool rhythms and rhymes.
You fool! Ah! Yeah!!
He's really...irritating!
He's got zero rapping talent!
What?! You fool! You jerk!
Will you shut up?!
I'm feeling good right now.
Just came up with
the greatest rhyme.
Thank you.
That's why I'll play with you...
You foolish baby!
I'll give you a taste of my hook.
What?! He countered it?!
He can stream his chakra too?!
Float...Float like a butterfly...!
Eight-Tails! Sting like a bee!
Sasuke!
And this is the finishing sting!
He also uses...
Lightning Style, which is my weakness.
Sasuke!
This is bad...
Here, Sasuke...
Hurry up and bite me!
Do it now!
He funneled the Lightning Style
through his body
and shifted the course of my attack.
He avoided a fatal injury...
And...that woman possesses
the ability
to heal others by letting them
suck her chakra.
Thanks, Karin.
Sure...
Sasuke! Let's do this together!
The fact is this guy is super strong.
We should go at him as if
we are trying to kill him, instead of not.
That way we can probably take him
down without killing him.
Looks like this battle is gonna drag on...
Check it out, yo!
Got you!
Sasuke, now! Just do the both of us!
Chidori!
Gone! Where is he?
So weak, yet so persistent...
I'm done playing,
now go home for some drinking! Yeah!
- Karin!
- I know...
Over there!
That woman's also a sensory-type, eh?
Can't be helped...
Going with the eighth tail.
Here it comes...
It's the same as back then.
Hmm...He's the first to dodge
my Eight-Tails form
since my brother.
Damn, he's going after the others!
First, you guys will be torn apart!
Are you all right?
Yeah...more or less...
He definitely has speed and power.
But he only moves in
a linear fashion.
My eyes should be able to
make them out.
Karin! Read his chakra and
predict his movements!
Stay on him and keep me informed
of his location at all times!
That's if you can really keep up!
Those eyes...The Sharingan!
Is this genjutsu?
I can't move my body.
Lariat!
Sasuke!
Wha--?!
What is this?
His neck and chest portion have
been blown off, organs and all.
He's beyond our...
He is like my reincarnation.
Hang in there!
Karin, it's all right. I'll do it.
The chakra you have now
can't deal with it.
What do you intend to do?
I'll distribute my body and chakra to
Sasuke by merging with him.
Since his body was compatible with
my curse mark, it should work.
In order to release the genjutsu,
I need a partner to disturb
my chakra and awaken me.
My partner is
the Eight-Tails inside me.
A genjutsu has no effect on
the Jinchuriki host,
which controls a Tailed Beast.
Your illusions I obliterate,
then you all I shall annihilate.
My true form of the Jinchuriki...
It's a monster, so watch it now,
Host Transformation, yeah...
Eight-Tails will pee your pants,
you lil' ants!
Such chakra...
Is this even possible?
That's the Eight-Tails?
An ox-octopus monster...
That's his true form?
To spear my foes,
my glorious longhorns!
His chakra is off the scale...
We'll die if we stay here!
Jugo, are you done yet?!
Thank goodness...Sasuke...
You're conscious.
Come on, get up!
All right, Jugo...Huh?!
He turned into a child?! Why?!
Jugo...
I won't let you die...
You're a memento of Kimimaro.
Come on! Hurry! We gotta run!
A Water-Style ninja...I knew it.
You have the advantage
of the terrain!
I'll take over from here!
Run while you can!
Suigetsu...
Let's go, Sasuke.
Heh. Who would've thought...
that I'd end up sacrificing myself
to save their hides this often?
As if I'd let you get away after
what you've done, you fool, you jerk!
Th-That really doesn't look good.
Could that be Lord Killer Bee's?!
Wh-What is it, Senpai?!
- Let's go!
- Yes, sir!
Th-That's...!
Lord Killer Bee...
Why has he transformed into
the Eight-Tails?!
And after all that lecturing
from Lord Raikage...
Look closely!
He's battling someone!
Those robes...
Are they the Akatsuki?
The ones who kidnapped Yugito?
Suigetsu is wasted...Damn it!
We can't get away...What'll we do?!
He's coming!
Amaterasu!
S-So those are the inextinguishable
black flames Sasuke spoke of!
A-Awesome!
Karin, run!
Damn! The black flames!
It's too late for Karin.
We need to get away before
we get caught too!
- Wait, Jugo.
- No!
Karin!
Jugo! Get Karin! Hurry!
The black flames are extinguished...
What's going on, Sasuke?
I was able to extinguish
the black flames of Amaterasu.
Are these the visual powers
of my Mangekyo Sharingan?!
In which case...
The Eight-Tails...
It seems he's barely alive.
Then...we managed to take down
the Eight-Tails without killing him.
Let's grab him and go.
No way...
Lord Killer Bee has been defeated?
I-It must be some mistake...
Shall we rescue him?
They're Akatsuki members.
Don't be hasty.
Huh?! That's...
What is it?!
The Uchiha crest!
Uchiha?
Rather than taking action ourselves,
we'd better get word to Lord Raikage!
If he hears what happened
to his younger brother...
Knowing Lord Raikage,
he won't be pleased at all.
You seem quite affected, physically.
Especially since, in addition to
losing Orochimaru's curse mark,
you haven't quite healed from
your battle against Itachi.
Yeah...
Though I really didn't expect
we'd have such a fight on our hands.
But now...
What?!
Killer Bee was taken?!
A member of the Hidden Leaf...
from the Uchiha clan
was among the assailants.
My partner is tailing them right now.
Lord Raikage, what are your orders?
The Akatsuki won't get away
with this!
The Akatsuki...!
Just you wait, my brother!