Say, that boy...
He's the one. The only one
who failed to make it!
Humph! Good for him!
It would be terrible if someone
like him became a ninja.
I mean that boy is actually...
Don't say another word.
It's taboo.
Damn! What's with all this?!
Good thing I took extra measures,
just in case.
They haven't returned yet.
Naruto?
Why you...!
Wait, Naruto! Stop!
No, Captain Yamato!
Let me just say this!
Old man Tonbei!
You knew the forbidden jutsu was
embedded into Hotaru's back, didn't you?!
Answer me!
The forbidden jutsu is in that girl?
Friends of the Hidden Leaf...
Please stop!
It was my grandfather.
You served Hotaru's grandfather
all through the years, didn't you?
So why didn't you stop him?!
Please stop, Naruto!
No, I won't stop!
Because of that...
Because of that, you're...
I asked that it be done!
What did you say?
I...I asked for the forbidden jutsu!
Lady Hotaru...
Hotaru...Why do such a thing?
Tonbei...I'm glad you're all right.
I should say that about you,
Lady Hotaru.
Friends of the Hidden Leaf...
Sir Utakata...
I am beholden to you
for all you have done for us.
Don't mention it.
But the Tsuchigumo Village was already
under the bandit's control.
I see...And that is why
you returned here...
Yes.
Never mind that.
Tell us the rest of what
you were saying earlier!
About the forbidden jutsu?
Yeah.
It was Grandfather's dream.
En no Gyoja's...?
The Tsuchigumo Clan was once
hailed as a proud clan.
By possessing
a powerful forbidden jutsu,
we were said to even be able to tilt
the balance of the Great Ninja War.
But at the same time,
our clan was targeted often
because of the forbidden jutsu.
And one life after another was lost.
When the Great War was over,
only a few remained who could
wield the forbidden jutsu.
Furthermore, Lord En no Gyoja and
the village elder had disagreements
over the clan's survival.
This led to the clan splitting
into two groups
with one in the Tsuchigumo Village
and the other at Mount Katsuragi.
However, Lord En no Gyoja was
already quite advanced in years
and few opted to follow him
to Mount Katsuragi.
Hotaru...I'm counting on you.
The future of the Tsuchigumo Clan...
Grandfather!
Grandfather believed that
protecting the Tsuchigumo name
was the way to make amends and
honor those who lost their lives
for the forbidden jutsu.
That is why I want to carry on the wish
of my grandfather, who was my master.
How stupid.
Just for that you had the forbidden jutsu
embedded in your body?
For your master, for your clan...
It's all so stupid.
Even so, it's a student's duty to
carry out the wishes of her master!
Hotaru...
You wouldn't understand...
Master Utakata...how I feel.
Lady Hotaru,
perhaps Sir Utakata is right.
Tonbei?
It is evident that the Tsuchigumo
Clan no longer has the strength
to safeguard the forbidden jutsu.
If we allowed the misuse
of the forbidden jutsu,
Lord En no Gyoja would
surely turn in his grave.
To prevent its misuse,
we have no choice
but to destroy the jutsu.
Destroy?
And how would you do that?!
The forbidden jutsu is
inside Hotaru's body!
You don't mean...!
Don't get me wrong.
Mr. Tonbei...
You mustn't move too much.
Do not be concerned.
What is this?
Lord En no Gyoja entrusted me
with that scroll.
It contains the way to remove the
forbidden jutsu from Lady Hotaru's body.
Is there such a method?
Lord En no Gyoja would never have
embedded the forbidden jutsu
into Lady Hotaru without
a way to remove it.
What kind of master would
even think of such a thing?
Please forgive me.
I should have advised you sooner.
Once it is removed from your body,
the forbidden jutsu will
no longer have any power.
I also longed to restore
the clan's former glory.
Without the forbidden jutsu,
that dream would fade.
But this is how it should be.
You can't be serious!
Friends of the Hidden Leaf...
Please help me remove
the forbidden jutsu from Lady Hotaru.
However, we cannot make
such decisions on our own.
Then hurry up and get
Granny Tsunade's permission.
We can't just leave Hotaru like this!
Please wait!
I haven't decided to let go
of the forbidden jutsu yet!
But Lady Hotaru...
Not only the forbidden jutsu,
but also your life would be in peril!
It's my life!
Come to your senses!
Sir Utakata...
I-I'm sorry.
Are you telling me to abandon
my clan pride and honor?!
Hey, wait!
Naruto!
I'll bring her back!
Lady Hotaru...
I'll go and convince her.
Hold on, please!
We cannot let you move around.
She can't have gone far.
I'll be right back.
I won't put Hotaru in danger.
All right. Sakura, go with him!
Yes, sir.
I'd be better at scouting her out.
There's something I want you
to do right now.
Yes, sir.
Grandfather...
Hotaru...take a look.
Once, the Tsuchigumo clan was
known far beyond those mountains,
and all one could see from here
was part of our lands.
Our clan was so grand, wasn't it?
Are you crying? Grandfather...
Was I wrong?
If I had not been the leader,
would the Tsuchigumo Clan...?
So your grandfather's grave is here?
I picked those near by.
Thank you, Naruto.
With a view like this,
your grandpa must be very happy
to be buried here.
I'm sure he's worried about you.
He's right. Let's go back, Hotaru.
Sir Utakata.
Well? Let's go.
But I...
If you truly wish to restore
your clan's glory,
you don't need to rely
on such a thing.
Having too much power only
gives rise to suffering.
There's still one other way.
Another way?
There is someone named Shiranami
among the Tsuchigumo Clan...
who is able to use
the forbidden jutsu.
Who's Shiranami?
He is grandfather's student.
En no Gyoja's student?
Well, more correctly,
he is the student's student.
Sir Shiranami's father, Sir Hato,
was my grandfather's first student.
I have heard that he was brilliant
with exceptional ninjutsu skills.
And it was said that his son,
Sir Shiranami, was even more skilled.
But during the Great War,
Sir Shiranami's father was killed
trying to protect the forbidden jutsu.
Grandfather sensed that
Sir Shiranami was also in danger
and had him flee the village.
Grandfather often said that
if those two were here now,
this village would not be
in such dire straits.
So where is this Shiranami fellow now?
You know of anything?
Well...
There's no telling when
the bandits will return.
We have no time to look for Shiranami.
Make up your mind, Hotaru.
All right then! I'll go and
find this Shiranami!
What are you talking about?!
Actually...Hotaru...
I'm sorta in the same dilemma as you.
You too, Naruto?
Naruto...that's...
I can't go into detail,
but deep down,
I've always been troubled by it.
Anyway, I can be like this now
because people like Sakura,
the Pervy Sage and all the rest
of my friends have stayed by me.
But Hotaru, you're awfully strong.
You accepted those troubles
and you've suffered all alone.
Carrying your clan and
your grandpa's dream on your shoulders.
That's why I want you to
fulfill your dream.
If this Shiranami fellow is found,
he'll be an ally, right?
Then you won't be alone.
And you don't have to suffer
by yourself.
Naruto...
Now don't worry.
Just leave it to me, Naruto Uzumaki.
Give me one...no, two days.
I'll find Shiranami without fail.
What a surprise.
I never would've guessed my name
would be mentioned here.
It's pretty much what I imagined.
What will you do?
It will be dangerous to keep
the forbidden jutsu intact.
But it says here they want to
keep the forbidden jutsu
and guard the girl at the Leaf village.
Without a doubt, it's necessary
to keep the forbidden jutsu
from falling into
a third party's possession.
Cripes...I acted like finding the guy
was no big deal for me,
but where do I start looking?
Well, it's no use thinking about it.
This calls for the strength
in numbers approach!
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Naruto is...?
Indeed, if Shiranami returns
to the village, we could...
Can he find him in only two days?
We may not be able to wait
that long.
If the bandits attack again
before Naruto returns...
You're right...
Just in case, we'll make preparations
and stand by to purge
the forbidden jutsu.
You understand, Hotaru?
Yes.
It looks like the Diremption Jutsu
requires potions.
Sakura, you'll be in charge.
Mix the potion and be ready.
Understood.
Lord En no Gyoja would never
have embedded the forbidden jutsu
into Lady Hotaru without
a way to remove it.
What kind of master would
even think of such a thing?
M-Master...?!
No, Utakata! He didn't...
Harusame didn't try to kill you.
It wasn't like that.
Could it be...
that Tsurugi spoke the truth?
If so, then what was
Master trying to tell me?
I must speak to Tsurugi once more.
Say, ever heard of a guy
named Shiranami?
Do you know a guy
I see...Don't know him, huh?
Anything you know?
If you find out, tell me,
Naruto of the Hidden Leaf!
It's no use...
I've used up my chakra and
I don't even have a clue.
What's the matter?
Standing in the middle
of the road like this.
Well...I'm looking for someone
and just can't seem to find him.
Hmm...Who might that be?
A guy named Shiranami.
Shiranami...
Oh, there is such a man.
No kidding!
Is that true?!
Are you sure about this, old man?!
Yes. There's a man by that name
who lives in a small hut
by the waterfall beyond this mountain,
and does ninja training.
Beyond this mountain, right?!
Thanks, old man!
Found him!
That must be it.
I've finally found you.
Hold tight, Hotaru.
I'm coming back with
Shiranami right now!
Mister...Shiranami?
I found you.
Are you Shiranami?
You fell for it.
How could you leave without a word?
Sir Utakata, I still...
I take it that you are Lady Hotaru
the granddaughter of En no Gyoja?
Wh-Who are you?!
My name is...Shiranami.
Shiranami?!
Release!
We finally meet, Lady Hotaru.
That's...
That crest is bestowed only
to those initiated
in the use of the forbidden jutsu.
Can you really be...Sir Shiranami?
I don't blame you for being surprised.
I came after hearing Naruto's story.
Naruto?!
Then you really
are Sir Shiranami!
Where is Naruto? I must thank him...
He's no longer here.
He asked me to take care
of the rest, and left.
I see...Naruto too...
Naruto told me that...
you wanted to revive the clan.
Huh? Oh...yes.
If you are truly serious,
then could you listen to
what I have to say?
Sir Shiranami?
I'm told Tonbei is alive and well...
and that he's planning to use
the Diremption Jutsu to destroy
the forbidden jutsu.
You know Tonbei too?
We trained together for a time.
However, I am opposed to
Tonbei's intentions.
Why?
Long ago...my father
was ordered by Lord En no Gyoja
to guard the forbidden jutsu.
My father was a hero who protected
the honor of the Tsuchigumo clan
along with the forbidden jutsu.
That is, until he was killed by one
who was after the forbidden jutsu.
My father's death motivated
Lord En no Gyoja
to move the forbidden jutsu to
the fort on Mount Katsuragi,
and he let me escape out
of the country.
I promised myself that one day,
I would return to the village for
the sake of the Tsuchigumo Clan!
Sir Shiranami...
Lady Hotaru.
My father was killed and
I was forced to run away
because we were the only two survivors
who knew how to use the forbidden jutsu.
He went through the same anguish...
But I've become strong
and now I'm back.
If we join forces,
we can revive the forbidden jutsu!
There is no need to destroy
the forbidden jutsu!
The restoration of the Tsuchigumo Clan
is my dedicated wish too!
Let us fulfill the dreams of my father
and Lord En no Gyoja!
But...
Beyond this mountain is
my secret hideaway.
Lady Hotaru!
I understand.
Is that for Tonbei?
Huh? Oh, yes...
I must let him know.
At least a short note to Sir Utakata...
Off you go...
Let's go, Sir Shiranami.
You're making this difficult...
What?
Go.
Huh?
What's...?
If you do as you please...!
I thought I had come
to terms with it...
So why am I thinking
about my master now?
What is that?
A word manipulated by chakra?
A carrier pigeon?
From Hotaru?!
To Sir Utakata,
I will work to revive the Tsuchigumo Clan
with Sir Shiranami.
Thank you for all you have done.
Good-bye.
From your student, Hotaru.
Hotaru...
So she met up with Shiranami...
That means I'm finally free of her.
Who are you guys?!
Don't tell me you have Shiranami--!
What a simpleton.
He's concerned about
Boss Shiranami.
If we let you see the girl
with the forbidden jutsu,
all our plans will be ruined.
You're telling too much.
No need to worry.
This is Boss' special barrier,
which takes away an enemy's chakra!
It's just not possible for anyone
inside the barrier to resist.
Wh-What?!
D-Damn you...!
Get him!
He's...strong.
Don't panic!
Just stick to the Boss' strategy
and use the next jutsu!
Multi-Mugenhouyo!
Let's see you free yourself
from this...
What?!
This is...
nothing!
Damn...
I can't believe he can still move
after losing so much chakra!
No time to be impressed.
Let's get this over with!
What is it?
You're...
I couldn't help but overhear
what you said.
So the leader of the bandits
is Shiranami.
Where the hell did you
take Hotaru to?!
Wh-What's with this guy?
This is bad, Akaboshi.
The Boss should be
in the village by now.
Time for us to go too!
- Right!
This is...the village
of the Tsuchigumo Clan?
Are you awake, Lady Hotaru?
Sir...Shiranami?
Come on out, everyone.
Lady Hotaru has come home.
These people are...
Did something happen
to the villagers?
I used a jutsu to make them
obedient, that's all.
What?!
I had no choice. It's all for the sake
of getting the forbidden jutsu.
Sir Shiranami! Did you trick me?!
I didn't trick you.
What I told you earlier is true.
Although I should add
that my old man,
who died protecting the forbidden jutsu,
was actually killed by me!
I killed my old man after trying
to take the forbidden jutsu
from him!
Lady Hotaru!
It's useless.
You're already under my jutsu.
The forbidden jutsu...
The forbidden jutsu is finally
within my grasp!
It's just a dried up branch.
Rather than tracking
the soil like that,
wouldn't it be faster if I just used
my Multi-Shadow Clones?
And destroy any trace left of Hotaru?
Looking at this imprint...
There's no doubt about it.
These are footprints of someone who
was carrying a body under his arm.
This way.
Hey! You're sure?
Every search begins by analyzing
all traces that are left behind.
That's one of the basic rules for a ninja.
For someone who boasts
about their master,
neither you nor Hotaru received adequate
training from your masters, have you?
That's not true!
Seriously...That's what happens
when you're obsessed
over something as stupid as masters.
H-Hey! Hold on there!
There's nothing stupid about it!
Hotaru is gone?
I searched around the entire fort.
I did relay Naruto's message
that he "found Shiranami."
She went after Utakata...
Could that be it?
All right, we'll postpone
the ritual preparations for now.
Finding Hotaru is our top priority.
Sai, send out as many
search mice as possible.
Let's go.
Yes, sir.
Ninja Art: Super Beast Scroll!
I learned all sorts of things from
the Pervy Sage.
Taijutsu...ninjutsu...
That goes without saying.
I mean, really great jutsu.
But he wasn't just strict...
He also taught me what's most important
about being a ninja...
The guts to never give up.
What I received from my master
was valuable.
It wasn't stupid or useless.
You had a master too, didn't you?
Memories of my master...
Mission accomplished!
Ninja must perform their missions swiftly.
Right, Master?
You fool!
Huh?!
Your mission was to track
the stolen scroll!
Who said to bring it back?!
Your life is precious!
Do not waste your life!
A ninja never runs away from
a battle that must be fought.
However, a ninja never fights
an unnecessary battle!
Still...
I'm glad that you are all right.
Master...
He cared for me...
That's what I thought.
It wasn't me he cared about...
but the "power" inside me.
He merely saw me as its vessel.
But...if what Tsurugi said is true...
Hey! Is this it?!
Huh? Oh, yeah...
Hey, this is the village of
the Tsuchigumo Clan!
It is?
But the tracks all led to this place.
I wonder if something happened?
The bandits attacked Hotaru here.
And...
And the villagers here didn't
think highly of Hotaru.
The fact that the forbidden jutsu was
shunned in this village is pretty obvious.
Yeah.
And if Hotaru was attacked
right in this village...
The bandits and the village
are connected,
or the village just turned
a blind eye to it.
In any case, the bandits are using
this village as their hideout.
Also, the footprints that
were left behind...
They just don't seem natural.
Maybe he became overconfident
after he got the forbidden jutsu...
Or maybe he's planning to ambush us.
You mean, a trap?!
I'm not sure. But tracking them
has gone too smoothly.
"Beware when the chase
seems too easy."
That is what my master...
Anyway, let's be careful.
Yeah.
Seems you did learn stuff
from your master.
After we rescue Hotaru,
you should teach her some of that.
Let's go!
H-Huh?
Are you sure this is the place?
I think so.
Thank you.
Sure.
Just for that, here!
What's going on?!
Here they come.
What? These guys...
They've joined up with the bandits
to come after us?
But...
Yeah, this is different.
They're being manipulated.
What?!
How dirty...
Here they come!
Damn!
We can't proceed any further
without hurting the villagers.
So, what do you suggest we do?!
What happened to
your earlier enthusiasm?
It's hopeless, eh?
Those guys are controlling
the villagers...
Get 'em, guys! Don't give 'em
a moment's rest!
What?
Sai!
Captain Yamato!
Naruto!
Sakura!
You idiot! Stop going off
on your own like that!
I-I'm sorry...
But how come you're here?
We were looking for Lady Hotaru,
who had disappeared from
Mount Katsuragi.
We had Sai push himself.
I'm really not cut out
for physical labor.
I didn't expect to use
so much chakra.
Here, have a food pill.
I'll have one later.
What are you talking about?
What if something happens to you?
It's my special food pill.
So get energized!
You know, that thing tastes awful...
Stop fraternizing!
Shoot!
We won't let you go past here.
You can't interfere with the Boss' ritual.
Wordbind Jutsu.
My years of painstaking preparation
are about to pay off.
Your heart must also be rejoicing over
the forbidden jutsu's release.
What is this?!
Sai! Sakura!
Captain Yamato!
Wood Style!
You two, go on ahead!
But!
Leave this to us, Naruto!
Go, Naruto!
You must save Hotaru!
Guys, I'm counting on you!
No wonder it was useless looking
for the forbidden jutsu.
He had used his own granddaughter
as its hiding place.
That En no Gyoja...
What a cruel thing to do.
If the forbidden jutsu is removed
from its human vessel,
it would become lost forever.
And unless the human who became
its vessel is skilled enough to control it,
the forbidden jutsu cannot be activated...
So even if someone were to come
after the forbidden jutsu,
they cannot lay a hand on it.
En no Gyoja's kindness has protected it.
However, if it stays this way,
the treasure will be wasted.
Right now, you are no more than
a storage tank accumulating natural energy.
You have yet to wield the
activation jutsu necessary to
set off that collected natural energy.
And then I come along...
The sole survivor of the Tsuchigumo Clan
who has mastered that jutsu.
What a lucky turn of events, right Hotaru?
The jutsu which will restore the clan
to its glory
is on the verge of
seeing the light of day.
Let's use it to give a scare to those
who denounced our clan.
What is it, Hotaru?
Aren't you happy?
Then laugh. Come on.
I see.
You're happy too? You should be.
You should be.
Tsuchigumo Style:
Forbidden Jutsu Release!
Big Bang!
It's coming...It's coming...
Now, the trump card
to our clan's revival...
The moment is here...
The forbidden jutsu shall awaken
after its decade-long seal!
Gather chakra!
Overflow in Hotaru's body,
which serves as the vessel!
And manifest your formidable power!
Utakata! What are you doing?!
Chakra is flowing...
Chakra?
I don't see anything.
It is probably chakra that exists
within the atmosphere and terrain.
What is this?
They're riding the chakra,
the chakra's current,
towards a certain location.
And Hotaru is...
She's there?!
Let's go!
Right!
Why is the chakra gathering there?
Hey, you're sure Hotaru will be there?
If you have time to talk,
then get moving.
Hotaru...
Over there!
All right!
Hotaru!
We're too late...
Useless bunch.
Couldn't they at least hold you off
a little longer?
Oh well, I don't mind having
an audience.
You bastard!
What did you do to Hotaru?!
Sir Utakata...
Hotaru's dream...
I'm just helping her to realize it.
The revival of the Tsuchigumo Clan.
And the key to that is
activating the forbidden jutsu
with my abilities.
Your ability? What do you mean?
She doesn't have the skill to
activate the forbidden jutsu yet.
She's only able to accumulate
the chakra in nature.
So I'll activate it for her,
from the outside.
In order to restore the tarnished honor
of the Tsuchigumo Clan.
What honor?! All you're trying to do
is steal Hotaru's feelings
for her grandfather, Tonbei,
and her people.
Everything that Hotaru holds dear!
Who needs something
as cheap as feelings?
I'm going to steal the world.
What?!
As long as I have this, be it
the five Kage's or the Lords...
No one will be able to ignore me.
A new village...
No, I can even attain lands
superior to the Five Great Nations.
Are you out of your mind?!
I've never been more serious.
Now that I've come this far,
I can take on the Five Great Nations.
With this forbidden jutsu,
taking over the world is
not just a dream!
I knew it!
You don't give a damn...
about the people of the Tsuchigumo Clan!
Yeah...that goes without saying.
What about...
What about Hotaru's feelings?!
As if I care.
She put her faith in you...
A carved seal of that magnitude
was embedded into her...
and she protected that
forbidden jutsu with all her might...
for the sake of her people.
And she entrusted you with it.
Huh?
It's true that I killed my own father
in order to satisfy my greed.
But you're not one to talk.
I know all about you.
You're listed in the Bingo Book,
aren't you?
You're a rogue ninja from
the Hidden Mist, right?
You turned your back on
the Hidden Mist.
I don't need to be lectured
by someone...
who doesn't care about his village!
I can tell we're alike, you and I.
We smell the same!
Did I hit it right on the mark?
Well, whatever.
But since Hotaru is
so attached to her people,
I'm willing to name my new nation
after the Tsuchigumo.
I'm not a bandit, after all.
Thinking of the land of my birth,
I'm helping to bring it back to glory.
I'd say I'm a pretty fine person!
Don't kid around!
You're right.
Maybe I don't give a damn...
about my village...
Utakata...
But what will happen to Hotaru?
She'll live. As the ultimate weapon
for the forbidden jutsu.
I will control this great jutsu...
and she will be my tool.
Tool...Did you say "tool"?!
Yes...
My tool!
Shut up!
Too bad. You can't oppose me anymore.
Just like Hotaru.
Good...More...
Let your body overflow with chakra!
Now then, what shall
I make you do?
How about making comrades
fight each other?
I can't move...
Or maybe bodyguards?
You can guard my tool.
Why you...
Don't think you can get near
my tool so easily.
Don't call her your tool...
Hotaru is not a tool!
Don't talk. You're irritating.
Forget it.
You have no grounds to object.
Hotaru chose me.
She chose to become the vessel.
To Sir Utakata,
I will work to revive the Tsuchigumo Clan
with Sir Shiranami.
Thank you for all you have done.
Good-bye...
From your student, Hotaru.
Hotaru doesn't want
to be rescued by you.
So stay there and watch as the Tsuchigumo
village disappears in an instant.
Sir Utakata. I'm so sorry.
It's all because I was so foolish...
Hmm...You still have the will to resist.
Sir Utakata.
Damn it!
Just a little more...Just a little more
and Hotaru's vessel will be full of chakra.
You will be my witnesses to
the resurrection of the forbidden jutsu.
There's no way we can put up
a fight against those four like this.
First, we have to stop the villagers.
But how?
It can't be helped if we get
a bit rough with them.
We'll isolate them all in one place.
I'm sorry!
I have to get a little rough.
Cha!
Super Beast Scroll!
Wood Style: Four Pillar House Jutsu!
We'll have them lay low there
for a while.
way to ruin our fun.
We can't keep letting them
have their way.
That's our line.
I wonder about that.
It's no fun...without an audience.
Oh boy...
There's just no end to this, is there?
Damn it...
You're doing well, Hotaru.
Our guests are probably
getting anxious.
Now surrender
your body and soul to me!
Unleash the chakra you've
accumulated all at once!
This place which rejected you...
Let's reduce it into ashes!
Ninja Art...
What?!
Bubble Bomb!
You blockhead!
When did you set that up?
If you had behaved,
you could've lived a bit longer.
Why did my Wordbind Jutsu...?
These guys...
The amount of chakra is unnatural...
Like we'd let you control us so easily!
I won't let you!
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Wordbind Jutsu!
Rock!
You bastard!
Hotaru...
Are you all right, Hotaru?!
Hotaru!
What do we do?
Why you...You still wanna fight?
Whoa!
Have you forgotten that
my Wordbind Jutsu controls Hotaru?
Get back!
Damn!
She isn't fully charged with
the chakra from nature, but...
Now Hotaru...Let us show them.
How dreadful
the forbidden jutsu is!
Now let us start.
No.
Let us show the world!
Our...
No, my...power!
No...No!
Die!
Fury Jutsu!
No!
What's that?!
It looks like the Boss took possession
of the forbidden jutsu.
Take a look Hotaru,
isn't it magnificent?
This is the power of
the forbidden jutsu!
The art we honed together.
No...
I couldn't have...
No!
I...I...
killed Sir Utakata?
Oh, come on...
This is a problem...
I don't need a vessel
that comes with feelings.
Now then, once more.
This time, the Tsuchigumo village.
Those worthless villagers...
Incinerate them all!
Wood Style Jutsu!
It's useless!
Hah! You see?
You can't hurt the villagers.
However, I couldn't care less
what happens to people like them!
This is the end!
We got them!
What?!
Benten?!
How did you guys...?!
Like this!
The jutsu created by the four of you
was quite formidable.
But with just two remaining,
you're no match for us.
With this forbidden jutsu,
I'll conquer small nations
and make the Five Great Nations tremble.
N-Not likely...
A-As if I'll let you have...
your way.
Utakata! This is no time
to be lying around!
Yeah...
We have to get Hotaru back.
Hmph! Don't know when to die,
do you?
Do you want another taste
of the forbidden jutsu?
Like I'll let you!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Go!
Don't underestimate me!
Wordbind Jutsu, Explode!
Utakata! Get Hotaru now,
while there's a chance!
I won't let you!
Wordbind Jutsu, Flame!
What's the matter?
Is that all you have?
No!
You can't form seals now...
Hotaru!
Damn it!
I'll pay you back tenfold!
Hotaru!
You...! You're activating
the forbidden jutsu again?!
It's not me!
Look at this...
My hands are bound!
Then what's going on here?!
Who knows?
Maybe it's from absorbing
too much natural energy.
Stop it right now!
And how am I supposed to do that
with my hands like this?
Release.
Now then...
Damn!
Hey! Hurry up and stop it!
The Wordbind jutsu...isn't working.
This is...
What's wrong?
It's getting worse.
If it keeps accumulating
the chakra from nature like this,
it'll explode along with
the entire village.
What?!
Hotaru...
Damn it...
The revival of the Tsuchigumo Clan...
The wishes of En no Gyoja...
After being forced to take on
all the grown-ups' selfish desires,
Hotaru has finally lost it!
Shut up! What the hell would
you know about Hotaru?!
All alone, she kept
the forbidden jutsu safe!
She happily offered herself for
the sake of restoring her clan.
She shouldered the entire burden...
by herself.
But then she met Utakata...
And although you tricked her,
she met you, her senior.
Hotaru...She was finally able
to find a comrade.
People she could share a bond with.
And you crushed it!
Comrade? Bond?
Don't give me that nonsense!
I'm the same as Hotaru.
For the sake of the forbidden jutsu,
they would sacrifice their student,
their own son, without hesitation.
Saying it's what a ninja would do...
That it's the only way to survive.
I went through it all
until I got sick of it!
That's why I went on the offensive.
I killed my father,
who had been my master,
and I tried to steal
the forbidden jutsu.
What?!
And you over there...
Didn't you basically
do the same thing?
I...I...
You're wrong.
Huh?
My master always...
thinks about his student...
About me.
No matter how far apart we are...
I can always feel his thoughts.
He's in my heart every single minute!
That's why I can believe in him.
Hotaru also has
her grandfather and Tonbei.
And Utakata...Your feelings should
have reached her too!
It exists deep inside her heart!
Even now, she yearns for her comrade,
for her master...
for her bond!
You don't know anything about her!
Don't talk like you do!
Dream on!
Wordbind Jutsu! Split!
Naruto!
Thanks...
Shoot...For now, I'd better fall back
before the vessel explodes!
Hotaru!
I'll bring Shiranami back.
- I'm coming...
- No!
You're Hotaru's master.
Stay with her.
I'm counting on you!
Got it!
Hotaru also has
her grandfather and Tonbei.
And Utakata...Your feelings should
have reached her too!
My feelings...are within her!
As well as within my heart...
That's right...
My anger had closed off my ears.
But I did hear...
No, I did feel...
my master's thoughts.
It was there.
My master's thoughts...
They reached me, and yet...
Utakata...
Live...side by side with this power.
I had sworn never to use
your power again.
But I beg you, help me,
for Hotaru's sake!
Hotaru...
I didn't want to hurt anybody...
And yet...
I hurt Naruto and Sir Utakata!
I'm right here.
Naruto and I are both alive.
I...
Hotaru?
I...I betrayed you, Sir Utakata.
Someone like me should disappear
along with this jutsu!
No!
I will not allow that.
A student should listen
to her master!
You said...Master...
We're going home, Hotaru.
What's wrong?
No!
No...Sir Utakata...
Please get away from me!
Please run!
Hotaru!
I cannot suppress it any longer...
The forbidden jutsu is going
to tear me apart...and explode.
It's all right.
Sir Utakata...
Believe in your master.
So be it, destroy this entire village!
Eradicate everything!
Damn it!
Multi...
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Persistent bastard!
Wordbind Jutsu, Flame!
Fool! I'm going through!
I'm not going to forgive you,
no matter what!
Wordbind Jutsu!
Slice!
Rasengan!
What?!
I've gotta take him to
Hotaru right away!
What is that?
Hey!
Utakata!
Are you all right?
Yeah...
Master...
What a troublesome student you are.
By the way, what happened
to the forbidden jutsu?
It seems to have disappeared.
Disappeared? But Hotaru's safe, right?
That's a relief.
Naruto...
Sakura!
Well then, the mission negotiated
between the Tsuchigumo Clan
and the Hidden Leaf has been
successfully completed.
Thank you for everything.
The forbidden jutsu is no more.
However...
Yes. I think it was for the better.
Now Lady Hotaru will no longer
be targeted.
And the villagers will accept Hotaru
without reservations.
But now...
Are you going, after all?
With Utakata?
I still have much more to learn.
After I have trained with
my master and become a ninja
strong enough to help restore
the Tsuchigumo Clan,
I promise to return to this village.
Good for you, "Master"!
Are you toying with me?
No, I'm happy that you've finally
accepted your role as a master.
Take care of Hotaru.
Well, everyone, take care.
It's nice, after all...
Having a master.
Hmm?
Now I kinda...
miss the Pervy Sage too!
This is where I first met you, Master.
Hotaru...Will you wait here
for just a while?
Is something the matter?
I'm going to meet with
the ANBU Black Ops from the Hidden Mist.
I'm done running.
I'm going to get their permission
to travel and train you.
Yes, sir!
No response, after all.
Did something happen to Tsurugi
and his men?
The Six Tails' Jinchuriki
Are you the ones
who killed Tsurugi and the others?
I'm going to build a new world.
And for that, I need you.
Rather, I need the Tailed-Beast
inside you.
So that's it.
I'm taking youSix-Tails.
Finally, you're taking this seriously.
Now that's the power we seek
Summoning Jutsu
Go!
It's been captured.
I expected as much out of you.
Now come, Six-Tails!
Hota...ru...
You...must live...
Sealing of the Six-Tails...
is done.
It takes time when
there are five of us.
There are two Tailed-Beasts left.
Yes...I've sent Sasuke to go
and retrieve the Eight-Tails.
Can we trust him?
I can vouch for Sasuke.
Are you all right, Sasuke?
Yeah...Let's hurry.
We're almost at
the rendezvous point.
As promised,
I brought the Eight-Tails.
You did well. I had faith
that you could do it.
Where are you going?
First, I'm going to tend
to my wounds.
Then...
I'm going to the Hidden Leaf.
I'm going to ask
one important question...
After learning about Itachi's life,
there is a chance
that you will carry out his wish
and protect the Hidden Leaf.
Tell me the truth.
What are your intentions?
Itachi showed me how a man
would give his life to protect his village.
But for me, the sadness
of losing Itachi
impacts me more deeply
than how he lived...
Unbearably more.
The peace that Itachi sacrificed
himself for isn't appealing to me.
Now that I know the truth,
following in Itachi's steps to
protect the Hidden Leaf
is the last thing I would do.
Most of all, I will never forgive
the three elders.
And I believe that everyone in
the Hidden Leaf enjoying the peace
gained in exchange for
Itachi's life is guilty too.
I thought you were only going
to kill the elders?
No...I wish to slaughter
the entire Leaf Village by myself.
I was just feigning in front of Taka.
Is that the truth?
After knowing just what Itachi
went through to protect the village...
Instead of carrying on his wish,
you'd destroy the village?
Are you serious?
You said so yourself.
The reason why Itachi couldn't
bring himself to kill me was...
he cherished my life more
than the village.
I feel the same way.
Itachi's life is more precious
to me than the village.
That's all.
They shunned the Uchiha clan.
They forced my brother to
kill his own parents!
The elders who cast him out
and sealed his death!
And the rest of the Hidden Leaf
who abide by the Senju clan!
They're nothing but scum!
They are all objects of
my vengeance!
If you want to ridicule me as a brat
swayed by his emotions, go ahead.
Carrying on Itachi's wish are
merely pretty words.
The foolish sputtering of those
who don't know hatred.
If anyone criticizes my way of life,
I'll kill every single one
of their loved ones!
Then they might understand a little...
...of the hatred I carry.
When a man learns to love,
he must bear the risk of hatred.