Is that it?
You didn’t kill all of them…
How naïve.
There are others I’d rather kill.
Unless you become heartless,
you will not defeat Itachi.
When I stand before him, I’ll be
heartless, whether I want to be or not.
Not even a tiny spurt of blood…
When I watch this boy…
I look back to the time
I was called a genius…
and think how ridiculous that was.
Very soon...so very soon,
he will be mine…!
What is this?
Ah! How lucky of you to find this.
It's the skin of a white snake.
I've never...seen anything
like it before.
Actually, neither have I.
It's a rare item that
you almost never see.
Why is it white?
Well, I don't really know.
No one really cares about
such things.
But from times past,
the white snake has been
a symbol of good luck and renewal.
Good luck and renewal...
It must be some sort of karma
for you to find it here.
Perhaps your parents are
now reborn somewhere.
Maybe someday...
you'll meet them when you're grown up.
When would that be...?
Who knows? I couldn't say.
Nawaki...sure is eager.
We're at war...after all.
Tsunade's team has been...?
Stop! Stop! Stop!
I said, stop!
That's enough! He's dead!
Humans...are such fragile beings.
Power that was not used in a lifetime
rests inside the human body.
If we could release that power...
Orochimaru Sensei!
What is this?
An amulet.
An amulet...? This...?
It's a very rare amulet for
good luck and renewal.
Renewal? With this...?
But...Orochimaru Sensei,
no matter how earnest you are
about your research,
you can't bring back the dead,
can you?
Yes...Bringing the dead
back to life is difficult.
But, I've grasped a clue
about regeneration.
By activating their bodies,
humans can become immensely
more powerful
and heighten their regenerative powers too.
I will share that power
with you some day, as well.
Yes! Thank you very much,
Orochimaru Sensei!
The Body Activating Jutsu
called the Curse Mark...
How foolish!
There's a limit to unreasonable training!
Beautiful...
So this is the power of the Sharingan.
No matter how many ninja try
to enter this territory...
No matter how hard they train,
they could never surpass the Uchiha.
I understand...
I understand the awesomeness
of this jutsu...
But, it would take at least one month
to master this forbidden jutsu...
How many years would it take
to master all the jutsu that are here...?
It's impossible to grasp all the jutsu
within the limited time
of a human lifespan...
There would be a limit even if I could
extend my life via a Reanimation Jutsu...
Once I die, everything would be lost...
In order to grasp every jutsu,
I would have to...
Orochimaru! So it was you,
just as I suspected...
Tell me! What were you doing here?
You probably couldn't understand...
You who puts the village
before your own reason.
To me, the lifespan of
the human body is too short.
Even if I were to be called a Hokage,
once I die,
everything would end there.
The jutsu you're experimenting with...
It can't be...?!
That very one...
the Immortality Jutsu!
Can't you reconsider Orochimaru?
Out of the question!
How stupid can you be?!
I'm so close...
So close with my research.
I will have everything.
My vessel is neither this body,
nor the Leaf!
To that end, I will use that organization
and anything else!
You destroyed the Uchiha.
What brings you to the Akatsuki?
One who possesses the precious Sharingan
appears before me...
How lucky I am...
I will have your body!
Could it be... that I...
am under a Paralysis Genjutsu...
What visual prowess...
Marvelous...
Orochimaru...
Any jutsu you use will have
no effect before these eyes.
Lord Orochimaru!
What are you doing, Kabuto...?!
Are you all right, Lord Orochimaru?
I'm fine...
That body will be mine shortly.
I will be reanimated soon.
I feel great...
You've reached your limit.
In your condition, if I don't administer
a rank 10 medication, your body will...
I will change medications.
It will just take a minute.
The nature of this chakra...
But, I've never seen
this change in chakra form before.
Who is it?!
You came...just as I thought you would.
I have nothing more to learn from you.
Even here before you...
I think I can become heartless.
Orochimaru, you are weaker than me.
There's no longer any need for me
to give you my body.
You have some nerve...
you're still an Uchiha fledgling!
If I hadn't been a fledgling,
you would've had no chance at me, right?
You...
Itachi didn't work out...
That's why you came after me, a fledgling.
Isn't that right?
You who they called the Genius Sannin.
But you turned out to be what they call
on the streets, "just an ordinary prodigy."
You couldn't even live up to
the Uchiha name, much less surpass it.
Even the best prodigy is only ordinary
against the Uchiha name.
What you did...
disgustingly trying to approach
the powers of the Uchiha
by drowning yourself in drugs and
trying to overcome your body...
It seems so shameless and comical to me,
who possesses that name.
And what's more,
I don't like the way you do things.
You continued to toy with others for
your own stupid and selfish reasons...
Why...Brother?
To measure my own abilities.
Measure your own abilities...?
Is that all?
Is that the only reason...
you killed everyone?!
That's what's important.
You make me sick!
A snake with white scales...
so that is your true form...
You conducted experiment
after experiment
so that you could move
from body to body...
and that's how you ended up?
Now, Sasuke...
Give me your body!
A snake that slithers on the ground
can only dream of flying through the air.
You wanted it so badly that
you went after the fledgling in the nest...
But you became targeted
as the prey instead...
By the eyes of a hawk
soaring high above in the sky.
Sasuke!
You've come.
Now, let's go...
My future lies in this child!
It's over...That was too quick.
Looks like it's beginning
to take effect...
The body fluid of the giant white snake
skin vaporizes upon contact with the air
and becomes an anesthetic.
I am immortal.
The likes of your jutsu cannot kill me...!
Now then...
I shall have you now!
What is this?
This is...a different
space inside my body.
Here, the Transference
Ritual will be held...
We'll begin now.
What visual prowess...Marvelous...
This is almost like...that time...
Those eyes...
Those eyes will be mine at last...!
He won't last with only the medicine...
He'll have to do the Transference Ritual
as soon as today...
But...
It's hard to believe that
Sasuke would consent willingly...
Well, even Sasuke
can't resist that ritual...
That is the cast-off skin
of the giant snake...
Does that mean the ritual
is already done?
What's going on?
Kabuto, is that you?
Which one...
are you now?
Which one do you think?
This is the Transference Ritual!
He's showing me the
memories of the ritual!
The ritual between the two
will be settled right now!
What the?
This...can't be!
This is a place I created.
This is impossible!
Impossible!
It can't be...
This is my only...
Orochimaru...
Any jutsu you use will have
no effect before these eyes.
You should have
realized that by now.
How hideous...
Sasuke's will is eroding this space!
I'm not going to let this happen!
I am the immortal Orochimaru!
Not here!
I won't let this happen here!
I am the one to unravel
the order of this world!
Everything...will be mine!
Lord Orochimaru is dead.
No...It's almost as if...
I took over all that he was.
I knew it was you...
The fact that you're here must mean
you killed Orochimaru.
Yeah.
But never mind that.
Let's get you out of here.
Free at last. Thank you, Sasuke.
Suigetsu, you're the first.
Come with me.
Me, first? There are others then?
Two others. I'm taking Jugo
from the northern hideout
and Karin from the southern hideout.
Are you sure about that?
What is it?
It's nothing...
Just that I don't like them.
I can't get along with them...
At least, that's what I think.
Sure, you picked me,
but I wonder about choosing
those two, Sasuke.
Enough with the rambling.
Put on your clothes.
We're going.
Ordering me around like a big shot, eh?
Let me clarify the relationship
between you and me...
All right?
Sorry, but you chose to rescue me.
I never said anything about following you.
Just because you defeated Orochimaru
doesn't make you better than me.
Everyone was after him.
You were Orochimaru's pet,
so you weren't imprisoned
and you stayed by his side.
You had more chances to kill him
than the rest of us.
Gotcha...Just kidding.
But I let you go just now,
so that makes us even.
I'm free at last,
so I'm going to do as I please.
I see.
That's unfortunate.
By the way...
It was your team, wasn't it?
The team that brought down
my great predecessor, Zabuza Momochi.
Whatever happened to his blade...
the Executioner's Blade?
Let's do this.
If you tell me where the blade is,
and I take possession of it,
then I'll be willing to help you.
Put some clothes on.
Is that the regular report?
Yeah...
A fog is forming.
According to the unit
we're taking over for,
it's apparently created by
the Three-Tails.
It induces hallucinations, so be careful.
That's news to me, hmm...
You! That costume...
Dam--!
Humph...
Oh wow! Deidara Senpai,
that was awesome!
That's the last of the lookouts.
H-H-Hey, Senpai!
Weren't you listening to the story
about the hallucinations?
Who do you think you're speaking to?
Don't underestimate my art.
Sheesh, he's got a short temper...
That's a huge lake to find
the Three-Tails in.
It'd be faster if it appeared on its own.
Oh! On closer inspection,
it looks something like a huge turtle.
A powerful one...
So that's the Three-Tails...
I think I'll leave it for you to handle,
Deidara Senpai.
Tobi, you formally became
a member of Akatsuki, right?
You take care of the rest, hmm!
No way...
It's coming!
If it's a water creature,
shouldn't we have let Kisame handle it?!
I'd say they assigned
the wrong person for the job!
Pitiful, I'd say.
Now!
The Great Naruto Bridge?
What a weird name...
Say, was the great Zabuza Senpai strong?
What's the matter, Sasuke?
Nothing. Let's go.
I did it! Banzai! Banzaai!
Deidara, did you see my jutsu?!
Just one time, and bam!
You can understand why
I was given this important assignment
right after formally becoming a member
of Akatsuki, can't you?!
No...It was probably my clay bomb
doing its artistic work.
You have my artistry to thank, hmm.
Don't get so carried away that
you forgot that I lent you a hand!
If you're a member of Akatsuki,
don't talk so much and act more cool.
In other words, "cool = art"!
Listen, art is a passionate moment
coming from cool emotions--!
Senpai, you talk a lot.
I was joking...!
As long as I have this blade,
I won't even lose to you...maybe.
So? Which way do we go? Oh wait...
The nearest route, right?
That would be your answer.
I'm starting to figure you out...
Right, the nearest route.
Listen, Tobi.
You shouldn't press your luck!
The Three-Tails was just weak
because it didn't have a Jinchuriki host.
It didn't have a mind to control its power.
Hey, Tobi.
You don't have to be so cool
as to stop talking altogether.
At least answer me...
Hmm?!
Oh that's the spot...
Oh my...
This is the perfect wake up
for you, I'd say. You bastard!
Just because Orochimaru
is dead doesn't mean
I'll let you have your way!
The feeling of this chakra...
I-It can't be...
Can I ask you something?
What is it?
Why are you gathering men?
I have a goal...
And I have a better chance of
achieving it with a small platoon.
Ever since I approached Orochimaru,
this moment is all I've thought about,
and I've been pre-selecting
highly skilled ninja.
Oh...?
So...why would you choose Karin?
Unlike me,
she's a follower of Orochimaru...
After claiming to be
under Orochimaru's orders,
she tinkered with
my body countless times.
Besides, her personality turns me off.
Granted, there were other strong ninja
I could have swayed.
But she has a special power
no one else possesses.
Well...I'll admit that.
You have one too.
That one is more suitable.
Open sesame!
So it's you, after all...Sasuke.
The fact that you're here alone
must mean that the rumors were true.
Geez, that's mean. I'm here too.
And? What brings you here?
Sasuke has something
to discuss with you.
We can't stand out here and talk,
so take us inside, will you?
It's been so long since I've walked...
I'm exhausted.
What do you want to talk about?
I said let's not stand out here, Karin.
Although I know
you're totally ignoring me.
Humph!
You disgust me.
What'd you say?
Cut it out, Karin. Take us inside.
Fine.
Karin, follow me. I need you.
Huh?! Why would I follow you?
I'm under orders to oversee this place!
Orochimaru is already gone.
What about the prisoners here?
Suigetsu...Release everyone
who is held prisoner here.
Wha--?!
Geez...You always
order people around.
You can't just come here
and take over!
You don't know what it took
to keep things in order here...
Without prisoners,
there won't be any need for a warden.
I'll say it once more.
Come with me, Karin.
Well, anyway,
I'll go and release the prisoners.
I refuse! Besides...
I'm under no obligation to follow you!
Too bad...
Since you seem dead set against it,
I'll just ask someone else.
I knew it!
The rumors that Sasuke Uchiha
brought down Orochimaru were true!
Yeah, it's true.
What'll happen to those of us in here?
Of course, you're free to go.
A-Are you sure?!
Yeah...I was once imprisoned too.
But as you can see, I'm free.
I'm going to unlock the cells.
Before that, I have one favor to ask.
What is it?! Ask us anything!
Well...
The one who defeated Orochimaru
and gave us our freedom is Sasuke.
When you're out,
spread the word to everyone...
A man has appeared who will
bring peace and tranquility to this world.
I'm coming.
Since you're so adamant...
I'll go with you.
What's this?
That was a quick change of heart.
After thinking it over,
I realized I'm tired of
guarding this place.
It's locked from the inside...
That woman!
That's Suigetsu.
Let's forget about that nuisance,
okay, Sasuke?
You...Don't get so close.
Look...what's wrong with
just you and me?
We don't need a guy like...Suigetsu.
Hope my blade isn't chipped...
Let's go, Sasuke.
Karin turned you down, didn't she?
No. It seems she's coming.
Wh-Who said I'm coming?!
I just...I just happened to be
going in the same direction.
That's all, nothing else...!
Oh, how nice.
Then we can travel together partway.
Yeah, just part of the way!
All right...Next is Jugo.
What? You're going to see Jugo?
That shouldn't concern you since
you're just coming with us part of the way.
Sure, I could care less,
but what's wrong with asking?
Wanna make something of it,
you jerk?!
Let's go!
Y-Yeah...
We have to walk again?
I'm exhausted.
Humph...We're going to
the northern hideout now.
At this rate, you'll be killed
the moment we get there.
I only know it through maps...
but is the place really that bad?
The northern hideout
is no ordinary hideout.
That place...
is where human experiments
are conducted.
And the unmanageable monsters that
result are kept locked up there.
A male...
No, a female.
No, I'll kill a male next, after all.
I see.
It's already begun...
Say, aren't you tired?
How about a short break?
You're already taking a break!
You are so hopeless!
We've still got a ways to go 'til
we get to the northern hideout!
My destination is different
from yours.
No need to bother with me.
Just go on ahead.
I remembered that I too have business
at the northern hideout!
So I'm going to take care of that first!
I don't know what your goals are...
But you want me to join your team
despite knowing about Jugo?
I know him a little.
We fought each other once.
He had an unusual ability
and was quite formidable.
But I couldn't figure out
what he was thinking,
and I didn't really like him.
I understand he sought out
Orochimaru.
He's got to be crazy.
According to rumors,
Jugo usually has that
unusual impulse well under control.
But when he loses it,
he transforms into a ruthless killer.
His personality and appearance
change completely.
In other words, he's a maniac
who loves to kill people.
But to Orochimaru,
Jugo's ability was enticing.
He invented an enzyme,
based on Jugo's body fluids,
which induced the same condition
in other shinobi.
You guys know it too, right?
That's...the Curse Mark.
Jugo is the one and only
original carrier.
I'm getting out of here!
I'll kill anyone who tries to stop me!
Who's...next?
Say, can we rest a bit?
Suigetsu! You keep stopping to rest!
We're almost at the hideout!
Is it the sword?
Is it too heavy for you?
Then leave it, damn it!
Tell him, Sasuke!
What's wrong?
Where's the guy who's on watch?
Huh?
You're right...That's strange.
Hey...
He's from the northern hideout.
He's still breathing.
What happened?
Y-You're...Sasuke Uchiha...
Help me...
What happened?
I-It all started...
with the rumors that
Orochimaru was dead.
The prisoners went wild...
At this rate...
Oh dear...He died.
You're...
What is that?
He's already in the
"Curse Mark Second State."
The northern hideout is over there.
Let's go and see Jugo.
Huh? Hey! Wait, Sasuke!
A male...
The next one I kill
will be a guy, after all...
The guards have all been killed...
and the prisoners have escaped.
Then there's no way
we can tell which one is Jugo...
Eh, Sasuke?
Karin, is Jugo among them?
Cripes, what a pain!
Just wait a bit!
Nope, he's not.
Well then, I can fight without
worrying who they are.
Just avoid killing them.
You're from the Hidden Leaf,
after all...
You should've killed that
guy back there too, you know.
So naïve...
Let's go.
All right, decided.
If the next one who comes
through that door is a woman,
I'll kill her.
You're strong...You're...
The keys!
I found them!
Karin, which way?
Lead the way.
Sasuke!
Why're you ordering me around, huh?!
Can you just hurry and check?
That's the ability you
pride yourself on, right?
That way!
What is it?
Actually, it's this way.
Let's go, Sasuke!
Why did you lie? Suigetsu went...
Suigetsu has a big mouth,
that's why I don't like him.
Let's go!
Let go...I can walk on my own.
So...the Curse Mark really does transform
the body into such an ugly shape...
Sasuke, does your Curse Mark
do the same to you?
Sasuke...Are you listening...?
That witch...!
Here?
Yeah, Jugo's inside.
There...
Now then, which will it be?
All right! I'm gonna open it!
I'll go in first. Karin, stay back.
S-Sure!
No...
It's gotta be a guy.
If it's a guy, I'll kill him.
Bingo! I'm gonna kill!
He's coming!
It's not over yet!
Sasuke's chakra...
...changed!
Not another copy of me...!
But you're quite a guy to be able to do
a Partial Transformation!
You're good at controlling
your Curse Mark!
He's strong! Haven't seen a copycat
this good since Kimimaro.
I have no intention of fighting.
I only wish to talk to you, Jugo.
Talk...?!
I'm getting you out of here.
Get me out of here?!
Are you crazy?! Without him...
Without him...
I can't...leave this place.
What?!
You're using a different technique
than before, Jugo. It's solid.
Stop it, Suigetsu.
That's right!
You're Suigetsu. I remember now.
We didn't come here to fight.
Let me talk to him.
I doubt that anything
you say will get through to him.
You just have to take him by force!
Stop it, both of you!
Keep going! Just kill each other off!
Do you both...want me to kill you?
Just now...that was real bloodthirst.
Y-You're irresistible...Sasuke...
H-Hurry up and lock me in!
Jugo...I only came to free you.
Come with me.
He's too scared.
No...That's not it.
I don't want to kill anymore people.
I don't want to go outside...
Leave me alone!
What is this?
Talk about split personality...
I told you so...
Jugo has this uncontrollable urge to kill.
He's unable to suppress the urge
even though he really doesn't want
to kill people.
I don't know when
I'll kill someone again.
So just put the lock on!
See, this guy is dangerous, Sasuke.
I can't even walk in front of him
without getting nervous.
What's with you guys?!
Just leave me alone!
Orochimaru is dead.
And this hideout has been destroyed.
If you stay here, you'll die as well.
That's fine with me...
I don't want to kill anyone ever again!
Don't worry...
I will become your cage.
I will stop you.
What can you do?
The only one who can make
these urges stop is Kimimaro.
Without Kimimaro, I won't leave!
Kimimaro? You mean
of the Kaguya clan...?
Yeah...Jugo and Kimimaro were
especially favored by Orochimaru.
They were kept together in this hideout
for human experiments
for a long time.
Plus, Kimimaro was strong...
Jugo was valuable for
human experiments
and Kimimaro was the only one able to
stop Jugo's rampages without hurting him.
But I thought that guy was already...
Yeah...
Jugo...Kimimaro died for my sake.
He's no longer here.
Died for your sake?!
Then you're...
Sasuke Uchiha...?
Yes.
Sasuke...
Uchiha...
Why are you being sent out?
You're sick!
This has never happened before...
Sasuke Uchiha...
The man who is taking my place
as Lord Orochimaru's vessel...
It's to bring him in.
Is he worth going that far?
If you take me out of the running
as a vessel,
then there is no one else.
He is like my reincarnation.
I will risk my life to bring him here.
I'm grateful to you, Jugo.
Your power made me much stronger.
Well Jugo...I'll be back again.
Is that how it is...Kimimaro.
That's pretty heavy food
to have in the morning.
Sakura, today's our day off.
How come you're up so early?
It's already noon.
Well, never mind.
Just wash up quickly and get dressed.
I'll be waiting.
Huh? Is it a date?
Idiot! Lady Tsunade has summoned us!
You're late!
What took you two so long?! Cripes!
What's wrong, Granny Tsunade?
Don't you have something
to talk about?
Well...
There's certain information that is
being spread throughout the region...
It's about that.
Information?
What? What about?
Orochimaru is dead.
It seems Sasuke Uchiha killed him.
Is...
Is that...true?
There's no mistake about it.
I heard it from a reliable source.
Then...
Heh! After all, there's no way
he'd get killed by Orochimaru!
That means Sasuke will be coming back
to the Hidden Leaf! Right?
That doesn't seem to be the case...
Now...
I have all the members I had in mind.
So I will tell you my goal.
My goal is to kill Itachi Uchiha
of the Akatsuki.
Thought so...
Itachi Uchiha...?
But that's his brother!
And I want to borrow
your strength for that.
Naturally, I won't force you.
Karin...You said you had business
to take care of.
What will you do?
W-Well...On second thought,
it's not that urgent...
Karin...Be honest with yourself.
Isn't being with Sasuke
all you really want?
Th-That's not true!
Whoever said such a thing?
That's...! I...!!
See, I hit it right on the mark.
That's why you're speechless.
So obvious.
I know all about it...
Long ago...
you had a crush on Sasuke...
Suigetsu, don't get Karin so worked up...
I thought I told you to be cooperative.
All right...Sorry, Karin.
But as much as you hate it...
I'm sticking to Sasuke like glue.
At least until I possess one
of the Seven Hidden Mist Blades...
Kisame Hoshigaki's
Great Shark Fin sword.
So you're just sword collecting?
How lame...
Suigetsu...
I know. Jugo, what about you?
Kimimaro used to say that
you were his reincarnation, Sasuke...
And he bet his life to protect you.
So I want to see with my own eyes
just how great of a ninja you are.
Then it's all set!
What's the matter with him?
Orochimaru is dead,
so why isn't he returning to the village?
Sasuke is possessed by
the desire for revenge.
He intends to approach the Akatsuki
in order to kill his older brother Itachi.
That guy!
Is he still...? Dammit!
From this point on, we move together.
And henceforth,
we will call ourselves...Hebi.
Well, let's get going.
Operation "Track Akatsuki"
is still ongoing, right?
Yes...
If we hunt down that
Akatsuki member first
we'll definitely run into
Sasuke eventually!
Hebi has but one objective...
In other words, our target is...
Itachi...
Uchiha!
Corrosion Style:
Scorching Rocks Jutsu!
This isn't a case of
mistaken identity I take it…
My weaknesses have already been
carefully researched.
So now, how will you deal with this?
He turned his body into lava?!
He's trickier than I thought.
Water Style:
Giant Exploding Water Shock Wave.
He's not all talk either.
I wish you'd just allow yourself
to be captured without all this fuss.
What a pain.
You're back.
Yeah, but having to bring him back
without killing him,
was quite a bother.
It's starting to rain.
Looks like it'll storm.
Let's take cover under a tree,
or we'll catch a cold.
Leader is waiting for word that
we've captured him.
Immediately thereafter,
the sealing of the Three-Tails
and Four-Tails is to occur simultaneously.
So we make him wait a little.
Once the sealing begins,
we'll be working for quite some time.
He seems near death.
You must handle the elderly
with care.
You say that because
you don't know him.
This Jinchuriki who uses the
Corrosion Style Jutsu of the Four-Tails
isn't what you think.
You didn't fight him yourself,
so you wouldn't understand
what I went through.
But, I was the one who asked
to go alone.
Say, want me to beat
your assignment half-dead too?
Don't get so excited, Kisame.
Well, I'm a bit tired, you see.
I wish we could catch all
the Tailed Beasts already.
Don't be so impatient...
It's going to take some time.
I wonder about that.
There's just a few more, right?
And it's been decided that
the Nine-Tails will be sealed last...
Otherwise, the balance
will be disrupted,
and the sealing statue
will be pulverized...
That's what Leader said...
After all, the Jinchuriki need
to be captured alive.
So I say just catch them quickly
and leave them tied up.
Humph...Fine with me,
but remember that Deidara failed.
If he's going to be sealed last, it's
no big deal if we capture him last.
And besides, Akatsuki is becoming
too conspicuous lately.
If we capture the Nine-Tails' Jinchuriki
too soon,
the Hidden Leaf will become
even more of a nuisance.
Heh...You really think so?
The Hidden Leaf Village has
very strong links with other villages.
If they begin to collaborate,
it will be difficult for us to act.
It will be wiser to collect up
to the Eight-Tails
with as little commotion as possible.
I see. I guess you're right.
There's the summons.
We've been caught dawdling.
You're late...
We had just finished catching
the Jinchuruki when you contacted us.
We tied him up good to
make sure he didn't escape.
That's what took us longer.
So, what's up?
I got an urgent message
I wanted to relay to you.
Orochimaru has been killed.
It's been ten years since
he deserted us...
So we've been spared the trouble
of killing him ourselves.
I would've loved to see him die
as much as I would've loved to
see the Zombie Combo die.
Hidan and Kakuzu were
our comrades.
Don't say such things.
Sorry...Back then,
they were done in by...
The Hidden Leaf.
The squad with Kakashi and
the Nine-Tails' Jinchuriki.
They're strong, that team.
Even Deidara got his butt kicked.
Tobi!!
Say one more word and my patience
will run out! It will!
It takes self-control to be patient...
And your fuse is too short for that.
Why you--! Tobi! You!
Pipe down, Deidara. Tobi's right.
You got chewed out!
But Tobi, you always talk too much.
Respect your superiors.
Okay! Sorry!
And we're supposed to get
the remaining Jinchuriki with these two?
But killing Orochimaru took
special skill. Who did it?
Sasuke Uchiha.
I was gonna be the one to
bring Orochimaru down.
Hmm...He's good.
I'd expect nothing less from
your kid brother, Itachi.
He's gathering members...
Really troublesome ninja at that.
What do you mean?
You know them well too...
One of the Hozuki Brothers
of the Hidden Mist...
You mean, Suigetsu?
That brings back memories.
And also, Bipolar Jugo.
So be on your guard,
Itachi and Kisame...
I dare say they're targeting you two.
And the rest of you should keep
Sasuke Uchiha in mind.
After getting information
about Itachi and Kisame,
they may just come after Akatsuki.
Kisame, what kind of guy is he...?
This Suigetsu...hmm?
It happened ten years ago...
He had such a cute smile.
A child prodigy who's been called the
reincarnation of the demonic Zabuza.
Are you a river child
who got stranded on land?!
Quit stopping to drink water so often!
Hmm...They seem like an interesting lot.
Hey, don't get too interested.
And just leave me out of it!
Never mind that already.
Itachi, Kisame...
hurry up and get the Four-Tails.
We'll seal him at the same time
as the Three-Tails!
Understood.
Cripes, and I thought
we'd get to rest a bit.
We have no choice. Let's hurry.
We target the member of Akatsuki
with whom we have
the highest chance of meeting Sasuke.
Well, I can see the logic in that.
Itachi Uchiha...What shall we do?
If we're able to take just one of
the Akatsuki into custody,
Ibiki can get information about
Itachi out of him.
I've already issued an order to
all teams to capture
a member of Akatsuki
if the opportunity presents itself,
and to transport him here.
That will probably be very difficult.
Kakashi Sensei...
We won't be able to make them
talk so easily.
Even those we've already encountered
were far too dangerous
and we couldn't even think about
taking them into custody.
Then what're we gonna do?!
Well, until we come across Itachi,
I don't think we have any choice
but to be very patient and search.
Well then...
Say we find Itachi. What next?
About that...
I have an idea.
Can you spare some time?
This is a big one.
So you've come...
All right, we'll begin the sealing
starting with the Three-Tails.
All right! Assemble.
Let's begin.
We're here.
What a creepy-looking place.
Let's go.
A hideout in an old ruin like this...
It's news to me.
Orochimaru has nothing to do with this.
My clan used this as a weapons store.
We'll prepare for the battle
that will be fought here.
The passageways look so similar,
it's easy to get lost in here.
But what a depressing place.
It stifles my breath.
Sorry if it's depressing here.
Huh?
It's been a long time,
Denka and Hina.
It's young Sasuke, after all...
What's your business here?
Weapons and medicine...
and various other things.
We're preparing for battle.
This is...
Oh, a talking raccoon dog?
Hey, come over here.
Yikes...
They're ninja cats.
Don't approach them carelessly.
They'll tear you apart.
You should warn us about stuff
like that from the beginning.
Did you bring us a present?
Here...a bottle of catnip.
Thank you.
Follow me. I'll take you to Granny Cat.
I owe you, Granny Cat.
It's been so long since we've met,
but you're in such a hurry.
Yeah. I have something important to do.
You're not a ninja cat, right?
There, there.
No, stop. Even this one is too small.
Sorry.
So you're going to see Itachi,
after all?
I've known you both since
you were little,
but little did I imagine
it would come to this...
You two are all that's left
of the Uchiha Clan...
And now, you'll have to
fight to the death.
I'm going. Thanks for everything.
Granny, don't we have something bigger
for him to wear?
In that box over there!
Nothing fits.
Then just wrap that curtain
around him!
I don't run a clothing store!
Granny! What a rude thing to say,
considering he paid us!
Fine.
Cripes, sealing the Tailed Beast
is such a pain!
And there's more to go after this, right?
Just thinking about it frazzles me.
Now then...which way? Hmm...
Umm...Excuse me, Senpai,
"which way" what?
What do you mean?
What do you think?!
Do we go for the Nine-Tails' Jinchuriki
whose team is led by Kakashi...
or Sasuke Uchiha...?
Hey, we shouldn't mess with either one!
Our assignment is over!
And furthermore,
Sasuke's not even a Tailed Beast!
Are you kidding...?!
The Nine-Tails' Jinchuriki owes me one
for punching me.
And Kakashi got my right arm...
Then there's Sasuke Uchiha...
I can't forgive him 'cuz he killed
Orochimaru, whom I planned to kill.
Geez...
Once he sets his mind to something,
he just won't listen.
Did you say something?
No.
Humph. We're going, Tobi.
Oh dear...That Deidara has gotten
all worked up
about going after your little brother.
Is that okay with you, Itachi?
Let's go!
I see. You've given it
quite a bit of thought.
Okay, I'm issuing the order
for a mission
to locate and detain Itachi Uchiha!
All of you, be extremely careful
and carry out your duties!
- Right!
Using this as the central point,
we'll search all four directions
for five kilometers.
If we find nothing,
then we'll move the central point and
spread out five kilometers from there.
And...we'll keep repeating this strategy.
Five kilometers...
Our wireless radio will be out of range!
And if we're separated,
it'll be dangerous!
The rules state that all patrols must
be done by two-man cells.
- If we encounter the enemy--!
- Sakura...
Don't get so worried.
Our voices which travel even farther
than the wireless radios,
and our noses that can instantly
sniff out danger, will protect you.
Pakkun!
All right, let me explain
the patrol team formation.
This time, two ninja hounds will
be assigned to each member.
Two dogs...? Huh? But...
Get along, all of you.
Hello, Sakura.
You're such a snappy female
as usual.
I'm partnering with Shino.
Ugh...You stink of insects.
You stink like a dog.
Hello.
Let's work together...
In peace and harmony...
Hehehe!
I wonder if...
I can become friends with dogs?
What about me?
Naruto, you're the Jinchuriki
they're targeting.
Just in case you're attacked,
you'll be with Yamato and
Sensory-Scout Hinata.
And Big Bark Bull.
L-Let's work together, Naruto.
Right!
And being ninja-hound users,
Kiba and I will each have one dog.
So we're all set!
Listen up, everyone.
Above all, you will track
Itachi and Sasuke's scents.
If you find either one of them,
verify their location,
then return to this spot.
Especially you, Naruto.
Don't go running off ahead of us.
I know.
All right then, let's head out.
Scatter!
I'm going.
Itachi Uchiha, eh?
I hope we can find him.
All right!
Sa-su-ke!
I'm staying with you!
You too. Get going.
Drat!
It's completely healed...
Yeah.
And? Which one are we going for?
Sasuke or the Nine-Tails...?
Well now, which will it be...?
W-W-Wait, D-Deidara Senpai!
Wait up!
Who are you?!
I guess underlings don't matter.
Go and check.
Yes.
Huh? Who are you?!
You're that Akatsuki...
What's his name?
Kaku...Kakuta...Kakusa...Kakushi...
K-Kakuzu...
Yes, that's the one.
You're that Kakuzu's henchman-
his bookkeeper, right?
I'll tell you anything
you want to know.
J-Just please don't kill me...
That's the way...Keep talking.
Let me ask you guys...
Akamaru! Don't lose to
the other ninja hounds!
We'll be the first to detect Sasuke
and Itachi's scents!
You're too slow, Shino!
Don't dawdle!
I don't like them...
Let's go! Pochi! Tama!
Pochi...?
Tama?!
Don't give me silly nicknames!
Sasuke...
What's the matter?!
I caught a whiff of
Sasuke Uchiha's scent...
What?!
Well?
The smell is faint,
but it's steadily getting closer.
He's near.
Sakura, do you see Sasuke around?
This isn't good.
The smell is going farther away.
I found it, Tobi!
Yeah!
No kidding?! That was fast!
And? Which one is it?
The Nine-Tails or Sasuke?
What an opportunity.
We're going together, Tobi.
So...Which one?
Just follow me!
Yes.
Naruto...Hinata...
You understand, right?
Yes.
Yeah...
You're...!
Show yourself...
Who are you?
You found me, after all...
Kabuto Yakushi...
You've got guts approaching us
by yourself.
I wanted to have a chat
with Naruto.
You're not getting away this time.
We're taking you in.
Hey! Kabuto! You would know!
Where is Sasuke?!
Humph! Still can't get over Sasuke, eh...?
Is it true that Sasuke
killed Orochimaru?!
Yeah...It's true.
More importantly,
I brought you a present today.
What's that?
Information our organization
has gathered regarding Akatsuki.
What of it?
It's yours. You can have it.
Now that Orochimaru is dead...
you're trying to negotiate with us?
Nope...I don't think it's as easy
as negotiating with something like this...
Especially with the Leaf Village.
Then why?
Unlike Orochimaru,
Akatsuki isn't after you.
It's a simple gift to Naruto.
A token of my gratitude.
Plus, Akatsuki is pursuing you.
Gratitude...?
After Lord Orochimaru died,
I lost sense of who I was.
I never knew my parents
or my homeland.
The enemy found me and
from the time I was little,
I moved around the lands
and villages as a spy.
Lands and villages didn't
mean much to me.
That is, until I began serving
Lord Orochimaru...
But now, he's gone too.
Just who am I?
The agony of not having an identity...
You can understand,
can't you, Naruto?
Like I'd understand
anything you say!
Humph...I wonder about that.
Are you Naruto Uzumaki?
Or are you the Nine-Tails?
In the past, you were shunned...
regarded with loathing.
You must have questioned yourself
about who you really are.
However, you had faith
in your strength
and told yourself that
you were Naruto Uzumaki...
and you boldly overcame
their views about the Nine-Tails.
What does he intend...
to do with Naruto?
I can't figure out his intentions...
And that's why you are sure
of your identity
and you found friends
who accept you.
But instead of overcoming
Lord Orochimaru,
I desperately clung to his power.
I'm really able to understand
how you feel now.
You made me realize...
that I want to be like you.
So now...
I'm going to surpass Lord Orochimaru
whom I absorbed,
and discover a new, stronger self.
I'll find my new self...
and you have given me
a hint to finding it.
That's why I'm grateful...Naruto.
Lord Orochimaru is
the symbol of reincarnation.
He continues to live on inside me,
as an existence that I must overcome.
Took...into your body?
Well...
It was just a small segment
of Lord Orochimaru's corpse
after Sasuke killed him...
which I transplanted into my own body.
But, his life-force is amazing.
It's now steadily trying to
take over my body...this thing.
That's ridiculous...
What is that?
Byakugan!
One-third of his body has
already been taken over.
But I've been fiercely resisting
this takeover!
I can feel this part of me that's trying
to overcome Lord Orochimaru!
Well, give it everything you've got!
In a jail cell in Leaf Village!
Wood Style!
All right! Gotcha!
Behind you!
Dammit...
When I'm able to fully control
Lord Orochimaru's power,
I will fight you again, Naruto.
But you come later.
First, it'll be Sasuke who
brought down Lord Orochimaru.
What're you gonna do to Sasuke?!
Until we meet again.
That outfit...You're...
So you're Sasuke...
You really do look like Itachi!
S-Scary!
Ha!
Tobi, look how he's glaring at us!
Where's Itachi Uchiha?
Huh?
Tell me, and I'll let you go.
Sharingan...eh?
He really is Itachi's little brother.
You were only able to kill Orochimaru
thanks to your Uchiha blood.
You're nothing but a fool
blessed with good genes!
He's fast!
Huh?!
One down.
So I'll ask you,
the one with the big mouth, about Itachi.
What're you doing, Tobi?!
Don't let your guard down
just because he's a kid!
His Teleportation jutsu is too quick.
We're no match for him!
That guy...!
First, I'll watch his movements
with chakra level C1.
Tobi! Stay back!
S-Senpai! Time out!
Don't do it!
Senpai! Behind you, behind you!
Ha!
Senpai!
He was strict, but a good partner...
I shall never forget about you,
Deidara Senpai--!
Will you shut up?!
Oh, you're alive?
The ability to produce
an explosive with his palm, huh?
I somehow managed to escape
by hiding in the bomb blast...
Good thing I kept
the chakra level at C1.
He definitely moves swiftly...
How about this then?
I'll play with you a bit more!
Child's play.
So stupid.
It's not over yet!
I guess...it's about time.
No way!
Huh?
Yeah, I thought so.
Hey...!
How's that?!
Oh...
He's not much, after all...
I knew it!
Hey, Tobi!
Whose side are you on anyway?!
Well, he's definitely quite skilled...
Then this calls for C2.
Th-That's...!
Ta-daa! One of Senpai's signature
art pieces, the C2 Dragon!
Tobi, you know what to do, right?!
Of course, Senpai!
We're going with "that," right?!
Yeah! "That" is the plan...
That huge thing becomes
an explosive too?
I'm counting on you, Tobi!
Right!
And judging from its looks,
it'll be attacking from the sky...!
This is bad.
Here he comes!
Let's show him, Senpai...
The power of your pop art!
Pop art is dead! My art is...
Superflat!
Ha!
It's different from before...
A guided missile?
Where's the other one?
Guess I'll start off with him!
Looks like it can only reach up
to five meters, eh?
Tsk...He figured out my limit.
That's Kakashi's trick right?!
I'll give you credit for the skill in
changing chakra form to extend and throw.
But the force of this one's different
from earlier.
Blow to bits!
He really is swift.
Got him!
Did I get him...?
That's...Orochimaru's Curse Mark!
He can even grow wings?
He managed to dodge it
by flying upwards...
Senpai! All the land mine clay is set
and ready to go!
Good job, Tobi! You stay back.
Yessir!
Guided missile attacks from above,
and land mines from the ground!
The key element of
the C2 coordinated assault
is using the land mines
to slow you down
and finishing you off with
a pinpoint missile attack.
Land mines are planted all around you!
Step on one and you'll set them off!
He plans to ram the guided missile
right into me.
And it's flying just outside
my attack perimeter...
With that wounded leg,
I wonder if you can dodge
my aerial attack...hmm?
The next one's gonna be big!
As if I'll let you fly away!
Ha!
That's what you get for trying to
guard yourself with wings.
You can't fly anymore, can you?
Not with one wing...
You're awesome, Deidara Senpai!
Well, let's settle this!
As if that'll hit me!
No foothold! Fall on a land mine
and you'll lose a limb for sure!
A-A foothold?!
What?!
He reached me?
Deidara's balance...!
He purposely stuck his sword
in the ground?
He tested for the presence of land mines
and created a foothold?!
The length of the sword,
which he used as a foothold...
And that jump using his single wing...
This position?!
I see. With that attack,
he lured me directly above the sword...
The shortest distance that
a chakra sword would reach...
Senpai!
I can't move...!
This is bad!
Below me are the land mines...!
Senpai!!
You did die by bombing, after all!
Deidara Senpai...you fool!
I keep telling you to shut up, Tobi!
Huh? Y-You're still alive...?
What a stubborn...
Those eyes...
It's those same eyes...
Damn it!
"Akatsuki"?
Like I care! Don't interfere with
my appreciation of art.
And I'm supposed to take
this kid as my partner...?
He's feisty, but looks like
the type to die young.
It's our leader's orders...
We can use his powers.
You know about my power?
Just who the hell are...?
You're the bomb terrorist
who's been supporting
the anti-government factions
in various lands.
What purpose would that serve
a rogue ninja like you...?
Purpose? I have no purpose!
I get requests to set off explosions,
so I do.
With my creations!
Creations?
That's right.
Look!
Well? Such refined lines,
and a form that pursues
two-dimensional deform.
This is art!
But that's not all there is to my art!
My creations flow!
When it has shape,
it's simply molded clay!
But this explodes!
And the explosion causes sublimation,
and for the first time,
the essence of my creation appears!
That instant of sublimation is
when I experience true art!
Art is an explosion!
How annoying...
Is he done?
Who knows...
Never mind...I'll do it.
What's with his eyes...?
You wanna fight?
If I win,
you will become a member of Akatsuki.
Don't belittle...me...or my art!
My ninjutsu is nothing
but noble, refined art!
Feel my art!
Ha!
You talked big...
but is that all you have?
It's over!
You should take a good look
at yourself.
Huh?
Wh-What?!
That was close.
A little later and
you would've blown yourself up.
I told you he was the type to die young.
A genjutsu! When?!
From the very beginning.
From the moment you looked
into Itachi's Sharingan eye,
you were under his genjutsu.
Beautiful...
This is...art!
Damn! I became fascinated
by the abilities of another?
That's art? No way...
I refuse to acknowledge it!
You lose.
Don't mess with me!
I'm better than you!
My ability is flawless...
It's art that is unbeatable!
I'm better than you! I can't lose...!
Lose to such a...
Lose to such a...!
Huh?! He's eating the Detonation Clay,
which means...
I saved the best for last!
I'll kill you with this!
Tobi, get away!
Whoa, yikes!
It's the C4 Karura!
Hurry!!
This was supposed to be
my trump card to kill Itachi, but...
What?!
Is this a bomb too? If so...
It's huge! If this goes off...
What, you're just gonna run away?!
You really think you can escape
from my C4 Karura?!
It misfired...?
No...That's not it.
What?!
I win!
Art is an explosion!
Sublimate!
Damn!
This can't...be happening!
Now this is my greatest masterpiece!
There we go!
The C4 Karura...
Super tiny, nano-sized explosives.
Using the blast created from
rupturing the giant Deidara,
explosives too small
for the human eye to see
are dispersed into the atmosphere.
Any living being that inhales them
will set off explosions internally
in all parts of the body.
And these little explosions will
destroy the body on the cellular level...
A frightening jutsu...
I have to thank Itachi...
I've won! I've won!
My art wo-!
It seems you've exhausted your chakra...
Your reaction was slow.
Those eyes...
Explosives too small for
the eye to see...
But my Sharingan can distinguish
a chakra by its color.
The mini-bombs molded with
your chakra...
They were as clear to me as
a cloud of smoke.
I could also tell that you were hovering
just outside the mini-bombs'
blast range.
So as long as I could see the explosives,
escape was easy.
But I saw you die from my C4...
That was my genjutsu.
So that was it, after all...
I avoided your vital spot.
Now tell me where Itachi is.
That's why I said...
"I have to thank Itachi."
A clay...clone?!
I anticipated your genjutsu.
You're just like Itachi!
I never fall for the same trick twice!
Yes...Ever since
the day I fought Itachi...
I trained my left eye to
counter the Sharingan.
As if I'd neglect training
to counter genjutsu!
This time, it's over for real!
Eat my C4!
It seems you're the one lacking chakra!
You don't even have
the strength left to dodge! Huh?!
Just as I thought...
Inside are the same invisible
C4 explosives.
Tsk! My wound hurts...
On top of that, I used up my chakra
with that last attack.
What a poor piece of work...!
Now what'll you do?! Hmm?
He used what's left of
his Lightning Blade...
Your Lightning Blades won't reach me
at this distance!
It's over.
Ha!
I won. I'm the winner!
My art triumphed!
Why?!
You...
Don't tell me you figured it out?
Yeah...Quite a while back...
When facing the Sharingan,
it's basic to hide and form your seal.
No matter how fast you are,
these eyes will read them.
Every jutsu you've used has been
with Earth Style seals.
My Chidori is the Lighting Style...
Get it now?
So you knew, after all...
Then that Lightning Blade
you used was to...
The Earth Style is vulnerable
to the Lightning Style.
Your explosives won't detonate against
my Lightning Style.
Isn't that your weakness?
You...!
I see...The Lightning Blade earlier
was to run it through yourself...
and you de-triggered the C4
that had entered your body.
Yeah...Thanks to that,
my body's in tatters.
Although the correct name for
my jutsu is Chidori...
He figured out the weakness of
my art in such a short time,
and so accurately...
When did you realize it?
After that blow from the land mine.
Although, I've been analyzing it
from the very beginning...
Since I countered your first attack
with Chidori senbon.
Among the bombs you created,
some exploded and some didn't.
That's when I formulated a hypothesis.
Hypothesis...?
That time, the only one that exploded
was the one you threw
when you tried to evade my attack.
All the explosives that I countered with
my Chidori senbon didn't detonate.
However, it was possible that
you purposely didn't trigger them...
because they fell close
to your comrade.
In other words, you weren't sure
if they didn't detonate
because of your Chidori or
because I didn't make them explode.
I see...So that's why you tested those
two alternatives on the land mine?
Exactly.
Step on one and you'll set them off!
If they were self-triggered,
your will was not involved.
So I could test if my Lightning Style jutsu
could disarm your Earth Style bombs.
That's right. That time I stuck my sword
into the ground...
I wasn't verifying the location
of land mines.
I shot through them with my sword
tinged with Chidori
in order to confirm my theory.
But...how?! How could you pinpoint
the position of the landmines?!
This eye distinguishes chakra by its color.
Didn't I tell you that earlier?
You could see the position of
the land mines...?!
He wasn't poking into the ground to test
where they were and where he could step?
He was checking whether
he could disarm the Detonation Clay...
But what would you have done
if the land mines exploded?!
It was one or the other.
But I had another back-up plan.
Although I didn't have a chance
to demonstrate it...
This guy...
He even had another jutsu...
Where is Itachi?
You may try to look good,
but you're barely managing too.
It seems your chakra got drastically low.
I win. I still have
Detonation Clay to...Huh?!
Under these conditions,
shouldn't you be panicking a little?
This time, my art will kill you for sure!
That's what pisses me off about you!
Both of you brothers!
Don't pretend to be so cool!
Those eyes!
That overconfident eye irritates me!
As if it denies my art! It's unforgivable!
Those eyes which show absolutely
no respect for my art...
Those eyes that ignore my art...
are unforgivable!
I couldn't care less about such a thing.
Never mind that. Tell me where Itachi is.
So you've drawn back your Sharingan...
You really take me lightly!
This is my ultimate art...!
Now I will detonate myself.
He's...!
With death, I will become art.
This never-before-seen explosion
will leave
a never-before-seen scar on this land.
And...! My art will win
never-before-seen admiration!
Sorry, Tobi...
In the midst of my admiration,
you will definitely die!
An explosion that will cover
a ten-kilometer radius...
You won't be able to get away!
Now, tremble with fear!
Be in awe! Despair!
Scream!
My art is...
An explosion!!
Wha--?!
What is that?!
What the--?!
Kakashi, what is that?
This chakra...
It's that Akatsuki member...
Wh-What could it be?
Let's go check it out!
Right!
Look!
Sasuke...It can't be...!
I can't sense Sasuke's chakra!
That's near our rendezvous point...
Don't tell me he's...!
Damn! It's just as I feared!
That Deidara...
He blew himself up.
Where's Tobi?
Probably dead...
He was within the blast range...
Deidara is dead.
In the end, he went out with a bang.
Oh dear.
Another member has been lost...
And I thought he was
pretty strong.
So? Which one did him in?
Sasuke? Or the Nine-Tails' Jinchuriki?
It was Sasuke.
However...
It looks like Sasuke is dead too.
Deidara took Sasuke down
with him, huh...?
You should feel grateful, Itachi.
Deidara did you a favor
and got rid of your problem.
Hmm...I feel like
we've forgotten something...
Looks like Tobi is dead too.
That Deidara detonated himself
without regard for his surroundings.
Ah yes, Tobi.
It must've been quite a jutsu
if that chicken was unable to escape.
No matter...
He can easily be replaced.
The loss of Deidara, however,
is unfortunate.
I liked Tobi.
When it came to lightening the mood
in our rather gloomy organization,
Tobi was quite talented.
I'm going.
I shall mourn Deidara's death in silence.
Then I'll mourn for Tobi.
You must really be bored, huh?
When the crest of
the snake vanishes...
Then...I do this...
Add a drop of Sasuke's blood...
All right.
Summoning jutsu!
S-So, this is Orochimaru's
Summoning jutsu...
Manda...
Even Orochimaru had trouble
controlling this guy.
How did Sasuke manage to...?
I see. He used genjutsu...
Whoa, you're a mess!
Who did you fight?
You...had the nerve...
to use me...
You damned brat...
Those eyes...you controlled me...
with those eyes...
I...of all...people...
Oh-ohh, he's dead.
Wasn't Manda Orochimaru's
favorite pet?
You ought to treat animals better...
And the whole manipulation
with the genjutsu...
There wasn't time to think.
I had no choice...
Found you!
I figured you'd be here!
Your chakra suddenly disappeared,
so I wondered what had happened...
Did you transport yourself?!
You hid yourself inside Manda,
then used the Transportation Technique
to escape into another dimension...
So why are you in such bad shape?
Just before escaping,
we both got hit by the blast wave.
My opponent was one of the Akatsuki.
He was stronger than I expected...
In any case, he needs time to rest.
Right, Karin?
Ahem! How pathetic!
And you call yourself the man
who killed Orochimaru?!
Orochimaru was already weakened
to begin with.
That's all there is to it.
It just won't stop.
It's strange to have this much rain
around here at this time of year.
You'll ruin your health.
I don't know what someone as cold as you
could be thinking about right now...
But from here,
you look as though you are crying.
It's too bad about your younger brother...
You are now the sole survivor
of the Uchiha clan.
No.
Hmm?
He's not dead. Also...
What do you mean?
Naruto!
Looks like it caught all our attention.
What happened?!
There are signs that Sasuke
was just here.
It's very faint,
but his scent still lingers.
I also detect other scents.
What does it mean?
From the damage to the terrain,
I'd say there was a battle here.
I knew it! One of the other scents
belongs to that fellow in town
on whom I detected Sasuke's scent.
Huh?
Looks like there are others
traveling alongside Sasuke.
He has a companion.
Then, back there...
It's probable that...
Sasuke has formed his unit.
One of the five other scents belongs
to Deidara from Akatsuki.
Wasn't he the one
who self-destructed
and was transported to another dimension
by your jutsu, Sensei?!
It seems he faked
his own death to escape...
The Akatsuki operate in two-man cells,
so there are three left.
Sasuke is moving with
a four-man cell.
Who cares how many there are.
Let's get moving and
trace Sasuke's scent!
We can't.
Huh? Why not?
The scent stops here.
What does that mean?!
Usually in a situation like this,
either Sasuke was blasted to bits
by the explosion...
or Sasuke used
the Transportation Technique to escape.
Transportation Technique...?
It's probably the latter.
My sense of smell is keener
than a dog's right now.
I've found Sasuke!
A nose that's sharper than
the ninja hounds...?
Impressive, Kiba.
Just what I would expect
from a member of the Inuzuka clan.
Kiba, lead the way!
Hah! You talked about killing Itachi...
You won't be able to move around
for some time in that condition!
We've been moving nonstop lately.
It's a good chance to rest up.
All you've done is rest,
you feeble punk!
There, finished.
You didn't do a thing at
the northern hideout,
so don't start telling me
what to do now.
What?! Wanna make something of it?!
Then let's do it!
Enough already!
Suigetsu, Karin...
Have you gathered data on Itachi?
You're in no shape to act so bossy!
I've picked up some tips
about Akatsuki,
but nothing specific
about Itachi himself.
I got zero.
Seems they're targeting
specific people though...
People with special chakra.
Special chakra...?
I did some talking to animals and
located a number of Akatsuki hideouts.
It seems they always sense
a powerful, unpleasant chakra
around each area.
That's what the animals have told me.
Wow, even simpleminded animals
can sense chakra, eh...?
Or maybe it's because
they're simpleminded...
Just like you Karin!
What did you say, you jerk?!
Suigetsu! This time,
you're not getting away with it!
Hey...W-Wait...hey!
Kill...I want to kill...
- Huh?
- Huh?!
Shoot! Jugo's killing impulse is loose!
Sasuke! Hurry it--!
Calm down, Jugo.
S-Sorry...
I'm sure of it. It's this way!
From his scent,
I can tell he's stopped moving.
It seems he's resting.
It's our chance.
Sasuke...
Our paths have finally crossed.
Come, Pain...
He's here.
And...what of Sasuke?
He's coming along nicely...
He was using the Sharingan's power
to his fullest...
His eyes will surpass Itachi's...
The time has come.
He must be ready as well.
After all, he doesn't have much time.
Then what about the Nine-Tails?
You hunt it.
As leader, failure is not an option.
Naruto Uzumaki...
He's no longer just a kid.
He has now mastered a formidable
jutsu...and has many comrades.
It won't be easy.
He even destroyed two of
Kakuzu's lives with a single blow.
To speak of the target as
a threat has no meaning before Pain.
He has never lost a battle.
Well, that's true.
We're done talking.
Tell the other members to hurry
with the remaining Jinchuriki.
I know.
At last...
We are so close to the moment
of achieving our goal...
Then everything shall be restored
to its rightful place...
The true power of the Sharingan...
The true power of I,
Madara Uchiha!
The sky is crying again...
Pain...Are you...?