They're thorns from a poisonous cactus…
You're from the Sand…
You should be familiar with
the plant life of your homeland.
It's pitiful.
Kouji…
Please get the bandages ready.
I know, Ameno.
I'm going to extract the poison
directly out of him.
Medical Water Style:
Water Mosquito!
Are you sure you don't want it?
A Medical Ninja stays
on the frontlines
in order to help comrades
stay alive.
We're not here to battle.
I'm not a Medical Ninja,
so that doesn't include me.
What was that?
Just joking!
I'd never live it down
if word got around
that I took a scroll from
an injured comrade.
Just hurry and get lost.
Would it have been okay
if they weren't comrades?
Did you do a sensory check
on the area, Shishio?
I could swear this wave pattern is…
H-Hey, can we slow down a bit?
See, Sakura? Choji is worried
about you.
He's worried about you, Ino.
If you need to rest, just say so.
Anyway, I hope you're right.
About what?
An oasis, what else?!
You're the one who said that
even with the scroll,
we'd never make it to
the central tower without water!
Come on, guys…
You're to blame for this
in the first place!
That brings back memories
of the last Chunin Exam!
All right! Let's find some weaklings!
Shut up! That was
a tactical withdrawal!
We decided to tread carefully
after we collected the scrolls,
and look at the result!
We should've just headed
straight for the goal
instead of going with
your strategy, Sakura!
What?!
I've been listening
to you patiently…
but you agreed to it!
W-Well…
At the time, I thought…
it would be easier.
You just drank too much water, Ino!
You bloated blister!
Bloated blister? Is that right?
Well, you'd have to drink a hundred times
more than me to fill yours up!
If drinking water is all that it takes,
I'd be happy!
Now, now, you two.
Get over it.
– Shut up, you fa…
– It's out!
Let's get out of here!
No way!
Is this trauma?
Choji!
Mind Transfer…
It's faster than it looks…
I can't do Mind Transfer.
Then I'll—!
Super Expansion Jutsu!
Way to go, Choji!
Clobber it just like that!
We did it!
Cha!
You know, tell us if you have
a move like that up your sleeve!
For an instant,
you probably have
more power than me.
I-I doubt that…
Let me see.
Even if we're Medical Ninja, it's hard
to heal your own fist, right?
Looks like it's the two women
and the fatso from the Hidden Leaf.
The team of Sakura Haruno…
Lady Tsunade's apprentice.
That powerful fatso's team? Interesting.
Besides that, this team
has two Medical Ninja.
Two Medical Ninja on one team?
Whatever. Let's get going.
Since you don't plan on
ambushing them, right?
We have to reach
the oasis sometime today,
or else our provisions
will be in trouble!
We have water that I extracted out
of that giant scorpion,
so we can still get by!
Well, I refuse to "get by"
with scorpion water
for the rest of the Chunin Exam!
It's just like you planned.
I didn't account for this.
You are...
Please hand over your scroll.
Then we will allow you access to
the water in the oasis up ahead.
And if you wish, medical treatment.
What?!
We don't need to be treated by you!
We have our own medical specialist!
Ino…
Yeah.
Besides, no one told us the oasis's
water belonged to anyone.
You tell 'em Choji!
Sakura, you tell 'em too!
We don't need treatment,
but we definitely need water.
Hey, we'll lose even before we fight,
if you get weak like that!
Ino!
Sand Formation: Shisa!
Are you all right?
So she was a pawn?
Jumping within my range of attack
without taking any precautions…
I heard this team had two Medical Ninja
and was curious…
But she doesn't have
the cool-headed judgment
required of a Medical Ninja.
How disappointing that
my expectations were unwarranted.
Which means...No more negotiating.
Seems that way.
You just fired us up!
Choji and I will break through this!
Medical Water Style:
Water Praying Mantis!
Don't worry.
Once we get your scroll,
I'll treat your wound.
It's not an ordinary Water Style blade.
It's as sharp as a chakra scalpel.
She's very strong!
Saganken: Sand Stone Fist!
Damn! I missed!
Partial Expansion Jutsu!
This sand fist…is equal to
my size and power…
But…
…it's ridiculously hard.
And it must be pretty heavy…
But he easily…
Let's see who's stronger!
Amazing...To see through
successive attacks…
Damn it…
Your attack is boring!
He just took a blind swing!
You seem to be having a hard time.
Not as hard as you.
You two…
are fooling around too much.
Did you finish infusing chakra?
Here I go!
Polarized Sand Formation:
Burning Sand Camouflage!
They disappeared!
Choji!
This is not the time…
to worry about the others.
Now, how will you fight
a foe you can't see?
Choji…
If we scatter,
we'll be at a disadvantage.
You got my back?
U-Uh-huh!
Sakura...Choji…
At 8 o'clock, distance 10…
At 3 o'clock, distance 5…
Two of them.
At 6 o'clock, distance 30.
It's no good!
My chakra's disrupted…
I can't tell!
If my concentration
lapses even a little,
my Sensory Perception
doesn't work.
I can't use this in actual battle…
I'm sorry, Choji.
I wanted to get this down
by the Chunin Exams, but…
It's okay.
The fact that you can even
do Sensory Perception
is amazing to me.
You can't use it in real battle,
that's for sure.
However…
It's these little tricks
you think you can't use
that somehow work in
an unexpected surprise attack.
Not yet...
…we can't let it end yet.
Nah...Let's finish things up here.
Choji, watch out!
How do I watch out for
a foe I can't see?
Figure it out yourself!
In the direction of six o'clock!
All right!
Thank you, Shikamaru!
Found them! The three of them
are on the move.
I sense their chakra…
The enemy should be
heading this way.
Since when do you
have sensory powers?
That's amazing!
"Right?!"
…is what I want to say,
but in actual combat,
it's still difficult for me.
If I have the time
to concentrate I can do it.
I see…
Well, no enemy will give us
the luxury of time…
If there's no time to spare,
you just have to steal it!
I pretended to be a pawn
to buy time
and use Sensory Perception.
Don't be so proud of yourself
for fooling us.
We thought he got you.
Now, now…
We're taking this.
You can't buy time
for damage this small.
What? What the hell is going on?!
I never expected a Sensory
type to be among you.
That counter attack was
perfectly executed…
I'm shocked it didn't work…
But the speed with which
she undid the damage…
I had kneaded chakra earlier
for this Medical Water Style
Water Jellyfish.
If it weren't for
this self-healing...
We would have been in trouble.
Kouji, Shishio…
I'm out of Water Jellyfish,
but can you still continue?
Sure...This time,
I won't allow any sensing!
Choji, Sakura!
I'll track them with…
Th-This is a sensory barrier?!
Blinding Sand Formation: Noise!
I won't let you sense us anymore!
Ino!
Be grateful to Ameno.
She gets really upset
if I do too much damage.
What? What is it?
You're so antsy.
Are you so worried about
your daughter's Chunin Exam?
I won't make any excuses, but…
my daughter's what you call
a jack-of-all-trades
and master of none.
Before I knew it,
she turned her back on
training in our Secret Jutsu…
and took up
Medical Ninjutsu training.
I mean...She's been such
a burden to you, Lady Tsunade…
Don't worry about it.
Besides, I don't intend to
make her a Medical Ninja.
Huh?
I just thought it would come
in handy someday.
Since she skipped out training
for the Secret Jutsu
to come learn under me...
If I can't sense them,
I can't get into
Mind Transfer mode.
So I'll contact those two
with Mind Transmission...
Sakura, Choji...Can you hear me?
I-I hear you.
Ino! Can you do something
to sense the enemy?!
My Sensory Perception
is being blocked.
But…I think the enemy's attack
follows a pattern.
That's pretty obvious!
The enemy attacks
from your blind side.
Like just now,
I can see Choji's opponent.
Except, it's already too late
when I see one coming.
I knew it…
You can communicate with
several people at once.
This is
the Mind Transmission Jutsu.
Transmission of intel is
a basic part of battle strategy.
As long as the enemy
doesn't find out,
it's a huge military asset.
You learned an awesome jutsu, Ino!
I-I guess…
The more useful the jutsu,
the riskier it is.
That goes for the Mind
Transmission Jutsu as well.
If you misjudge your level of skill
and carelessly increase
the jutsu's intensity,
in the worst case you could die.
By increasing the intensity,
do you mean
widening the scope or increasing
the number of people involved?
I guess that would change
how we strategize…
Yes…
There are levels within
the Mind Transmission Jutsu
that correlates to the user's skill.
Transmission speed, the scope, the
number of people in the conversation…
These change according
to the user's level.
And when truly mastered,
you are able to transmit
what is most precious.
What is most precious?
The Mind Transmission Jutsu…
In other words, using your body
to communicate what is in someone's heart.
On the battlefield,
when you can feel the intensity of
your teammates thoughts for you…
that gives you more courage
than anything.
I've only scratched
the surface of this jutsu…
If only I had spent
more time training…
If only I had spent the time
I used training in Medical Ninjutsu,
training with Dad…
That happens because
your chakra control is too rough.
Control your chakra more delicately!
Lady Tsunade…
Sakura, Choji, listen up!
Huh?!
You can do that?!
It doesn't matter...I have to do it.
I have to raise my level
much, much more.
Mind Transmission Jutsu!
Send Sakura's thoughts to Choji!
It worked!
Send these thoughts to Choji.
I did it!
I saw something, but at this rate,
I won't make it in time.
Transmitting takes too long.
I have to send Sakura's thoughts
straight to Choji.
I won't give up! More! More!
I will raise the level of
my Mind Transmission!
More…more…
More…more!
My thoughts this time!
Cha!
How?
How could you...Impossible!
Intense feelings decided
the outcome of this fight.
Ino, are you still up to it?
Of course!
Then let's finish this.
Right.
W-Wait!
– No excuses!
Extreme delicacy is
required to perform
the Secret Ninjutsu of
the Yamanaka Clan.
I have no doubt that the chakra control
skill required in Medical Ninjutsu
will come in handy.
Lady Tsunade…!
It may seem she's taking a detour,
but she's learning what she must.
And you, as her father must
be well aware of that.
In time, you will surpass me…
In fact, I have faith that you will
become the best of the Yamanaka Clan!
Those guys were pretty formidable.
Who knows what would have
happened if you weren't here Ino.
Don't say that. You two bought
me time, that's why.
If you two didn't give it your all,
who knows…?
I'm sorry, Dad, for skipping out
on my training.
Please forgive me, Lady Tsunade…
For thinking that Medical Ninjutsu
was an easy way out.
Your guidance and training
in Medical Ninjutsu helped me to grow.
Calm decision-making,
delicate chakra control…
Everything is pushing me in
the direction that I'm destined to go.
All right, let's do our best
and reach our goal!
Okay.
Hey, we have both scrolls,
so let's go straight for the goal.
I wish we could,
but there's a high risk of
getting ambushed.
We should stick to Sakura's plan
and take the detour.
Sakura…?
Sakura!
Sakura…
Two dams…
Next, I'm going to teach you
the jutsu to revive all the organs,
the entire system.
It's called the Ninja Art:
Mitotic Regeneration Jutsu.
Ninja Art…
Mitotic Regeneration?
This isn't a jutsu that revolves
around healing skills.
It's the same kind of
regeneration jutsu
that the First Hokage used.
The First Hokage had
such enormous chakra that
he could activate it
without weaving signs.
I don't have
that kind of immense chakra.
So…there's one more jutsu
I will teach you.
It's called
The 100 Healings Jutsu.
The 100 Healings Jutsu?
Even I don't have the kind of chakra
that the First Hokage had.
So I developed this jutsu.
By using it, you can keep
a huge amount of chakra in reserve.
By combining these two,
the body will continue
to regenerate and
you will not die during that time.
A-Amazing…
However, there's a problem with
the 100 Healings Jutsu.
Not only does it require extremely
delicate chakra control,
you must amass chakra
for three years.
Three years…?
You have a constant amount
of chakra infused.
Well, you must maintain
that state for three years!
I have to maintain this condition
for three years?!
Sakura!
Due to the effect of
the 100 Healings Jutsu,
your normal chakra level
has become extremely low.
This will only be a hindrance
during healing and in battle.
At this rate, I can't allow you
to perform any surgery
or go out into the battlefield.
The 100 Healings Jutsu creates
a smaller secondary dam
in which to store
the chakra reserve…
If I keep two dams of chakra and
make sure I use each of them
for their specific purpose…
I should be able to perform surgery
as well as fight in battles!
My optic nerve is connected.
Foo!
Wait!
Where do you think you're going?!
We have both scrolls!
So let's head straight
for the central tower!
I don't want to!
I still haven't made any friends!
I just want to have
a little more fun first!
Have you already forgotten?!
We're taking the Chunin Exams to make
a name for the Hidden Waterfall!
We may not beat
the 97-minute record
set by the Kazekage
when he was a genin,
but we can still shoot
for first place!
Yahoo!
– She's not listening!
Calm down.
Yeah…
Foo, the village chief would
be disappointed if he saw you now!
Shibuki...?!
Yes, bringing glory
to the Hidden Waterfall
is Lord Shibuki's greatest wish!
Shibuki…
Think of how he would feel!
Okay, okay!
I guess I have no choice.
The lord's wish always
comes first with Foo.
I don't know why,
but she calmly obeys whenever
his name is mentioned.
Foo! Not again!
Where are you going?!
To the central tower, where else?!
– You're going the wrong way!
With the Sand Eye,
there's no danger to him physically.
But as long as Gaara
doesn't change his mind…
We can't let down our guard.
Gaara…
Shall we break for dinner?
I agree. It's getting late.
No, I'm okay right now.
All right.
He snubbed us.
Sure did.
Where are we headed?!
We're heading to the central tower.
Wait, we don't have two scrolls!
Use your head!
The earth here is to our advantage!
Actually, we don't have the
"Earth" scroll, just the "Heaven" one.
That's not what I meant.
Any team with both "Heaven" and
"Earth" scrolls will be targeted.
So they'll head straight for the
central tower as quickly as possible.
But, traps are laid throughout
the surrounding area.
Except this eastern route.
The eastern route is clear?
Then everyone will
be using that route!
Except…this place has naturally
occurring hidden quicksand pits.
Once you fall in, you can't get out.
So we'll get there first, wait patiently,
and then steal a scroll.
How's that plan?
You're so smart.
It sounds a bit cowardly though.
Do you want to pass
the Second Exam or not?
Don't be a hypocrite.
You're right. Let's do it.
So you're Houichi.
You look quite young.
Yes, I am young.
But I've studied
the Priest Bunpuku's power
to mold currents since I was a child.
Bunpuku, you say?
Yes.
Gaara has become the Kazekage,
but he still poses
a threat to this village.
As long as he remains,
measures are necessary
to control this fear.
The Chunin Exams present
the ideal opportunity
to extract Shukaku, the One-Tail.
Ultimately, this means
that he must die.
Yes.
First, we must make sure
the Kazekage is alone,
and lure him to the tower.
I'll now release the barrier
that obstructed long-range
sensory perception.
This place is called Demon Desert
because it's difficult to survive
its massive sandstorms
once you get stuck in one.
That's why
the Sand Investigative Unit
uses long-range sensory perception
and stays on guard.
What?!
What is that?
Hey, this is bad!
However, if long-range sensory
perception wasn't functioning,
what would happen?
By now, chaos must be
breaking out at headquarters…
A massive sandstorm is forming!
Why wasn't it
detected until now?!
I didn't sense anything unusual!
He's right. I didn't detect
anything either.
Could someone be interfering
with our long-range sensory...?
Like blocking your perception
with a barrier?!
Who would do this, and why?
More important, we need safety
measures for the exam participants first!
Isn't survival part of this exam?
This sandstorm is way too big!
There will be hell to pay
if they all die.
Damn it!
What a hopeless bunch.
The Second Exam will
be postponed temporarily…
and we'll lead all
the exam participants into shelters.
I leave the Kazekage to you two,
because it seems like he's going
to take matters into his own hands...
Make sure he does not
set foot outside.
– Yes sir!
Are you ready?
– Yes, ma'am!
Teams One to Three,
come with me.
The rest, with me!
Let's go!
I can't believe we didn't detect
a sandstorm of this magnitude.
Who could have interfered?
I just hope
nothing bad happens…
Yeah. I agree.
What is this—?!
It is a sandstorm!
I know that!
So this what a giant sandstorm
of the Demon Desert is like.
It's way bigger than I imagined.
We can't stay here, that's for sure.
This is bad…
That's why I insisted on
going straight to the central tower!
Watch out!
What's wrong?
Uh, nothing.
A sandstorm huh…?
This gives us
the home-court advantage.
I really wouldn't say that now...
This is bad.
We haven't seen a storm
this massive in quite a while.
Yeah, I hope the exam participants
are all right.
Yeah...
Hey, where is Lord Kazekage?
He's fine. He's staying put.
That's good.
Yeah…
I can't even see an inch
in front of me!
It's just a little sand!
The central tower is
right up ahead.
Let's overcome this
with gutsiness!
Byakugan!
This is going to take a lot more
than gutsiness to overcome...
Let's look for a spot nearby
to wait out the storm.
I can't open my eyes!
The sand stings!
I-I can't breathe…
I can't…hang on…
Use this.
It's a sand mask!
The Second Exam is
temporarily postponed!
We'll take you to the shelter.
Don't give in to
a sandstorm like this!
Wind Scythe!
All right, now's your chance
to move forward!
Come on, hurry!
Are you okay, Lee?!
My Hidden Leaf cloak isn't much help
against a sandstorm this bad.
All right, then…
Eight Trigrams Palm: Rotation!
Now, Tenten!
Leave it to me!
I think I have something that
will help us block the sandstorm!
Let's go inside and
sit out this storm.
– Okay!
– Yes!
I'm amazed you had
something like this handy.
Situations like these are
the only times I'm useful.
I see!
As expected.
At least one of you refute me!
I can't walk any further…
Hang in there!
We're almost at the central tower!
Are you sure about that?
You've been saying that,
but we haven't reached it yet…
I'm sure!
Look! The hidden quicksand!
See, I was right!
This is not time to be saying that!
Mikoshi!
Hang on!
We're going to pull
Mikoshi out of there.
Okay!
I-I'm sinking!
Pretty soon now…
Almost there!
Now! Grab my hand!
I can't stand this!
We'd better make it to
the central tower fast
or we'll be swallowed up.
Shibuki!
It's okay!
I will always protect you.
Why?
Why did you protect me?
Because you're precious to me.
Why else?
That's why you have to protect
those who are dear to you too.
If people bond with each other,
there wouldn't be wars in this world.
So first, make a hundred friends.
What is it, Foo?
The central tower is that way!
Hey, are you listening?
Lord Shibuki will—!
For Lord Shibuki's sake—!
I'm sure Shibuki will be pleased
with what I'm going to do now!
All right! Stay still!
Come on!
I am Gaara, the Kazekage of
the Village Hidden in the Sand.
I'm Foo from
the Hidden Waterfall Village.
Why did you save them?
You're taking the Chunin Exams too,
aren't you?
Oh...Our village chief, Shibuki,
taught me.
Shibuki?
Many people might
misunderstand you.
But you must hold
the people around you dear…
And do your best
for these people.
If you do, then someday…
I'll have a hundred friends, right?
Y-Yes…
He taught me that one day
I'm sure to have 100 friends.
I see, that's why…
As I watched you,
I remembered a certain man…
And now, I know why.
Who is this man?
He's a lot like you.
I faced him in battle…
And he taught me
that we can learn
to understand the pain and sorrow,
and the joy of others.
Wow...I'd like to meet someone
like that and become his friend.
Hey, what scroll do you guys have?
The "Heaven" scroll…
Take it!
Really?!
You're a lifesaver!
We can't.
We can't accept it.
Why not?
I have a new goal,
so I don't need it!
We were taught by Lord Gaara…
To break down the barriers
that we create,
to overcome and win,
and grasp the results that we desire.
We want that scroll
more than anything,
but if we allow you
to give it to us…
we can't claim that we fulfilled
the conditions of the Second Exam.
We will obtain it through
our own power.
I understand!
– Foo!
It'll be a pain if they catch me…
So, I'll be going now!
Good bye!
– Thank you!
She's interesting…
I'm sure we'll meet again somewhere.
Lord Gaara…
Prepare to die.
So this is the legendary sandstorm
of the Land of Wind!
I'd heard rumors,
but this is mind-blowing!
Postponing the Second Exam
was wise.
Yes, one careless move
and you're dead.
Are you from the Hidden Leaf?
We have a letter from Lady Hokage
to Lord Kazekage.
It's very urgent.
We'll deliver it to him.
Our instructions are
to deliver it to him in person.
Will you please let us through?
No.
The Second Exam is under
the Sand's jurisdiction.
That's unfortunate.
Well, since they won't let us through,
should we return to the Leaf Village?
Yeah, I guess we should.
That's really bad acting, you two.
Well, so long!
What?!
Don't let them get away!
I can't take it anymore!
Hang in there!
Do you want to rot in the desert?!
But…
Don't get flustered!
I'm Kankuro,
a Hidden Sand proctor.
I'm going to get you out of here.
You came personally
to rescue us, Sir Kankuro?!
Follow me!
I'll take to you the shelter.
– Yes, sir!
I can't walk…any further.
Listen to me!
Think of this as part of
the Second Exam and get through it!
Lady Proctor!
If you end up whining
over a mere sandstorm,
you'll never make it
as a Sand chunin!
Talk about exceeding
one's expectations…
I've never seen
a sandstorm this massive.
I can barely breathe…
Leave it to me! I'll stop it.
Third Gate, Gate of Life…Open!
All right, follow me!
Okay, let's go.
Yes.
Hey, stop moving around!
Sorry! But staying still is so stifling…
Instead of getting buried
by the sand like this,
maybe we should make
a run for it…
Wait…
Byakugan!
I broke through!
The sandstorm should subside
in about an hour.
That's when we'll move.
I understand.
We just have to endure
a little bit more.
I have a report on the situation
for Lord Kazekage.
You may enter.
Excuse me, my lord.
We've received status reports
on the sandstorm from the teams.
Nearly all exam participants have
been evacuated to the shelter.
Lord Kazekage?
What is this?!
What's wrong?!
Are you men blind?!
A-A Sand Clone!
Where is Lord Kazekage?!
Thank you very much!
If you thank anyone,
it should be Foo of
the Hidden Waterfall…
– Y-Yes!
Now go!
The Second Exam will
probably resume shortly.
Y-Yes!
What?!
An enemy?!
Where's it coming from…?
We chose the wrong route.
We can't see what's happening
on higher ground from here.
That sound gives me the creeps.
We should high tail it out of here.
Yeah, but let's proceed
with caution.
Power of Dharma: Silhouette.
The tempo's changed.
Let's hurry.
Yes.
What is this?
Huh?! The shadows…!
What are these things?
Sand Clone!
Lord Gaara, what's going on?!
Their target is me.
There's no need for you
to get involved.
It's our duty as Sand shinobi to fight
when our Kazekage is threatened!
Return to the Second Exam.
That is your duty as Sand shinobi!
Dharma Sealing Jutsu:
Sen no Rikyu!
Get down!
I'm losing…my power…
The chain!
Let's pull out the chain!
– R-Right!
Go! I can do this alone…
But…
I order you as the Kazekage
to withdraw immediately!
And not a word of this
to anyone, understood?
W-What'll we do?
How should I know?!
Let's go to the central tower
and get help!
But…Lord Kazekage swore us
to secrecy!
You fool! His life is in danger!
Resistance is useless.
This is the sealing jutsu passed on
to me by Priest Bunpuku!
Now, I can extract Shukaku
from Gaara.
Yukata! Are you all right?
I-I…can't move anymore.
Matsuri! Yukata can't go on!
What do we do?
Mikoshi, take care of Yukata!
I'm going to inform headquarters
about Lord Gaara!
But, by yourself?!
Watch Yukata! I'm going!
Matsuri…
I wonder if I'm going to make
a hundred friends...?
She is so impulsive!
She's abandoning the Chunin Exams?
What is she up to?!
Foo…
We finally caught up…
Where are you going, Foo?!
Are you going back
for the Second Exam?
I just can't figure her out!
– Hey!
– Wait!
The friend I just made
is in trouble!
Friend?
Don't tell me
you're going to help?!
Of course!
Come back, Foo!
Damn it!
Never mind
the Second Exam already!
We just have to
get her back safely!
Y-Yeah…
Hey! Let us pass!
We have a letter for Lord Kazekage
from Lady Hokage!
We'll take it!
That won't do!
We must deliver it
directly to Lord Kazekage.
I explained that's not possible!
He's not here!
Not here either!
Something's up.
Yeah...The Kazekage isn't here.
What in the world?!
The Kazekage...?
This chain…
is extracting my chakra…
That's...!
There's no mistake.
That's Tailed Beast chakra!
If left alone, his Tailed Beast
will be extracted…and he'll die!
Foo!
Stay away!
This has nothing to do with you.
It does have something
to do with me!
You know about me…don't you?
Yes. You're a Jinchuriki too.
That's why I can
feel your pain too.
And you taught me that friends
understand each other's pain.
Stop it…!
It's sucking out my power…
Are you all right?!
So there's another one…
How interesting…
Not even Lord Bunpuku ever
sealed two Tailed Beasts at once.
This is the perfect opportunity to test
the power of the Dharma Seal.
Foo! Be careful!
Foo!
I-I'm sorry…
I think I failed…
Dharma Sealing Jutsu:
Sen no Rikyu!
If the sandstorm continued
any longer,
this would have
become our grave.
You never know
what will happen next.
That's the Demon Desert!
Let's get this Second Exam
over with.
Right! The central tower
isn't far from here.
All right! Let's go!
What's the matter?
Did you forget something?
Yeah…
There's something we need to do
before we head for the central tower.
Yes.
There's someone I want
to settle things with too.
Do you have someone
like that too?
No, it's nothing like that.
Is there something
the matter with them?
We have two scrolls.
Actually…
– What?!
They're both "Heaven" scrolls.
How could you?!
Why did you keep something
so important a secret?!
I didn't intend to
keep it a secret.
It's just that things happened and
I didn't have a chance to tell you.
That's a really bad excuse…
Well, we'll just have to recoup
and obtain an "Earth" scroll somehow.
Byakugan!
Over that way!
Please wait!
Oh, come on!
H-Hey! You're going to take
a scroll from someone
who's ready to drop
from exhaustion?!
We can't do something
so cowardly!
Don't jump to conclusions!
We can't ignore someone
in distress.
That's right!
Neji would never stoop
to such a dirty trick.
Of course not! The thought
never crossed my mind…
Did something happen?
It's Lord Kazekage!
Someone is attacking Lord Gaara!
Gaara?!
Just a little longer.
I'll give this to you,
so please, help me!
Don't worry about that!
Can you just show us the way?
Yes!
Over there.
Byakugan!
Found them!
What are you planning to do?!
We can't ignore them.
But that could mean defaulting
on the Chunin Exams.
I-I'm sorry.
It's not your fault.
It's my decision to take action.
R-Right.
You're right, Tenten.
This could mean a default
on the Chunin Exams.
But in a situation like this,
he wouldn't…
Naruto wouldn't hesitate
for a moment to act.
Yes, I'm sure he wouldn't.
You're right!
Naruto would scold us if
we ignored someone in need
in order to pass
the Second Exam.
Naruto and Gaara both
challenged their destinies
and overcame hardship.
They wouldn't turn their backs and
say it's someone else's problem.
Damn it...I told you not to come.
How can I stay away?!
If your friend was here,
I'm sure he'd come to save you.
Friend?!
Yeah, that's because he's a fool…
Ninja Art: Cocoon…
What is that?
This is…?
My power. But it isn't enough
to break this chakra chain.
So, I'm going to try
to buy us some time.
This is…!
The flow in the chakra chain
is becoming sluggish…
That cocoon has the power to suppress
the absorption of chakra?
What did you do?
I made a cocoon with
my chakra threads.
My cocoon is
a complicated tangle of
super-fine chakra threads.
And it weakened its absorption,
just as I thought.
It didn't stop it.
The rate of chakra being sucked out
has definitely slowed down,
and lessened the pain…
But eventually, our Tailed Beasts
will be extracted…
and we'll die.
Negative thoughts aren't good.
I'm sure someone will come
to save us!
How can you be so positive?
Someone once praised me
that I was born special.
No one will come to help us.
Don't say such things!
Hey! Is someone out there?!
Your voice won't travel
through this cocoon.
Oops! Darn it.
All right then…
I'll just pull this out
with brute strength.
We'll have to wait
to be rescued, after all.
No matter how long we wait, no
one from the Sand will come to our aid.
Again with those negative thoughts!
Would you still say that
if you knew
the person attacking us
is from the Sand?
Are you serious?!
How futile.
All you did was throw away
any way of escape.
Just how long do you think
you'll last in there?
In the past, the only way
I could relate to others
was with hate and a desire to kill.
Now that I am the Kazekage,
some believe that
I will rule through fear,
and are trying to eliminate me.
That can't be helped.
I'm the one who brought it on.
If I have any regrets,
it's only that I wish people knew
how much I was trying to change.
That friend of yours
taught you, right?
That you can share and
understand the pain,
suffering and happiness of others!
Yes, that's right.
But it's difficult for a Jinchuriki.
That's not true!
I'm sure it'll all work out.
Even a Jinchuriki can make
a hundred friends.
I just know it!
The Village Chief told me so.
They're alike, after all.
The sound of a lute?!
What is that?!
It looks like a giant cocoon!
And who is that man?
You're exam participants
from the Hidden Waterfall!
Yes…
We're looking for Foo.
She wandered off.
Foo wandered off?
What?!
Chakra is being extracted
from Gaara and Foo.
What's wrong, Neji?!
What is in that cocoon?!
It's your teammate.
Are you fine with this happening?
At this rate, they'll both die.
If we act now, we can save them…
Please…
Save Foo.
All right.
From what I gather,
the priest's back is vulnerable.
This is what I've come up with.
We'll divide into two teams…
An attack and a rescue team.
The attack team will sneak in close
and attack from behind…
The rescue team will seize
the opportunity and rescue the two.
Lee, Matsuri and the two
from the Hidden Waterfall
will attack the lute-playing priest!
– Understood.
Right! We'll pulverize him!
I'd like to be on the rescue team!
No, I need Tenten for the rescue.
The two of us will go.
Okay!
Scatter!
Shuriken Shadow Clone!
Water Style: Water Shuriken!
Deadly Shell Meteorite!
Leaf Hurricane!
Dharma Barrier:
Celestial Pillars!
What is that?!
Some defensive jutsu?!
No, that's not the only thing.
Let's use caution!
Tenten, I need a chakra sword.
Got it!
Aim for a section of the cocoon!
Right here!
Damn it! We can't get close to him!
It's an impregnable barrier!
At this rate, we're not helping
Lord Kazekage at all.
No, this is sufficient.
What?
Just drawing his attention away
will make Neji's job easier.
That is what we are here to do.
Neji, are you all right?!
Are you two okay?
See!
Someone came to help, after all!
I gave strict orders
not to tell anyone…
Don't be angry with
your subordinates.
They were worried sick about you.
I figured as much…
This chain has penetrated
your chakra points.
And they are causing direct damage
to the chakra network.
They're controlling the flow of
chakra through the chakra points and
siphoning away
your Tailed Beast chakra.
Yeah…
Eventually, the Tailed Beast chakra
will be weakened enough
and he'll extract the Beast itself.
Can you please help?
Tailed Beast or whatever,
chakra is chakra.
If we plug the chakra point that's being
used to siphon the Tailed Beast chakra,
we may be able to stop the flow.
Is that possible?
Yeah...It'll be tricky,
but it's worth a try.
Please do.
Here it is!
Gentle Fist: Chakra Point Needle!
What happened?
The Tailed Beast chakra is
so powerful that it repelled me.
I didn't think it would
be this strong!
So I guess Gaara and
Foo's Tailed Beast chakra
are just as powerful as Naruto's.
Please don't give up!
We're counting on you!
Yeah, I know. I'll try again!
All right, the flow stopped!
You're next, Foo!
Okay!
What?!
The chakra flow has stopped?!
Why?!
Why isn't the Tailed Beast
chakra flowing in?!
The lute-playing priest
is acting strange…
Yes, something must
have happened.
Did the Leaf's Byakugan user
do something?
Well, the enemy definitely
looks flustered.
What's happening?
It looks like it's alive!
That's creepy!
Be careful!
Unless I do something,
the chain will continue searching
for Tailed Beast chakra!
It will find the chakra that
it has already stored up in me…
and start siphoning
that Tailed Beast chakra…
until it destroys itself.
The barrier's been broken!
May I ask you to spare him?
Yes, I understand.
Neji…
I see…
It's the same theory as earlier.
The chakra points are closed.
There are more chakra points
here though…
Everyone, please stand back!
We can still save him.
Let's take him to the Medical Team.
Yes, understood!
You have my thanks, Neji.
Imagine, being rescued by you.
Is everyone all right?!
Yes, we're okay now.
Lord Gaara!
Thank goodness you're safe!
Matsuri performed admirably too.
Over there!
It seems like they don't need
our help, after all!
Yes, I guess we were
a little too late.
I'm Foo of the Hidden Waterfall!
I'm trying to make
one hundred friends!
So please, be Foo's friend!
O-Okay, okay!
I get it, just let go of my hand.
Neji! You're so lucky!
Woohoo! Woohoo!
Friends! Friends!
He's not on the north route.
He isn't on the south or
west routes either!
Where could Lord Gaara
have gone?
The massive sandstorm
seems to have passed.
Lord Gaara?!
What's the big commotion?
Stop making a fuss and
resume the Second Exam.
Yes, sir!
Hurry! Prepare to resume
the Second Exam!
It's unusual for Houichi
not to send a message.
Did he fail?
Lord Gaara!
Fugi…
I've wanted to have
an in-depth discussion with you.
Well then…
What did you want to talk about?
I've always thought of you as
a valuable citizen of the Hidden Sand.
Of course, I still do.
I am humbled.
In the past, words like "citizen"
and "friend" were just that…
Mere words that held
no meaning to me.
For a long time after I was born,
even though I recognized these words,
they were not part
of my existence.
Oh. And when did these concepts
become real to you?
When I infiltrated
the Hidden Leaf Village
with the intent to destroy it.
There, for the first time,
I met someone I could call a friend.
Ironically, he was an enemy
who belonged to the Hidden Leaf.
Although he and I
shared similar circumstances,
he empathized with the pain of others,
and shared in their joy and tears…
Meeting him made me realize…
how precious and important
the word "friend" is.
And it made me want
to become like him…
a human being who is valued
and needed by others.
Lord Gaara, you are and
will always be,
a person who is essential
to the Hidden Sand.
All this time, I've been considered
a military weapon to be feared.
And that continues to instill fear even
in the hearts of the Hidden Sand.
But that's—!
I know.
If this were not so,
my own father would not
have tried to kill me six times.
I am aware of the deeply rooted opposition
to my tenure as the Kazekage.
Should I accept position
or should I turn it down?
It was a dilemma for me.
But after my friend, the Leaf shinobi,
taught me about friendship,
I thought it over and decided…
that I wanted to heal the pain
I had caused everyone.
But it's been difficult to
get the people of the Sand
to believe that I am sincere.
There was a time I felt the wounds that I
inflicted on my people would never heal.
I thought I should just disappear
from the Sand Village,
then the fear would
finally disappear too.
But I found there were people who,
without any prejudice,
accepted my feelings.
You are frightened of yourself.
When you handle a weapon,
you must suppress your feelings
and become emotionless.
Y-Yes, sir!
I once met someone just like you
in Hidden Leaf Village.
Through sheer perseverance,
he has become a fine shinobi.
Shira, I predict you will be
as good a shinobi as him.
These shinobi have to come to accept
and rely on my guidance,
and are maturing steadily.
We're almost there.
But we still need one more scroll.
Well, a lot of things happened.
Let's forget about passing
the Chunin Exams until the next time.
In that case, I don't know
if we'll get a scroll,
but there's someone
I want to fight just once.
That person received guidance
from Lord Gaara
and developed into a shinobi,
just like me.
There's something
I want to confirm
by fighting someone who received
the same teachings as me...
We did it!
We made it! We made it!
But we still only have
the "Heaven" scroll…
It can't be helped.
We're physically at
the end of our limits!
If I hadn't stopped along
the way for a personal battle…
Don't say that!
That's right.
This is all we can do right now.
I'm sure we'll get
another crack at it.
Thank you!
What is it?
Shira, please fight me.
If I lose, you can have this.
It's senseless for Sand
to fight Sand.
We've already made a decision.
Hey!
This is useless to us!
Take it!
Really? You're a lifesaver!
We can't accept it.
What?
Truth be told,
we don't want the scroll.
I just want to use this opportunity
to fight you, Shira.
Fight me?
You and I both…
have been taught by Lord Gaara.
We are the ones who will carry out
Lord Gaara the Kazakage's will…
and support
the Hidden Sand Village.
I want to make sure
we deserve that right.
Fine. I accept your challenge.
Is this okay?
If that's what you wish, Shira.
Y-Yeah…
Thank you, Shira.
Who are they?
The promising youthful power that
will sustain the future of the Sand…
I believe in them and
have high hopes for them.
Those who wish to hunt me
are free to do so…
However, do not involve those youths.
I don't want them colored with
hatred and vengeance.
Come on, Matsuri!
Right!
There were times when
I doubted myself as the Kazekage.
But after coming into contact
with them,
I realized that perhaps even
someone like me can accomplish things.
I want to erase hatred
from Hidden Sand Village,
and create bonds with people
I can call friends…
Friends who understand and
share each other's pain.
If you object, then take my head.
But leave them out of this.
Come on.
Thank you very much.
Please take this.
– Huh?!
This won't work…
Lord Gaara has matured indeed.
Perhaps we old soldiers
worried needlessly.
We must let the horrible memories
of the past fade into the darkness...
And leave it to the next generation
to build a new future.
I alone was responsible
for all of this.
Please accept these.
Two "Heaven" scrolls
are not acceptable!
Oh, but that's—!
No, no, no!
I can't reveals any details, but there were
extraordinary circumstances
that prevented us
from collecting scrolls!
Please ask Lord Kazekage!
It doesn't matter what circumstances
there were. No means no!
You are stingy!
– Now, now…
– Just give it up.
No…! I can't just give up!
Cancel the Third Exam?
I'm sorry.
I can't go into details,
but this is a domestic matter
within the Sand.
Then how do we determine
who passed the Chunin Exams?
We've prepared detailed reports
about each team's performance
in the Second Exam.
I'd like the respective villages
to use them
to decide whether their participants
should be promoted to chunin.
Well, these exams were meant
to test their ability
to carry out missions as chunin…
It can't be helped if
things turned out like this.
But the participants put their lives
on the line to cross the Demon Desert…
Will they be satisfied with this?
I understand that.
Looks like the Third Exam
is cancelled.
What happens to
the Chunin Exams then?
I did have a bad feeling
about this…
Does that mean all that effort
was for nothing?!
We continued to the very end and
didn't give up, so we should be okay.
Those who dropped out midway
are the ones who should be worried.
I sort of feel sorry for them.
All we gained was hunger
and exhaustion.
That's no gain!
At the very least,
perhaps we gained self-confidence.
Exam participants!
I commend your hard efforts!
With the passage of time,
our shinobi world needs
a new system with new laws.
Until today, we shinobi were
required to sacrifice
even the lives of our comrades
for the sake of our laws and rules.
But I have realized that we have
something even more precious
than rules and regulations.
That is friendship, with our
fellow villagers, our fellow shinobi,
and the bond we share with others
who understand the same pain…
I believe that
each of you who stands here now
knows exactly what I mean.
Therefore, I deem
the Third Exam unnecessary…
Furthermore, I am rescinding part of
the requirements for the Second Exam.
So what does that mean?
For each of you standing
here right now,
a detailed report of your performance
will be sent to your respective villages.
Your Kage will make the final decision
on your promotion.
That means we have
to wait longer?
But it also means we still
have a chance, correct?
When you reach
the northern border, be careful.
Thank you.
Yome, since you're going up
there too, try to be nice!
Huh?! What? Huh?!
We got assigned to
the same place by chance, that's all!
Yeah, sure!
Go for it!
Yome, let's go!
Hey, wait up!
I hope they're going to be okay!
We've gone through the report
from the Hidden Sand,
and your chunin promotion
has been approved.
Thank you.
And I'm going to assign you
to an S-rank mission right away.
I've gone over
your Second Exam reports.
And…Hinata, Shino, Kiba,
Choji, Ino and Sakura…
You six passed with flying colors
and are promoted to chunin!
After all, we didn't have
the second scroll…
Komugi, Gennai, Inaho…
You will be given another chance
next time.
Finally…although they did not
collect two scrolls,
they performed admirably…
and are more than qualified
for promotion.
Lee and Tenten,
you are now chunin.
Lady Tsunade!
Team Guy is one for all, all for one!
How can Neji not be included…?!
Just let me finish!
Neji Hyuga is given a special
double promotion to jonin!
The Kazekage himself noted,
"In particular, Neji's performance
was most impressive and"
"due consideration has
been given in this report."
He's already proven himself to be
more than capable as a chunin.
Way to go, Neji!
Congratulations!
Thank you very much!
Thank you to you both.
I made it to chunin because
of Team Guy's teamwork.
Our three-man squad is forever, right?
Yes, I hope so.
I finally overtook Naruto!
He's going to be so mad that
he missed the Chunin Exams.
I wonder what kind of training
Naruto is doing now…
It will soon be time to
wrap up training
and return to Hidden Leaf Village.
Ouch!
That chest wound still hurts, right?
Pervy Sage, you just rest up!
I'm gonna continue my training!
Yourou!
I know...We're being followed.
Fuu...Let's go to that rocky area for now.
What? How boring.
We don't know who you are…
But we've been on to you
for a while now.
I told him to stop…
since not being able to kill you
is such a pain in the butt.
Say, mister! Aren't you a former
Hidden Waterfall?
What?
I know you! After your failed Hokage
assassination attempt,
you stole the hearts of
the village elders and escaped…
You're Kakuzu!
Kakuzu?!
Impossible! How old does
that make him?!
I always thought if
I got to meet you,
I'd like to be your friend!
Kakuzu...Is she stupid?
I wouldn't know.
I deserted the village
a long time ago.
How about we start out as
casual acquaintances over tea?
I didn't come here today
to become your friend…
Well, that's too bad…