Aren't you being a little too laid back?
Oh, well you know, things were
pretty tense around here recently
with the incident in the Sand Village.
But now that it's been settled...
I'm suddenly overcome
with exhaustion...
Even so, we don't know
what's going to happen next.
Only by being cautious at all times
are we able to prevent...
You won't last if
you remain cautious at all times.
Come on, relax, relax!
Move, move, move!
Last spurt! Goal!
First place!
Sadly, second place!
- What kind of race is that?
- Beats me...
Hey Lee, you need to train more.
Yes! I will try to be
first place next time.
But, there is regrettable news.
Wh-What is it?
Lee, you are not second place.
You are...third place!
Huh?!
Second place is Kakashi,
whom I am carrying!
Kakashi, you are too lucky!
You don't need to thank me.
I feel like I learned another
important lesson from you.
As usual, I can't keep up
with their craziness.
Although we did run along after them.
Ridiculous!
Okay, everyone's here, eh?!
Then let's go report to
Lady Tsunade right away.
Um, Guy Sensei...
What is it?
Kakashi Sensei is...
Huh? Oh!
Guess it's the hospital before reporting.
It looks like Deidara was done in too...
There's no question that his cause
of death is from an explosion...
Don't you agree, Zetsu?
He's probably laying there dead
somewhere around there...
Get your hands off, you jerk...
Hey! He's alive!
What happened to the Jinchuriki?
I've met my quota...
Oh dear, oh my...
You barely made it, Deidara...
You all right? Guess not.
Tobi, even the patience of
a saint has limits...
Try saying something again and
I'll decide your cause of death myself...
No doubt it'll be death from explosion.
That's...past the limit...
Death from suffocation...
Oh! He's awake!
So I'm back here again...
Good job, Kakashi.
Master...
Lady Tsunade...
No, Kakashi Sensei!
Don't push yourself.
I examined you earlier,
but you need to be in bed for a week.
It will take a few more days
until you can return to duty.
I guess that's how it goes...
Seems it will still take a while until
you can master the new Sharingan.
Yes...
Just rest. Try not to push yourself
for a while.
Team Guy should rest today too.
You can turn in the report later.
Yes!
Let's go, Shizune.
Yes.
Oh...Master!
Is it regarding that matter?
Yes.
Did you tell Kakashi?
Since Kakashi Sensei has been
like that all this time, I haven't yet...
How about Naruto?
I thought I should first consult you...
Give me the details.
It's what I heard from
the Akatsuki member, Sasori.
He said it was a reward for beating him...
In ten days...at Tenchi Bridge, huh...
Four days has passed,
so it will be in six days.
Can you trust your source?
Considering the situation,
it's safe to say we can trust it.
What would you do if it were a trap?
There is a possibility that
Orochimaru is just bait,
and the Akatsuki will
be waiting there.
If it is a trap,
I'll fight with all my might!
Fight? Kakashi will be in bed
for more than a week.
But we only have six days left.
For that matter,
ever since Sasuke left,
Team Kakashi has been short on staff.
Yes...
We can only add another member
and create a new team.
Lady Tsunade!
What is it?
Then, you should send a different unit
to investigate the situation.
Even if you let Sakura go,
you should leave out Naruto!
Shizune...
Yes.
Like you, Sakura is
one of the few ninja
whom I can trust from
the bottom of my heart.
I will definitely let Team Kakashi go,
mostly because Sakura is on it.
Wouldn't it be the same
if my team went?
It's not the same!
Sakura and Naruto are both
desperately trying
to seek out Sasuke,
their former team mate...
They wish to save Sasuke
more than anyone.
That strong desire will
lead the mission to success.
You and Sakura are different...
I understand, but,
for this mission, Naruto should...
Now that he's heard this...
what would Naruto say?
Let's search for our new team
member immediately!
Later!
Sheesh, that impatient brat...
I wasn't done talking yet.
The child who was entrusted
with the First Hokage's necklace...
Indeed, Naruto might not
be an ordinary kid.
Sasuke...
I'll find two members to fill in the holes
left by Kakashi and Sasuke.
Make sure to tell Naruto as well!
Yes, ma'am...
Tsunade...
I need to speak with you...
Let me see you for a moment.
Hmm, who might be good?
I need to think about this
very carefully.
It would be a pain
if I mistakenly choose someone
who would slow me down.
Plus, even if the person is skillful,
there might be a problem
with their personality,
and that will ruin the teamwork.
And Sakura is a sucker
for handsome boys,
so it would be dangerous
if he were too good-looking.
This is hard.
Long time no see, Naruto.
Huh?
Who are you?
Even though we haven't
seen each other for a long time,
you should remember
your comrade's face.
Because the one that spoke
to you will feel bad.
Oh...um...that really indirect speech...
could it be...?
Shino!
You finally remembered.
If you cover up that much,
no one will know--
Shino, you're here early!
Are you Kiba?
Oh!
This smell! It is Naruto!
You knew it was me 'cause of that?
That dog, could it be...
What are you talking about?
Of course, it's Akamaru!
Huh?!
Hey, did you grow?!
Naw, naw, naw...
Akamaru is the one that grew.
Do dogs become that big
in such a short amount of time?
Really? Since we're always together,
I can't really tell.
Can't tell?! That Akamaru,
he used to be on your head!
Right, Shino?!
Seems like you noticed Kiba right away,
didn't you, Naruto?
Oh shoot, he's upset.
Na...
N-Naruto...
I heard that he came back
to the village.
Wh-What should I do?
I'm not ready yet since we haven't
seen each other for a while.
What should I say...?
Um...Um...
Oh, it's Hinata!
Why are you hiding?
Huh?! Hinata.
Hey, Hinata, hey, Hinata!
Why do you always faint
after seeing Naruto?
Please! We need a new member!
You came at the wrong time,
we just got a mission and
we're waiting for Kurenai Sensei.
Oh that's right.
Then, then...
Hey, Shino is...
You noticed Hinata
right away too, Naruto.
He is still sulking...
Naruto's voice...
Hinata! Just shut up and
come with me!
"Just shut up and come with me"...?
No way...no way...so suddenly...
After all that fuss, I still got rejected.
In that case...
I guess I'll ask those guys.
I told you already, haven't I?
It's annoying, but I'm in charge
of the Chunin Exam.
I mean, yeah, we have
a long history together,
so I want to lend a hand.
But I'm not in a position
to do whatever I want.
The Fifth appointed me,
so she will kill me if I reject the offer.
I get scolded enough by my mother.
And here I was thinking
"I can count on Shikamaru,"
but you go on talking like
it's so annoying and all...
Even if you look at me
with those puppy eyes,
what's impossible is impossible.
Then I will lend a hand!
Here! Shikamaru.
This is the lunch box that
your mom asked me to hand you.
Hey Choji, are you sure you can say
such an irresponsible thing?
Don't you have a mission
with Asuma and Ino?
I can't ignore what Naruto is saying.
I will try to discuss it
with Asuma Sensei.
Choji, thanks!
It's not going to help...
If you tell Asuma because
he works under Lady Tsunade.
Just like always,
you're still eating, huh?
You...are fatter than before...
Over there, huh...?
I haven't seen him before,
but he wears a Leaf head band.
It was so sudden...
I don't know what he is aiming for,
but we need to capture him and...
give him to the Interrogation Unit!
I'll assist you! Go Naruto!
Right!
Ninja Art: Super Beast Scroll
Naruto! Just keep charging at him!
Ninja Art: Shadow Sewing
Who the heck...are you...?
What did you want to talk about?
Since you two advisors are here,
this probably isn't going to be pleasant!
Shizune recently came to us
seeking our advice...
It's about Naruto Uzumaki.
From now on,
do not assign missions
with a possibility of contact with
the Akatsuki to Naruto Uzumaki...
From here on,
make sure he works in a four-man squad
with more skilled shinobi
and increase surveillance on him
as well as protection.
Furthermore, you should decrease
the amount of missions
you assign him as much as possible,
and limit the scope of his activities.
No way!
Tsunade...
Naruto's not just an ordinary kid.
He's a Jinchuriki!
Under normal circumstances,
the logical thing to do
would be to keep him
in the village and under surveillance...
It may not sound like it,
but this is a compromise.
I agree that he should work
in a four-man squad.
But Naruto shouldn't have
so many restrictions placed on him!
Even if we keep Naruto in the village,
the Akatsuki will definitely come
after him, come after the Jinchuriki...
Even in the recent incident
in the Hidden Sand Village,
they went after Gaara, the Jinchuriki,
even though he was
in what was considered
the safest location in the village.
There's a strong possibility that
they'll take a similarly hard-line approach
in regards to Naruto as well.
If Naruto stays on the move,
the enemy won't immediately be able
to figure out what he's doing.
First of all, Naruto does have talent...
He's a shinobi who should be
a great asset to the Leaf Village.
That's a pathetic objection, Tsunade.
You call yourself the Hokage?
I'm trying to compromise too, you know!
Then can you ensure that,
until then,
Naruto won't get taken out
by the Akatsuki?!
And can you ensure that if the Akatsuki
takes the Nine-Tails from Naruto,
it won't bring about bigger calamity
for the Leaf Village?!
Naruto...won't be beaten!
I believe that...
If...that judgment turns out
to be mistaken...
what will you do?
If perchance, the Hidden Leaf Village
and the Land of Fire
become endangered
by my decision...
then as the Fifth Hokage,
I will protect them with my life!
Very well...If you're willing
to go that far, do as you like.
However...
In exchange for that,
you will use the shinobi we select
as the additional members
of the four-man squad.
Fine.
Danzo...Come on in!
Long time no see...
Princess Tsunade.
To think you'd show up...
I see...So the new team members
will be from The Foundation, huh...?
You're sure weak.
Are you sure you have any
"balls" with that kind of skill?
Wha--?! You little!
Who the heck you are?!
We'll be seeing
each other again...Naruto.
Hold it!
Who was that...?
Choji! I thought you'd be here!
For crying out loud!
Asuma Sensei's angry and
wants you to get a move on!
Sorry, Ino...
We got attacked by some weirdo...
Some weirdo...?
By weirdo, do you mean...
Isn't that Naruto?!
No...when I said weirdo,
I didn't mean Naruto...
Naruto! Long time no see!
- Don't bother, Choji.
- How have you been!
- This atmosphere's such a pain...
- Hey, you've gotta tell me your stories!
So you will be arranging
the two additional team members?
No...
Just one member...
So you also weren't expecting
the team leader, Kakashi...
to be out of action, huh...?
Since Kakashi Hatake is
recuperating right now,
an additional member will be required
on Team Kakashi's next mission.
Then you should select
someone very skilled
from the ANBU Black Ops under
your direct control to lead the team.
Yes! That would be good.
You've no objections, right, Tsunade?
Leave the selection to me.
Is that okay with you...?
Then, I'll do it as I please...
L-Lady Tsunade...!
Geez, I don't like this!
I-I'm very sorry...
But I had absolutely no intention
of betraying you...
I'm not talking about you!
What...?
I'm talking about that man.
I'd also thought of having someone
from the ANBU Black Ops
under my direct control replace Kakashi.
I have someone specific in mind...
But...I never thought they'd
suggest that from their end.
I totally thought they were
going to force
one of their own subordinates on me...
Does this mean one person
is enough for the surveillance of Naruto?
Or...are they after something else?
Uh...Umm...Lady Tsunade...?
Of course, I've got tons of things
I want to say to you!
Yikes!
That said, the formation of Team Kakashi
is a more immediate concern.
You're going to work really hard!
Oh, y-yes, ma'am!
That was fast...
I heard it was a matter of urgency...
You know why you're here, right?
I have a general idea.
I want you to take Kakashi's place.
It's an honor to be able to work
in Kakashi Senpai's stead...
This isn't an ANBU Black Ops mission.
It will be a regular mission.
Therefore, take off that mask
and I will give you a codename.
During this mission,
you'll be known as "Yamato."
I understand...
An additional member...a new recruit from
the ANBU Black Ops Training Division
will be dispatched to Team Kakashi.
From the...Foundation?
However...
What is it?
Keep a close watch on his actions.
What...do you mean?
Danzo recommended this new recruit.
The Foundation has since been
disbanded and he has fallen from power.
But I still can't figure out
what he's thinking...
Perhaps you're worrying too much...?
Never mind...
Meet up with the team immediately.
Yes, ma'am!
Hey, Sakura!
This is the spot...
where we're supposed to meet, right?
Yeah...No doubt about it.
Nobody's here yet, considering...
Did Granny Tsunade really arrange
new members for us?
It'll be okay. We just got here
a little too early, that's all.
We've still got a little bit before
the meeting time.
I hope they don't turn out to
have the habit
of showing up late like Kakashi Sensei...
Hi...
Stop it, Naruto!
I'm the replacement captain
for this team
while Kakashi is in the hospital.
Call me Yamato.
You're comrades on the same team,
so you guys need to get along.
C-Comrade...? This guy?
Sorry about before.
But thanks to that,
I now know you're a worthless guy
with questionable "equipment."
Hey, what did you say?!
- We're going to be teammates!
- Damn you!
- Don't start fighting right at the start!
- Some things are inexcusable!
But you're kind of a rotten guy,
aren't you...?
Is that so?
People won't like you if
you say stuff like that.
I like nice...ugly women like you.
Hey, what did you say?!
- Try repeating that, you twerp.
- Hey, do you remember...
- Don't try being cocky with me, cha!
- ...what you just said to Naruto?!
At any rate, the four of us
will be starting our mission now.
And yet...
What's up with this?
I don't have time to put you all in
a cage to get used to each other.
Come on, introduce yourselves.
Naruto Uzumaki.
I'm Sakura Haruno.
My name's Sai.
Well, that's enough getting
acquainted for now.
I will now explain our mission
as Team Kakashi.
The four of us will now head
for the Tenchi Bridge...
capture the Akatsuki spy who has
infiltrated Orochimaru's organization...
and bring him back here.
It's an opportunity for us
to get information
on Orochimaru and Sasuke Uchiha.
We will obtain a precious source
of information
with which we can draw up plans
for both the assassination of Orochimaru
and the retrieval of Sasuke.
Be sure to proceed with caution!
Right!
Yes, sir!
We'll meet at the main gate
in an hour!
We'll leave once you've equipped
yourselves with your ninja tools!
Good move.
Listen carefully...
Never let your guard down.
What is it...Senpai?
Listen carefully.
The classified mission
you've been given is Lord Danzo's...
A cat, huh...?
Anyway, Lord Danzo's vision...
for the future of the village rests
upon this classified mission.
Failure is not an option.
I know.
Good.
You're still carrying that
around with you...?
This is...
In The Foundation,
...you have
no name and no emotions.
You have no past...
and no future.
There is only the mission...
Never forget the will of
The Foundation,
which supports the giant tree known
as the Leaf Village from underground...
unseen.
Oh, don't you look silly.
Master Jiraiya.
I heard you'll be in bed...
For a week, huh?
Well, it seems so...
Hey, don't force yourself.
It's a get-well gift.
Both volumes of the deluxe edition
of "Make-Out Paradise."
You may have already read
it several times,
but it should at least help
pass the time.
Thanks...
Surely this isn't the only reason
why you returned to the village.
I'll give you the details once he...
and Tsunade get here...
Sorry to keep you waiting!
You're late.
I got held up with this and that...
Very well...
Kakashi's waiting.
It looks like they're here...
It's been a long time, Senpai!
You...
I see. So you're the one
called Yamato, huh?
I get it...
Yes! As of today,
I will be known as Yamato
while I work as the substitute captain
of Team Kakashi.
Yamato, huh?
I brought him here...
because there's something
I'd really like him to know
since he'll be working as
the captain of Team Kakashi.
And that is...
the biggest reason why he was chosen
as Kakashi's replacement.
Is this about Naruto?
You know that Naruto has
the Nine-Tailed Fox
sealed inside him, right?
Yes, I do...
Sometimes the Nine-Tail's chakra
leaks out from inside Naruto's body...
and takes the form of the Fox Spirit.
We call it
the "Nine-Tail's Cloak."
The Nine-Tail's Cloak, huh...?
Does it happen often?
It happened on
our previous mission.
I see...
So it appeared just as I thought...
Judging from the shape
of the chakra,
the number of tails will
probably continue to grow...
and eventually...
there will be nine.
That's about the size of it...
Master Jiraiya,
how many tails have you seen...?
I've come close to dying twice
in my lifetime...
The first time, I broke six ribs
and both arms,
and several of
my internal organs ruptured...
It was when I was trying to peek
into the women's bath at a hot spring...
and you pounded me good, Tsunade.
The other time was...
during Naruto's training
when I saw the fourth tail
of the Nine-Tail's chakra.
His anger became the trigger...
and the number of tails
he grew increased.
He maintained consciousness up
until the third tail.
But by the fourth tail,
he had lost all rationality and was
controlled by destructive impulses.
He was just like a small version
of the Nine-Tailed Fox.
Even with the
Fourth Hokage's seal...
It can go that far?
Yes.
I don't know the details,
but I can say this for certain:
The Fourth Hokage's Sealing Jutsu
might very well...
be weakening.
There's more...
It may appear that when Naruto
is in the Nine-Tails state,
he's being protected by
the Nine-Tail's Cloak...
But in actuality, his body was
continuing to suffer damage
from the Nine Tail's Cloak itself.
After the Nine-Tail's Cloak
dissipated,
his wounded body
was healed by the Nine-Tails chakra
inside his body.
But if he continues to get hurt
and then heal at that
speed over and over...
Naruto's body will break down
and his life span will shorten.
That's why we need you...
Yamato!
You, who has inherited the cells
of the First Hokage.
Now you're the only one... who
can control the Jinchuriki Host.
Fortunately for us,
Naruto happens to be wearing
the First Hokage's necklace...
Master!
Oh...
What is it?
You should still have some time
left before you're to assemble.
I wanted to have a few words
before we leave.
I see...
So it's already going badly, huh...?
Yes...
It can't be helped...
For the time being,
you keep Naruto under control.
I'll do what I can, but...
Come in!
Who's that?
Danzo, huh...? What is it?
Did you place
a skilled ANBU Black Ops member
as the captain of Sai's unit,
Princess Tsunade?
I selected the best man I have.
He's worked since
the Third Hokage's tenure.
Very well...
But I just hope...
he hasn't been tainted by
the teachings of the Third Hokage.
Just like how the teachings
of your grandfather...
tainted the Third Hokage...
I guess I'm more or less relieved.
Now I can enjoy my meals
without worries.
Excuse me.
Who the heck...was that?
A long time ago...
he competed with
the late Sarutobi Sensei
over the position of the Third Hokage.
Unlike the Third Hokage,
he's the leader of a hard-line
military faction based on rigid logic...
and is Sai's superior.
He hates me because
I'm the granddaughter of the First Hokage
as well as a student of
the Third Hokage who was a moderate.
Umm...
Isn't it about time...?
Oh!
That's right.
Isn't it almost time, Sakura?
Yes, it is...
I'll be going now.
Okay...
Team Kakashi, will now set out.
Please don't stare at me like that...
I'll pound you.
Hey! You tick me off with
everything you say!
I don't really mean it.
You liar!
I'm just trying to portray myself
like that kind of character.
You won't do at all!
Hey! Hey! Don't act like that...
in front of your captain, Naruto.
I'm sure Kakashi taught you
that trust and teamwork
are most important to a team.
He's not a member of Team Kakashi!
The other member of
our Team Kakashi is...
Sasuke!
Well...
He betrayed the Leaf
and ran off
to serve Orochimaru...
I don't want to be lumped together
with a cockroach along the same lines...
as Orochimaru.
Y-You creep!
Sai...Naruto still doesn't know you
very well.
So he may have been out of line.
Please forgive Naruto...
Sakura...
Thank goodness I've got at least
one kid who's less objectionable.
It's okay. It doesn't bother me.
Really? Thank goodness.
You don't have to...forgive me.
So that's another way of using
a fake smile, huh...?
I'll remember that.
How can you grin like that
after getting punched?!
A smile is the best way to get
through a tough situation.
Even if it's a fake smile.
Surprisingly enough,
everyone gets fooled.
That's what it said in the book.
It seems it doesn't really work
if I do it, though.
You jerk!
Four-Pillar Prison Jutsu!
I'll really toss you guys into
this cell if you keep fighting.
We don't have much time
until we get to the Tenchi Bridge.
This is the secret jutsu that
only the First Hokage could use...
The Wood Style Ninjutsu!
How come Captain Yamato
can use the Wood Style Ninjutsu?
As your peacemaker,
I offer you this suggestion.
In order to improve your rapport,
I can toss you guys into
this cell for a full day
or we can stay at a hot spring inn
for a night.
Which would you prefer?
You guys probably don't really
know me all that well.
I prefer the kind and gentle approach,
but I'm not against controlling you
by fear either.
Sure enough, getting naked together like
this is a great way to bond, isn't it?!
Don't you think so?
Y-Yes, that's right!
His eyes are totally scary!
He's already controlling us
with fear...
Oh...So you do
have "equipment," after all.
Don't be looking!
Naruto...?
Shut up with all that talk about
my "equipment!"
For crying out loud, Naruto...
You're talking too loud!
You jerk!
It's your fault I'm being laughed at...
Aren't you glad that Sakura's pleased, too?
Sakura...?
Now then...
I'm getting out now.
Before that, let me tell you
an interesting story, Naruto.
When Master Jiraiya was young,
there was one time when he almost died.
He broke six ribs and both arms, and
several of his internal organs ruptured...
It seems Lady Tsunade beat him up
real good with her incredible strength...
This happened because
he did what you're now...
attempting to do...
I wonder what Sakura would do...
What's he doing over there...?
So you draw.
Is there something you want?
You're foul-mouthed,
but you've also got a sensitive side, huh?
That's a surprise.
That fake smile...So you're
still not through hitting me, huh?
Not quite...
I'm kidding!
I just came to check out your picture.
I was wondering what you were drawing.
I see...
At first, I thought you were drawing a
landscape since you're drawing out here...
But it's an abstract, huh?
What's the title of this drawing?
It doesn't have one.
I've drawn tens of thousands
of pictures...
but I've never given one a title.
So this doesn't have one, either...
But you're supposed to give
a title to a picture, right?
If it's a portrait,
you give it the name of the person...
Or with other pictures,
you use the situation,
your feelings or emotions at the time...
To be exact, I couldn't title
one of my drawings even if I wanted to...
Nothing comes to mind.
I don't...feel anything.
Nothing...
No wonder you can only say
such callous things!
It's about time for us to leave!
Captain Yamato told me
to come get you.
Right.
This drawing's nothing special!
You're right...
Just like your "equipment."
I'm going to be straight with you!
I can't stand you!
If you've got a problem, stop the fake
smiles and tell me straight to my face!
I'll take you on anytime
you want to fight!
I've got...
no problem with you.
I don't care about you at all.
Please go on ahead.
I'll catch up once I've tidied up.
I'll help.
This...isn't printed.
Did you draw this, too?
Yes.
Wow, it's a picture book, huh?
That looks cool.
Oh! Say...
can I take a look
at it along the way?
I can't let you see it.
It's not finished yet...
This is my older brother's book, so...
I guess this spot is okay.
Wood Style: Four Pillar House Jutsu
We'll camp out here tonight.
I don't think you can call something
like this camping out.
Gather around, everyone.
And I want to ask
you something, Sakura.
What is it?
It's about the Akatsuki's Sasori.
For the time being, I've received a
file on Sasori from the Hidden Sand...
But tell me in as much detail
as you can
about his personality, behavior,
mannerisms and habits if he has any.
What's this about?
The spy who's infiltrated
Orochimaru's organization thinks
Sasori is going to meet him
at the Tenchi Bridge.
They might see us through immediately,
but it's probably best to approach
by transforming into Sasori.
Being a spy is a very risky act, after all.
Which means the spy is probably
being quite cautious.
Then are you going to transform
into Sasori, Captain Yamato?
I'll probably have to.
Also, assuming this turns out
to be an Akatsuki trap...
I'll approach him alone at first.
You guys stand by until
I give you instructions.
The way he talked being near death...
I don't think he was lying...
And there was indeed a spy
called Yura in the Sand Village...
Either way, there's no doubting...
that spy is probably
considerably powerful.
Let's do this!
Let me explain the mission in
a little more detail.
Our goal is just to arrest the target.
We must not let him die,
even if we end up having to fight.
We'll lose an important source of
information if the target is killed.
And a mission like this is more difficult
than just killing an enemy.
As this is a delicate mission,
I will make the first move.
And you guys will be my back-up...
The strategy is simple.
First, I restrain the target.
Second, if I should fail
to restrain the target
and this turns into a battle,
you guys shift to battle formation.
I will give you a signal when
I want you to do this.
And in the event of the second case,
you are to operate with
the Buddy System.
First, Sakura and I will be one team!
And...
the other team will be...
Naruto and Sai!
Looking forward to it
There's that fake smile again.
Damn it!
Captain Yamato.
What is it, Naruto?
Why...Why do I have to team up
with him?
Is there a problem?
U-Understood.
Good.
I think Naruto and I would
make a better team.
We've been working together
for a while
and we know each other quite well, so.
You're the only medical ninja
on this team.
We can't let you get hurt,
and that is why you'll be with me.
As Sai said earlier,
we can assume the enemy
will be very skilled...
A mistake in teamwork
could prove fatal.
tomorrow we'll devote half a day
to a team-play simulation.
A simulation?
That's right.
All I know about you guys is
what I've read in your files.
I want to get an idea
of your fighting styles, battle skills
and jutsu types...
with my own eyes.
Damn it!
Come at me for real!
Not nearly good enough.
Ninja Art: Super Beast Scroll
No way am I letting go!
Wha--?!
Why are you grabbing me, too?!
Hey, Sai! Do something about this!
That way, huh?
H-Hey! Where are you going, Sai?!
I've already captured Captain Yamato,
so hurry up and untie me!
Huh?
Damn it! Hey, Sai!
Hurry up and untie this snake!
You did well to capture me, Sai.
You jerk!
What is it?
Don't you know what
the word "comrade" is?
Of course I do...
What of it?
That's not what I'm trying to say.
H-Hey, Naruto.
Please don't blame your lack of
individual competence on others.
What did you say?!
If you hadn't let the Captain get
a rise out of you...
I could've remained hidden
without being exposed.
And it wouldn't have been
this much trouble
to capture the Captain.
What do you mean?
Even if you go to the trouble
of transforming into me...
you'll be exposed as
a Shadow Clone immediately
if you use one of your jutsu.
Because of that,
the Captain saw through our strategy
and escaped into the forest
using a Substitution.
Then why didn't you break
the jutsu right away
if you knew it was a Substitution?
It isn't ideal to fight
while protecting someone who
has lost his cool.
All I did was consider the best way
to successfully complete the mission,
make a judgment and take action.
I won't acknowledge you.
I'll never acknowledge
the likes of you
as a comrade or as a member
of Team Kakashi!
I guess these two just won't work
as a team, huh?
I wonder what Sasuke would've done.
Would he have fought
while protecting you?
He's a Team Kakashi
comrade to you, right?
If you call someone who betrayed
his village and hurt you...
a comrade, that is.
If it's to save that comrade,
then I'll do whatever it takes.
I'll even team up with you.
Why does he feel so strongly
about Sasuke?
It's because Naruto...
thinks of Sasuke like a brother.
You've got a brother, too,
don't you...?
You should understand
a little about how he feels.
No, not at all.
I told you about titles for
my drawings, right?
I have no such thing as emotions.
What do you mean...
you don't feel anything
or have any emotions...?
I mean just what I said.
Even so, if you have a brother,
you should be able to imagine
what it would be like to lose him, right?
Hm...? Yeah, well...
you could say that.
My brother's dead, after all.
Then all the more...
I wonder if I should've looked like that.
This guy...
That's enough talking.
We're moving out pretty soon,
so gather your things.
Sakura, in regards to Naruto...
Yeah, I guess I'd say you're nice to him.
I once read something
like this in a book.
I don't know why such feelings arise.
Guys.
Let's get a move on.
This will all come to nothing
if we don't get there
by tomorrow afternoon.
Here he comes.
Captain Yamato...
I hope you do okay...
It's been a long time, Lord Sasori.
It's been five years, hasn't it?
Kabuto Yakushi...
Were you followed...?
We're okay...
How're you doing?
I've still got the strange sensation...
from when I remembered who I was
after your jutsu broke...
I still feel heavy-headed...
Him again...?!
Who would've thought...
the Akatsuki spy was Kabuto.
I've got some questions for you.
I don't have much time,
so please keep it short.
I risked my life to get here
without Orochimaru finding out.
I want information about
the location of his hideout
and Sasuke.
There are several hideouts.
We move to
a different hideout each week
so as not to get discovered.
Of course there are hideouts,
not just in the Village Hidden
in the Sound, but in other lands as well.
Spies for Orochimaru infiltrate
and act as informers.
But there are all sorts of
means of transport,
so they're not easily tracked...
Where is it now?
We're now in a hideout on a
small island on a lake to the north.
We'll be moving again in three days.
Sasuke Uchiha is there as well.
The sound of the wind is so loud
I can't hear anything.
You idiot! That's why we were
able to get this close.
The wind blows away the noise and
smell, so we can sit here unnoticed.
By the way...
Oh...it's just a wild rabbit.
About what you ordered me to do,
Lord Sasori...
Uh oh...
I still had a few more things
I wanted to ask him
while I had the chance, but...
I'll be discovered if the conversation
continues any further...
Even after his reincarnation,
Orochimaru uses a jutsu
to apply a protector
to the cellular specimens
from his discarded body...
And therefore I was unable
to analyze the cellular data.
I see...
What's he doing?!
He should just grab him!
His opponent is Kabuto.
Being overly cautious is just fine.
It's all over if he gets away, right?
Now, please hand over
the item in question immediately.
I can't be hanging around here
any longer.
If it's discovered that I'm here
with you like this...
I'll be killed.
Okay...
I can't hold out any longer...
I just have to capture him
here and now!
That conversation sounds interesting.
Would you guys let me
join in as well?
If you hadn't pulled out
a kunai knife,
I wouldn't have been able
to get away before I noticed.
It looks like he's
misunderstood nicely...
I guess I still haven't been
discovered for now...
But...now that Orochimaru
has shown up...
What should I do?
That outfit...sure takes me back...
Sasori...
Did you follow Kabuto?
Oh...I just thought I'd thank you.
This kid you sent to me...
has come in very handy.
The number of human subjects
necessary for the development
of one new jutsu is over a hundred...
Thanks to this kid's medical ninjutsu,
I've been able to reuse
test subjects several times.
There's been a great shortage
of them, you see...
What do we do?!
We just have to stand by until
the Captain gives us instructions.
It would probably be
impossible for me
to take on Orochimaru alone...
But even if I can stop Orochimaru
by working together with Kabuto...
he'll find out immediately that
I'm not Sasori by my fighting style...
Even so, if I call those three...
then Kabuto will find out
who I am
and it will become difficult
to capture him...
Either I have to immediately call
the three and defeat both of them...
or retreat as is without calling them...
I'll have to do one or the other...
Have I been discovered?
No...that's not it...
What's the meaning of this?!
Multiple Striking Shadow Snake!
This is a Substitution created
with the Wood Style ninjutsu...
You...could it be...?
Lord Orochimaru.
Is this Sasori's real body?
No...It isn't...
Kabuto...you didn't know
his real face
even though you were
his subordinate?
He was a broody guy
who always stayed hidden
inside his puppets, after all...
What's the meaning of this...?!
Kabuto...you were supposed
to be an Akatsuki spy...
Weren't you caught in one
of Sasori's jutsu all this time?!
Lord Orochimaru...broke that jutsu
for me ages ago...
I can't believe you went
to the other side
pretending to be caught
in one of Sasori's jutsu...
Did you get caught in one
of Orochimaru's jutsu...?
No...that's not it.
I just empathize with
Lord Orochimaru's ideas.
By the way, who are you?
The plan was to take
care of Sasori.
But something has gone
quite wrong.
Kabuto...I'll tell you
about this kid later...
More importantly...
Why don't you call the three
little mice behind you over here?
So he's seen through
everything, huh...?
There's the signal!
You again, huh...?
I've seen that face often...
And it looks like
the Nine-Tails kid's here, too...
Maybe I'll play with you guys a little.
Let's see who's gotten stronger,
you...or Sasuke.
Give Sasuke...
back...!
"Give him back" is not the correct
way of saying it, Naruto...
Your reasoning is off...
Sasuke came to us
because he wanted to.
For a man, you're too obsessed...
about the past.
You need to resign yourself.
Shut up, four-eyes!
You don't even know
how Naruto feels...
Stop acting so cold
about everything!
If you want to know about Sasuke,
try forcing it out of me...
If you can, that is...
What is that?
Naruto...you've grown considerably
as a Jinchuriki Host.
The power of the Nine-Tails
is rapidly getting stronger...
You're starting to become more like
a Jinchuriki Host, aren't you...
Naruto?
So that's why you were chosen to
keep watch over him, huh?
So my experiment turned out
to be somewhat useful...
The Leaf should be thanking me
a little more for this...
Don't you agree...
my adorable little test subject...?
I thought all the test
subjects had died...
but I never thought one of them
would still be alive.
I see...
So it looks like we'll now
be able to obtain
a sample from a product
of old research.
More important than that...
I'd like to test out how strong
my Sasuke has become...
by having him
fight against Naruto.
He doesn't...
He doesn't belong to you...!
Don't talk about Sasuke...
in front of me...
like he belongs to you!
That's...
What's...that chakra?!
The air stings...
Interesting...
With chakra alone...
With chakra alone,
he caused this much damage...
Finally, the top-secret mission starts.
Sakura! Answer me!
Did she hit her head
when she fell just now?
Passing out
at a time like this...!
Wood Style Ninjutsu!
I can't support it...!
Ninja Art: Super Beast Scroll!
Sai!
Sai! Help Sakura...
Damn!
I see...
You borrow
the power of the Jinchuriki...
And yet, that's
the best you can do...
You're still no match for Sasuke...
Sasuke...?
Sasuke!
Wait...
Wait for me...!
This feeling...it's different
from before, isn't it...?
Are you all right?
Y-Yes...
Hey...!
Sorry...
I'm okay now...
What happened here...?
Naruto did it...
Where's Naruto now?!
On the other side of the bridge...
with Orochimaru.
The Jinchuriki...
It only stands to reason
that they'd want it too...
Naruto is a real handful...
What's that smoke...?
I have a bad feeling about this...
Wood Clone Jutsu!
I'm counting on you!
Right.
Wood Style: Doomed Wall!
Simply unbelievable,
the things this child can do...
Oh shoot...
Such incredible shockwaves...
Just from a swing of his arm, geez!
At this rate, there's no way
I can move closer...
What's this...?
That looks like trouble.
Anyone who has chakra
that high in density...
will most certainly die.
With that much high-density chakra
making it difficult...
for him to even move...
I wonder how he plans
to do battle with me...
So that's his move!
Triple Rashomon!
What an incredible battle!
Trying to find
an opening and fight...
It doesn't even seem like an option!
Naruto is over here...
That thing is not human...
Sai, what are you doing?
Got it.
Continue to observe.
Sakura!
That's...Naruto...
I can't pierce through...
even with my snake sword...
This is what Master Jiraiya
was referring to when he said...
he's "like a small Nine-Tailed Beast."
It's useless to go on fighting
with the snake sword...
Wait! Sakura!
Naruto!
That's...that's enough!
I will save Sasuke, no matter what!
That's why...
Naruto, it's enough...!
Damn!
I didn't make it in time...
Naruto...
Now's the only chance...!
Hokage Style: Elder Jutsu
10th Edict on Enlightenment!
Naruto...
What is he trying to do?
Now is my chance...
Looks like it's about time...
As expected,
this body is rejecting me.
Too bad, but the fun ends here.
Patience...Patience now...
I have Sasuke with me...
I am Danzo's man.
I am not your enemy...
I have something
to speak to you about.
Danzo...that doddering old fool
is still alive, huh?
So...
What do you want to talk about?
I have a message from Danzo
to Lord Orochimaru.
The truth is...
Before that...
Choose your words carefully
when you talk to me.
If not, you'll die.
I can only relay
what Danzo has told me.
If that does not satisfy you,
then I'll leave it up to you...
You really don't have
any manners do you, child?
When you address someone
who's higher-ranking than you...
it's common courtesy
to show your face.
All right...I'll listen to you.
His wounds are slow to heal...
Up to now,
Naruto has always been a fast healer
thanks to the Nine-Tail's chakra...
The fourth tail that Jiraiya
was talking about...
I wouldn't have imagined that
it would be as powerful as this...
Captain Yamato...
That jutsu that stopped Naruto
earlier on...
Would you teach me that jutsu...?
That's not possible...
The only person in the Leaf Village
who can use that jutsu is me,
since I inherited the First Hokage's cells.
What that jutsu does is
forcibly suppress the Nine-Tail's chakra...
It's impossible for someone
without that special power to use it.
My power, which is just
an experimental copy,
is certainly not on the same level as
the First Hokage's original.
What Naruto has hanging around
his neck is something
that belonged to the First Hokage...
It's a chakra crystal that
only resonates
to the First Hokage's chakra.
With that necklace,
one can control a Jinchuriki's chakra.
It is said that this power is
the very reason
that the First Hokage
became the Hokage.
And it's also the reason that I was
chosen to be the Captain of this team...
It's always like this...
All I can ever do for Naruto...
are the smallest things.
It's not important whether
the things you do are large or small.
What's important...
is the magnitude of the feelings
you have for Naruto.
Sakura...I can tell that when
I look at you.
You truly...
S-Sakura...
Owww!
Naruto...!
What happened to me...?
I was chasing that jerk Orochimaru...
and then...
And then, what did I do after that?
Hey, Sakura...
Huh?
Why are you crying, Sakura?
I just got something in my eyes...
That acid-tongued Sai said something
abusive to you again, right?
Like, "You're ugly!"
Or, "You're Herculean!"
That jerk!
Sai hasn't called me Herculean...!
R-Really?
Don't make up stuff...
You jerk!
By the way...
Captain Yamato...
Where's Sai?
That's everything that Danzo
asked me to convey.
That's extremely interesting...
Why should I believe it?
What's going on here?
Just calm down...Kabuto.
That child is going to be one of
our subordinates starting today.
Can you trust...this guy...?
Look inside that envelope.
It's for you, from Danzo.
This is...
What does it say?
Kabuto, let go of that child
We're taking that child along with us.
Sai...was it?
Shall we go then...?
Just as I thought...
The bridge...
I did plant one on him back at
the hot springs, just in case...
Oh well. I'll continue
the pursuit as is.
I might not look it,
but pursuit is actually one of
my strong points.
Captain Yamato...
Oh yeah...
Right now, Sai is...
traveling together with Orochimaru.
Together with...?
What does that mean?
Both of you follow me.
The earth is still soft.
The bridge is busted...
and this place is in
such an awful state...
What the heck...happened?
Don't you remember?
So it's just as
Master Jiraiya said, huh...?
Come to think of it...
why was I unconscious?
You were unconscious because
you got creamed by Orochimaru.
Are you serious?!
Damn!
Sai's things are scattered
all over the place...
But why is this here...?
If he had to leave something
so valuable behind,
it demonstrates that he was in
a tense state in front of Orochimaru.
You seem to know that as if
you witnessed it yourself.
Until earlier on...
I placed my Wood Clone here, and
was in communication with it,
using the wireless radio
implanted here.
What happened to Sai?
After Sai's...conversation
with Orochimaru,
he went away with Orochimaru
and Kabuto.
What does that mean?!
What did they talk about?
They were talking a distance away...
so I couldn't make out
the conversation.
I wonder what
they were talking about?
He might have been kidnapped
and taken away.
No, it seems that he approached
Orochimaru of his own volition...
and handed him something.
It was just like he was trying
to cozy up to Orochimaru...
W-Wait a minute!
Even a disgusting guy like him
wouldn't betray us, would he?
No, there is a possibility...
Captain Yamato, do you know
a person named Danzo...?
Yes, I know him.
Who is...that guy?
A man from the Hawk Faction who
in the past opposed the Third Hokage.
He's Sai's boss...
And an old gramps who doesn't
think well of the Third Hokage's will.
Danzo may be using Sai to make
some kind of move.
It's possible that...
Sai may have been given
a mission...
by Danzo that is separate from ours...
There is a possibility that
he was charged...
with some kind
of top-secret mission...
So he's just using our mission...
in order to make contact
with Orochimaru?!
That's the gist of it.
This may sound like
an over-the-top theory...
but it is not outside the realm
of possibility...so listen carefully.
Danzo...
may be trying to destroy
the Hidden Leaf Village!