The Eight-Tails, huh?
It seems Sasuke was successful.
Pain will bring the Nine-Tails.
Not only Yugito,
but now Bee too...
I cannot believe that Bee
has been taken down!
We have been receiving several
messenger lizards from Jay.
Once we've pinpointed
the enemy's whereabouts,
we'll send in four cells to
rescue Lord Killer Bee,
and wipe out the enemy.
I heard it was an Uchiha from the Hidden
Leaf who kidnapped my little brother!
Why is there an Uchiha
in the Akatsuki?!
Sasuke Uchiha...
It appears he went rogue from the
Hidden Leaf quite some time ago.
Why hasn't the Leaf's Hokage dealt
with this rogue ninja?!
They were so quick to react
over the Hyuga incident!
You are so useless!
Why'd you leave behind
my Executioner's Blade?!
Shut up, Suigetsu!
Just be thankful
we didn't leave you behind!
Look who's talking!
You were also passed out, Karin!
I got knocked out trying
to protect you guys!
It's the result of us trying
to protect each other.
We're like fish and water, so close
we can't do without one another.
So quit quarreling.
Fine.
By the way, are we really
going to get
the Tailed Beast's power, Sasuke?
Hmph. Who knows?
But it seems there's no need
to rely on that anymore.
What's wrong, Sasuke?
It's nothing.
I sense a chakra outside.
It seems we've been tailed.
Now, go!
Forgive me, Lord Raikage...
It appears my tail was unsuccessful.
What?!
What do you mean the messages
from Jay have ceased?!
It seems Jay has either
been killed or captured.
So we're unable to confirm
the enemy's location.
Use whatever information we have
to narrow down the location,
and search every inch
of the place!
I don't care if you have
to dispatch a battalion!
Y-Yes sir.
Summon Samui's platoon too!
I'm giving them a document of
intent to deliver to the Hidden Leaf
stating that we will take care
of Sasuke Uchiha!
And have them give us
intel on him!
Yes, right away!
Furthermore, I'm going to convene
a Five Kage Summit Conference
with the Five Great Nations!
The Akatsuki will not be forgiven!
Jay...
We were too late.
Omoi, Karui...
Lord Raikage has summoned us.
Summoned, eh?
What in the world could it be?
Maybe there's a crisis...
Or maybe...We're getting scolded?
Did he find out that my body fat
percentage has spiked?
Maybe eating potatoes with
mayonnaise wasn't a good idea?
Omoi, you always think too much!
Why would he scold you
for something like that?!
The most that would happen is you
could get sent to buy some protein.
Being around you guys
is so tiring.
Makes my shoulders ache.
The stiff shoulders are probably
caused by those big breasts of yours,
although one can't say for sure.
What you thought was just
a stiff shoulder could actually...
Will you shut up!
Quit yakking and let's go!
You ought to think things
through more carefully.
A flat-chested person like you
may not get stiff shoulders, Karui, but...
Shut up!
Oww! Now that kick will cause...
You got more to say?!
You two...
If you're ninja, act cooler.
Let's go!
Mission acknowledged.
I'm counting on you!
I knew it...
I had a bad feeling about this.
Damn!
Don't worry!
No way Lord Killer Bee would
screw up like that.
It's probably some bad joke.
How can you be optimistic?!
He could be suffering right
this moment!
In fact, he could already...
Shut up! I don't want to hear
your pessimistic thoughts!
He's our master!
We're talking about
Lord Killer Bee here!
There's no way he'd be defeated!
Aren't you worried about Lord Bee, Karui?
Don't get morbid ideas just
because you're worried!
Enough, you two!
We'll save Bee,
no matter what it takes!
We will save him!
- Lord Raikage!
Oh, it's you, Kakashi Sensei.
Lady Hokage has summoned you.
Let's go.
Huh? Chief Toad and Gamakichi?
Yo, Naruto!
What're you guys doing here
so early?
Did something happen?
Actually...
Gamakichi! It's not your place
to say anything.
Leave this to the Boss and Tsunade.
What's going on?
Just hurry up.
He is Jiraiya-boy's student?
Yes...This is Naruto Uzumaki...
The "Child of Prophecy"
you mentioned.
A geezer frog? What the hell?
Hey! Watch your mouth, Naruto!
This is Lord Fukasaku, one of the
Two Great Sages of Mount Myoboku.
He came all the way here
to speak with you.
Well, to be more accurate,
I am a Great Sage Toad.
But never mind that.
You are, without a doubt,
Jiraiya-boy's student.
Jiraiya-boy? "Boy"?!
You talk as though
the Pervy Sage is a kid!
Who does this geezer frog
think he is?!
I said to watch your mouth!
This great man is the one who
taught Sage Jutsu to Lord Jiraiya.
He is Lord Jiraiya's master.
Pervy Sage, eh?
What a fitting nickname
for Jiraiya-boy.
So what does this geezer sage
want with me?
I'm not sure where to begin.
But let's see...
I suppose
the most important thing is...
Jiraiya-boy has died in battle.
Huh?
Wh-What are you talking about?
I know this is sudden.
I don't blame you if
you don't believe me.
For quite some time,
there were rumors
that the leader of the Akatsuki
was in the Hidden Rain Village.
Jiraiya-boy went in person to
verify the truth of these rumors.
The leader of the Akatsuki was
in the Hidden Rain Village?
As I recall,
that village is difficult to infiltrate.
A village closed to the outside world.
Yes...However, Lord Jiraiya was skilled
in infiltration and
espionage tactics.
Exactly...
However...
To corner a ninja like Lord Jiraiya...
How did this Pain...?
He possessed the Rinnegan.
What did you say?!
Rinnegan?
The Rinnegan is an Ocular Jutsu
that was said to be possessed by the father
of all ninja, the Sage of the Six Paths.
I thought it was just a legend.
Not only that...
There were six of them
who possessed the Rinnegan?!
How can that even be possible?
Most likely, only Jiraiya-boy,
who was there,
discovered their secret.
But...
Jiraiya-boy!
Even after he had his throat
crushed by Pain,
Jiraiya-boy left a message
before collapsing.
This is that message!
It's a code...
I'm sure he did this to prevent
Pain from noticing.
I've told you everything
about Jiraiya-boy.
Did you...let him go, Granny?
That's right.
Why'd you allow such
a reckless thing?!
You knew Pervy Sage better
than anyone!
How could you send him to such
a dangerous place, alone?!
Enough, Naruto.
You of all people ought to
know Lady Hokage's feelings.
Naruto! Where are you going?!
If Pervy Sage had been
the Fifth Hokage...
he wouldn't have let Granny Tsunade
take such risks...
Never!
Naruto!
Sakura...It's all right.
Let him be.
But...
I can see that child truly loved
and admired Jiraiya-boy.
I can't help but hope that
he is the Child of Prophecy.
Anyway, the clues left by Jiraiya-boy...
There is something besides
the hidden message on my back.
A Hidden Rain ninja captured by
Jiraiya-boy is inside his belly.
And, one more thing...
Inside this fellow is one of Pain's bodies
that Jiraiya managed to kill.
Pain's?
This is Pain...
The ripple pattern...
Is it the legendary Rinnegan?
That's correct. If we study it well, we
may find clues on how to defeat him.
A ninja's corpse is
a treasure trove of information.
We will gather skilled medical ninja,
and begin an autopsy immediately.
Shizune.
Yes, ma'am. I will take care of it.
Hmm...That is a good photo.
I have given you all that
was entrusted to me.
Yes, indeed.
I will return home now.
Let me know what you learn.
With Jiraiya-boy's student here,
you will be able to
contact Mount Myoboku.
Thank you very much.
I promise that we will find
a way to defeat Pain!
Now listen, Naruto.
I have only three years to
make you strong.
I will spend that time
training you vigorously.
Be prepared for that.
You bet! This time, I'm going to
bring him back for sure!
There's no time for me to waste.
Cripes...I can't stand this...
What is this?!
What's with this lame training?!
Fool! Nothing in training is lame!
You foolish student!
You're mine!
You're not the only one
who uses Shadow Clones.
You're still so naïve...
Damn! I was so close!
Liar. It'll take a hundred years
before you can beat me.
I can't wait a hundred years!
Just wait...Next time...
This is super-cool!
Hmm...Fine feathers make
a fine bird, eh?
Yo! Naruto.
I hear you've been real active
on missions and such.
Everyone in the village
is talking about you.
Hey, let's go somewhere and catch up!
How about Ichiraku for some ramen?
No thanks...
What? Right now?
Yes. Take that,
and go immediately.
The Cipher Corps folks
don't work this late.
Summon them and tell them
it's on my orders.
I'm putting you in charge of this case.
I know it's a very important encryption,
but can't you ask someone else
who's not on a mission right now?
Wait...Where are you going?
I came here on a different matter.
Shikamaru!
But...
Lady Tsunade has been busy
since morning, and...
I must say...
You've grown even more beautiful.
You haven't changed...
But...If you try anything to
betray the village...
At that moment, I will kill you.
Then how about making a bet with me?
You bet that I will die.
After all, you always lose.
But if I make it back alive...
Joking! I'm just joking!
You know, I'm grateful to you.
Heya...I'm Jiraiya!
You can send me the love letters later!
Nice to meet ya!
You fool...
Naruto...
I heard about Lord Jiraiya.
I wanted him to keep watching
over me.
I wanted him to see me
become the Hokage.
But I only ended up showing Pervy Sage
the worst, most un-cool side of me.
I was...
Lord Jiraiya only had praise for you.
He was always boasting about you,
saying you were like
his own grandchild.
He had faith that you were
the one who would inherit his will.
And truly believed that you would
one day become a great Hokage.
Lord Jiraiya will always
watch over you.
Even this very minute,
he's watching from somewhere.
He wouldn't be happy
seeing you sad like this. So...
Be your usual self,
the one he praised so much.
Don't stay depressed forever.
For Lord Jiraiya himself,
one of the Legendary Sannin...
acknowledged you as
his promising student!
Thanks...Iruka Sensei.
Thank you for your efforts.
How's it going?
Oh...
I checked very carefully...
But this isn't a Hidden Leaf code.
It doesn't correspond to any
of our algorithms.
But considering the fact that Lord
Jiraiya wrote this in his dying moments,
I don't think it could be
anything too complex.
It's a string of numbers, so it
has to be a shared-key encryption.
Can you...decode it?
Ahem.
Err...Frankly, it's impossible
unless we know the key.
Key?
Namely, if you don't know the rules
that define the code, you can't break it.
Unless we know something about Lord Jiraiya
that could be the key, it's impossible.
So how do we figure out what the key is?
I wouldn't know...
But perhaps someone who
was close to Lord Jiraiya
would recognize the key.
Although, given the circumstances
of his death,
the encryption could have
been hastily created
to prevent the enemy from
discerning his message.
So we can't say for certain.
Consider who he may have
intended that message for,
and ask that person.
And perhaps you'll find some clues.
Which means...
Lady Hokage or Kakashi Sensei...
Thank you very much.
If I learn anything new,
I'll come again.
Sure, but I'll be home in bed,
so just come by the house, ok?
Well...I'm heading home to sleep.
What about you, Shiho?
Someone's gotta stay behind.
This frog supposedly contains
a captured Hidden Rain ninja.
We received prior notice
from Lord Jiraiya.
Now, grow.
Be as rough as you need to be.
Get everything you can from him!
I intend to.
This is one of the three crucial sources
of data Lord Jiraiya left us.
We must learn everything
we can from it.
- Yes, Ma'am!
All right. Let's begin.
9...31...8...106...7...207...15...
Can you think of anything?
Maybe in a conversation
with Lord Jiraiya?
Something about these numbers...?
This number 106 is...
Lord Jiraiya?
It's 106.
What is?
106 centimeters.
No...That's not it.
I can't think of anything.
Why don't you try
Lady Hokage or Naruto next?
I already asked Lady Hokage.
Which leaves Naruto...
The secret code is a concern.
But I'm also worried about Naruto.
Try to cheer him up.
Don't get your hopes up too high.
Shoot...He's out.
Shikamaru...What do you want?
For starters...Can I come in?
Well? Can you think of anything?
Hey Naruto, I said can you think
of anything?
Naruto!
Oh sorry. What was it again?
Come with me.
Where?
Just come.
Wh-What is it?!
Why'd you bring me here?
Just wait.
Ah! Here she comes.
Huh?! Kurenai Sensei...
Yeah...
Were you hospitalized for
eating too much barbeque?!
Your stomach's bigger than Choji's!
She's pregnant, not fat!
Cripes, you're still
as obnoxious as ever.
Huh?!
You mean...she's...?
Shikamaru, stop coming here so often.
Sorry, no can do.
Asuma asked me to do so.
Shikamaru...What did Asuma
ask you to do?
That child will be my student.
Huh?
Asuma entrusted that child to me.
I heard about Lord Jiraiya.
I lost my teacher,
so it's not like I don't understand
what you're going through.
But whining and sulking isn't going
to make things better.
We're way past that point in our lives.
What do you mean?
My teacher entrusted me
with many things.
Some important, some petty.
All sorts of things.
You too, right?
In fact, you must have a ton of stuff.
So don't you think it's about time
for us to step up?
Time for what?
Time for us to become
the ones who entrust.
It's a pain,
but we can't keep complaining.
You will eventually be
the one treating to ramen,
and you'll be called Naruto Sensei,
or something.
We can't stay brats forever...
If we wanna become super cool ninja
like Asuma and Lord Jiraiya, that is.
You're right.
Thanks, Shikamaru.
Pull yourself together.
You got work to do.
Right!
You haven't said a word.
You see something, right?
I talked to Lady Hokage
and Kakashi Sensei,
but neither of them had any clue.
That means Lord Jiraiya probably
left this message with you in mind.
No, I'm positive he did.
There's got to be something there.
If anything pops up in your mind,
tell us.
We're not asking you to
instantly decode the message.
There is one thing that's been
bothering me since I first saw this.
What is it?
Well...
There's all these numbers.
So what's with this
one katakana letter?
Huh?
Katakana?
Where do you see that?
Right here.
What are you talking about?
Isn't that the number "9"?
That's what I thought at first...
But this is not the number "9."
It's the katakana letter "ta."
Well, I guess you could
look at it that way.
But I think that's a big stretch.
I wonder...
Uzumaki, what made you think
this nine was the katakana letter "ta"?
He was an author, after all.
And I traveled all over with him.
He always made me read
his handwritten drafts,
and asked what I thought about them.
They were really boring though...
What the heck?
What's "Nine-ctics"?
And whenever there was
the letter "ta," it was hard to read
because it would look
like the number nine.
I see...A penmanship quirk!
That was his habit, huh?
So what you're saying is...
When writing the katakana "ta,"
Lord Jiraiya had a habit of
shortening his first stroke.
So the first and third strokes
get connected.
And since he rounds
his second stroke,
it looks like the number nine.
Frankly, this was the common link
between Lord Jiraiya and Naruto.
Why didn't you mention such
an important thing sooner?!
Well, what's the big deal about
knowing that it's the letter "ta"?
The code refers to that
book you were reading!
That's it, Shikamaru!
Right! Frankly, Lord Jiraiya's book
must contain a hint.
Those numbers must represent character
numbers, line numbers or page numbers.
I'm certain they hold the key
to the code.
Naruto, which book is it?
Umm...Hmm...Make-Out...
What was it?
Well then, how many of
Lord Jiraiya's books have been published?
I'm not sure...Four? Five?
Then let's just check all of them!
It's probably this one.
Make-Out Tactics...
- "Ta"?!
Kakashi Sensei!
It's been on my mind, so I decided to
stop by when I overheard your voices.
I think I caught most of it.
This is the book you're looking for.
"Make-Out Tactics."
That's right.
That's the one Pervy Sage was
working on during our training.
I see...Only Naruto would've known that.
So Lord Jiraiya did pass
the key on to Naruto.
Uh-huh!
This "ta" is the first character
in the code.
Of Lord Jiraiya's books, this is
the only title that begins with "ta."
When a character is used
in a code,
it could signify word placement
or line number,
but the established protocol is
to check the page number first.
So...the numbers separated
by commas
are 31, 8, 106, 7, 207, and 15.
Six sets.
Meaning there are six pages
worth of information.
Let's start with page 31.
Flip to that page, please.
Page 31...
Okay, here it is.
Where do we look next?
In situations like this, we look
at the first character on the page.
Please read the sentence out loud
starting from the top.
Wha-?
No...I mean...
What is it?! Hurry up and read!
Hurry it up!
"I-I-I...really...
love you."
There! We now have all six pages.
Well?
If I read the first characters
of the code in order...
The-Real-One's-Not-Among-Them...
That's what it says.
What does that mean?
I don't know.
We ought to relay this
to Lord Fukasaku.
He fought with Pain,
so he may know something.
Then let's go right away to the Lady
Hokage to ask this Lord Fukasaku to come.
May I come along?
Yeah, please do, Shiho.
Yes, sir!
All right! Let's go let Granny know!
"The-Real-One's-Not-Among-Them."
Well, Geezer Sage?! Anything?
Of those six, not a single one
reminds me of Nagato.
Yet a completely unrelated Pain
knew of a conversation
that the Rinnegan-bearing Nagato
and I shared alone.
The faces are different,
but I definitely sense Nagato in them.
I don't know...
This alone is too vague.
But there's something?
I've already told you
what I know about Pain.
Even if he dies,
he can resurrect himself.
So I can't say just from speculations.
Under such conditions,
taking Pain on is too dangerous.
We must uncover all his secrets first.
What about the other sources
of information?
How are the autopsy and
interrogation coming along?
It looks like they will take
more time.
Like how long?
I can't say.
Oh, come on!
We can't be wasting time right now!
Interrogation aside,
an autopsy requires minute cell
and tissue analyses!
These things take time!
It'll be a week at the soonest.
That long...?
Now, Uzumaki...
Don't be so disappointed.
So what should we do, Lady Hokage?
Shizune is heading up the autopsy...
It should be quicker than usual.
Still, we have no choice but to wait.
I'll go and make them speed it up.
Naruto! You get in Master Shizune's
way, and I'll give you a beating!
I will avenge Pervy Sage!
I can't just sit around doing nothing!
But Naruto-boy...
Even if we decoded the message,
it has nothing to do with you.
Just what do you mean by that?!
In any case, at this point,
you couldn't beat Pain.
What?!
Tell me. Even Jiraiya-boy
couldn't beat this opponent.
Are you saying you're confident
you can?
Well...
Being asked to come was
quite opportune.
I was planning on coming
to get you, Naruto-boy.
I am just as mortified...
I, too, want to avenge the death
of my student Jiraiya-boy.
I believe that the only one who
can do that is you, Naruto-boy.
Me...?
You want to avenge Jiraiya-boy,
don't you?
Of course I do!
Then come with me.
I'll train you in Sage Jutsu
at Mount Myoboku.
Everything that I drove
into Jiraiya-boy,
I will do the same with you.
Will it let me win against Pain?!
That I can't guarantee.
It all depends on you, Naruto-boy.
Is that fine with you, Tsunade?
Of course...
Naruto, go.
Sage Jutsu training is more rigorous
than you can ever imagine.
Are you up to it?
Pervy Sage did it, right?
Then I can't lose to him! I'll do it!
An entrusted student...
The Child of Prophecy.
Nicely said!
Then, let us go.
Naruto-boy, say your goodbyes.
I'm off.
I'm counting on you with
the code, Shikamaru.
Don't worry about us.
I will contact you the moment the results
of the autopsy and interrogation are in.
I will leave
the messenger frog behind.
If there's anything,
give it to him.
Yes sir.
Good luck, Naruto!
Right!
All right! Let's go!
By the way,
which way is Mount Myoboku?
Can we really trust this guy?
It takes a month to
get there on foot.
It's also known as
Maze Mountain.
If you don't know the secret route,
you won't be able to get there.
It's hard just to get there, eh?
Naruto-boy...
You already signed
a binding contract with us toads.
There's no need to worry.
Hey! That's the...
Well then, I'll be borrowing this boy.
Please take care of him.
But what do you mean,
there's no need to worry?
He disappeared?
It's a Reverse Summoning.
Wow...
Good luck on your end too.
All right!
Let's concentrate on figuring
out the data Jiraiya left us.
Roger.
Where...are we?
Geezer Sage...
What is this place?
The Land of Toad.
The Land of Toad?
Naruto!
Gamakichi!
I summoned you here, Naruto.
I see...Is that how?
Before we train, we must eat.
Come along.
Food?!
Now, eat up! I went all out
to prepare this meal!
Now, now...Don't be shy.
Try these caterpillars.
Th-Thank you...
Now let's begin your training.
Yes sir!
First of all, I must explain that
what I'm about to teach you
is not ninjutsu, but Sage Jutsu.
Explain?
Listen well...
As opposed to ninjutsu, where
you utilize your own internal energy,
Sage Jutsu involves taking in
outside energy for your use.
Outside? What do you mean?
As you're probably aware,
ninjutsu utilizes chakra that is molded
from one's Mental and Physical Energy.
Sage Jutsu involves
taking that internally generated chakra
and adding Nature Energy
from the outside,
resulting in an even
more powerful chakra.
And that leads to all
your ninjutsu, genjutsu,
and even your taijutsu getting
a real power boost.
Mental and Physical Energy
within oneself,
and Nature Energy from the outside.
jutsu and techniques born
from the chakra
created by these three combined energies
is what's known as Sage jutsu.
Hmm...
Look at it this way...
If you add mint flavor to chocolate-vanilla
ice cream, then it tastes even better.
That makes it more confusing, Gamakichi!
Oh...I get it!
You understood that analogy?
That's the kind of guy Naruto is.
So what's this Nature Energy
really about?
Energy that is external to you.
The energy that exists in
the atmosphere and the terrain.
Atmosphere and terrain...Okay...
As in, the air and in the ground.
Oh, is that what he meant?
Bah! Enough words. I will show you.
This should be good enough.
Wow! Lord Fukasaku is amazing!
Look at him gather all
that Nature Energy!
Where? Where?!
Oh, wow...
H-He lifted it!
How about that?
This is the power of
Nature Energy-enhanced Sage Jutsu.
But I don't know what you did...
I only saw you weave a sign
at the beginning.
Well, naturally.
Right now, you're not yet able
to sense Nature Energy, Naruto-boy.
So it's impossible for you to absorb it.
Then how do I do it?
You must become one with nature!
Become one...?
As in, you have to die.
Die?!
How come becoming one
with nature means dying?
Gamakichi, what's with the dying?!
Don't make such weird analogies!
But...
Relax. You're not actually
going to die, Naruto-boy.
Then what?
Just wait 'til I'm finished...
I'll explain it stepwise.
Absorbing Nature Energy...
It means the ability to sense it
around you and draw it into yourself.
In addition,
by becoming one with nature,
you also gain full control over the Nature
Energy entering and leaving your body.
Practically speaking,
in terms of your training...
Yeah, yeah?
Sit still.
Huh?
It means sit still!
When you cease your flow
of animal instincts
and harmonize with
the flow of nature,
you will be able to sense
Nature Energy for the first time.
So I just stay still?
That seems easy enough.
Naruto, you really don't get it, do you?
For animals, not moving is
the hardest thing to do.
Jumping, running, molding chakra
with all my strength...
I've done those sorts of training.
But staying still? I don't quite get it.
But that's how you take
in Nature Energy, right?
It's impossible to do it right away.
This training requires time,
since the degree of difficulty
is very high.
It's gonna take that long?!
Don't take it so lightly, Naruto-boy!
Our enemy is Pain,
who possesses the Rinnegan...
The power of the
Sage of the Six Paths.
A powerful enemy
who killed Jiraiya-boy.
With that kind of attitude,
you can't possibly win!
I know all that!
Pain is the leader of the Akatsuki,
who are after Tailed Beasts.
They could come for me
at any moment.
I don't have much time to waste.
Well, it's not as though
there isn't a better way...
There is?!
Then teach me that!
This waterfall behind me...
It's the secret toad oil
of Mount Myoboku.
Toad oil?
Come over here and
put out your hand.
Here.
This toad oil has the property
of attracting Nature Energy.
It helps with the training.
Hey, that's useful!
Whenever you rub this oil
on your body,
Nature Energy can enter
through there.
And gradually, you'll gain the ability
to sense Nature Energy.
You're right...
I think I feel something
through my skin.
It is a tool to help grasp
the concept.
In time, you won't even need
to use the oil.
However, there is a risk.
When used by one who is inexperienced
in controlling Nature Energy,
you start to turn into a frog.
Wh-Wh-What the hell is this?!
Help!
I don't wanna be a frog!
Oww!
What's the big idea?
I'm back to normal.
It's all about balance.
You're used to turning your Mental
and Physical Energy
into ninjutsu chakra,
so you've got a balance there.
But now, you must add
Nature Energy into the mix.
Getting the perfect balance
is extremely difficult.
Balance, huh?
Take in too little, and you won't
get Sage Jutsu chakra.
And yet, if you take in too much,
Nature Energy will overwhelm you
and turn you into a frog.
Of course, if you only take in
a little too much, it's reversible.
But get beyond a certain amount,
and you'll stay as a frog,
never reverting back to
a human again.
What I meant about you
having to die
is that you might stop being human.
Once you turn into a frog,
then you progress further toward
permanently becoming one with nature.
And the past students
who've failed in this training...
are those stone statues.
All of them?
Well, don't fret too much.
You have me.
And this baton beats Nature Energy
out of one's body.
If you start transforming into a frog,
I'll beat you thoroughly to reverse it.
Speaking truthfully,
even Jiraiya-boy wasn't able
to completely master this.
When molding Sage Jutsu chakra,
Jiraiya-boy always acquired
some frog features.
But he was among the skilled ones.
I doubt that you'd hesitate
after coming this far,
but let me ask you...
What will you do?
I'll do it!
My Ninja Way...
is the same as the Pervy Sage's!
Oww!
Tomorrow, I'm going to be bruised
and bleeding on the inside.
What? Giving up already?
Hey, I know a much better
training method.
What is it?
Use Shadow Clones for the training.
They exponentially increase
my progress!
You have a point.
The experience of the Shadow Clones
reverts back to the original.
But the reverse is also true...
If a Shadow Clone completely
changes into a frog,
it's over for the original.
I know that already.
Very well. But four is the limit!
Any more and neither the baton
or I can keep up!
All right!
We're not playing a game
of whack-a-mole!
This is training!
I'm not gonna last doing this!
Damn!
Oww!
My face is like this from being hit!
I'm not turning into a frog!
What?! Sorry.
I never thought that training
to feel Nature Energy
would be so hard.
Only through perseverance shall
true strength be gained.
I know that!
If it'll make me strong like
the Pervy Sage,
anyone would endure this.
No...That's impossible.
This training is not for everyone...
You could say it's only possible
because it's you and Jiraiya-boy.
Or else I wouldn't have even
brought you here.
What do you mean?
Unless you already possess
enormous chakra inside you,
Nature Energy would just take
over you right away.
That is how intense Nature Energy is.
Plus, they must have the guts
to never give up.
That's the kind of person who
can become a Sage.
All right! Let's do this then!
Fool! Do you want to kill yourself?!
I can see it!
- Yes!
- It seems he's starting
- I can see it! I can see it!
- to get the feel of Nature Energy.
- Lord Fukasaku, I'm getting hungry.
- I saw it! I saw it!
- You're right.
- I saw it!
- Naruto-boy, time for a break.
- I'm awesome, yeah!
Let's eat.
Eat up now.
After the break,
I'll have you try to lift up
the stone frogs using Sage Jutsu.
Y-Yes sir!
Good, huh?
They're Ma's special dishes.
They're all favorites of mine.
That actually tasted quite good.
I'm becoming less human, after all.
Now then, I want you to
raise the stone frog.
But first, try it using only
your ninjutsu chakra.
O-Okay.
All right!
I can't lift it!
All right, stop!
Now, mold some Sage Jutsu chakra!
Right!
Good! Now try lifting
the stone frog once more!
Okay!
Oh!
That's it! Naruto-boy!
Nice, Naruto!
This lad's quicker on
the uptake than Jiraiya-boy.
I did it!
Fool! How dare you treat your predecessor
with such disrespect!
Though he's a lot denser
than Jiraiya-boy too...
All right, Naruto-boy!
Now put all the toppled stones
back in place!
Are you serious?!
It appears you've mastered
toad oil assisted control.
Now you need to master controlling
Nature Energy without using the oil.
I can feel the power flowing into me!
ninjutsu chakra consumes
your internal energy.
The more you use it,
the more exhausted you will become.
In contrast, Sage Jutsu chakra
draws in external energy,
so it will not tire you.
In fact, you will recover and
heal quicker too.
I get it...
Well...With the Nine-Tails' chakra
in the mix too,
he's showing a truly remarkable
recovery rate.
Now maybe I can do that too...
Do what?
Huh?! Oh, nothing...
Nothing at all!
Never mind then...But here.
I thought I'd give you
this today, Naruto-boy.
What is it?
A book.
Book?
This is the first novel
Jiraiya-boy wrote.
A lot of Jiraiya-boy's mind and
heart are contained within it.
You should read it.
Tales of... a Gutsy Ninja.
Why don't you give it up?
This game of tag is getting boring.
Give it up.
Can I say one thing?
I don't care to listen!
Die already!
Give up...
on me giving up!
Even if you bring me down,
another assassin will attack
the village...
As long as we are cursed to
live in this ninja World,
there will be no peace.
Then...I'll break that curse!
If there is such a thing as peace,
I'll seize it!
I'll never give up!
Wh-Who are you...?
My name is...
With so few people,
it sure is taking a while.
Shut up!
Be quiet and focus.
It appears...
Sasuke has blundered.
An octopus leg!
Quit laughing!
Ow!
Owww...
Focus!
Though it's just a little,
your body is moving!
Don't forget, "stay still"!
Doing this without using the oil
is a lot harder than I thought.
Of course it is!
Don't expect it'll be so easy
when you don't use the oil!
Not even the slightest quiver!
Say, I was just thinking...
What is it?
Why can't I just take this oil
with me when I fight?
Then I won't need to learn
how to take in Nature Energy
without the oil.
That is impossible.
Huh? Why?
Outside of Mount Myoboku's climate,
this oil vaporizes immediately.
No kidding?!
I thought I told you.
The oil is only to help you
grasp the concept.
Yes, sir!
But the way you change
into a frog so quickly...
Naruto-boy, you lack concentration!
You're not taking it
seriously enough!
No, that's not true.
After all, I did get the knack of
this thing from the previous training.
Enough! Just follow me!
Hey...This isn't what
I'm thinking, is it?
It's exactly that.
This is your next training site.
Stack a stone slab atop that summit
and begin Zen meditation.
If your concentration wavers
and you move even slightly,
you will fall to the bottom
of the ravine.
F-From up there?
Hmm...This should do.
Follow me, Naruto-boy!
Stay still!
You must learn to stop
your motion as an animal.
Find your own center of balance,
and motionlessly synchronize
with nature!
S-Saved.
Taking in Nature Energy
will have to wait
until you first perfect staying still.
No way!
Oww...
Maybe it's time for a break.
Damn...
It's this hard just to stay still...
Isn't this training sorta ridiculous?
Such nonsense!
Your master, Jiraiya-boy,
managed this feat.
Huh? Don't tell me...
Pervy Sage trained here too?
Yes. He and I came here often.
Say, how long did Pervy Sage
take on this training?
Well, Jiraiya-boy came here to
train between missions,
so it took him some time...
I see.
Naruto-boy?
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
I don't have the luxury of time.
So I have to pick up the pace!
Pervy Sage did the same training!
So I've gotta do my best too!
It's no good...
Focus, Naruto-boy!
That's pretty colorful
and yummy looking.
Oh, would you like one, Naruto-boy?
It's my favorite, larva riceballs.
No thanks!
Oh no!
Oh...
It's looking good.
He's rapidly amassing Nature Energy.
He's finally got it!
I'm impressed at how far
he's gotten without using the oil.
He's displaying the rings around
the eyes. Proof of Sagehood.
And no frog aspects either!
This might mean Naruto-boy has
become a Sage, surpassing Jiraiya-boy!
And it seems he's able to build up
even more Sage Jutsu chakra
than when he was using the oil.
How does it feel?
Hmm...Now I kinda get what it means
to become one with nature.
Owwww...
Huh? It doesn't hurt that much...
And that is Sage Mode!
Your body has been activated
on many levels.
W-Wow! Sage Mode, huh?!
Now that you've mastered
Sage Mode,
we've come to the final step.
What?! Final step?
You mean there's more?!
It's a type of sparring
that Sages perform using
Sage Jutsu chakra.
Now I shall teach you
how to do Frog Kumite!
Naruto-boy, let's call it a day.
No, not yet!
I'm the one that can't go on.
However...you're starting to
get the hang of it.
Yes, sir!
I pulled it off!
Even though it's far from perfect...
I need more practice while
in Sage Mode.
And, I have to make sure
no one sees me.
Well then...
I'm going to procure us
some fresh ingredients.
Not more of that gross stuff...
Aw man...
Ma! Make sure you get
some stamina-building stuff!
You are able to mold
Sage Jutsu chakra
and have pretty much mastered
Frog Kumite and Sage Techniques.
Now I have one final thing
to say to you.
Wh-What is it?
You're suddenly so serious.
Well...It's about the risks of
using Sage Mode.
Risks?
Yes...Once you fully grasp
the risks involved,
then you can use Sage Mode
to its fullest extent!
So, what are the risks?
First, as you're probably aware,
you can't maintain
Sage Mode for too long.
Maybe five minutes at most.
Also, to amass the Nature Energy
necessary to enter Sage Mode,
you must follow the principle
of staying still.
Thus, it cannot be used
once you begin battle.
For when you are still, you become
an easy target for your enemy.
Ow!
I see...
Right?
So the only time you can go
into Sage Mode is
when you've got plenty of comrades
around you that can free you up.
If you are alone,
but must go into Sage Mode,
withdraw from the battle momentarily
and gather Nature Energy.
What?! Then Sage Mode is useless!
So what was all this training for?!
Don't be so disappointed.
That is why I am here,
to alleviate that risk.
What do you mean?
If you and I merge our bodies,
it'll be fine!
No!!
When I say merge,
it simply means to be lightly
attached to your shoulder or back.
Oh, that's all...
But how does merging
make things fine?
Simply put, it's to split
the roles of stillness and action.
When one is moving,
the other stays still and
gathers Nature Energy.
In Jiraiya-boy's case,
the final form of his Sage Mode
had Ma and me both
riding his shoulders.
I see...I get it now...
Don't you worry, Naruto-boy!
Okay!
A genjutsu block...
I'm going to take a peek into your mind.
So many genjutsu blocks...
No wonder truth serum
didn't work on him.
How did it go?
It's no use...
Someone's placed blocks
inside his mind.
It's going to be difficult to
navigate past them.
It's probably some jutsu placed
on him by the one named Pain.
Please be careful, Inoichi.
There may be genjutsu traps
set in there as well.
Yes, I'm aware of that.
These black rods, which
were embedded in the corpse...
Could they be a special feature
of these men known as Pain?
Why did they embed this
into the body?
I must learn more about
the properties of this metal
before the autopsy.
"The-Real-One's-Not-Among-Them."
Maybe the six Pains were genjutsu...
A jutsu created by the female Akatsuki
member who was also said to be present.
And she's the one who physically
attacked Lord Jiraiya from the shadows.
No...That's hard to imagine.
According to Lord Fukasaku,
Lord Jiraiya died from being stabbed by
real weapons wielded by all six of them.
Well, he took down three of them,
but they supposedly
resurrected themselves...
It does sound like some
unbelievable genjutsu.
Common sense has no meaning
when it comes to the Akatsuki.
There have been others
who were immortal.
In any case, let's keep hypothesizing
all possible scenarios
until we get reports from the others.
You're right.
Let's at least be a little closer
to solving Pain's mystery
by the time Naruto returns
from his training.
So here you are.
Naruto-boy, every once in
a while, you disappear.
Where do you go?
Well...nowhere in particular.
I just wander around...
Well, no matter.
I want to practice merging starting now,
so come down here.
All right! This completes
the steps to Sage Mode...
We'll now begin the merge training!
Y-Yeah...!
So basically, you're gonna get
on my shoulder, right?
Correct.
While you move,
I draw in Nature Energy.
This is a training to hone
that combination.
Now then, let us synchronize
our breathing.
Okay...
Sage Art: Amphibian Jutsu!
It seems this is not possible.
Not possible...?!
I suspect that the Nine-Tails
inside you is rejecting me.
No way!
Then what was all that training for?!
What are we gonna do?!
If we can't merge,
I have no choice
but to pull in Nature Energy
while I'm moving!
And I said that's impossible!
I never imagined this would
happen after coming this far.
I'm not giving up!
If that's what it takes,
then I'll keep at it until it works!
But I'm saying it's impossible!
I-I'm sorry...
I know this is hard to accept,
but it's physically impossible.
That code on your back was a message
to me from the Pervy Sage.
Yes, I know that.
And thanks to you, Naruto-boy,
it's become a key to solving
the mystery of Pain--
Not just that.
It's also a message for me not to
give up until the very end.
But still...
I'm Pervy Sage's student.
And if that message was
my master's Ninja Way... then I...
I have no business whining!
Oww!
Not just yet!
Let's keep on going!
He's so stubborn...
Let's take a break, Naruto-boy.
Otherwise, I won't be able
to keep up.
That's no good!
We have to keep going to make up
for the time we spent on
the training up until now!
Look, you've never had this kind
of training before.
To run and gather Nature Energy,
for which the foundation
is being still,
is like telling you to look to the left,
when you are looking to the right.
What is it?
That's about it...
Scouting complete.
Same as usual,
nothing suspicious.
It's another nice day.
Granny, hurry! Hurry!
Now, now. Don't be so hasty.
A stick of this after a mission...
This is what I live for.
C'mon, hurry and pick a card.
Byakugan!
H-Hey! No fair!
You can't use Byakugan
in a game!
Well, I guess I'll start on
the next report that's due.
Is he from...the Akatsuki?!
Right! Must report this
to Lady Hokage!
What?!
The time has come.