Naruto, Hinata,
congratulations on your marriage!
Huh?
Oh!
What're you doing, Sai?
Where's your congratulatory message?!
Well, I don't think I can say it well.
You're a former Team 7 member!
You're gonna do this!
Naruto, Hinata, congratulations
on your marriage!
Hey, you're being too stiff…
Naruto, Hinata, congratulations
on your marriage!
Uh, act more natural.
Like I told you before,
I don't think I can say it well.
Naruto! Hinata!
To the both of you...
Have a hot, hot, hot married life!
Brother Lee, you're way too close…
When you say it, it doesn't sound
like a congratulatory message…
Something's missing!
Guy Sensei!
My dear Lee…
Think if your hot-blooded wish
will permeate through the lens
and be conveyed 100% to
Naruto and Hinata
when your message is played.
It needs something
symbolic on-screen.
I know! The sunrise!
The sun rising over the horizon
to mark the beginning of
their married life together!
Give your message with
the sunrise in the background…
and you'll increase the impact of
your hot-blooded feelings by 300%!
Don't take them too seriously.
Hi Naruto and Hinata!
I hope you're well!
What's up with that?
Of course, they're well.
Hey, enough with the wisecracks!
Tadah!
Hey Naruto! Hinata!
How ya doin'?
Hey Kiba! Don't butt in!
– Isn't there anyone who's a friend of
– I heard you were making
– Big Brother Naruto who'll let me
– a congratulatory video!
– get a proper message?
– I searched for you all over town!
Uh, Naruto, Hinata…
congratulations on your marriage...
Iruka Sensei, you're too nervous, c'mon!
Sorry, sorry! I'm not good
at these sorts of things.
Just say what you feel.
If he hears his mentor, Iruka Sensei,
speaking from his heart…
Big Bro Naruto's gonna cry!
His mentor?
That's going a bit too far.
Okay, let's go for a comment
that's deeply moving! Here we go!
Ah...Um...Well…
I can't think of anything so suddenly,
so can we do this later?
Since Naruto's getting married…
Naruto, Hinata…
Naruto! Hinata!
Congratulations on your nuptials…
That's too stiff!
Iruka Sensei!
Big trouble!
Look at what they did
to the memorial statue!
What do we do?
Now, Sadoru Sensei,
you just became an instructor recently,
so I understand how upsetting this is.
But this sort of thing is quite minor…
Hey!
Tsukune, Sansho, Mibuna!
So, this is your doing, after all.
How'd you know we were here?
I know exactly what you're thinking.
We were just playing hide-and-seek!
Don't go off and treat us like criminals!
Don't lie!
I bet you enjoyed seeing Sadoru Sensei
having a hard time, didn't you?
No!
You don't even like, have any proof.
So, stop jumping to conclusions!
I see.
So, you guys didn't do this graffiti…
For a prank, it looked pretty cool,
so I figured it was you guys…
Hey, you've got a good eye!
To tell you the truth,
I'm really proud of it!
Shh!
Make sure you clean it up completely!
– Yes, sir…
You're amazing, Iruka Sensei!
Compared to Naruto's antics,
this is cute.
Naruto?
You mean, Naruto Uzumaki?
Were you his teacher?
Huh? Well, yes…
– No way!
Naruto Uzumaki, the super-famous
Naruto Uzumaki, right?
He's on a completely different level!
There's no way an ordinary teacher
– like you taught him, Iruka Sensei!
– Ordinary…teacher?
You're just trying to inspire us…
by saying that even
Naruto Uzumaki was a bad kid,
so us bad kids should
try our best, right?
Yeah, like, don't make up stories
if you want to send us a message.
I-I see…
Well then…
While you're at it, rake the yard
and clean the toilets!
– What?!
– No fair!
"I really did teach Naruto."
Even if I said that,
students now wouldn't believe me.
Naruto is a super-hero to them.
Oh, there you are!
Iruka Sensei, do you have a minute?
Yes?
Vice-principal? Me?!
You've been here a long time.
And you're popular
among your colleagues.
You would be perfect person
for the job.
Lord Kakashi,
I've brought you some tea.
Can you drop the "lord"?
Is anything the matter, sir?
You seem quite perturbed.
And don't be overly formal.
I'm not used to it.
Anyway, the date for Naruto and
Hinata's wedding is set, right?
I'm thinking of a way for
everyone to be able to attend.
I see…
If everyone attends the reception,
we won't be able to fulfill
any missions on that day…
let alone handle any emergencies.
Their close circle of friends are
all significant jonin now, right?
It would be a problem if
all of them are unavailable.
Naruto, it's been awhile.
I hear you're getting married—
That's right!
The previous Hokage, Lady Tsunade,
had a rule in case
of emergencies like this.
Huh?!
"One: when there is
a marriage among shinobi,
the gift that each shinobi
will present will be assessed
to determine who shall attend,"
it seems…
Huh?! What's up with that?
It's got to be a joke.
It seems like a joke,
but it's right here.
You're right!
But this is like eliminating people
by the size of their gift.
Perhaps so, but it's the rule.
No one would agree to something
that measures friendship like that.
I'll be called
the worst Hokage in history.
I understand how you feel,
but it's more important
to fulfill the responsibility
that's right before you,
as the Hokage.
Welcome!
I'll have ramen.
Make mine a super-size ramen!
Oh! Iruka Sensei!
Did you come up with
a congratulatory message?
Uh no, sorry, I forgot…
An advancement exam?!
One of the board officials recommended
I take it to become vice-principal.
W-Wh…? Why only Iruka Sensei?
Does that mean
I'm not among the candidates?!
No, that's not right!
What's the matter, Ebisu Sensei?
N-No, nothing's the matter.
But this is a great opportunity!
Oh?
His mentor is being promoted…
This will make Naruto's wedding
even more auspicious.
Then we'll have to start
calling you Vice-Principal Iruka.
Oh, please stop.
I haven't even decided
if I'll take the test or not.
Huh?!
You're not going to pass up
a chance like this, are you?!
Ebisu Sensei, you look sorta glad.
I admit I'm grateful for the chance
to be promoted. Besides…
Naruto Uzumaki, the super-famous
Naruto Uzumaki, right?
There's no way an ordinary teacher
like you taught him, Iruka Sensei!
I know I should strive to get ahead.
But there's a part of me that wants
to continue teaching kids one on one.
Of course!
You shine in the classroom,
Iruka Sensei. You really do!
I still think you seem a little too happy…
What's up?
Lord Kakashi…
Could you drop the "lord" part?
How long have you been there?
I didn't notice you at all.
Well, you were all going on
about Iruka Sensei…
So, I didn't want to interfere.
Lord Kakashi…
I mean, Kakashi…
Is something going on
with you as well?
Oh, no…
But what's going on with you,
Iruka Sensei?
He was asked to take
the advancement exam for vice-principal!
Vice-principal?
Oh yeah, the position is open.
And I'm not sure if
I should take it or not.
You? Take the advancement exam?
Now that would be difficult.
– Huh?
– What?!
Well...I'd better get back to work.
Thanks!
Thanks for coming—
Hey, Ayame.
Did you take Lord Kakashi's order?
What?
Huh?! When did he—?!
What's going on here?
Was he talking about Iruka Sensei
taking the advancement exam?
Why'd he say it would "be difficult"
for Iruka Sensei?
I got it!
As the Hokage, Lord Kakashi
doesn't think
Iruka Sensei is suitable to be
the vice-principal!
– Whaa—?!
That's what he meant.
The advancement exam?
Iruka Sensei?
Even if he takes it, with Iruka's
Sensei's skills and experience,
getting the promotion
would be difficult.
Now, now I didn't say it!
I'm just surmising what
Lord Hokage meant.
For him to say that taking
the exam would be difficult…
It's like saying he knows
the outcome
before Iruka Sensei
even takes the exam, hey…
You gonna stand for that, Iruka Sensei?
You want to give Naruto something else
to celebrate at his wedding, don't ya?
Dad, don't egg him on like that.
What're you saying?
Earlier, even you were—!
I'm taking it!
I'm going to take the exam
and I'm going to pass.
It will be Naruto's biggest day
in his life…
and I'm going to present him
with auspicious news!
Iruka Sensei!
Well said!
You're the man!
All right!
A prank like this is old news.
But Naruto, who used
to play tricks like this,
became the village hero.
Maybe there's a future
"Naruto Uzumaki" among you.
Now listen, anyone can become
a hero like Naruto Uzumaki!
So believe in yourself
and do your best!
– Yes, sir!
Not Naruto Uzumaki again?!
What's the matter?!
Come on, put some more spirit into it!
Sadoru Sensei,
you just have to be confident and
take on the students head on
at times like this!
– I'm sorry.
We're very sorry.
I'll make sure to
teach them better
so that this never
happens again, so please…
Hey, Tsukune…
Damaging the statue is going too far.
Iruka Sensei will really
get mad this time.
So what?
I figured you were up
to something like this.
I told you, didn't I?
I know exactly what you're thinking.
I'll say this…
you do things on such a small scale.
Why, to Naruto, scrawling graffiti
on the Hokage's Great Stone Face
was nothing.
He even took the Book of Seals and
wreaked havoc in the village.
So, Naruto Uzumaki really
was your pupil?
Shut up!
Who cares about Naruto!
I am me!
Iruka Sensei did?
Yeah.
He's been gung-ho ever since.
I keep hearing good things
about him from everyone.
He's gonna make it for sure!
Ebisu Sensei, you're looking
a little too depressed now.
I'm going out to get a bite to eat.
Ramen again?
Eating ramen every day isn't healthy.
Well, that's okay.
You're really gonna do it?
'Course!
Lord Hokage is gone.
Now's our only chance.
I can pull off anything
Naruto Uzumaki did, just as easily.
Let's go!
C-Count me out!
Me too!
Wimps…
Good evening.
Oh welcome, Lord Hokage!
Look, could you please drop the "lord."
Huh? What's wrong Ebisu Sensei?
Why are you spaced out?
We were talking about Iruka Sensei
passing the advancement exam.
Huh? Iruka Sensei plans
to take the exam?
Sure, thanks to you, Kakashi!
Me? What did I do?
Anyway…
What a delicious smell!
Is it ramen?
Seems like they didn't
order pot stickers, though.
Is that what happened?
I didn't mean it that way.
What do you mean?
Anyway, regarding
the advancement exam, they say…
Lord Kakashi!
How many times do I have tell you
to stop it with the "lord"?
Never mind that! Bad news!
The Book of Seals was stolen?!
Yes. No one knows where it is,
and all shinobi are
now searching for it.
Don't tell me…
Iruka Sensei!
Sansho! Mibuna!
Where is Tsukune?!
We tried to stop him…
I knew it…
See?
That was easy.
Next, I'll use this and mess up
the Great Stone Face.
Stop!
I knew I'd find you here.
You planned to use a Shadow Clone
from the Book of Seals
and pull off a flashy prank, right?
You wanna say that you know
exactly what I'm thinking, right?
No, I don't know
what you're thinking.
What am I doing?!
I keep comparing students
to the ones I had in the past.
And I can't see into the heart…
of the precious student
that's standing right before me!
Iruka Sensei…
I realize it now, Tsukune.
You just wanted to
be acknowledged, right?
And I didn't see that…
and kept bragging about
an old student of mine.
How long have I been
a teacher anyway?
I'm such a fool!
I'm sorry!
Please forgive me!
Did you mean it?
Huh?
About what you said…
Anyone can become a hero
like Naruto Uzumaki!
So believe in yourself
and do your best!
Yeah. Of course!
'Kay then…
I'll try a little bit harder.
I'm very sorry about what my student did.
I take full responsibility.
Oh, yeah?
Then check and confirm
the inside for me.
Huh?
"To me, love is life.
Love is everything, you see?!"
There's no way
I'd place the real thing
where it can be stolen easily.
True…
By the way, Iruka Sensei…
About the advancement exam…
You were right, Kakashi.
That position is far more than
I can handle right now.
Huh?!
No, no...When I said
it was going to be difficult,
I meant that
the advancement exam
is on the same day
as Naruto's wedding.
What?
You are his mentor, Iruka Sensei…
You can't miss his wedding, right?
So, that got me thinking…
I'm thinking of reserving another
extra day for the advancement exam.
I really want you to become
the vice-principal, Iruka Sensei,
and serve as a shining example
to all of the Academy teachers.
I'm sorry.
I'm not going to take
the exam, after all.
I got carried away about
going to Naruto's reception
as the newly promoted vice-principal
and forgot about my student
who was right before my eyes.
I've failed as a teacher.
I have no right to
go celebrate with Naruto.
First, I must take care
of my current students
and cherish the things right
before me.
Then and only then,
can I properly congratulate Naruto.
Cherish the things
right before me, huh…
…it's more important to
fulfill the responsibility
that's right before you,
as the Hokage.
You're right. I've decided too.
Huh? What did you—?
I asked you to assemble here today
to relay something as
your Sixth Hokage.
Listen. I am giving you
a secret mission
in which you shall each prepare
a congratulatory gift
for Naruto and Hinata's wedding.
Have it ready and report back
one week before the reception.
A wedding gift?
That's great!
– He has it all planned.
– What a drag.
Leave it to Lord Hokage!
That is all.
Kakashi, what is going on?
We're going to assess each gift
and give it a ranking to determine
who will attend the wedding reception
and who will be placed on duty
for that day's missions.
In other words, we're going to sift
and screen through the gifts.
But that's like measuring
their friendship?!
Yeah…
But what's most important is
what's right before me, right?
I'm prepared to be called
the worst Hokage in history.
"The worst Hokage in history"?
It's all thanks to you, Iruka Sensei!
Wha—?
What?!
A mission to find
a wedding present, huh?
The Hokage is giving us a wonderful
opportunity to find a great gift…
…that personifies our friendship.
That's right, we've never had
a wedding celebration like this.
– Well, they are the first
– Hey, Shino! Cut it out!
– among all our friends
– I didn't say anything until now,
– to get married.
– but I've had enough of
– We gotta do our best to find
– your insect antics!
– something they'll both like.
– Hey, Akamaru!
Me too! I'm getting fired up!
I'm gonna make sure
they definitely love my gift!
Do you know what
you're getting already, Lee?
I haven't a clue.
Huh?!
However! If I put myself
in Naruto's shoes
and think about how he feels,
I know it'll come to me naturally.
I won't lose to anyone!
Wake up, Akamaru!
Usually, you don't compete
with wedding gifts
to see who wins or loses…
Well then…
Let's give it our all!
This is for Hinata.
Let's all put
our best effort into this.
There's no need to
get so worked up.
The reason is, if you just
let it come naturally to you,
you'll think of something.
It seems everyone got
really fired up about this.
I can't think of anything.
What about you, Choji?
I have a pretty good idea.
Damn it...What a drag.
We're going to assess each gift
and give it a ranking
to determine who will attend
the wedding reception
and who will be placed on duty
for that day's missions.
In other words, we're going to sift
and screen through the gifts.
I'd better not mention
any of that to anyone.
Hello!
Oh, it's Lee!
I'll have an order of the ramen
Naruto orders most often!
Naruto's favorite ramen?
Let's see…
That's so obvious! It's our large
miso and char siu ramen.
– Oh, yeah that's right!
– I see!
But why the sudden curiosity?
If I'm to understand
Naruto's feelings,
I figured I should first try
the things he likes to eat.
I don't get it but…
anyways, take a seat.
Okay!
Idiot…idiot…
How is it?
It's delicious!
Light, yet rich, but not too heavy.
It has volume and punch,
and its impact is so great,
you want to slurp it down
all at once!
So…do you know how Naruto feels
a little more now?
I understand why he always
orders this ramen!
But other than that, no.
I guess not.
If you could tell how a guy feels
just by eating ramen,
life wouldn't be so hard.
Oh!
Iruka Sensei,
you were Naruto's teacher.
You must know.
Iruka Sensei?!
I'm sorry, I was deep in thought
and didn't notice you!
Don't worry.
You're Lee, right?
Guy Sensei's student.
Yes! You were Naruto's teacher…
So you must know how Naruto thinks.
Please tell me about him!
Well, I was his teacher
a long time ago.
And he's become
so praiseworthy now…
I only see him once in a while now…
I see…
But why are you trying to
understand Naruto's feelings, Lee?
For his wedding gift.
In order to find
something he'll like,
I thought I should first
understand his feelings.
I see, so that's it.
In any case,
in order to convey my intense
regard for my friend Naruto,
I'm going to put
my entire being into
finding the best
wedding gift for him!
Well then, please excuse me,
Iruka Sensei!
He's exactly like Guy Sensei.
I'm so sorry it was so loud!
Oh no. In fact, I'm happy that
Naruto has a friend like him.
Found ya, Iruka Sensei!
You didn't record your message yet!
That's right…
Can you wait a little longer?
Not again…man.
Naruto's wedding gift…
Naruto's…wedding…
Yes!
How about dumbbells?!
Naruto! Hinata!
Congratulations on your marriage!
Please use these dumbbells
and find everlasting happiness…
No, no, no, no, no!
Stop!
Dumbbells are definitely useful.
Its heaviness is surely symbolic of
the solidity and depth of my friendship…
And more importantly,
they can make you stronger.
Nothing else could
better symbolize our friendship.
But…
It's possible Naruto will get
so hooked on muscle training
that he'll totally ignore Hinata…
Even if Naruto and I
have a special bond,
giving him dumbbells
might meet with some resistance.
I must think of something else!
Ahh! I can't think of anything!
During times like this—!
What gift would make
Naruto and Hinata happy?
I guess it would be something
that reminds them of me.
Now if a kunai like this was
specially ordered and made cute…
Marriage, huh?
How nice…!
Hold on a sec!
One is in love with her dream man
and getting married, happily ever after.
While I don't even
have a boyfriend,
and train every day from
morning until night…
This would be…
Kunai again?
But it's Tenten, after all…
When you think of Tenten,
you think kunai…
Maybe I should think of
something else…
Get something
that doesn't kill people,
within the set budget
– that captures a maiden's heart…
– Tenten!
– I need to ask you something!
– That voice…
Idiot…idiot.
Calm down when you
ask people something.
I'm sorry.
I just couldn't do it by myself.
I had no choice but to ask for
your help and came looking for you…
But…I guess you're in a bind too.
Uh-huh…
Sending the usual gift
won't convey our feelings…
And yet, something that's more
like me may not make them happy…
A wedding gift…
is more complicated than I thought.
What would Neji do?
We must not do that!
We must go and investigate!
Investigate?
Yes!
I get it.
Rather than thinking alone,
looking at actual items can give us
more ideas and variations.
There are so many items,
I'm sure we'll find something
suitable that fits us,
while also making
Naruto and Hinata happy!
You're right! For example…
How about a sword like this?
Umm…
It looks expensive,
but it doesn't have any connection
to a wedding, does it?
No…
They can use it for
their first joint effort.
To cut the cake…that's all?
Not good?
Isn't a cake-cutter pretty low
on the usefulness meter?
Then how about…
…this?
Tonfa?
It's totally you,
since you're a taijutsu specialist…
That has no connection
with a wedding either.
No…
I figured it would be useful
for everyday married life,
since they'll have
more laundry to do…
For hanging laundry?!
Still, I don't think Naruto
will be too pleased with this…
Maybe you should think of
something a bit less strange.
You're lucky, Tenten.
All you have to do…
…is send this thing
that you always use.
Huh? Would getting kunai
make them happy?
It's not necessary at all
in married life.
No! You can make full use of it!
It's perfect for newlyweds
who can't decide
what to make for dinner!
Is that any way to use a kunai?!
Idiot…idiot.
We didn't find a single thing.
Let's try hard again tomorrow.
I can't think of a single thing.
Lee…
Hey, Lee!
Neji!
When you get hooked on one thing,
you even struggle with it
in your dreams…
That's so like you, Lee.
Neji...Is that really you, Neji?
You were groaning pretty loud.
I couldn't find a gift for
Naruto and Hinata's wedding.
I spent the entire day looking,
but I've used up
all my ideas and energy…
What about you, Neji?
I had one thing I had to tell you…
Neji, I'm…
I know.
Say no more.
Lee, remember this carefully…
Physical strength over endurance!
Physical strength over endurance?
And don't forget…Hyuga.
What? H-Hey wait, Neji!
I thought you appeared
because I was
in such a dilemma
about a wedding gift
and you wanted to give me advice!
Oh…
Neji!
Neji?!
Naruto, Hinata,
congratulations on your marriage.
Naruto, who would have expected
a bad little kid
would become such a great man?
Hinata, please take care of Naruto.
I think that's it!
Okay!
It's perfect!
I can just see Big Brother Naruto's
eyes welling up with tears!
Okay, I'm off to edit this!
I can't wait!
Oh, Lee!
H-Hello, Iruka Sensei…
What happened to your face?!
I can't decide on a gift
for Naruto's wedding…
On top of that, an old friend
appeared in my dream
and gave me advice that
doesn't make any sense at all and…
…I couldn't sleep
thinking about it.
2765 sheep, 2766 sheep,
2767 Neji, 2768—?
Neji, you jerk!
Oh, that sounds terrible…
At this rate,
I'll never be able to convey
the depth of my friendship
to Naruto!
There, there…
Don't take it so seriously.
I'm sure it's a big struggle
for you all…
But I'm very happy.
Happy? Why?
I'm happy to know that
a student I taught
has a friend who will go to
such great lengths.
Although, it may sound like
I'm just trying to
make you feel better…
Oh, no such thing…
Actually,
I've never had a chance
to talk like this
to a friend of Naruto's.
Thanks to his upcoming wedding,
I got to talk to you
and the others,
and you've shown me a valuable side
of Naruto I never knew.
I'm grateful for that.
Now that I think about it,
since he graduated,
you guys know much more
about Naruto than I do.
Is that so?!
Huh?
Why so shocked?
I thought I could ask for your help
with ideas for
Naruto's wedding gift.
Sorry, I'm no help.
But considering the effort
you're putting into finding a gift,
I know Naruto will be happy,
whatever you choose.
Do you think so?
In fact, if he dares to complain,
as his teacher,
I'll knock some sense into him
all over again!
Did I sound pompous saying that?
As his teacher…knock some sense…
all over again…
That's it!
Huh? What?
I had forgotten
something very valuable!
Iruka Sensei, thank you!
Well then…
What was that?!
So you've come, Lee!
Guy Sensei!
I figured it would be around now.
Judging from your expression,
you're still in a dilemma, eh?
What? How can you tell?
One look at you and I can tell if
you've been training all night
because something's bothering you.
Guy Sensei!
And let me guess…your worries
have to do with the wedding gift.
Huh?!
G-Guy Sensei!
Can you read my heart?!
How long have we been together
in the springtime of our youth?
Guy Sensei!
I can't even decide what to give
Naruto for his wedding gift…
I'm still only half a shinobi!
Please knock some sense into me!
Well said, Lee!
Let's search together
for a wedding gift!
– Guy Sensei!
– Lee!
Let's set up some rules before
choosing a wedding gift.
First, it can't be
something common.
But it mustn't be
too unconventional.
Yes, we figured out that much.
It's from that point
that we got stuck.
And…the wedding gift should be one
that leaves a lasting impression,
and conveys friendship, effort,
and triumph in choosing it.
So what would be a gift
that personifies me…
and the hot springtime of youth—
…what would that be?
If it does exist, it would…
definitely include wearing
a fashionable bodysuit!
Huh?! Why a bodysuit?
Yes! The hot spring of youth
means sweat and tears!
Can sweat and tears
be given as gifts?!
– No, of course not!
– Just a minute, Lee!
In the first place,
can man live on will power alone?!
Can he overcome the dangers of
divorce with only patience?!
W-Wait, Sensei…
You're going off the subject…
I've been thinking the same thing!
Should curry be medium-hot?
Or super-spicy?!
Aw man! We're on totally
different wave lengths!
All right! I'm going to do a handstand
and walk around the village 5,000 times!
Then I'll go 5,200 times!
Fine, then I'll go 5,300 times!
– 5,400 times!
– 5,500 times!
Stop it!
It's true.
We've gone way off the subject.
So, let's just go back
to the beginning.
And go over the basics once more.
Basics?
Yes.
First of all,
what is a wedding ceremony?
Th-That's a very
philosophical question…
Uh, is that really
where we're starting?
Then let me ask you this?
What is absolutely necessary
for a wedding ceremony?
Wouldn't that be…love?
You are a poet.
However, Lee…
I think it's the bride and groom!
Oh! Y-Yes, there's no wedding
without a bride and groom!
Right?
A wedding ceremony
without a bride and groom
is not a wedding ceremony!
It's just a ceremony!
And by ceremony,
who knows what kind of ceremony!
How blind I am!
Guy Sensei,
you have the ability to see
what something is
beneath the surface!
You are amazing!
You don't need to go overboard…
You have always been my role model…
– My everlasting hero!
– No one's paying any attention.
So now, we can think about
what kind of gift
would please
a bride and groom, right?
Exactly!
I'm starting to get a bad feeling
about this…
All right!
I'll be the groom.
Lee, you are the bride!
Yes, Guy Sensei!
I knew it…
Why do I have to play the baby?
Not this again?
Hi…
I'm home.
What time do you think it is?!
It's the new spring fashions!
– Move!
– How cute!
– That's mine!
– She took it!
Give it back!
How dare you!
Seventh Gate of Shock! Open!
– Damn it, – Well, Lee?
– what are you making me do?
– Is something forming in your mind?
I think I'm almost there…
But after that, it's still far off…
Well, never mind.
You won't get an answer
if you think too deeply.
If Neji were here,
he wouldn't even speak to you.
No, but Neji would,
if it's for Hinata's sake.
The husband's female coworker
appears out of nowhere
to threaten
their peaceful family life.
Neji would show up
to take on that perfect role!
He would not!
Besides, how can you misinterpret
Neji like that?!
Neji…
Even if as a ghost,
Neji would appear.
Neji would appear?
Physical strength over endurance!
I see!
I get it.
So that's it, Neji.
So that was meant for Hinata,
not me.
What do you mean?
Physical strength is essential
to protect a family!
– The highest form of strength!
– Absolutely!
Cooking, washing, cleaning,
raising the kids, shopping…
The newlywed life is
a nonstop test of muscles!
Yes!
The newlyweds
must prepare for that!
If that is so,
there is only one answer!
The truest gift from us should be…
– Dumbbells!
You've got to be kidding!
– Guy Sensei…
– Lee…
– Guy Sensei!
– Lee!
Hah!
Lee! You shall present
the left dumbbell!
Right!
And I'll present the right!
Let's go, Guy Sensei!
Yes!
Our wedding gift…
will lose to no one!
Okay, yeah...I'm gonna go with
a custom-made kunai.
What, you fool!
Delivery?
– I see…
– It's gonna take some time.
– You've decided on a wedding gift?
– Is that okay?
– Yes, and it's all thanks to
– Okay, sorry.
– Guy Sensei and you, Iruka Sensei.
– Ayame is out right now.
– It pays to have great mentors!
– Is that okay? Thank you.
– Well, if that's what you believe,
– Thank you.
– it makes me very happy.
– What's your order?
What are you saying?
Naruto is blessed to have a mentor
like you, Iruka Sensei.
I'm sure he feels the same way!
Oh, thank you.
Okay, I'm going to take a look
at some dumbbells.
So if you'll excuse me!
Naruto's mentor, huh…?
I should find out more about
how Naruto's grown
after leaving my care,
and what kind of bonds
he's made with friends.
If I'm truly Naruto's mentor…
Oh! Iruka Sensei!
We meet again!
Konohamaru, just in time.
That message I recorded last time…
Can I do it over?
Sure. But why?
I want to find out
more about Naruto,
and send him a proper message…
A message from his mentor…
I'm back!
Sorry to keep you waiting.
What will you have?
Um…
I'll have the miso char siu.
Make it a large.
Coming right up.
One large miso char siu ramen!
All right!
A large miso char siu ramen!
Miso?!
Hey Ino…you here?
Yeah? What are you two
doing together?
Remember what Kakashi Sensei
said last time?
I am giving you a secret mission
in which you shall each prepare
a congratulatory gift for
Naruto and Hinata's wedding.
Of course!
And? What about it?
Oh...I thought we'd discuss
what to get them.
Oh, sorry!
I've got something great
picked out already
and I'm about to go
to the store.
Which store?
We'll go with you!
No, you aren't!
We can't get gifts from
the same store.
You two can think of
something on your own!
Later!
What are we gonna do?
Excuse me, Miss!
I'd like to get some ice cream
for dessert.
What about you, Shikamaru?
None for me.
You sure can eat, though…
Your appetite hasn't changed
since you were a kid.
But these days,
I've started liking thigh meat,
as well as meat that's really rare,
so I think I'm going towards
more grown-up tastes.
So it's your taste buds?
Anyway, getting back
to the subject.
Maybe yuzu sorbet would've
been better than ice cream…
No! I'm talking about the wedding gift
for Naruto and Hinata!
Oh that.
Here's your ice cream.
Oh, it's here!
Judging from Ino's attitude,
she'll be no help…
If this keeps going,
we might be the only ones
who can't find a present.
What do you mean by "we"?
I've already picked
something out.
R-Really?!
What are you getting?
I'm thinking about
giving them this.
Hey, this is a—!
Yup, a gift certificate
for a dinner!
And it's not just for
an average diner!
It's a gift certificate for
a super-fancy teahouse
that VIPs like the Hokage go to!
Well, it is a special occasion…
What's going on?!
This is Choji…
And he chose the perfect gift!
Having dinner in a restaurant
you wouldn't normally be able to go to
is special and really memorable
for a couple!
Not a lot of gifts would have
as much impact!
And even if this was
for a special occasion…
Choji's willing to part
with a gift certificate
to a super-fancy restaurant,
just like that?
Miss, may I have another bowl
of ice cream?
Are you really
the Choji I know?!
It's not just your taste buds
that grew up.
Have you completely
become an adult?
What?
Here's your ice cream.
It just happened to be
a three-for-one special.
Why is it three to a group?
Usually a romantic dinner
is for two.
You'd think a fancy restaurant
would be aware of that!
Choji will tag along
if it's three to a group!
Shikamaru?
What's wrong, Shikamaru?
It's nothing…
Are you planning to go too?
Are you joking?
Even I know better than to tag along
with some newlyweds…
R-Right? Of course you would.
I was gonna ask the waitress to
seat me at a different table.
So, you ARE going?!
Still, this is not the time
to get on Choji's case.
I still haven't decided to
what to get them.
And I can't waste a minute
on deciding.
I'm thinking…
something useful.
A decorative item would just get
in the way if it's not to their taste.
Flowers or food would
be gone eventually,
and it would seem like
a seasonal gift.
Sending them something
is really risky…
So that leaves…cash!
That's not a bad idea.
They can get whatever they want,
and it's way better than getting
something they won't use
or something that's identical
to someone else's gift.
But wait a minute…
What if I'm the only one
giving them cash?
It's not a lot, but please accept it!
Not good!
Everyone will think I was
the only one too lazy
to go out and buy a gift and
just gave them cash
without thinking.
Shikamaru, you okay?
U-Uh, yeah...I just felt a chill.
Sorry, did you get cold from
watching me eat all that ice cream?
That's not it…
I got hot from eating all that
barbecue, so it was just what I needed.
Besides, I'm the kinda guy
who can eat ice cream
even if I'm traveling
in snow country!
My appetite beats
the cold every time.
Damn it, no one can
beat your appetite—
Choji! What did you just say?!
My appetite beats the cold?
No, before that!
What about snow country?
Oh…
I can eat ice cream even if
I'm traveling in snow country…
That's it!
A honeymoon?
Yeah...I'm gonna gift Naruto
and Hinata a honeymoon.
So where are you off to now?
I have to decide on a place,
and go check it out.
And I need to get
a woman's point of view
so I can get a sense of
what Hinata might like.
If only Ino were here…
There she is!
H-Hey…
It's been awhile…
ever since that day, huh?
Y-Yeah.
What are you guys up to?
Uh, stuff…We just had
some lunch. And you?
I'm here to discuss
the Chunin Exams
and making my rounds
to people…
O-Oh…that so?
What the hell?!
I thought you meant
Ino was there…
You said
a "woman's point of view,"
so it doesn't have to be Ino.
But she's a warrior-type
to the core.
I can't talk to her about
a wedding gift…
What?
A honeymoon as a wedding gift?
Talk about a silly
and pathetic idea.
I just know she'd say
something like that.
Wouldn't that apply
to Ino as well?
Hey, what're you two
whispering about?
Oh, it's nothing…
I think Shikamaru wants to talk
to you about something.
T-Talk to me?
Maybe…next time…
we can go get a bite to eat.
T-Talk about what?
Damn it, Choji!
I can't come out and
say something like,
"It's no use talking to Temari
about honeymoons."
Well…
I guess have no choice…
Well, you see…
I'm seriously thinking about
a honeymoon.
So, if it were you,
where would you like to go?
Huh?!
A-A honeymoon?!
W-What's the matter?
N-Nothing.
A honeymoon, huh?
W-Why would you ask me that?
Huh? Well, I just figured…
Wait a second.
I can't come out and say
it really doesn't matter who,
I just need
a woman's opinion, can I?
I figured you'd be
the best one to ask.
I-I'm the best one?
I-I see.
O-Okay then, I'll hear you out.
O-Oh…
Well, I thought a hot spring
would be nice and relaxing…
Does that sound like something
an old man would like?
No, a hot spring sounds great!
Really? Awesome!
Good food and hot springs…
perfect, right?
Good. At least I got confirmation.
So now…
Now you have to
choose where, right?
Huh? Oh, yeah.
Maybe we can check some out.
It's still early.
Why not go now?
Yeah, that's true. Then…
I'm going to Amaguriama.
So why don't you two go?
Huh?!
Sorry, I just have to have
some dessert after eating!
You just ate!
I always save room for dessert.
You just filled that room earlier!
You idiot!
Because of Choji's big mouth,
Temari's standing there
red-faced and upset!
Sorry, Choji didn't mean to
get you upset or anything.
Since we're talking
about honeymoons,
he figured there's no sense
I go alone.
Yeah, that's right.
A honeymoon is meant for two,
so you guys should go.
Okay, you two. I'm off.
Hey, uh…Mr. C-Choji?!
What am I supposed to do now?
I'll go with you.
Huh?
How did it turn out like this?
W-What's with this strange
nervousness?
Anyway, I never expected
Temari to help me out
with choosing a wedding gift
for Naruto and Hinata.
However…
Why is she so silent
all of a sudden?
I can't get a read
on her at all!
First, I have to get her
out of her bad mood.
W-Well...Since we're out…
should we stop by
a couple places?
O-Oh, sure…
That's rare of you to miss.
What?!
Sorry…
This was all I could win.
I'm not completely sure,
but I think she's in
a good mood now.
Thank goodness!
It's still here!
I knew it was
the perfect wedding gift.
It's cute and simple.
It's one of a kind!
I had to get money
from my savings,
but I know Hinata will love it!
Anyway, my wedding gift
to them is set!
I-Ino…
Imagine seeing you here.
I can say the same about you.
– No way!
– She isn't—!
B-By the way, have you seen
Naruto lately?
No, not at all.
Imagine that,
Naruto getting married.
He used to be crazy
about you long ago.
That was back when we were kids.
I'm really happy
he and Hinata are together.
There's no mistake…
She's also…
– planning on that for a wedding gift!
I have to get this picture frame
before her!
But how…?
Hey Sakura, were you planning on
getting this for Naruto and Hinata?
Huh?
That's right! I have to provoke her
and make her too proud to buy it.
That's impossible, right?
You wouldn't get something
that tacky, would you?
I'm not gonna fall for it.
This woman's trying to diss that
picture frame, so I won't buy it.
What are you talking about?
You were totally about
to buy it earlier…
Th-That's…
Why would you even think about
buying something tacky? How stupid!
Stupid?!
I didn't say
I was going to buy it!
I was just gonna move it out
of the way because it's trash.
Really, you may have brute
strength, but you have no taste at all!
Brute strength?!
Talk about a lame comparison!
Excuse me!
You're annoying
the other customers.
See, Ino!
You're annoying the others!
You're the one who's yelling!
You started it!
This is mine!
Hey, that's mine!
I found it first!
Now, now…
Please don't pull so hard,
or else—!
– Shut up!
You've got some nerve!
Because of you,
we got kicked out!
That's my line!
You have no sense
of mutual compromise!
You have no regard for anyone, you have
no chest, all you have is brute strength!
Huh?!
My chest has nothing
to do with this!
There is nothing you
can beat me in,
so you always try to bring up
something unrelated! You should stop that.
I don't know the meaning
of not winning.
And I win hands down
in femininity.
Feminine?!
You? How?
Now, now…
Stop your fighting, you two.
Choji! Perfect timing!
Who's more feminine?
Me or Sakura?!
You can't just ask something
like that out of the blue…
Even your own teammate, Choji,
won't pick you. How sad!
Huh?!
Choji's not on your team, but he won't
even try to flatter you. That is so sad!
H-Hey, cut it out.
Hmm...Okay then…
If you want to know,
why don't you put it to a test.
– A test?
Personally, I think someone who
can cook is very feminine.
So maybe you should see
who cooks better?
Okay, let's begin the challenge!
The one who makes
the tastiest food pills wins.
You just watch, Sakura.
I know what you like
and dislike.
I just have to make something
that'll make you gag.
The judge will be Choji.
Huh?! You're not going
to eat it?!
Fine with me!
I just ate a mountain
of ice cream,
but I always have room
for food pills!
W-Wait!
Choji's my teammate.
That gives me the edge!
You should be okay with
having the advantage…
Don't tell me…
You weren't planning to poison them
to make me sick, were you?
Like I would!
Come on, let's get started!
Okay, without further ado!
The food pill contest to see
who's more feminine, begins!
Ready, fight!
Whoa, what's this?!
Instead of using
a mortar and pestle,
she uses her fine chakra control
to get the ingredients
to the desired size.
I can't wait to taste
the sensation
when I put it in my mouth!
Whoa!
She's searing the ingredients
with super-fire power!
Sakura is using some
legendary golden honey.
Ino is using cacao powder.
Both seem irresistible!
Th-This is…?!
Th-This is…
Yummy!
So delicious!
Rich, yet not too overpowering…
That indescribable something
that explodes when
it hits your tongue…
That delicate aroma
and taste that lingers…
It's a treasure chest
of sweetness!
Choji!
So? Which is it?
Which one tastes better?
Oh, I wolfed both down,
so I can't tell.
But they were both really…good…
– Choji!
Choji! Choji!
I've made a lot of friends too.
Noooo!
Choji! Don't die!
What's happening?
Is his life flashing
before his eyes?
Ino!
You did used poison,
didn't you?!
You know I wouldn't!
Just who do
you think I am, anyway?!
I've made…a lot of friends…
This is bad!
Choji's delirium is getting worse!
What are you doing?
I have to see what's inside it
before I can treat him.
If there's poison in it,
my tongue will go numb…
I told you,
there's no poison inside!
Damn it!
It's delicious!
Uh-huh!
Why?
I really love this taste.
Me too! I love this flavor!
Boy, that surprised me.
I ate too many sweets…
Seems my blood sugar shot up.
But I'm okay now!
Is that all?
Thank goodness.
Hey, Ino.
Why would you go out of the way
to make something I love?
Well…
I figured if I surprised you with
a flavor you'd love, I'd win.
What, really?
That was my strategy too!
Huh?! You too?
No wonder I love how it tastes!
Ultimately, we saw right
through each other.
Okay, since we know
each other so well,
there's something
I want to say to you.
What is it?
Don't you think we'd find
something even better
if we looked for
a wedding gift together?
What now?
I was thinking the same thing.
That inn seems nice.
Huh?
I'd better hurry up
and choose or
I'll just keep mulling over
this wedding gift.
I just have to pick something!
Okay. Let's go in!
Huh?!
What's the matter?
Weren't we just going to…
look around?
Yeah, but we have to go inside
or we can't make a decision.
No, but…
I'm not mentally prepared…
What? Mentally prepared?
Is she panicking because
this place too fancy?
It's okay.
Temari, let's just go inside
and then we can decide.
I-It'll be too late once
we go inside!
I might get caught up
in the mood…
What's she talking about?
The mood?
The mood of that inn?
What does she mean
by getting caught up in it?
I don't get it!
Hey…you don't…
…have a fever, do you?
I-I'm going home!
H-Hey, wait!
It's gonna get dark soon!
If you're not feeling well,
we really should book
a room and rest!
Please wait!
I really…need you!
Are you sure…I'm the one?
Yeah! You're the only one!
Besides, I can't go into
the women's bath.
What?
Temari, I need you to go
into the women's bath
and report back
every detail to me.
That's all. Easy, right?
So, uh…
Just what is this all
about anyway?
What else? I'm going
to gift Naruto and Hinata
a honeymoon for
their wedding gift,
and I need to choose the inn.
Oh...So that's it.
Huh? Didn't I…tell you?
This is the first
I've heard about it.
So, you're back to square one
in your search for a wedding gift?
Yeah…
But I think it turned out
for the best.
What about you, Shikamaru?
Trying to explain
everything is a drag…
Welcome.
It's been a while Lord Sixth.
I apologize for being late.
Have the other Kage
arrived already?
Yes, they just arrived.
I don't see the Mizukage…
Due to inclement weather en route,
they are running about
a half a day behind.
During this time,
please relax and enjoy what
our village has to offer.
I've assigned Hidden Leaf shinobi
to accompany you.
By the way, Lord Sixth.
I understand Naruto is
going to marry.
Yes, so you've heard?
I've prepared a wedding gift
from the Hidden Rock.
May I ask you to present it
at the wedding celebration?
The Hidden Cloud will
also be sending a gift.
I ask the same of you.
I understand.
I'm sure Naruto will
be very happy.
Naruto…is getting married, huh?
We didn't hear anything about
Naruto getting married!
Temari, you were here just
a little while ago…
You must've heard about it!
Y-Yeah…
Why didn't you tell us?!
Shut up! I forgot, okay?!
What's come over you?
Y-You're being scary.
In any case, we should
prepare a wedding gift.
Since it will be from the Kazekage,
we should get something extravagant.
Extravagant, huh?
Do you think Naruto would
appreciate that?
You think Naruto wouldn't be happy
with something extravagant?
When you put it that way…
Gaara! It's been a very long time!
Yes, it certainly has.
We are going to show you
around the village
until Lord Mizukage arrives!
Hey, Lee.
He's here for
the Five Kage Conference
and we're on duty as well.
Don't get too casual.
No, let's not stand on ceremony.
We appreciate your company.
We're looking forward to it.
So, is there somewhere
you want to go first?
Let's see…
Actually, I want to know
what kinds of things Naruto likes.
What Naruto likes?
Let's see…
I know just the place!
I'll take you there now!
Great. Are you both coming?
Of course!
I'm just going to relax here.
It will be awkward if I run into him.
What's up, Temari?
You seem weirdly irritated…
There's nothing going on!
You guys just go!
Hello!
Oh! Welcome, Iruka Sensei!
I'd like a large miso char siu ramen.
Sure thing!
But, Iruka Sensei, you've been
coming around a lot lately.
Don't be rude, Ayame!
He's a very important customer!
What's going on with you?
You seem to be troubled.
Well…
Everyone's in a tizzy over
what to get Naruto
for his wedding gift for
the past few days.
It doesn't involve me
since I'm not a shinobi.
But I still want to give him something.
And I came up with…
this!
A free ramen pass?
Oh! Not this.
I see...He gets to eat free ramen
for a limited time.
I'm sure this'll make him
very happy.
But I wonder about a whole year…
A year is too long.
Too long…
It's the same with half a year.
Yeah, you're right…
I see.
You want to give Naruto
a wedding gift too?
He'll definitely be overjoyed!
So, does that mean
you have something already, Lee?
Of course!
I see.
This is the first time I'm getting
something like a wedding gift.
I don't have a clue
on what to get.
Then you must consider what
a wedding is in the first place!
What is a wedding ceremony?
What is absolutely necessary
for a wedding ceremony?
Wouldn't that be…love?
I'm getting a bad feeling
about this…
"What is a wedding ceremony?"
That's a very philosophical question.
Yes, it is.
So think about it this way…
What is absolutely necessary
for a wedding ceremony?
Absolutely necessary for
a wedding…?
Wouldn't that be…love?
Yes!
That was my answer too!
Why is this going exactly
the same way as before?!
However, my mentor whom
I greatly respect, Guy Sensei,
didn't stop there.
He realized that
it's the bride and groom
who are most important
in a wedding…
and if you put yourself
into their shoes,
you would see what would
be the best gift.
And the result of that was…
I got them dumbbells!
D-Dumbbells?
I'm only a shinobi…
so I think that's most suitable thing
for me to present.
However, Gaara, you are the Kazekage,
so we must consider your position.
So, I think some extravagant barbells
would be great!
B-Barbells, huh…
I don't know about barbells…
But I agree with
the "extravagant" part.
– Hello!
– Welcome!
Iruka Sensei!
Hey, Lee! We meet again!
Gaara, let me introduce Iruka Sensei,
Naruto's teacher.
Iruka Sensei,
this is Gaara the Kazekage!
H-How do you do?
Why is Lord Kazekage
with you two?
We've been assigned to show him
around the village
until the Five Kage Conference begins.
Gaara is also thinking about
a wedding gift for Naruto.
Naruto and Gaara are friends.
Friends?!
Anyway, we're going to send an extravagant
gift representative of the Hidden Sand.
I'm very grateful to
the Lord Kazekage
for making such
an extravagant gesture…
and I'm sure Naruto will
be overjoyed as well.
Now, if you will please excuse me.
See? Naruto's gonna be happy!
His own teacher confirmed that.
You think so?
One thing's for sure,
Naruto loves flashy things!
There's no way he won't be happy
with an extravagant gift.
I see…
I guess I'm gonna go
big and grand too,
and give him a year's free pass—
Father…
Y-Yes…
Pops, I'll have a large
miso char siu ramen!
What is that?
Naruto's favorite item
on the menu.
It has an extravagant helping
of char sui.
Even his ramen is extravagant?
Then I'll have that too.
Me too.
Okay, Pops…
A large miso char siu ramen
for all of us!
Hold it!
Make mine a regular,
without char siu, and for the topping…
Topping?
Seems Naruto fish cake
is ranked number one.
way back, it used to be
the least popular.
These days, it's Naruto fish cake,
hands down.
That's the kinda effect he's had.
Then I'll have the regular miso
ramen, with the Naruto fishcake topping.
Please add that to mine too.
All right! I'll give you an extravagant
helping of the topping!
Boy, did we eat.
Where would you like to go next?
Are you all right?
You've been deep in thought
this whole time.
I was thinking about what
to give Naruto as the Kazekage.
As the Kazekage?
Kankuro wants to give
something extravagant,
but that just doesn't sit right with me.
I see…
Hey, c'mon, Gaara…
But after listening to
Naruto's teacher
and the ramen shop's proprietor,
I'm convinced.
As long as it makes Naruto happy.
That's more like it!
I'll help in any way I can too!
– Huh?
Huh?
Hey, you Hidden Sand
and Leaf guys!
Guess who I am, yay!
What an awful rap…
You're Lord Killer Bee,
the bodyguard of Lord Raikage, right?
Isn't anyone accompanying you
in the village?
I prefer my freedom.
My brother's at
the conference reception.
Me, I prefer a village exploration.
By the way, Kazekage, are you
planning on giving Naruto a wedding gift?
Yes, I intend to.
Finding a gift is
my personal mission.
Let's do our best to make
a good decision, yay.
Sounds like the Hidden Cloud
are really into this.
Our gift will be something
to marvel at.
Listen well and remember that.
Seriously? Do you have to answer
in rap all the time?
Decorated for a special occasion…
Sake produced by the Hidden Cloud…
Ten giant kegs of which
we're proud, yay.
Hidden Cloud beef of
super high-quality…
We'll present it roasted whole,
in its entirety, yay.
Premium games…
The best of the best.
Ten great games, no less. Yay!
That sums up my presentation.
A wedding's an important celebration.
Yay.
A-Amazing!
I didn't get the details
because of your rap…
but I did get that
it'll be extravagant.
So what's the Hidden Sand getting?
Have you already ordered it?
Well…that's just it.
Okay! Okay!
I apologize, I should have realized…
Our gifts are so extravagant
that it's made you hesitant.
But that's not important.
Huh?
Doesn't matter
if it's not fancy,
what comes from the heart
is the best choice.
That's what'll make
Naruto rejoice, yay!
Don't patronize us!
K-Kankuro?!
We're gonna give a gift that
equals the Hidden Cloud's!
We plan to cover the reception hall
with flowers grown in the Hidden Sand!
And to highlight
the celebration dinner,
we'll send the finest tuna
in the land…a whole bluefin!
And we'll prepare boxes of sweets
as wedding favors for every guest!
How's that?!
Hold it. Who said anything about—?
Amazing!
You came up with all that
in such a short time!
No…we haven't decided—
Oh, I forgot something important.
Fool, ya fool.
For entertainment, Brother might perchance…
perform the "Hidden Cloud Dance."
Yay.
The Raikage…
The Hidden Cloud Dance, you say?!
No, no, no...no way, no way…
So now you get the drift…
How the party will get a lift, yay
T-This is bad! At this rate…
Gaara will lose!
No, giving a gift isn't
about winning or losing.
Dance...
Huh?
Show up the Raikage…
and dance too, Gaara!
That is the only way!
The Mizukage should be arriving soon.
Then we should call the Kazekage.
Lord Kakashi…
Drop the "lord."
We received a request to
adjust the entertainment time
allotted at Naruto and Hinata's
wedding reception.
Huh? What's that?
How come I wasn't told about
a wedding reception?!
At whose request?
It's from…Lord Raikage's bodyguard…
What?!
He mentioned
the "Hidden Cloud Dance" by the Raikage.
Okay! Gaara will do
the "Hidden Sand Samba."
Oh! This is getting more
and more exciting.
Stop joking. I can't dance.
Besides, it wouldn't make
Naruto happy.
Actually, I think he might take
the initiative and join in.
W-What…?!
Y-You're right.
Still…
The Kazekage shouldn't dance
in front of people!
But he said the Raikage
is going to dance!
The Raikage's gift of dance
is a must-see
If you miss this opportunity,
behind the times you'll be, yay.
That fool!
I beg your pardon if
I make a scene…
No, I doubt there will be
a need for you to intervene.
The Raikage's wedding gift
of dance is a must-see
If you miss this opportunity,
behind the times you'll be, yay.
Wedding...Behind the times?
I'll kill you.
I now call this Five Kage
Conference to order.
However, before we begin…
In regard to wedding gifts for
Naruto Uzumaki and Hinata Hyuga…
I ask that you use your good sense and
keep things in moderation.
And so, let's move on
to our agenda.
H-Hey…
S-Sorry about last time.
No...I'm sorry as well.
Want to get a bite to eat?
Might as well…
Lord Kazekage…
So, you were still here in the village!
The conference ran long…
So, I decided to stay the night.
I'm grateful that you've chosen
our ramen for dinner!
Well...I've never had anything
so delicious.
And I've never had such
a compliment.
By the way, I heard about
the remarks Lord Hokage made
about Naruto and Hinata's wedding gifts…
It was to be expected.
Things were getting out of hand.
I'm sure everyone's feeling
remorseful now.
Even I…
And I went overboard too.
I apologize.
Don't worry about it.
Oh! Iruka Sensei.
Welcome!
Lord Kazekage…
I just overheard you.
I want to apologize too.
But Naruto's teacher shouldn't…
When I met you last time…
I'm very grateful to
the Lord Kazekage
for making such
an extravagant gesture…
and I'm sure Naruto will
be overjoyed as well.
I'm at fault too,
for putting it like that.
I'm very sorry.
There's nothing to be sorry about!
I was just…simply happy.
I learned that Naruto
has wonderful friends
who will go above and beyond
to celebrate him.
Friends…huh.
Thank you very much.
No, I want to thank you too.
Huh?
I was confused,
and you've cleared it up for me.
I was thinking only
about appearances,
and forgot the most basic thing.
What do you mean?
I'm going to honor Naruto not
as the Kazekage,
but as his friend.
Would that be all right?
Of course.
A large miso char siu ramen
with Naruto fishcake topping!
Oh, thank you.
What'll you have, Iruka Sensei?
Make mine the same…
A large miso char siu ramen
with Naruto fishcake topping.
Coming right up!
Dad, I'm done cleaning up here.
Okay, thanks!
Not going home yet?
I'm gonna go on ahead.
Make sure you lock up!
All right...Finished!
Have a safe trip back home.
Gaara! Please come again!
It would be great if you come back
on your own next time,
and not on official
Kazekage business.
Yes, that won't be
too long from now.
For Naruto and Hinata's wedding.
I'm sorry, but I don't plan
on bringing
a special gift from
the Hidden Sand.
Huh? Why?
Let him finish!
I want to honor them personally,
as a friend.
I think that will please Naruto more.
Gaara!
Gaara…
Yes, please do that.
I think it turned out for the best.
Feels like everything's all settled!
You're in a good mood, Temari.
N-No, I'm not!
Besides, seeing you so depressed
is more shocking, Kankuro!
You can't blame him,
since we're not going all out
with an extravagant gift.
No, that doesn't bother me.
I'm just disappointed we won't get
to see you dance, Gaara.
No, there's still hope!
He can dance as Naruto's friend!
No chance.
Bugs are super gross!
There are bugs here too!
Bugs! Everywhere!
Good job.
What happened to the ones
who haven't returned?
What's up with these bugs?
Chase 'em away, Tsukune!
I can't stand bugs.
But these aren't ordinary bugs!
Cut it out, you guys.
It's because those insects
are my friends.
– These bugs are your friends?
What's up with this old guy?
Those kids!
This period is for extracurricular
work. Where did they go?
– Wow! Amazing!
Cool!
I've never seen
an Insect User before!
They'd be a huge hit at a party!
No way...The party would be
crawling with bugs.
It seems you don't like insects.
However, if you keep living with them,
you become quite attached to them.
Y-You're right...They're kinda cute.
I wanna try too!
Do you think you want to
become an Insect User?
Not gonna happen. This guy wants to
become the future Hokage.
The Hokage?
I wanna surpass Naruto Uzumaki
as a shinobi.
I see. Well, if you want to
surpass Naruto,
you'll have to become the Hokage.
You think so too?
Then I guess while I'm at it,
I'll become the Hokage too.
I know someone else who wants to
become the Hokage.
But kid, you're the top contender.
It's because I don't know anyone
who says he'll become the Hokage
as an afterthought.
Right? See I'm the top contender!
You just talk big!
Shut up! You just watch me
ten years from now!
Are you aiming to become
the Hokage too?
No, I never gave it a thought.
So, you wanted to become
an Insect User?
Yeah…that's right.
What's necessary
to realize a dream?
I want to take that first step
as soon as I can!
The first step in realizing
your dream is…
Hey, what time is it?
Uh-oh! We forgot about class!
You'd better hurry back.
And do your best to surpass Naruto.
Yeah! I'm gonna reach my dream,
just like you Big Bro!
See ya!
Dream…huh?
Sorry to keep you waiting.
You're late, Shino!
So? How'd it go?
It seems just about everyone's
gotten their wedding gift.
Oh yeah? I guess we'd better
decide soon too.
Hey, Shino…
Kakashi Sensei said
this was a mission, right?
I understand why Kakashi Sensei and
the others are putting it that way.
But to me,
this is a serious mission.
It's our final mission as Team 8.
Team 8's final mission…
Once Hinata gets married,
we won't get to work together
like the way we used to, right?
Yes…
That's true…
And I have to get serious
if I intend on becoming
the next Hokage.
I can't keep relying on you.
Yeah, let's keep it that way.
What do you mean by that?!
Sorry.
In any case, this is for Hinata,
our last mission as Team 8…
Right?
Right.
The question is…
what do we get them?
– Hmm…
A gift for Hinata, huh?
It's gonna be from us
to Hinata and Naruto.
What would make them happy?
Akakiba!
Akakiba and Kibamaru!
You're mixing up the names…
Give me a break, Mirai…
Rather than hot tea, I feel like
relaxing with some shochu.
Oh, that's right.
Speaking of alcohol,
have you heard about this story?
Back in the day,
the Senju Clan had a custom of
giving honey wine
as a wedding gift.
Long ago, the Senju Clan
who lived in the forest
discovered an unusual liquid
that was produced by chance
from rainwater
that collected in beehives.
And that was
the start of honey wine.
It was a nourishing, yet rare wine.
And since the olden days, it's been
served only during auspicious occasions.
Honey wine could be used as a
medicinal tonic as well as for cooking.
Hinata would find
some good uses for it.
She may appreciate
something like this!
And it conveys the wish
that Hinata and Naruto
spend their days in sweetness.
That's a cheesy joke.
Hinata wouldn't find it funny!
It's strange seeing you two
so lively without Hinata…
But I guess you'll get used to it.
Anyway, where do we find
this honey wine?
I heard there's a place
called Soraku.
And it seems the beekeeper
who lives there makes honey wine.
Finding people
is your specialty, right?
Okay, it's decided.
Let's go find this beekeeper.
Bye bye, Kibamaru! Akakiba!
It's Team 8's final mission!
Let's go, guys!
Our last mission, huh?
What a desolate place…
And it's pretty depressing too.
Sorry, it's so depressing, meow.
Judging from your headbands,
you're Hidden Leaf shinobi, meow?
You reek of dogs, you reek of bugs,
and you're a real dog.
Damn it, what a sorry bunch, meow.
A ninja cat?!
We're looking for a beekeeper
who lives in a place called Soraku.
We're not sketchy guys.
Meow, you're totally sketchy, meow!
I've got nothing to tell you, meow.
So that means you know where
this beekeeper is, right?
Okay, how about we catch it
and get the info out of it?
Let's do it, Akamaru!
Dumb humans, meow!
H-Hey!
Insect Summoning Jutsu!
Saved!
You're gonna mess around with us?!
Fine, then…
Tadah!
Here.
What is this?!
This is catnip.
It's very similar to silver vine.
Well?
Can't ignore it, can you?
Damn it…
My pride would never forgive me
if I got caught by someone
who reeks like a dog.
Hey!
Don't steal it!
You damn cat!
Momo!
Who are you guys?
How dare you chase after my Momo!
Must be that ninja cat's master.
Be careful, Kiba, Akamaru!
Oh…her name's Momo?
Fancy that…
My dog's name is Akamaru.
K-Kiba?
By any chance,
was my cat rude to you?
I'm so sorry.
No, no...She's a cute ninja cat.
Just a minute ago,
you called me a "damn cat."
My name is Tamaki.
I'm Kiba…
This is my ninja hound, Akamaru.
You're a ninja hound user?!
Amazing!
Oh, it's nothing.
Although…I'm on the inside track
to become the next Hokage.
The next Lord Hokage?!
What's really amazing!
Nah…
But what is an important person
like you doing in a place like this?
Actually…
Actually…we're looking for
a beekeeper who lives in Soraku.
Would you like me to guide you
part of the way?
You know him?
That would be great!
Right, Shino?
He lives in the bamboo grove
beyond here.
You probably
won't be able to find him.
Even cats get lost
in this grove, meow.
We're shinobi!
We won't get lost.
Well then, be careful.
Yeah! Thanks!
Yes, I know.
Intruders…
First, I'll track him with my nose.
And if I find him,
send in your insects.
That girl might be
talking about us.
Are you in love with her?
Huh?! Are you crazy?!
It's nothing like that!
This is a crucial time if I'm gonna
become the Hokage!
I have no time to fall in love!
You're easy to read.
Huh? What did you say?
Nothing. I just said I envy you.
Huh? Really?
And I have to get serious
if I intend to become
the next Hokage.
Kiba always talks big, and maybe
I viewed him with indifference…
However…
What's necessary
to realize a dream?
I want to take that first step
as soon as I can!
The first step in
realizing your dream…
Who am I to criticize anyone?
Once Hinata gets married,
we won't get to work together
like the way we used to, right?
"The way we used to," huh?
Kiba!
Hey, Kiba!
Where are you?!
Really? You guys don't know either?
This is definitely someone's jutsu…
Yellow jackets?!
What is this jutsu?!
You belong to the Aburame Clan
of Hidden Leaf Village.
Correct.
You're skilled to be able to
deceive me…
But how?
The poison should have…
The poison got me…
But it's not a problem.
It's because this amount of poison
won't kill me.
Well now, it's my loss.
It can't be helped.
I'm proud to die by the hand of
an Insect User of your caliber.
No, hold on.
I don't want your life.
I want your honey wine.
Thank you, how much do I owe you?
I don't want money.
You can take it. It means nothing.
I see…
Now, if you can tell me
the road back, I'd be grateful.
There is no road.
What do you mean?
Exactly what I said.
This bamboo grove is surrounded by
something like a barrier.
Once you step inside,
there's no way out.
You'll continue to wander through
an endless fog…that is all…
That's the kind of jutsu this is.
What?!
I'm sorry to tell you that
this jutsu cannot be broken.
Even if you kill me…
What do you mean?!
Originally, this mist contained
a special component
meant to lead people astray.
I incorporated a little of it
into my jutsu formula…
But that can't be why
you can't break the jutsu?
No…
But, the nasty thing
about this jutsu is…
…that it takes the doubt inside of
its victims and turns it into fog,
making it thicker and thicker…
What?!
Haven't you noticed?
This bamboo grove
makes people lose their way…
and when the jutsu is used,
a thicker fog
confuses them even more.
In other words,
this jutsu has no effect on someone
who has no doubts.
So…you're saying I have doubts?
Yeah! I'm gonna reach my dream,
just like you!
Once Hinata gets married,
we won't be working together
the way we used to, right?
It's strange seeing you two
so lively without Hinata…
But I guess you'll get used to it.
I understand…
I've been questioning
how to live as a shinobi
after Team 8 disbands
when Hinata gets married.
To be together always,
with my friends in Team 8.
That was my dream.
I see…
I was doubting myself…
You and I are alike.
I'm still lost
on this path called life.
So, how about it?
There is doubt,
but there is no suffering here.
I am finally living life now!
Your friends understand too!
It's okay to have doubts…
It's not your fault
that you have doubts…
Kiba...Hinata…
It's not necessary to move forward.
Abandon it all, and stay here
with your doubts.
If you agree, stay with us…
C'mon, Shino…
It's Team 8's final mission!
Let's go, guys!
No…
That's not what…I'm looking for…
What?
What I'm looking for is…
What I'm looking for…
…is to be with my friend
who keeps moving forward.
Not someone who stays
in the same place with me!
I can't be stuck here like this.
I have to return to the village
right away.
It's because…I have to attend
an important friend's wedding.
You think you can find
your way out of this fog?
When you're in so much doubt
about your life?!
Yeah.
To make sure he can walk
his path without worry,
I'm definitely gonna
find my path in life.
And I have no doubt about that!
An entrance…
No, it's the exit.
So, you were able to see the path
beyond the guardian deity of travelers.
I see...Then go quickly.
Before you lose the path.
Wait...You just said
you're living life now.
But is that really true?
What?
Someone who remains
stuck in the past,
and cannot see the future…
Is that really living?
I know people
who live every moment,
striving as hard as they could to
reach a goal that seems so far…
They're the ones
who are really living life.
That's my belief…
I'm shocked.
You're nothing like the quiet man
I thought you were…
You are very passionate
on the inside.
I feel like I'm being lectured
by my teacher.
What are you saying?
Now go.
In time, I will be like you…
Where have you been?!
You disappeared suddenly!
Sorry.
However, I got a hold of this.
Whoa! When did you—!
I was sure you were lost.
Yeah, I was lost.
But I've found my way.
It's because…
Anyway, let's take this home,
Akamaru!
What about that girl?
Huh?!
Why are you bringing
that up again?!
Sorry.
Damn it.
Maybe I'll write her.
Letters? How unlike you.
Huh? Why?!
There's nothing wrong with letters.
Right, Akamaru?!
Akamaru, not you too?!
Yikes! Bugs again!
It's so amazing!
Maybe I'll make my goal to
become an Insect User too.
Yeah…
I'd better get started too,
or I won't become the Hokage.
You're wrong, kid.
You've already taken that step.
Huh?
It's because…
Putting your goal into words…
…is the first step towards
realizing one's dream.
I got it!
Thanks, Big Bro!
Let's go!
Tsukune, come on!
Yeah!
Iruka Sensei…
You completely won over
those bad kids.
Maybe you should become a teacher.
A teacher?!
It's difficult even for us
to keep up with
mischievous kids like that
year after year.
You're quite impressive.
It's not that difficult for me.
It's because…
I've always been around…
…the bad kids…
Hmm…
What a dilemma…
What's the matter, Lord Kakashi?
Please, drop the "lord"!
Anyway, remember the mission
I assigned everyone?
Do I really have to
assess each thing?
Of course!
Oink oink.
The honey wine's really great,
it's perfect for
a special occasion.
You can tell Team 8
went all out for this.
And these gift certificates
for a dinner
and the hot springs vacation
is very thoughtful!
I wasn't expecting this
from Choji and Shikamaru.
They outdid themselves.
You can really see
the girls' personal tastes
reflected in their choices.
That's just cute…
but take a look at this.
It's unbelievable, right?
Oh, and Konohamaru hasn't even
turned in a report.
I-It turned out well, though.
Now they can be the ones on duty
on the day of the reception.
True, if I'm to assess the gifts
and make my selections,
these three should be
the candidates.
But it this really all right?
Kakashi Sensei?
Oh?!
Hinata! It's been awhile!
What's up?
I'm meeting up with Sakura
and the girls. It's been so long.
Your last ladies' get-together
as a single woman, huh?
How are your wedding plans going?
I take it Naruto's doing okay?
Huh? Oh, yes.
He's doing really well!
Where are you headed,
Kakashi Sensei?
I'm going to take a quick nap.
Oh...I'm sorry to have bothered you.
Please excuse me!
Oh…
Hmm…
What's the matter, Iruka Sensei?
Was the ramen bad?
No, no!
The ramen was delicious!
It's not that…
I knew you'd be here, Iruka Sensei!
K-Konohamaru!
This has gone on too long.
I really need to get
your congratulatory message!
Otherwise, I can't turn in
this video as my wedding gift!
I'm so sorry!
So, is that what
you're agonizing about?
Yes, I can't think of what to say.
Well, you're agonizing too much!
Get ready,
I'm gonna record you now!
H-Hey, wait!
Get it together, Iruka Sensei!
Konohamaru's right, Iruka Sensei.
How can anyone not know what to
say in a congratulatory message?
You're Naruto's teacher,
aren't you?!
That's the reason why!
– That's the reason?
Back when Lord Kazekage
came to Ichiraku…
I'm going to honor Naruto
not as the Kazekage,
but as his friend.
When I heard that,
I began to wonder in what role
should I celebrate him?
What do you mean?
What else? You're his teacher.
Without a doubt, you may all
see me as his "teacher."
That's right! So, hurry up
and let me record you,
or I can't finish it!
Yeah…
But I kind of feel like
it shouldn't be coming from
the point of view of
a teacher to his pupil.
I don't even know if it's right
to do this as his teacher, or not…
But I feel Naruto's a little
different than my other students.
And that's why I can't proceed
as a teacher.
And yet, I don't think
you can call us "friends"
in the way Lord Kakashi described.
Anyway, the more I think about it,
the more unsure I become
about my message for Naruto.
That's for sure…
You and Naruto being friends
doesn't feel quite right.
Anyways, I'm gonna charge you
for that bowl…
And? And?
Are all the preparations for
the reception finished?
Yes, most of it.
Anyways,
I'm so surprised the first one
out of our group to get married
are you and Naruto!
How is Naruto lately?
Is he helping you at all?
Of course!
More than Naruto, it's my father
who keeps telling me what I should do.
It's true about the father
of the bride being a pain.
I guess planning a wedding
is a huge task.
Of course it is!
Even with us…
Kakashi Sensei gave us that…
Ah!
Hey, Sakura!
What's the big idea—!
Even with us, Kakashi Sensei
gave us that mission…
Damn it!
– Oh!
– Ah! Ah!
What about Kakashi Sensei?
– Huh?!
– Er…um…
He's going through a lot trying to
wrap up all the missions
before the wedding.
That's all.
Yeah!
And unlike us, you already
have Naruto, so you're lucky.
That's all.
Yeah, that's right!
Well, I guess so.
So? So?
Are you going to wear a kimono?
You're gonna look so pretty
as a bride!
Yeah, yeah!
Hey, Hinata!
Long time no see!
Kiba, Shino!
Have you been doing all right?
Yeah! You two seem great as well!
Of course, since we'll soon be
celebrating your wedding soon.
It's because…
How's Naruto doing?!
We rarely see him these days.
I guess he's busy getting ready
for the big day.
Yes.
Naruto's busy with his missions,
but he's been helping a lot
with the reception.
He's really dependable.
Oh, yeah?
Well, we're completing
a huge mission
and we're gonna make you happy…
Kiba!
Huh?
Oh!
Make me what?
Anyways…
What he means is you and Naruto
will definitely make a happy home!
We're looking forward
to the reception!
Oh, thank you.
Lady Tsunade!
It's been a while, Shizune!
How have you been?
Great, thank you!
How has your wagering
been going lately?
There's Naruto and Hinata's
upcoming wedding,
so I'm not spending excessively.
That is a wise decision.
Anyway, what did you
want to discuss?
Yes…
Actually, it's about Lord Kakashi…
Kakashi?
What's the matter with Lord Sixth?
I have no choice…
I don't have footage
of Iruka Sensei,
but I'll report this as
my wedding gift for the time being.
Wedding gift items?!
Yes, in addition to shinobi
gathering for the reception,
there's the standing rule to assess
the gifts everyone will be presenting
in order to determine who will
be attending the wedding, correct?
I remember that rule…
Lord Kakashi has been
in a dilemma about
how he will judge and
who he will eliminate.
When you think about it,
having anyone
not being able to attend,
will make Naruto and Hinata
very sad.
And yet, someone still has to go on
missions and be on guard that day.
He's worrying about that?!
Damn it.
This is really bad!
Everyone's acting a little weird.
Hey! I'm not lying!
Our gifts will be judged to determine
who can attend the reception?
What's the meaning of this?
I don't get it at all!
Please stop!
I'm not to blame for this!
This is the worst!
Well…it's like this…
Most shinobi of the village
will attend
Naruto and Hinata's reception.
That said, it doesn't mean that
we won't have missions on that day.
We'll need people on duty.
Plus, we'll have important guests.
And it'll be crucial to have
sufficient security for the reception.
That's right.
Many of Naruto and Hinata's friends
are top-ranked jonin.
So, what does that mean?
We'll have to draw lots to see
who can attend the wedding?!
No way!
If that's the case, we won't be able
to truly celebrate with the couple!
I didn't think our wedding would
cause so much trouble…
It seems this is troubling
Kakashi Sensei as well.
I see how it would.
Why did it turn into
such a big affair?
Naruto's someone who connects
the entire village.
So, I guess it would
turn into a big deal.
So, we just sit and wait
until the final judgement?
There's no need for that.
I'll do the dirty work,
and that'll be that.
Yes! I want everyone
to attend the reception, so…
I'll volunteer for duty!
That's right! I'll do it too!
Fine, I'll sign me up too.
That's not right!
If Team 8 isn't there,
Hinata will be sad.
But, I'm not okay with someone
missing the reception
just so we can.
We feel the same way.
Now then,
sleeping won't solve anything.
Kakashi Sensei!
I'm so sorry!
Huh?
What?
W-What's wrong, Hinata?
What happened?
I just heard…
The dilemma you're going through,
all because our wedding reception.
Huh? What?
What's this about?
You haven't decided
who can attend on that day, right?
What? You heard?
Yes!
About the mission too?
Yes.
Everything?
I see…
We would never want to
put anyone through any trouble,
just to celebrate our wedding day.
No, no, no, no!
We have to have a reception
for you two!
Then is it possible, at least…
…to have the Hyuga Clan fulfill
the missions and guard duty
for that day?
There's no need for that!
Huh?!
The day of your wedding
is a happy day
for your clan too, right?
It's my duty as the Hokage
to make sure
every member of your family
is there for you.
I…see.
I'll do something about
duty assignments.
So don't worry about anything.
All right.
Focus on yourselves, that's all.
Oops, I'd better get back!
See you!
What?!
What's going on, you guys?
We heard.
About Naruto and Hinata's
reception…
And that some of us
won't be able to attend.
And the mission to find the wedding
gifts was in order to assess them.
I see...So, you all found out too.
And also, that you've been
agonizing over this.
It's my job as the Hokage.
And what about it?
You're here to oppose?
No, actually the opposite!
What?
Everyone here will handle
the assignments.
But if you do that,
Naruto and Hinata
are sure to be sad.
That's why we're all going to
the wedding reception.
What do you mean?
Simply put, we'll make a schedule
of assignments and guard duty,
and work in shifts.
If everyone puts in some time,
everyone can wish them well!
Helping each other out
is something Naruto taught us.
Well?
This way, you won't have to bear the
all the burden, right Kakashi Sensei?
You guys…
Thank you!
But if we do this,
we'll have to change the rule.
Don't worry.
Through hell or high water,
I'll think of something.
You'll drown…
Besides, there won't be a need
for all that.
Lady Tsunade.
Lord Sixth…
Actually that rule
was put into effect
when there was a sudden
upswing in weddings…
…and there was
a serious shortage of manpower.
In addition, that was during
the Great Ninja War.
The situation is different today.
And more importantly,
the present Hokage is you, Kakashi.
Don't get caught up in old rules.
Choose the path that you believe
is most fair and just.
Then you'll choose to
let us all work, right?
That won't do.
Why not?!
My job is
to ensure that anyone who wants to
celebrate with Naruto and Hinata,
is able to attend.
I won't allow any early departures
or any late arrivals.
But there's no way around it.
I'll do something.
Hinata?
If it isn't Hinata!
Iruka Sensei…
What?!
Did Naruto do something?!
Huh?
Forgive me, Hinata!
I never taught him about
how to treat women!
I mean, I don't even know
about that kind of thing!
I don't know what happened,
but please…
For me…
Please forgive Naruto!
I beg of you!
What's so funny?
Iruka Sensei…
I didn't say anything,
but you decided that Naruto
must've done something bad
and started to apologize…
Oh? That's not it?
It didn't even cross my mind
that having a wedding
would trouble so many people.
But thinking back on this,
I guess I should have known.
It's not just for us…
but Naruto's a hero that connects
every village together.
I was probably being naïve
just thinking about marrying
the man I'd loved for so long.
You're wrong, Hinata!
Huh?
No matter how great he becomes,
no matter how big a hero
he becomes,
Naruto will always be Naruto…
To me and to everyone.
Iruka Sensei…
Nothing will change our desire to
wish the best for you and Naruto…
So, don't think of it
as a big fuss.
Yes!
I see…
I feel bad for
what I put Hinata through.
I'm sorry too, Iruka Sensei.
Oh no, I understand how
Hinata feels too.
Naruto's someone that connects
everyone in every village together.
Every village…
Thank you, Iruka Sensei!
I know what I have to do!
Huh? What do you mean?
I just have to
bow my head a little, that's all.
Iruka Sensei!
I know you're in there!
At this rate, I'll be the only one
without a wedding gift!
What is it?
Now that Hinata's found out about
the wedding gifts from everyone…
it's no longer a surprise.
So Konohamaru, I think
I'm going to put you to work!
Huh? Huh?
What is it?
And so,
would it be possible to dispatch
some Hidden Sand shinobi
on the day of the wedding?
I kindly implore you.
Please raise your head, Lord Sixth.
The Raikage, Tsuchikage
and Mizukage,
and I have all been thinking about
what we can do.
We didn't want to overdo things…
I plan on celebrating with them
personally as Naruto's friend,
but I also wanted to do something
as the Kazekage.
Now then, we'll gladly cooperate.
This is all possible because of
the peaceful bond that was forged…
And it was through
Naruto's strength.
It's only fitting that we help
to make Naruto's wedding
a great success.
Thank you very much.
Then may I be so bold
as to ask for one more favor?
What is it? Please tell me.
Konohamaru! Come here!
Yes, sir!
Oh, a video message!
Gaara, say something!
Say what?
Like a proverb or something!
I can't come up with
something just like that!
Come on! You're no Kazekage if
you can't come up with a proverb!
That's right.
Iruka Sensei, what's this all about?
Remember, you recorded me before?
Huh? Oh yeah…
That boring message with no
style or punch?
Congratulations on your marriage.
C'mon, don't say that.
Could you just use that one?
But you said you wanted
to re-do it,
so I've been waiting around
this whole time!
I'm sorry about that.
But the more I think about it,
the less sure I am about
what to say to Naruto.
But you held out for so long,
so you should just
make up your mind
and send him a cool,
heartfelt message, okay?
You're the only one left!
I'm sorry. I'll treat to you a bowl of
ramen next time, so please forgive me!
Okay?
Hey! Tsukune, Sansho, Mibuna!
You were messing around with the
Third Hokage's statue again, weren't you?!
I can't believe it's almost next week…
Naruto's wedding.
Will you be making
an official congratulatory speech?
Oh no...I think Lord Hokage
will be taking care of that.
Iruka Sensei!
Oh, you're Ichiraku's—!
Is anything the matter?
You haven't been around
at all lately.
Oh, I just wanted to hold off
until I figured out
what to say for the message
that Konohamaru asked me to do.
I have to practice some self-restraint.
So…Did you finish your message?
Well…uh…
I'll stop by again soon.
Please say hello to your dad.
What? That's easy!
Then can you jump to here?!
Oww!
I knew it.
Shut up!
I won't lose at fence-jumping though!
It's all thanks to you.
You acknowledged me back then.
That was the first time.
That's why, I am who I am today.
I was able to change.
Naruto expressed
his feelings so directly.
What am I doing?
Oh man…
I really shouldn't do things
I'm not used to!
Huh?
Yes?
Naruto!
H-Hey, Iruka Sensei…
W-What's wrong?
Nothing. It's…well…
I was thinking about you.
And I just stopped by
to see if you were alive!
What the hell's that about?
You know,
I'm gonna be getting married.
And you're still single and all,
so I was worried about you
being alone.
I'm coming in!
Hey, wait! I'm in the middle of…
What happened?
Uh, just some stuff.
But what about you?
What's going on?
Uh…well…
Oh yeah! R-Ramen!
Want to go get some ramen?
Ramen?
Actually, I'm making dinner
right now.
Oh, that explains
this crime scene right here.
Y-Yeah…
You really should hurry up
and get married, Iruka Sensei!
Shut up!
What about you?
Are you sure you should
be neglecting Hinata right now?
"Neglecting"?
We're not married yet,
so don't worry about it.
Don't worry about it?
My single days are numbered!
I'm gonna have fun
with everything I've got—
You fool!
Do you even have a clue about
how hard Hinata is working,
preparing for your wedding?!
What's wrong, Iruka Sensei?
It seems there were a lot of things
I failed to teach you
on how to be a human!
I take full responsibility!
Come with me!
I'm gonna knock some sense
into you!
Huh?
Where are we going, Iruka Sensei?!
To Hinata's!
I'm going to apologize to her
for raising you into such
a thoughtless man.
Please stop!
If Hinata's around,
I won't be able to say
what I wanted to talk to you about!
What do you want to talk about?
T-That's why I thought
we could have some ramen,
and you could have
a drink or two…
and we could have
an enjoyable conversation and
have some fun.
Enough.
I guess I didn't need to mull over
what to say and
how to congratulate you.
I have a request…
A request?
Will you attend the ceremony
as my father?
Naruto…?
Is that what you wanted
to talk about?
You can leave it to me!
Iruka Sensei!
Thank you.
What are you talking about, Naruto?
I should be saying that.
Thank you!
Cut it out.
See you later, Iruka Sensei!
Yeah!
Good evening…
– Hey!
– Oh…
– Welcome!
– What's going on?
Something troublin' you again?
Huh? No…
I was just thinking about how glad
I am I chose this profession.
I see.
So, what'll you have today?
Oh! A large miso char siu ramen topped
with naruto fishcake.
One large miso char siu ramen!
Okay, one large-size miso
char siu ramen coming right up!
Hinata!
Iruka Sensei?
How are the preparations going?
Just about all done.
Now, we just have to wait
for the big day.
That's good.
Anyway, I…
have something to tell you.
It's about the wedding ceremony…
You're going to attend
as Naruto's father, aren't you?
Oh, you knew?
Yeah, of course you would!
Seems it was on Naruto's mind
for a long time.
You're definitely
Naruto's teacher, Iruka Sensei.
But he didn't want to consider
your relationship
simply as a "student-teacher"
or "mentor" relationship.
Huh?!
But I kind of feel like
it shouldn't be coming
from the point of view
of a teacher to his student.
Naruto was thinking
the same thing as I was.
And so, his answer was to ask me
to attend as his father.
Yes.
And so, please continue
to support him, Father!
Y-Yes…
It's sort of embarrassing
to be asked so formally.
So anyway…
What is this?
It's not much, but please put it
toward the reception fees.
What?!
Naruto asked me to stand in
as his father.
I have to do this much, at least.
Please don't worry about that!
Please!
I-Is that so?
I guess I'll just have to
accept your answer
and wait for the big day.
I wish I could've done something
fatherly though…
W-What is it?
You look just like my father,
with that expression.
You're already acting like
the father of the groom.
Y-You think so?
3…2…
1…
Rolling!
Naruto, Hinata…
Congratulations on your wedding!
Naruto!
What's the matter, Iruka Sensei?
Lost for words again?
Oh, sorry, sorry.
This time, I'll do it right!
So can I start over,
just one more time?
Naruto, Hinata…
Congratulations on your wedding!
Please create a home
as bright as the morning sun!
May you always be happy!
Happy wedding!
Congratulations!
Do your best!
Don't gorge yourself on
delicious home-cooked meals!
Congratulations.
Congratulations!
Mr. Naruto! Miss Hinata!
Congratulations on your wedding!
Stop by once in a while for
miso char siu ramen, okay?
Congratulations, you two.
Congratulations!
Naruto, Miss Hinata…
A lot of things have happened,
But congratulations on your wedding.
Big Brother Naruto, you did it!
I'm gonna do my best too!
Naruto Uzumaki,
congratulations on your wedding.
Dear Naruto, do your best.
Yeah!
Naruto, Hinata…
Congratulations on your wedding!
Help each other and may you
have long lasting happiness!
Naruto! Hinata!
Congratulations on your wedding!
Hinata, Naruto is absent-minded
and reckless
and will need your support.
I ask you to
please take care of him!
Naruto, I just have this
to say to you…
You better make Hinata happy!
Okay! That was perfect!
Phew…
It went without a hitch!
Uh…
Could you get
the receiving desk set up?
Lord Kakashi!
Like I said, drop the "lord."
The Lords Kage have arrived.
Huh? Already?!
Shall I escort them?
Yes. It's rude to keep them waiting.
Huh?
Hey, Kazekage entourage!
We're the Lightning entourage…
Here to give our wedding blessings.
So forget the past…
Let's be friends 'til the last.
Of course!
I don't feel like fighting
like brats anymore.
Oh say, see my gift
and be surprised
Even the couple will rapturize.
Enough already!
The reception desk is now open.
– Hey, where'd Temari go?
– Please sign in, in order of arrival.
I haven't seen her since we came.
How much are you giving them,
Ebisu Sensei?
Well, it's accepted etiquette
for working adults like us
to give about…
Huh?!
It's okay to give that little?
I put five bills in my envelope.
What?!
Did you say five?!
I'll lose face as a teacher.
You mean, our wedding gift?
We'll be giving…
…this!
Not that one, Dad!
Huh? Oh…this one.
Seriously?
Now listen, Lee!
When we honor people,
we hone our mind and spirit.
That's what a reception's for!
What you mean is, to
never forget to train, even at a party!
Naturally!
Look, people are staring like
you're weird, so will you cut it out?
We'll start with dumbbell juggling!
Let's go!
Yes, Guy Sensei!
What a day! What a joyous day!
Yes! This training is especially joyous!
You two have too much joy
in your heads!
So? Did you get a hold
of the honey wine?
Of course!
We're gonna tell Naruto about
the history of the Senju Clan.
You're that versed in history
to do that?
Huh?! Well, yeah…
Why don't you run it by me first?
Well, that's…uh.
Giddy up!
Run!
Mirai, what are you doing?
Playing horsey-back!
Akamaru is a dog.
You can't ride a dog and
call it horsey-back riding.
Then, doggie-back riding!
True, it is doggie-back riding.
But Akamaru looks a little tired.
You might want to come down.
It's because…
No! I wanna ride some more!
I guess I have no choice.
Let's go Shino-back riding, then.
– Was Shino always that good
with little kids? – Higher! Higher!
Seems he thinks he might
be suited to teaching.
What are you smiling about?
Who said I was smiling?
Whatever…
Men go to wedding receptions
to meet the friends of the bride,
don't they?
That's not it.
What a drag! Let's go over there.
Hey!
Oh, sweet!
It's definitely gonna be sweet.
When did they hook up?
Who are you talking about?
Shikamaru and Temari…
Did you know they were like that?
Hmm.
Anyway, everyone probably
thinks about us the same way.
Sasuke…
What's the matter, Iruka Sensei?
Is something still worrying you?
Well…
It's going to be all right.
Thanks to you, Iruka Sensei,
we have guard duty covered
with enough shinobi.
No, that was all you, Kakashi.
No, I didn't do anything.
I just helped a little.
It's all thanks to the bonds
Naruto forged.
Naruto's here, and
that's why everyone is here today.
I'm sure he will make Hinata happy.
Are you still worried?
Well…
I forgot to prepare
my final message.
Brother Neji…
I'm going to get married.
Elder Sister! It's time!
All right!
Wow!
You look so beautiful, Elder Sister!
Doesn't she, Father?
Okay, ready to go?