There's something kind
of creepy about this place.
This place is called the Forest of Death.
You'll soon find out why.
That threat won't work on me!
I'm not scared!
You've got a lot of energy.
A kid like you will be the first to die,
spilling all that blood I love.
I'm here to return your kunai.
Thanks for the trouble...
However... you shouldn't stand behind me
while reeking of such bloodlust.
If you don't want a quick death...
I tend to get excited
at the sight of blood.
And my precious hair was cut,
so I got a little excited...
Naruto...
I'm sorry...
Wh-What's with that proctor?
Seriously, she's a psycho!
This one, too...
And what's with that woman's long tongue?
Looks like we've got a lot of
hot-blooded kids this time.
Well, before we start the second test,
I have something to hand out.
It's a consent form,
From this point on,
people will die.
And for that, I need your consent!
Otherwise, I'd be held responsible.
All right! I'm going to start explaining
the second test to you.
To put it simply, this is an extreme
survival test.
A no-holds-barred battle for scrolls!
The Heaven Scroll and the Earth Scroll.
Your job will be fighting for them.
There are 78 of you, in 26 teams.
Half the teams, or 13,
will be given Heaven Scrolls.
The other half will be
given Earth Scrolls.
Each team will have
one of the scrolls.
The objective is...
to acquire both scrolls
and bring them to the central tower
as a team.
For this second test,
the time limit is 120 hours.
You have exactly five days!
Five days?!
What do we do about food?
You'll have to fend for yourselves!
The forest has everything you need to survive.
There's more than enough food...
However...
It's teeming with fierce
man-eating animals,
poisonous bugs, poisonous plants...
the list goes on.
On top of that, you're surrounded
by nothing but enemies,
you'll even have trouble
getting any sleep...
And aside from injuries sustained
while fighting for the scrolls...
there will be contestants
who can't endure the harsh environment.
Next, the conditions for disqualification.
Rule 1: If all three members
of the team can't make it to the tower
with the Heaven and Earth Scrolls
within the time limit.
Rule 2: If a team loses a member,
or a member becomes incapacitated.
And one more thing...
Absolutely do not look at
the contents of the scrolls
until you have reached the tower!
Wh-What happens if we peek inside
before we get there?
You're welcome to take a peek
and find... out.
Huh?
A Chunin is often entrusted
with top-secret documents.
This is a test of your integrity.
That concludes the explanation!
Exchange your team's three consent forms
for one scroll at that hut over there.
After that, pick your entrance,
and all gates will open simultaneously
I see, so you won't know which
scroll was given to each team...
and you won't know which of the three
members is carrying the scroll.
If what Ibiki said was right,
this test is a life-or-death
battle of information.
Which means it's possible
we'll have to kill.
Looks like they're starting to understand
the meaning of these consent forms...
Yeah! Survival is our forte!
Hinata, don't let them see
you're scared.
Uh, okay...
Life or death...
What a drag...
but I guess we have no choice.
Now that we're here,
let's make Naruto our target.
For snacks, I brought some potato chips...
- And a shortcake.
- You two are unbelievable!
All right! I'm not going to lose!
I'll take down
anyone who gets in my way.
Heh heh... The time has finally come.
We have the chance to truly begin
our mission.
Sure, the enemy teams are scary but,
I'm more scared of spending
five days with him.
Target the rookies first.
Now that they've said
killing is allowed,
that makes things easier.
Guy-sensei, I'll do my best!
I'll absolutely succeed!
We now start the second
test of the Chunin Exam!
Look for the brats!
Those three, right?
All right! Let's go!
Okay! First, let's start tracking.
Can you do it, Hinata?
Yes.
Byakugan!
Slow down, Lee!
We just started.
I know. But...
I can't stay still!
Who knows what kind of
powerful foes are waiting for us.
Hot-blooded fool...
As you already understand,
we have only one target!
Anyway, the tower is the
goal for everyone, right?
Then it would be smart to set up
traps near the tower.
Heh... kids.
Standing out in the open like that,
they're just asking to be found.
What happened?
You're pale.
Wh-What is that?!
The Leaf's flying leeches sense
body heat and perspiration,
then, in a mass, swoop down
on their prey.
If they continue to suck
your blood for five minutes,
you'll be dead.
It sounds like they've already started.
Wasn't that someone screaming
just now?
I-It's nothing to worry about, Sakura.
I-I have to pee...
Y-You... idiot!
What are you doing
in front of a lady!
Go do it in the bushes!
Aaah, that was a lot!
I feel so much better.
I told you, not in front of a lady!
S-Sasuke... That's too much.
You don't have to go this far.
Wh-What was that for...?
What are you doing all of a sudden?!
Speak! Where's the real Naruto!
I have no idea what
you're talking about!
What happened to the scratch
on your face?
Your shuriken holster
is on your left leg
and you're not right-handed!
Unlucky for me! So you figured it out.
In that case...
Which one of you has the scroll?!
Looks like I'll have to use force, then!
Fire Style: Phoenix Flower Jutsu!
Heeeey! Sasuke!
You've got to be kidding me, you loser.
All right!
I caught you off guard! Lucky!
Paper bomb!
This is lucky!
Move and you're dead!
Now hand over the scroll, nice and easy!
I won't let you get away!
You're always so late, Naruto!
Absorbing it with my chakra.
Sasuke...
Don't just stand there, Sakura!
There's no guarantee this guy's alone!
Got it?!
Let your guard down for a second
and you're dead.
Unlucky... I came alone
to remain hidden,
but that just backfired...
He got away, huh?
If there's an instance that
we become separated,
don't trust someone just because
they look like one of us.
Just like now there's a possibility
that an enemy will transform
to get close to us!
- Yeah.
- So what do we do?
We'll decide on a password.
Password?
Listen, if the password is incorrect,
no matter what he looks like...
presume he is an enemy!
I'll only say it once, so listen closely.
You ask:
"Ninja verse, ninja chance."
And the answer is this:
"When enemies are many and their movements
unknown, wait and watch for an opportunity."
"If there are no enemies in a quiet place,
do not conceal your presence."
"For a shinobi, knowing
the right time is everything."
"Strike when the enemy is tired and
lets their guard down."
That's it.
Okay!
See? Brains are what
matter most for survival!
Right, Akamaru?
Lucky for us,
the guys who got caught in
the trap had an Earth scroll!
We'll be the first
to the tower at this rate!
Don't get carried away.
That's dangerous.
Even the smallest insect must
always remain on guard.
We have to pay attention to avoid
coming across any enemies...
This is a path to safety.
I know that!
Man, you always talk in riddles. Can't you
just talk like a normal person, you bug freak.
Um... B-But...
What Shino said...
He has a point.
I know! C'mon.
Naruto...
I hope nothing's happened to him...
Hey you two, stop!
Byakugan!
There's someone there.
It seems there are... six people...
Okay! Let's go look!
Huh?
Kiba! What are you saying?
We're not doing that.
The proctor said we need one "Heaven"
and one "Earth" scroll to pass.
She didn't say we couldn't
take more than that.
If we take more, that means
some other teams will be left out.
B-But...
We'll just see what's going on first...
If it looks too dangerous,
we won't pick an unnecessary fight.
- Let's go!
- Oh!
What's up, Akamaru?
What happened? You stopped suddenly.
Akamaru suddenly got frightened.
Wh-Why is that?
Akamaru can gauge an enemy's
strength by the scent of their chakra.
But this is the first time
I've seen him this scared.
The people fighting up ahead
are no ordinary shinobi.
Some brats from the Sand village
are challenging us.
It's foolish.
What's with that redhead?
Picking a fight with those guys...
Hey brats, you should have
chosen your opponents more carefully.
Now, you're all going to die.
Which scroll do those guys have...
Hey Gaara!
Shouldn't we follow them
and gather information before we attack?
If they have the same scroll as us,
there's no point in fighting.
Unnecessary battles are just...
It doesn't matter.
Once they've met my gaze...
I kill them.
Well, let's do it. Quickly!
Die, kid!
Ninja Art: Senbon Rainstorm!
Up, down, right, left – there are
no blind spots with this jutsu.
Not only that, all the senbon
are controlled by my chakra
and attack their intended prey!
Is that all?
I-It can't be...
Not a single one?
Not a scratch? Impossible!
Senbon Rainstorm, huh?
Then... I'll make it rain blood.
A wall of sand?
You guys can't defeat our Gaara.
Don't underestimate me!
This guy's a goner...
That's what you get
for rebelling against Gaara...
Sand Coffin!
I can't move!
Let me go!
I can cover your loud
mouth and kill you...
But that would be no fun at all.
Sand Burial!
There's no pain.
I applied more pressure than necessary
and crushed him to death.
T-The scroll...
We'll give it to you!
Please, just let us go!
N-No!
This is bad.
Let's escape quickly!
If he finds us he'll kill us!
Lucky. It's a Heaven scroll.
Okay. Let's go to the tower.
Shut up.
It's still... not enough.
U-Uh oh!
Did he notice us?
Let's quit... Gaara.
Are you scared, coward?
Gaara!
It's certainly no problem for you,
but it's dangerous for us!
One set of scrolls is enough!
More than that, this is...
Don't give me orders, you weakling.
That's enough!
Why don't you listen
to your big brother for once?!
I have never once thought of you
as my brother.
If you get in my way... I'll kill you.
G-Gaara, cut it out! Please...
Don't say something so cold.
For your sister's sake... Please?
Fine.
This why I hate brats.
What? So that was it, Akamaru?
C'mon, you should've told me sooner!
I'll carry the scroll!
Hey, wait Sasuke.
Ouch!
A new enemy?!
Go on and play around...
I'll do this alone...
Sakura!
Sasuke!
Don't come closer!
First the password...
"Ninja verse, ninja chance!"
Ah! Umm...
"When enemies are many and their movements
unknown, wait and watch for an opportunity."
"If there are no enemies in a quiet place,
do not conceal your presence."
"For a shinobi, knowing
the right time is everything."
"Strike when the enemy is tired and
lets their guard down."
Good.
Owwww!
Hey, are you two okay?
Naruto, wait!
The password...
"When enemies are many and their movements
unknown, wait and watch for an opportunity."
"If there are no enemies in a quiet place,
do not conceal your presence."
"For a shinobi, knowing
the right time is everything."
"Strike when the enemy is tired and
lets their guard down."
- What?!
- Huh?!
What are you doing?!
So, you're someone who
can dodge my attacks, huh?
What are you saying, Sasuke?
Naruto just said
the password properly.
The fact that he could recite it
perfectly is the problem!
There's no way he could
memorize such a long password.
Oh!
That's how it is, huh...
But if you knew he would forget it,
why didn't you just make
the password shorter?
I knew that you were
underground
listening to everything we said.
I see. So you're not tired
or letting your guard down.
This might be more fun than I thought.
Huh?
Owww
And heave!
Huh? Where are Sakura and Sasuke?
S-So huge!
This is the first time I've seen...
a snake this huge!
Behind?!
T-Tail!
You want our Earth Scroll,
don't you?
'Cause you have the Heaven Scroll.
Well, let's begin...
the battle for the Scrolls.
A life-or-death battle!
Genjutsu?!
No, that's not it.
This is pure killing intent.
What's going on?
Just by looking in her eyes...
I saw my own death.
Who is this... woman?!
Sa... kura?
If we don't move,
the only thing waiting for us is...
Death!
Can't move already?
She's going to kill me!
Move... move... move!
Move!
Move! Move!
Even if it's just a little...
Move!
What do you intend to do... with that?
Don't you worry.
I'll finish this in an instant.
You won't even have
time to feel the pain.
Move!
He's using pain to overcome his fear.
Just as I expected,
he's no ordinary prey.
Let me out! Hey!
Spit... me... out!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
I'm a shinobi who will become Hokage!
I'm not going to die and become
snake food in a place like this!
Sasuke, are you all right?
We have to get away quickly,
or we'll be discovered.
How do we make our escape?
How do we get away?
Sasuke is so shaken up.
I've never seen him like this.
Sasuke, a snake!
I was so distracted;
I didn't even notice the snake.
Stay away!
You can't let your guard down
for even a second.
When you're the prey,
you become tense
before the predator.
I'm sorry, Sasuke...
I forgot the password.
Naruto!
You may think
you're paying me back
by coming here to rescue me...
Just stay out of it!
This is way out of your league!
His coming here doesn't help
the situation at all.
What do I do?
There's no other way!
I'll give you the scroll.
So please, take it and go.
What?! Sasuke!
Have you gone crazy?!
What's the point of giving
the enemy the scroll?!
I see...
Well, in order to
escape a predator,
the only way for prey to save
itself...
is to offer the predator
a different meal.
Take it!
You jerk! Stop interfering!
Don't you understand
the situation?!
What the hell are you doing?!
I forgot the password.
So there's no way I can confirm it.
But you're not the Sasuke I know,
are you?!
You loser...
I'm the real one!
Don't lie!
The Sasuke I know isn't a coward
who'd do something so stupid!
I don't know how strong
this guy is.
But where's the guarantee
that she'll let us go
after we give her the scroll?!
You're the one who doesn't
understand the situation
because you're too scared!
Naruto...
You are right.
A scroll can be easily...
obtained by killing for it.
Quit joking around!
Stop it! Get out of here, Naruto.
Summoning Jutsu!
Naruto!
For now, stay put.
Damn it! Take this!
That's Naruto?
This brat... impossible!
This is getting interesting.
Sasuke, you're next!
What will you do?!
Hey, are you hurt... scaredy-cat?
There are three corpses.
This is some kind of jutsu,
isn't it?
This is bad.
Inform Anko,
the proctor of the second test.
Yes, sir!
You know, when it comes to dango,
nothing beats anko paste!
With this setup, the quicker kids
should clear it soon.
The Leaf Village mark, perfect!
We have a problem, Ms. Anko!
Huh? What, so suddenly?
Corpses! Three of them!
Moreover, they're strange.
Anyway, please come!
Strange?
Show me the photos of these three
from the Village Hidden in the Grass.
It's on their applications.
Yes!
So he stole this one's face.
Then, at that time it was already...
I'll return... the kunai.
We're in big trouble.
Huh?!
Communicate this to
Lord Hokage right away!
Send for the ANBU Black Ops
to assemble more than two squads
to the Forest of Death!
Starting now,
I'm going to follow these guys!
Got it?
Yes!
That guy...
That man...
he's in the Hidden Leaf Village!
Huh?!
Damn it!
Let me go!
You stupid snake!
To think the Nine-Tails kid was
alive all this time...
When he gets excited, a little bit
of the Nine-Tails' power leaks out...
He's grown into quite
an interesting specimen.
Look...
The Seal is appearing on
your skin like a tattoo.
Five-Pronged Seal!
Sasuke! Help Naruto!
Twelve years since the seal...
Naruto's chakra and the Nine-Tails'
chakra are beginning to synchronize...
But now... you're in the way.
He's going to fall at this rate!
Naruto!
What happened Sasuke?!
Naruto's certainly different
from you, Sasuke.
He's reckless and
always messing things up.
But, he's never been a coward!
You know that, don't you?
Just what I'd expect from the Uchiha clan...
His blood has begun to stir...
I should take my time and
confirm his true power.
But it's me who was being stupid.
Naruto!
Sakura!
How can someone who can't put his life
on the line at a place like this...
defeat that man?!
I can see.
I can see!
I can see you!
It's pretty good...
You can see my moves, can't you?
I got you!
A substitution!
Sasuke!
Humph!
That was too easy.
You bring shame to the Uchiha name.
That's okay.
I'll just take my time and play
with you before I kill you...
Like a worm.
Fire Style: Dragon Flame Jutsu!
He did it!
Sasuke!
You did it!
You okay?
Hang on.
Paralysis?
You are truly a member
of the Uchiha clan.
I do want you, after all.
You're definitely his brother.
Your eyes hold more potential
than even Itachi's.
Who in the world are you?
My name is Orochimaru...
If you wish to see me again, you'll have
to fight your way through this exam.
- The Scroll!
- Defeat the three...
Sound ninja under my command.
You're not making any sense!
We don't want to see
your face ever again, got it?!
That won't do.
Sasuke!
You, what did you do to Sasuke?
I gave him a parting gift.
Sasuke will undoubtedly
come looking for me...
seeking power.
You've provided me with plenty
of entertainment.
The sun will set soon...
I must find him quickly!
Once it's completely dark,
my disadvantage will only increase.
But why now, of all times...
what's his goal?
Sasuke!
Hold on, Sasuke.
C'mon!
Sasuke...
Sasuke, c'mon!
Naruto!
Sasuke's... Sasuke's hurt!
What?
What should I do?
It's been a while...
Anko.
You're an S-rank criminal,
an extremely dangerous person on
the most wanted list.
Orochimaru!
You can't win.
Striking Shadow Snakes!
I won't let you escape.
I got you.
Orochimaru,
I'm going to borrow your left hand.
You and I are
going to die here.
You intend to commit suicide?
Substitution.
As you are a special Jonin
of the village.
Surely you wouldn't use the
Forbidden Jutsu I taught you... on me.
I told you it wouldn't work.
A little while ago,
I gave that same Curse Mark
as a gift.
There's a kid that I want.
Selfish as always.
That kid will die.
Certainly... the odds that he'll die
are 1 in 10,
but he may survive just like you did.
You've really taken a liking
to this kid, haven't you?
Unlike you, that kid will excel.
For one thing, he has inherited
the Uchiha's visual prowess.
He has beautiful features and
is an ideal vessel to become my heir.
If that kid lives,
it will make things interesting.
Be sure not to cancel this test.
Three people from my village
are also under your care.
Do try to entertain me.
We've secured food and water after
spending half a day
so most teams have stopped
moving by now.
As we planned,
this is the time that we attack.
We'll split up into three and go scouting.
However, whether we find
other teams or not,
we return to this place.
Got it?
Okay.
Roger.
Scatter!
His breathing is gradually
becoming regular...
but he still has a terrible fever.
I have to protect them both.
Lord Orochimaru ordered us to wait
until daybreak.
Sasuke Uchiha is our target,
not the others.
If they get in the way,
it's okay to kill the other two, right?
Of course.
I can't fall asleep...
Is it daybreak already?!
A squirrel?
Don't surprise me like that!
Oh!
That was too close.
Do you think she noticed?
The Paper Bomb we put on the squirrel...
No, that's not it.
Huh? Then what? What was it?
We'll probably find out if we go closer.
So... we should get going now.
Okay!
If I can catch all twenty of these leaves
before they hit the ground
Sakura will fall for me!
If... if I can't catch
every one of these falling leaves...
It'll be an unrequited love forever!
Or rather...
One, two, three, four...
five, six, seven, eight...
nine, ten, eleven, twelve, thirteen, fourteen,
fifteen, sixteen, seventeen, eighteen,
Ugh! Nineteen...
Just one more!
That's...!
Phew... just in time.
This is a paper bomb,
and it's set to explode.
Who did such an awful thing?
Stop hiding and come out.
Ugh! And we went to all that trouble
to stay hidden!
Man, he's such a pain!
We've been discovered!
Strategy One, "hide and let it pass,"
was a failure!
So now we carry out Strategy Two!
Huh? Are you serious?
What? You have a problem with that?
There's no question of success.
Well, I guess it's all right but...
Wow! To meet the top rookie from last year,
Neji Hyuga, here of all places!
C-Can I have your autograph?
So it's just you guys?
Take that! Strategy Two:
"Fall for My Seductive Charm"!
I'd been wanting to meet you
for some time, you know?
Get lost!
Why? Why doesn't my seductive charm work?!
Ugh, I'm seriously so ticked off!
You raised your fist at me.
Does that mean you want a fight?
N-No...
Of course not.
Then get lost.
Taking a scroll from cowardly wimps
like you
would only bring shame upon the Leaf.
Y-Yes!
Hmph... Pathetic. Just like cockroaches.
All right! Let's go find some wimps!
Like I've been saying,
there's no one wimpier than us...
So, an all-night watch?
But it's not necessary anymore.
Wake Sasuke up.
We've come to fight him.
What are you saying?
What is it you're after?
I know that someone named Orochimaru
is pulling your strings from the shadows!
Huh?!
What's that strange mark on
the back of Sasuke's neck?
You did this to Sasuke.
How can you say you want to fight him?!
I wonder... what he is planning?
However, I can't stay quiet
after hearing that.
Wait, Zaku.
Huh? What is it?
It's so cliché.
The color of freshly dug earth.
This grass, it doesn't grow in
a place like this, does it?
Damn!
Huh, how ridiculous!
So that kunai was to stop the squirrel
from getting caught in the trap?
We kill her now!
A log?!
Or so you thought.
What?!
Clearly you have no talent.
Leaf Hurricane!
What?! This guy...
You should at least try
to pull your weight!
Who are you?
I am the Hidden Leaf's
Beautiful Green Beast, Rock Lee!
Or should I say...
This was for you. Now, get to safety.
And right now, I'm your opponent!
I told you this once before, didn't I?
That I would protect you with my life.
I guess it can't be helped...
Zaku. You can have Sasuke.
I'll kill them!
As far as I can tell,
Sakura is in no condition to fight.
That guy with the bushy brows is
pretty good with his taijutsu...
Looks like I can have some fun!
There's a trick to your attack,
isn't there?
I won't just evade it.
You've already shown me your jutsu.
Having said that,
the odds aren't good since
it's one versus three.
I'm going to have to take a chance.
One person at a time...
I'll give it my all and
take them down one by one!
Huh?!
Hey! Sasuke has collapsed...
... and Sakura is fighting.
What did you say?
Hey!
He's late.
That Lee...
Something's not right.
He's always precise about time.
Perhaps he ran into the enemy...
Could it be?
Hmm, that's unlikely.
In any case, let's find Lee!
Right!
Guy-sensei...
I will use that jutsu without
holding back!
Because this is the time you spoke of...
"When you are protecting
someone precious to you!"
He disappeared?!
It's just the beginning.
He has no way to break his fall!
Take this!
Primary Lotus!
This feeling...
Just in time.
T-That's impossible!
That's a fearsome jutsu...
To do this much damage,
even on soft ground...
Now, it's my turn.
Oh no! With what I just did...
my body still isn't...
Your jutsu is indeed fast.
But our jutsu surpasses yours.
It's the speed of sound itself!
Lee!
My left ear...
It's sound.
Even though you evaded my fist,
sound assaulted you.
Sound?
Vibration?
That's right. In other words,
to hear a sound means,
that the eardrum captures
the vibrations in the air.
You won't be able to move your body
freely for some time.
An outdated art like taijutsu
is useless against us.
Well, since I've even gone this far
to show you my jutsu...
Don't think you're getting off easy.
This isn't like your worthless techniques.
Next is...
You!
He's coming!
What?!
No way!
Leaf...
Hurricane!
It seems the effect of my last attack
hasn't worn off.
I'm somewhat surprised...
This device on my arm amplifies
and projects powerful sound waves.
It's basically a speaker!
And the sound I attack with isn't limited
to the direction of my arm...
my chakra ensures it converges
on my target!
Lee!
Oh well.
Even Lee was taken down.
Now, Sakura's all alone.
What are you going to do, Ino?
What do you mean?
Well, Sakura's in deep trouble!
And you're just going
to let that happen?
Huh?!
You two were once close friends,
weren't you?
Hey, Ino!
What are you going to do?!
I know, but what am I supposed to do?!
I can't just go rushing out there.
Even if I went out now...
I'd be taken down without a doubt.
I also...!
Your hair's shinier than mine.
Hey! If you have time to worry
about your hair,
you should practice!
Preening like some girly-girl...
Zaku, how about you kill Sasuke
right in front of this cute little pest?
Yeah! That sounds great!
Hey, hey...
I won't let you!
Don't move!
Sakura.
My body... It has no strength.
So...
Let's do this!
Hey! They're going after
Sasuke and Naruto next!
Wh-What should I do?!
I always...
act as if I'm a full-fledged ninja.
All I ever do is talk about
how much I like Sasuke.
I'm always acting like a know-it-all
and lecturing Naruto.
I've always just... watched them from behind.
And yet...
This time...
I want all of you...
to watch me...
... from behind!
Sakura?
Sakura...
Kin! Kill her!
Substitution Jutsu!
Kin, get out of the way!
Useless!
Slicing Sound Wave!
This is more than enough for you!
Where next?
Huh?!
This time... it's not a substitution!
Get off me! Hey!
Sakura...
I've heard you like Sasuke, too, Ino.
From now on, we're rivals.
Your hair. It's grown quite a bit.
Ino...
Why...
Why are you on the
same team as Sasuke?!
I will not lose anymore... to you, Ino!
Me too! I won't lose to you, Sakura.
No matter what!
... Sakura!
I must... protect everyone!
You brat!
Huh?
Sakura! I promised
I wouldn't lose to you, didn't I?!
Sorry to get you involved.
We're a three-man squad, after all.
We're all in this together, aren't we?
Well, we'll see.
No! I don't want to die yet!
Let go of my scarf!
You're annoying! Stop squirming!
You can just drop out, fatso.
What did that guy just say?
I... didn't quite catch it.
That's the one word
you never say to Choji.
I said if you don't like it,
get lost, fatso.
Fatso... fatso... fatso... fatso... fatso
Don't call me fat! I'm just big-boned,
you bastard!
All right! You understand this, right?!
This is a battle between
the Leaf and the Sound!
Lucky! He's lost it!
Man, what a drag.
This is going to be a pain.
That's my line.
Formation Ino!
- Shika!
- Cho!
Expansion Jutsu!
And now, Leaf Style Taijutsu!
Human Boulder!
What is this jutsu?
Isn't that just a fat guy rolling around?
Slicing Sound Wave!
He jumped?!
The wind pressure of my
Slicing Sound Wave
is less effective
against his rotation.
Even if I use the Super Sound Wave,
if that thing touches me,
the bones in my arms will be crushed!
Think I'll let you?!
You're the most annoying one, so...
Ninja Art:
Shadow Possession Jutsu!
My body!
Huh?!
Dosu?!
What are you doing at a time like this?!
Shadow Paralysis Jutsu, huh?
Ino, you're up. It's a woman's fight.
Shikamaru, I'm counting on you
to guard my body.
Gotcha!
Huh?
Ninja Art: Mind Transfer Jutsu!
Kin!
What happened?
This is the end of the line.
Make a move, and this girl,
Kin, is dead!
If you don't want this
to end right here,
leave your scroll and walk away!
Once you're far enough away that
I can't sense your chakra,
I'll release this girl!
Ino!
Uggghh. I'm dizzy.
Wh-What kind of person...
would hurt their own teammates?
Careless.
Our goal isn't the scrolls or
even passing this test.
What?
It's Sasuke.
Hmph...
My jutsu...
So your precious
Shadow Paralysis Jutsu
only lasts for five minutes?
It's not Shadow Paralysis Jutsu,
it's Shadow Possession Jutsu!
In addition, it seems that
this girl's jutsu...
is a jutsu that
seizes an opponent's consciousness.
From the looks of the blood
she's spitting up,
if I kill Kin, that girl will die too...
Are you going to kill...
your own teammate?
If I need to...
That's too bad...
Your strategy is flawed.
You're too soft.
Hmph!
I don't like this at all...
You pathetic Sound Ninja...
acting all triumphant just for beating
some second-rate opponents?
What?!
They're Lee's teammates...
That guy with the bowl cut lying over there...
he's our teammate.
This was your doing, wasn't it?!
If you're going to keep this up,
I'll fight you with my full strength!
Huh?
What's wrong? Neji...
If you've got a problem, then stop
acting so cool and get down here!
No. Evidently, there's no need for that.
Sasuke! You're awake...
Huh?!
Sakura...
Who did this to you?
Who is it?
Me!
Ino!
If you stay like that
you're going to get involved!
Come back to your body!
Choji, you too,
come over here and hide.
Y-Yeah.
Uh oh.
Release!
Wha?!
Wh-What's this?
No matter...
how you look at it...
his chakra is...
immense!
Dosu, this half-dead bastard
is nothing to be afraid of!
Stop, Zaku! Don't you understand?!
Super Sonic Slicing Wave!
Heh! He must have been blown to pieces.
- Who was?
- Huh?!
Fire Style:
Phoenix Flower Jutsu!
I'll blow them away!
Shuriken in the fire?!
It seems like you're
proud of your arms...
You!
S-Stop it!
You're the only one left.
You...
At least try to entertain me.
This is not like...
Sasuke!
Stop it.
Please...
Stop.
Sasuke!
You're strong.
Sasuke... We can't defeat you
while you're like this.
This is a token of our truce...
Please, let us leave.
Huh?
Forgive our selfishness,
but there's something we need to confirm.
That being said, let's make a promise.
If there's another opportunity to
battle with you in this test,
we won't run or hide.
Wait!
Just who in the world is Orochimaru?
What did he do to Sasuke?!
Why Sasuke?!
I don't know...
We were just ordered
to pressure Sasuke.
Hey! Are you okay?!
This is such a drag...
Ino, Lee is all yours.
Got it.
That chakra...
It's abnormal.
The Uchiha clan...
so this is their true power, huh?
Sakura's in danger!
It's okay...
I'll protect Sakura.
Well, what should we do
with this guy?
Kick him awake?
Can I do it?
What did I...?
That guy...?
Everyone hide!
No, get down quick!
Wh-Where is that guy?
Naruto...
That idiot, he finally woke up.
You're really something else.
Actually, you're really starting
to get on my nerves.
Sakura!
- What?
- Your...!
Your hair!
Oh! This?
Just felt like a change... that's it!
I liked it better long but,
when I move around in
a forest like this,
it gets in the way if it's long.
By the way...
why are you guys here?!
Hah... It's such a pain
to explain it to you.
I'll take care of him from here.
Ah... Okay...
Keep it together! Lee!
Oh? Tenten, why are you here?
I came to help.
Huh?
Where are those Sound Village ninja?
A kid named Sasuke
drove them away!
Really...
Why did you recklessly decide
to act on your own?!
Besides, you really got beaten up!
S-Sakura was in danger.
So as a man, I...
You're really stupid.
I can't argue with that.
You, Bushy Brow!
Naruto!
Don't say rude things to Lee!
Lee...
Thank you.
Because of you, I feel like
I've finally taken a step forward.
I feel like I've gotten a little stronger!
Sakura...
It looks like my efforts
weren't enough!
Sasuke...
Just what you'd expect
from the Uchiha clan.
I got beaten to a pulp.
What?! He was beaten to a pulp?!
Were those guys really that strong?
Special Technique:
Shadow Clone Jutsu: Fishing Version!
Thrash about more!
I want to catch some for cooking!
Three isn't enough!
Sasuke!
The firewood is ready!
A fireball, please.
I guess three will be enough for now.
What?
Hey, wait a minute!
It's already been four days
since the second test started.
Yeah.
That's right.
For all we know...
there may not be any Heaven scrolls.
What do you mean, Sakura?
Well, in this second test...
four of the five-day
time limit have passed already.
That means we've already used up
eighty percent of our time.
Seventy-eight participants
and twenty-six teams.
There are only thirteen each
of the Heaven and Earth scrolls.
At most, only 13 teams can pass.
After parting ways with
the Leaf Village bunch,
we allotted two days for healing...
So from here on, we have to cover
more ground.
At any rate,
the next enemy is our last chance.
I'm going to get some drinking water.
Say! Say!
I've got a great idea so we won't have
to fight anyone!
What?!
I have lots of blank scrolls stocked up.
A ninjutsu manual, a deadly poison manual,
and one for notes...
If we tweak this a little and make it
look exactly like a Heaven scroll...
H-Hold it!
Huh?
Even if you do that, you don't know
what's written on the inside!
If a proctor looks inside,
they'll find out immediately!
Idiot!
Generally with things like this,
there's a password or
something written inside,
and you can't understand it
unless you have both scrolls.
If you don't know the contents,
there's no use making a fake!
What if we could predict the contents...?
This Earth scroll...
No!
You! Have you forgotten
even the rules, you idiot?
We were told not to look inside
until arriving at the tower, right?
But at this rate,
we'll be in big trouble, right?
Damn it... They're all monsters!
How can we steal a scroll
when defending ours
takes everything we've got?
But we can't back off!
The pride of our village
is on the line!
Then we'll go back to tracking.
And we'll definitely
get it done this time.
What should I do?
You'll only be in the way
if you come along.
Take this and stay hidden.
Okay.
Oh yeah.
I have to keep hidden.
Lions Barrage!
The Earth Scroll... same as us.
My glasses!
See ya.
I wouldn't do that if I were you.
Man, you guys are hopeless...
That was close.
W-We're sorry.
Those who ignore the rules
will be disqualified.
In the previous exam, a hypnotic
genjutsu was placed...
to affect the eyes of anyone who opened
the scroll before reaching the tower.
It was a measure to put them to sleep
until the test ended.
By the way...
If I'm not mistaken, you're Kabuto, right?
What are you doing hanging
around here alone?
It's not that I'm after your scroll.
I didn't think so.
If that was your intention...
you could've taken it from Naruto.
So you're also after the Heaven scroll?
No.
I already have them both.
See?
What?
One thing led to another...
I was hurrying towards the tower
to wait for my teammates
after getting separated.
Now, if you'll excuse me...
Wait!
Fight me.
Lucky!
Fight you, you say?
S-Sasuke.
You big idiot!
What's this all of a sudden?
Are you serious?
Sorry, but we don't have any more time.
Hey, Sasuke! Kabuto saved us!
Sasuke, I'm not so sure about that myself.
Shut up!
It can't be helped.
I said it before, too.
This is what it takes to survive
in this forest.
Hmm... That's a lie.
If you were really serious
about this test...
Why would it be necessary to fight me?
You should have attacked me
when my guard was down,
instead of announcing your intentions.
That's... a ninja.
So, I'll show you the path you should take.
However... let's talk as we move.
The smell of fish cooking on the fire
has traveled a long way.
At this rate, we'll attract
fierce animals... and enemies.
Humph!
Are there really still enemies around?
Yes, no mistake.
If you think about it a little,
you'll understand.
Do you know the smartest way
to approach battles...
in a vast forest like this one?
No.
The tower in the center of this forest,
is the common goal for all participants.
That means on the final day
of the test...
the area near the tower is
the best place to gather scrolls.
Oh, I see.
Ambush, right?
In other words, we go after the scrolls
of the teams
that have both the Heaven and Earth scrolls
and are heading for the tower.
I see.
I understand the reason
why you appeared before us.
You're scared, too, right?
That's right.
It's becoming a real disaster,
but we can't cancel this test.
What do you mean?
Excuse me!
What is it?!
We're in the middle of something important!
Excuse me.
But... Uh...
Please take a look at this!
The video?
Ready? Here! Look at the time!
T-This is...
It's a recording inside the tower,
one hour and thirty-seven minutes
after the start of the second test!
Three ninja from the Hidden Sand Village
have broken the record.
This can't be!
In a mere ninety-seven minutes...
This has never happened!
This is unusual.
Those kids aren't Genin level.
They've rewritten the
fastest time by four hours...
It's not just that.
What do you mean?
It's 10 kilometers
from the test entrances to the tower.
Ferocious animals, poisonous insects,
the rugged forest road...
as if none of those things were there...
Especially the redhead in the lead...
What about him?
You don't notice?
I see. This is quite a surprise.
What about him is so impressive?
Look closely at his body.
He doesn't have a single scratch.
What's more, there isn't even
a smudge of dirt on his clothing.
Even I...
No, any of the other Chunin...
It's impossible even for us to
make it to this tower without a scratch.
It's likely that it has something
to do with his ability.
It's been a long time since such
a promising candidate has appeared.
Now then, the tower has finally
come into view.
From here on out, it gets tough.
There!
Oh, it's just a centipede.
Yikes! It's huge.
All those legs are so gross!
Naruto.
Huh?
As long as time allows, we should
go slowly while remaining hidden.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Sure.
I've... had it...
Oh, Sakura!
For crying out loud,
how far have we walked?
The tower hasn't gotten any closer.
And yet, we can see it
right in front of us.
Strange...
No mistake about it.
It seems that we've walked right
into their little "welcoming party."
Take a look at that.
Huh?
Oh, that can't be!
Is it genjutsu...?
So it seems.
We were lured in perfectly.
Even though we were being so careful,
they've had us walking in circles
in the same area.
We're being watched...
Probably.
They intend to wear down
our physical strength
and strike when we're exhausted
and our guard is down.
If so, then this is all part
of the enemy's strategy.
Then... They'll be coming soon.
They're here.
The perfect number for a handicap.
There's quite a few.
And... they're clones.
You're like rats in a trap.
Shut up!
I'll see through them!
Sharingan!
Naruto!
Watch out!
What are you doing?!
Damn it!
It's useless!
Forget it! They're illusions!
A genjutsu created by the enemy!
But Kabuto's wound is real.
No, Sasuke is right.
No doubt, the enemy is
hiding somewhere
and attacking from
a different location
to coordinate with the attack
of their genjutsu user.
And they're making us think that
these genjutsu shinobi are
the ones who are attacking.
Okay then, if we destroy all
these illusions at once,
things will go back to normal.
And the enemy won't be able
to throw their kunai.
We'll find out
where they're hiding.
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Shadow Clones!
Damn it!
We've worn them down.
All that's left are their real bodies.
Lucky!
You really did a number on me.
You're the one who got
my left shoulder, right?
It's time for payback!
You're trapped like rats.
It worked, Naruto.
Impossible! When did you...
Stupid! You jerks finally show yourselves!
This kid... no way.
Looks like you genjutsu users just got
a taste of your own medicine!
Now, it's our...
Naruto, you used up
too much chakra!
I'll take care of the rest!
As if! I'm not going to let you take over
and show off.
Is this really the Naruto I know?
What is with this amount
of chakra?
Right after his Multi-Shadow
Clone jutsu,
he could still transform three of them
into perfect copies of us.
All that...
And he can still move.
This is the fifth day.
Great job Naruto!
What happened there? Are you hurt?
That's a terrible mark.
It's nothing.
Here it is, here it is!
Look, the Heaven scroll!
Good for you.
There's something about this guy...
that I don't like.
Oh, it's you guys.
You're late, Kabuto.
I got a bit involved in something.
Sorry.
But hey, thanks to you,
we got both scrolls!
No, it's because you guys fought hard.
We're going through this door.
Well then, I wish us both luck.
Yeah!
How was the "harvest"?
Right...
More than I expected.
I've collected all his data
from this second test.
You need this, right?
So, how was it?
As I thought, it appears you're curious.
Lord Orochimaru.
I want to ask your opinion.
As a Sound Village spy...
That's not necessary, is it?
You will be the one to decide all that...
I like that cleverness of yours.
There's nobody here.
I'm okay now, Sakura.
O-Okay.
That's too bad!
Cha!
Say, say, what are we supposed to do?
Oh! Look at that...
"Heaven"... "Earth"...
I don't get this at all.
"If you lack Heaven, gain knowledge
and await your opportunity."
"If you lack Earth, run across the
land to gain your advantage."
"When Heaven and Earth align,"
"the perilous path shall be overcome..."
"This is the secret
that guides one to the path..."
What's that?
It looks like there's a character missing.
It probably has something to do with the scroll
I think this means we're supposed to open
the Heaven and Earth scrolls at the same time.
All right then, I'm opening them!