Oh... guys... How have you been?
Kid, where are you going?
If you value your life, go no further.
A demon lives there.
A demon?
He's known as Jugo the Unstable.
Look at that.
Because of Jugo,
no one lives in that village, to this day.
No one's ever gotten close to him
and come back alive.
I don't mean to lecture you,
but you should go back.
What? You've followed me?
But stop where you are.
Don't come any closer.
Now, go back home.
Don't come near me! Go away!
Come any closer and I'll kill you!
I'll kill anyone who comes in here!
Who is it?
Go away!
Go away! I said to go away!
I'll kill you...
I'll kill you too!
I see... Your strength is amazing...
I thought I was a goner.
Wh-Who are you...?
Kimimaro... I came for you.
Would you like to come to
Lord Orochimaru's side with me?
Orochimaru...?
There are many people at
Lord Orochimaru's side
who are just like you and me...
You're all alone, aren't you?
If you go to Lord Orochimaru,
you won't be alone anymore.
I'm not normal.
I can't control myself.
There's no telling when I'll start killing
the people around me.
I won't get killed.
I'm not that weak.
Aren't you... afraid of me?
No, I'm not, Jugo.
I will become your cage...
As long as I am by your side...
I will be the one to keep you in check.
Huh? Is that... true?
Yes. I'm going to absorb the enzyme
from your body into my own.
Just like you,
I will possess the power of the Curse Mark.
Hold on a minute.
The Curse Mark doesn't adapt
to just anyone.
If it doesn't adapt...
I know... At that moment, I'll die.
If you know, then stop this!
This is a form of treatment for me.
My body is being eaten away
by disease.
Perhaps your Curse Mark
will slow its progress.
Your power will save me.
Don't worry so much.
It's all right. We're friends.
There's no way your power
will reject me.
Just as I thought...
I wasn't chosen this time, either.
Kabuto-sensei, I...
Take care of your body.
Your role is now finished.
From now on,
it's the Sound Four, Kimimaro...
I... still haven't...
Your replacement has
already been found.
He possesses power equal
to your Earth Curse Mark!
He has been given
the Heaven Curse Mark!
Additionally, he even
has a Kekkei Genkai.
Wonder who's stronger...
What's the matter?
Don't get too excited.
Kabuto-sensei...
How much... time do I have left?
You shouldn't talk anymore...
P-People...
are born for a reason...
Since people are born,
there must be some kind
of important calling
Recently, I've started to think that...
That the meaning for being born...
For people, finding that meaning is...
the only true freedom given to us.
I understand what you want to say.
Indeed, Lord Orochimaru
is now suffering.
It's an unprecedented crisis,
but I will be blunt.
What can you do now?
You've now lost your value
as a vessel.
A new vessel is heading this way.
Well...
At this point, it's too late, but...
Indeed...
My body is no longer a worthy vessel
for his Reincarnation.
It will be difficult for someone like me,
who has lost everything...
to find my own purpose.
I've finally understood that...
Even if it's not me,
I'll bring in the new vessel
even if it costs me my life.
This is how I will repay my debt
to Lord Orochimaru.
That's the only way for someone
as worthless as me to find redemption...
We're close!
There are two enemies left...
There are three of us...
It's three against two.
If we play this right, one more
engagement should do it.
All right! All right!
Let's do it!
No! It's four against two!
Okay, okay! I'm sorry.
Counting Akamaru,
it's four against two!
Let's end this quick with
our new technique!
Hey, hey! If we have to,
I'll bust out my awesome Shadow Clones,
so we'll be fine!
That's reassuring...
But my strategy comes first. Got it?
Y-Yeah...
For that purpose,
We have to catch up before the sun sets.
I know. Let's go full speed!
The sun's starting to set...
Neither Jirobo nor Kidomaru
have returned.
It seems they're having
a hard time.
It doesn't matter...
Lord Orochimaru is more important.
We've only completed one third
of the journey in half a day...
Yeah, this is bad...
We don't know whether
we'll make it in time at this rate!
Lord Orochimaru...
Sasuke...
Sasuke's not... here yet?
He's running out of time...
He can't go on any longer.
Lord Orochimaru...
Several bodies have been
prepared for you!
And... you could even use me,
if necessary...
It has to be Sasuke...
How long do you think I've waited?
It's a matter of urgency!
The Third Hokage's jutsu...
His curse was stronger
than expected!
If you don't reincarnate right now,
you'll lose everything!
Is that what you want?!
I've selected and prepared
suitable bodies for you.
Please leave it to me! Also...
I'll handle bringing Sasuke
here as well.
Curse you...
Third Hokage!
Release!
Listen well, everyone!
I shall release you from this prison...
However, I will only release one of you!
Okay! You said you were going
to let one person out of here.
You're going to keep
your promise.
What are you doing?
Open the door now!
What? There was another one?
Hurry up and...
No... I'm... I'm going to be eaten...
I'll let you out of here...
And I shall grant you
just one wish.
My clan... They were captured
for your experiments.
Please release them.
Sure. Consider it done.
You don't have to worry.
Your strong will shall live on
as a part of me.
It's not like you'll lose everything.
Now then, your flesh is mine...
With this, Lord Orochimaru has
taken a new vessel.
He won't be able to reincarnate
again for several years.
However, there is the next time.
Hold on a minute!
Are we almost there?
No... It should still take a while.
More importantly...
What are those idiots,
Jirobo and Kidomaru, doing?!
We caught up!
All right! I'll take care of
this nice and quick!
R-Right away?!
Eat this!
Multiple Fist Barrage!
Chakra in his palm...?!
A transformed Shadow Clone?
Rasengan!
N-No way... His hands just now...?!
Pointless if I get you before you can even move!
Fang Over Fang!
They lined Sakon up with me...
So I was their target from the beginning?!
You think you succeeded
just with that?!
Damn!
I've been caught!
Shadow Possession Jutsu succeeded!
A diversion...
He's coming!
Tayuya! What are you doing
just standing there?!
N-No!
Why do you move forward?!
I can't dodge!
Here you go!
Nice! Kiba, Shikamaru!
Shikamaru! Let's get out of here!
Yeah!
I won't let you get away!
They're fast.
Akamaru.
Hurry back after you've set the bombs!
Messing with me.
Akamaru.
Don't you bark at me, you mutt!
Hold on.
You!
Kiba! Akamaru!
Damn it.
You punks!
We have no choice.
I'll take care of this, so you take
the coffin and go on ahead.
Shikamaru...
Get going already.
Wh-Why are you...?
I'm sorry, Naruto.
I miscalculated.
Kimimaro.
You were taking too long, Tayuya.
And what happened to the other three?
And you call yourselves the Sound Five.
You persistent bastard...
I'm starting to understand
that feeling a little...
of the soul escaping
the prison of the flesh.
The feeling of experiencing
a taste of Lord Orochimaru's dream.
Orochimaru...!
This vessel... is an important vessel
for his dream...
The flesh that Lord Orochimaru
truly desires.
But you guys were a bit too late.
Some dangerous guy
has appeared again.
That air about him is
nothing ordinary.
Anyway, we need
to sort out the situation.
If we were to carelessly
plunge in...
You jerk!
What's all this nonsense you're spouting?!
Naruto!
Give back Sasuke!
Hey, wait!
The reason why I won't kill you now
is because you have a mission
you have to complete.
And my mission is to deliver
that to Lord Orochimaru.
Isn't it too late now?
Humph. I told you.
That's the body that Lord Orochimaru
truly desires.
The next vessel, huh?
That's right...
And this is the only thing that
I can do at present.
I'll leave the trash to you.
Sasuke...
That punk!
Calm down, Naruto.
How can I calm down?
At this rate,
Sasuke will get even farther away.
Naruto's right.
This is a mission to bring Sasuke back
to the Leaf Village.
We must choose what would be
the most rational means
to execute the mission.
Damned punks.
I'll finish this in a flash.
Naruto, listen up.
Please follow the plan
I'm about to explain.
He's a typical
close-range combat idiot
with Shadow Clones
as his only saving grace.
And he's a mid-range
combat type
who binds his enemies with
a jutsu using shadows...
and a sharp-witted squad leader, huh?
Got it?
Yeah.
Come on already, you punks.
It's two versus one.
We've got the upper hand.
It's an opponent we can beat
if we team up.
Let's go, Naruto.
All right.
For jerks like you,
it doesn't matter how many
of you there are.
Don't underestimate our teamwork.
Let's go!
Bring it.
Now... Naruto.
I'll blow you away.
Farewell.
Blast.
You tricked me.
Teamwork? Don't make me laugh,
you little punks...
Blast.
You wouldn't fall for the same trick
over and over, huh?
Small fry... You've got nerve.
Well, I guess I'll settle for just
having been able to let him get away.
Remember this.
It's not just jutsu that are weapons.
I'm counting on you, Shikamaru.
That Tayuya... if she ever comes back,
I'll kill her.
Hold it.
Hey!
Now then, how shall I defeat you?
You...
Those eyes...
It seems he possesses
a peculiar chakra.
What does Orochimaru want to do...?
Why's he after Sasuke?
Lord Orochimaru has already
obtained an Immortality Jutsu...
It takes a long time to master every
jutsu and obtain everything in the world.
What does that have to do
with Sasuke?!
Being Immortal doesn't mean
the body lasts forever...
Before his body decays,
a strong and new body is needed
as a vessel for his soul.
That's...
Are you saying that's Sasuke?!
Yes... That's right.
I won't let such a thing happen!
Idiot... What good will it do
sending one little punk after him?
And looking at things
in terms of time,
up until now you probably sacrificed
one member each time
in order for the group
to move forward.
Is that guy Sasuke
really that important?
How many of your men do you intend
to sacrifice for just one person?
You useless punk.
Heh... Indeed...
For me, this is my first mission
as a squad leader.
I couldn't help but feel anxious
as my comrades were picked off one by one.
I didn't know if my own judgment
was truly the right one.
As a squad leader entrusted with
the lives of his team
the by-the-book move would be
to prioritize...
the lives of the whole squad
over the one captured by the enemy,
and decide to abort a mission
that's too dangerous.
Then, why didn't you do that?
Things rarely go by the book...
Since not one person in my squad
would do something like
abandoning a comrade
just to save their own skin.
Me included.
I'm just a guy who likes to watch the clouds...
I am not cut out to be a squad leader
who orders comrades around.
The only thing I can do for them...
is to have faith in them.
Listen. I'm not thinking that
they were sacrifices.
I'm not thinking that they've died.
Don't mock my comrades.
Yahoo!
Got you!
Damn!
Listen, Akamaru.
We're going to attack from both sides
with Fang Over Fang.
Here we go!
Fang Over Fang!
Summoning Jutsu!
This doesn't look so good.
I'll play a melody of death for you.
What's with this guy?
What?!
Two on two is perfect,
right, Sakon?
I will never let you take Sasuke!
There's a lot of trash scattered about.
But after all, trash is trash.
It simply needs to be cleaned up.
Shut up!
Come on.
I'll crush you!
Akamaru!
Oh, so you're the real one!
Multiple Fist Barrage!
One more!
My brother and I get along very well.
Usually, my older brother Ukon
sleeps inside of me,
but when there's a fight,
he comes out and helps.
This is this guy's ability.
Ukon can stick out
his arms and legs, his head,
from anywhere in my body
and attacks or defends.
Like this, see?
Multiple Leg Barrage!
It's a three-legged kick.
Works well, doesn't it?
So next, it's...!
There's no time to waste, Sakon.
We'll finish this quickly!
Get into the second state!
All right, all right...
You're too impatient, bro.
I see, you're saying those horns
aren't just for display, huh?
As soon as that right one came out,
his chakra increased massively.
Tch!
It seemed hopeless before,
but now it's even worse.
What?! You're saying
we're going to do that?!
No, Akamaru!
It's too dangerous to do it here
without our comrades!
You understand, don't you?
If we use that jutsu,
both you and I will use up
most of our chakra
and won't be able to move.
If we miss, we'll die here in vain.
Akamaru...
So this is the so-called
melody of death.
So she's manipulating them
with the sound of the flute.
Damn! She's getting
further and further away.
What should I do?!
What is it that I should do?!
Huh?!
This is really looking bad!
What a pitiful master I am...
that you had to bite me.
I understand, Akamaru.
Just like you said,
we only have that left!
Wolf Fang Over Fang!
Now, Akamaru!
What?!
It's Dynamic Marking!
Playing dirty like that!
All preparations are done!
Inuzuka Style: Man-Beast Transformation Combo!
Two-Headed Wolf!
I wondered what it was going
to be and
it turned out to be
a drooling runt of a dog.
What can a dog like this do?
Take this!
Drool?!
Sakon, what are you doing!
To the right!
Damn!
Wolf Fang Over Fang!
Heh! How's that!
Wolf Fang Over Fang's rotation speed
is too fast.
It's such an intense, high-speed rotation
that our visibility becomes zero.
Even without direct contact,
flesh is cut...
A direct hit
and you're torn to pieces.
Really... getting carried away...
Perfect timing.
We were thinking of separating anyway.
What?! He split into two?!
It's true...
If we'd taken that hit as one,
it would've been bad, but...
The real battle begins now.
Damn it...
Yeah... I know Akamaru.
One more shot of
Wolf Fang Over Fang.
The next one is our limit.
We'll take them down with this!
Wolf Fang Over Fang!
It's no use hiding!
I told you we don't chase
with our eyes!
We attack by chasing smells
we've marked with our noses!
- A!
- Un!
- Summoning...
- Rashomon!
That's an impressive power...
To turn Rashomon,
the ultimate defense meant to protect
Lord Orochimaru, into this state.
But...
- This is the end!
Akamaru!
Akamaru...
To protect me, you...
Damn! He did it again!
My eyes...!
Damn!
Damn...!
This time it's not ordinary piss!
It feels like my eyes are burning
with strong acid!
Where's the other one?!
Hey...
Who are you looking for?
I'll take care of the rest.
Go wash your eyes in that river.
This is my ability...
specialized in assassination.
You can't beat me just by
having a good nose and claws.
You can't beat my ability!
You know that the chakra network
through which chakra flows
is deeply interwoven with each
internal organ, right?
The chakra network is interwoven
in a variety of complicated ways
and is linked to the tissues that
make up each organ.
Also to each cell that makes up
the tissues,
and even to proteins,
which are the main component of cells...
In the second state,
I can dismantle or reconstruct these cells
or proteins as I wish by using chakra.
To put it simply,
I can break my body down into particles,
enter my opponent's body...
and then reform inside their body
and come back out.
Akamaru...
I'm sorry... Akamaru...!
However, this time,
I'm sunk...
My cells can swim inside
your body as I wish,
and I can even target
and destroy only your cells.
In other words,
a slight state of fusion.
We'll be sharing a body, so to speak.
Sharing?
That's right... a cruel way
of killing that only I can do...
Little by little, I'm tearing
your cells apart from the inside.
I see.
If that's the case...!
Let's see what happens if I do this!
Suicide?! That's ridiculous!
Die with me...
What are you thinking?!
Are you in pain?
All right then, let's end this now.
There's not enough blood...
Damn!
Damn...
Where'd he go?
So he left his little dog behind
and fled.
It's the right decision,
but he's more cold-hearted than me.
What?!
It couldn't be!
What a relief...
He's still breathing.
What a relief!
Akamaru... You really gave it your best.
Because of you, I was able to stall
the enemy for a while.
We've managed to injure
the enemy too.
It's enough... You've done enough.
I'll kill you!
Hey! Sakon! Where are you?! Sakon!
Sakon!
Enough already.
You're so noisy, Big Brother.
Your yelling stings my eyes...
Big Brother!
I'll kill him... is what I'd like to do,
but it's almost time for my sleep.
Capture those bastards alive in my place.
When I wake up,
I'll kill them.
All right, Sakon?
Capture them alive...
Yeah, I got it...
But...
The killing part,
we'll do it together.
Behold!
Willow Dance!
Bones?
This is my... Kekkei Genkai.
What's with this guy...?
Is he attacking with bones sticking out
from all over his body?
He's grabbed his own bone!
It'll be soon...
He's turning the bone...
into a sword!
It's futile. It's not just ordinary bone.
My densest bones are as hard as steel.
So what?! I'll just have to break it!
I possess five Dances.
You'd better not think
you know my strength from just this.
What?!
Allow me to demonstrate...
The Dance of the Camellia.
Come!
I'll crush you!
They're getting closer and closer.
Damn!
This isn't good, traces of blood!
Damn, I did save Akamaru
for the time being,
but maybe I went too far.
This smell...
What does it mean?
Why... Why are those guys
headed to a place like this?!
I don't understand anymore.
In any case,
we need to leave this place quickly.
I can't...
I'm starting to feel light-headed
from the pain and loss of blood...
My body won't move at all either...
Akamaru...
Huh?
So he fled by floating down the river...
Damn!
Damn...
This is it!
So, I've cornered you, you stinking rat!
Pretty impressive...
You timed the attacks of those three well.
You must have practiced quite a bit, huh?
Since it's a pretty complicated song...
Well now...
Not only did you
immediately understand
that I'm manipulating these guys
with my flute,
you understood how difficult this song is.
You're a pretty impressive punk.
But you can't completely
understand this song.
You're so right...
since art is so foreign to me.
But since she uses that flute
to manipulate,
it means that song must contain
individually specific sound patterns
to control every single move
those guys make.
I'm pretty confident
when it comes to just analyzing,
but this time it's not looking good.
The reason is that
I don't understand
musical notes whatsoever.
There's no one that's heard
this song and lived.
Demonic Flute: Phantom Sound Chains!
The melody's changed!
Something's going to come!
What the...?!
What?
This is...?
The speed at which he flees
after determining
that these Chakra Phantoms
are dangerous...
Pretty impressive.
But...
I've used my precious paper bombs
and smoke bombs all at once
and all I could do was hide.
That white one...
drained my physical energy.
Seeing that shuriken passed through,
that thing is
partially materialized.
It's chakra itself with an appetite.
It's probably chakra that's shaped
mostly by mental energy.
That's why it seeks stability
and craves physical energy.
If I continue dealing with
those hungry chakra forms
I won't be able to build up my chakra.
They're pretty dangerous.
She's a shinobi who can
make special chakra like me...
It's without a doubt, a secret ninjutsu.
Which means I should leave
the white thing alone
and aim for the main body!
The quickest way would be
to stop the sound of the flute, but...
it'd be impossible to get close to
that woman in this situation.
The next thing would be to capture
those three with Shadow Possession Jutsu.
But that's difficult too since they're
attacking me separately at different times
If I let even one get free,
I'd be attacked and it'd be the end...
This woman has no openings
in her offense or defense...
Heh! I bet she's a good Shogi player.
My remaining ninja tools
are twelve kunai knives,
nine shuriken, twelve meters of wire,
one flash bomb and one paper bomb...
Man...
It feels like playing a game
without my rook and bishop.
There's no use hiding.
Unless you can predict
these guys' movements
there's nowhere to run, you little rat.
I'll find you and tear you to pieces!
All right. Everything's in place.
Now I just have to do it.
There'll be nine attacks.
The outcome will be decided
in these next few moves.
One!
Wishful thinking!
A jutsu controlled by sound
is invincible.
Any plan you have to beat me...
is useless!
Two!
Scampering around, you little rat!
Where are you?!
Three!
So you're over there!
Four!
So it's a cheap trick.
You think you can make a fool of me?!
Five... six...
seven... eight...
Scurrying around to get away.
What is he thinking?
Light?!
Nine!
Oh no!
He's lengthened the shadows
with light and...
Shadow Possession Jutsu!
Shadow Possession Jutsu...
a success!
That's impossible...
How were you able to predict
these guys' movements?!
There's no way you could have heard
the differences in my music patterns!
I wasn't listening to
the sounds at all.
There's something other
than the sounds
that give away your command patterns,
isn't there?
Your fingers!
It can't be!
The movement of the three...
You're saying you predicted their movements
by memorizing my fingering?
There's no way that's possible!
Your right index finger
and ring finger...
The sound that you make
with those
along with the left middle finger
and pinkie,
the one with the pincer-like arms
gets ready to move.
Your right thumb and index finger,
and your left index and little fingers,
the one with the club charges.
While you were dodging my attacks
and looking for me,
I was observing each of your
finger movements in detail...
analyzing and memorizing them.
It's no use...
They're bound by
Shadow Possession Jutsu.
The most interesting rule
of Shogi is that
you can use pieces you obtain
as your own pieces.
Now... it's my turn to attack.
This time, I'll hunt you down
with these three pieces.
You're looking pretty composed.
You should at least have a kunai ready.
My weapon is just this flute!
I already told you, there's no one
who's heard the sound of
this flute and lived, idiot!
That's some confidence!
Retreat!
Too bad you aren't able to
use those pieces, idiot!
Next it's my turn!
What?!
Shadow Possession Jutsu,
successful.
I told you.
That I'd hunt you down
using those pieces.
I used them as bait.
The first move is always a feint.
The basic strategy is to land a hit
with the second move.
Bastard...
It can't be helped.
Now that it's come to this,
I'll have to force my way out.
I didn't think I'd have to use
State 2 in a place like this...
It ticks me off but...
I'll acknowledge it.
For a scumbag, he's pretty sharp.
What is... this?
It's true you're somewhat sharp, but...
It won't go as
you've planned from here!
What?!
Is she going to force herself out
of the Shadow Possession Jutsu?
What's with that tremendous chakra?
The jutsu's going to come loose!
I can't be worrying about
saving chakra anymore.
There's no other way
but to use that jutsu!
Ninja Art: Shadow Strangulation Jutsu!
Is he grabbing my body
with the shadow?
It's just as if I'm being grabbed
by a real hand...
But this is as far as you go!
Damn! What incredible strength.
At this distance
I'll lose to that strength!
Take this!
Demonic Flute: Chains of Fantasia!
This is bad!
Is this a... genjutsu?
Where are you aiming?
I can't move my body...
While in State 2,
I manipulate many genjutsu
with my flute.
Of those, this one is
appropriate for that little rat.
The reason is...
his genjutsu paralyzes
and binds its prey!
Well? How does it feel
to be the one tied up?
Little rat!
What...?
This guy...
He broke his own finger
with his shadow!
Did he release the genjutsu
with the pain?
On top of that, he kept pretending to
be bound by the jutsu?!
I told you this already...
The first hand is the trick,
a fake.
The basic strategy is to score
with the second move.
And this second move...
is a bit different from the last one.
With the Shadow Strangle Jutsu,
the closer in distance you are
to the subject the stronger the hold.
Damn. I carelessly got too close...
No, that's not it.
You're looking pretty composed.
Stand ready with a kunai at least.
My weapon is just this flute!
I told you that
there hasn't been a person
who's heard the sound of this flute
and lived, idiot!
No way...
That's right.
The reason I threw the kunai
right in front of you and missed...
It was to lead you to pick it up
and come closer to me, understand?
I'll acknowledge you.
You're not only sharp...
You're also very determined...
And besides... I'm a gentleman.
Striking a helpless woman
is against my policy...
But however I look at it,
you don't exactly seem like
a helpless woman...
in your case!
Don't be getting full of yourself
just because you released
the genjutsu, you little clod...!
She's still not completely bound.
Damn it...
I can't lose!
A little more...
What incredible chakra!
Even if I bind her
at point-blank range,
she still pushes back...
But, I'll get hammered
for sure if I let go now.
After all, I just have to settle this
with this jutsu.
As I thought, things are getting risky
if I stay in the water any longer
with this wound...
Damn it!
One more... to go...
This guy's crazy strong...
Not a single hit with that
many shadow clones...
It's about time...
I've been eagerly waiting.
Lord Orochimaru's ambition...
The first step...
Sasuke...
Sasuke! What are you doing
with these guys?!
Come on! We're going home!
Sasuke...
You can hear
my voice, can't you?!
Wait, Sasuke!
It's futile.
Die.
Who are you?
The rejuvenated...
Hidden Leaf's Handsome Devil...
Rock Lee!
B-Bushy Brow?
Bushy Brow, you!
What about your body...?
More importantly, Naruto.
Go get Sasuke.
But... you...
Please leave this one to me!
This guy's... good...
Bushy Brow! Be careful!
He uses his own bones to attack.
Bones... you say?
He's crazy strong...
What are you doing?!
Please go, quickly!
Naruto...
You made a "promise of a lifetime"
to Sakura with that pose, right?!
I'll bring back Sasuke, no matter what!
It's a promise of a lifetime!
This man... I'll defeat him!
I promise!
Right!
I won't let you!
Die.
Please don't ignore me!
Oh...
Bushy Brow...
However...
If Sasuke is inside that coffin...
It's impossible for a team of Genin
to take them on...
I'm not such a fool.
I anticipated that already
and it's been taken care of.
In here!
What's wrong, Guy?
You're on the brink of exhaustion.
Did something happen
on your mission?
No... I finished the mission
and ran back as fast as I could...
More importantly...
Lee! What happened with
Lee's surgery?!
It was a success.
He can start training tomorrow
if it's just for jutsu.
Well, bed rest for a while
would be best though.
Th-There's trouble, Lady Hokage.
Rock Lee is gone!
No!
Damn it... Last night while
I treated Genma and Raido?
That fool... He went after them.
He must've been really flustered...
He mistook my bottle of sake for
a bottle of medicine...
Sake?!
Uh... Uh oh...
He's agile... My kicks don't hit.
You're flexible to a surprising extent...
And your movements are certainly unique.
You're too... straight forward.
It's over...
Please wait!
I'm sorry.
It's about time for my medicine!
I have to be sure to drink it, so...
Excuse me a moment.
I've always disliked medicine.
It... happened before when
I took him to a restaurant
to celebrate his learning
the Hidden Lotus.
Lee mistook my sake for water...
As soon as he drank just
a small cup...
of the sake, things got ugly...
Got ugly...?
After a silence, like the calm
before a storm...
The moment I realized it...
The restaurant...
was completely wrecked...
Medicine always tastes strange...
What...? What did this guy drink?
He went on an incredible drunken rampage!
Who the hell are you?! Hey!
Who are you anyway?
Acting cool... So irritating...
Hence, he's a natural user of...
Drunken Fist!
If you're not going to come...
then I'll go!
His attacks are straightforward
as usual, but...
Oh!
Ouch!
It's your fault!
I... I...!
I'm enjoying my youth!
He's too unorthodox...
And most of all... he's fast!
Right in the middle of my youth...
Dance of the Camellia!
Here!
I can't read his movements...
To land an attack on me...
That's quite some taijutsu...
I have no choice...
My special ability is bones...
You heard that
from the Shadow Clone brat, right?
I'll sober you up right away.
I'm... not drunk... or anything!
Then I'll wake you up!
I'm not drunk or anything!
In the first place, I'm a minor!
Minors shouldn't drink at all!
Unorthodox, isn't it?
This is my Kekkei Genkai.
Humph. With that wound...
It seems he wasn't able
to escape very far at all...
This is my limit...
I can't move...
Damn it...
He's already caught up?
And...
My head's pounding...
And what's with this wound...?
It seems I was drunk, huh...?
Your appearance...!
It seems you've sobered up...
This is my Kekkei Genkai...
Kekkei genkai...
My Kekkei Genkai freely controls
osteoblastic and osteoclastic cells...
It even controls the concentration
of calcium. It's an ability to form bones.
Basically, there are over two hundred
bones in the human body...
But for me, that's not a set number.
Are these really human bones...?!
If so...!
Dance of the Larch!
I've had it...
So close... you clod.
The smell is moving away...
I'm saved...
Who is?
How?!
I knew it...
My coat?!
It seems you didn't notice your own scent
since you're so used to it...
With that you erased your own scent?
You understand the nature of scents.
No wonder I didn't smell you.
And... as expected,
it's tough to deal with
when you guys split up...
Damn it...
Please wait!
The real deal... starts now!
My role now is to stall this person
as long as possible...
So, I should've avoided any major techniques
that would leave me vulnerable...
But it seems this isn't an opponent
easy enough to beat
without using my secret technique...
Here I go!
I just had surgery
and am not at my best.
But if I just open the first
Inner Gate, the Gate of Opening,
I should somehow...
The first gate... Gate of Opening...
Open!
Primary Lotus!
The impact of the kick
was suppressed by the bones...?!
That's some speed... But it's over.
Damn it... No matter how much I think,
I can't come up with any good strategies!
I've had it... I can't hold any longer...
With me right in front of you,
you can't even howl like a loser...?
Eh?!
Die!
You're mine!
Don't you go smiling
before your death!
What?!
Who are you?!
A Sand...
Shinobi...
Ally of the Leaf!
The Sand...?! Am I still drunk...?
Ten-Finger Drilling Bullets!
Did he shoot the bones
in his fingertips...?!
Impetuous...
You...
When you fought me...
you had more speed and sharpness.
Easy to say...
It's not that I'm holding a grudge...
But, because of you,
I've had kind of a tough time.
I see...
But... why you?
I owe a lot...
to the Leaf.
Sasuke!
I heard you Sand traitors
reconciled with the Leaf...
But to think you'd switch sides
so easily...
It's not like we attacked the Leaf
for the fun of it...
It was an order...
In the same way
that I'm here now.
I see. The Fifth Hokage
asked the Sand...
That's a big help.
By the way...
has your sharpness gotten worse?
Huh?
Are you going to give up again
or something?
This time, I'll finish it for you!
Sorry, but I can't give up.
A man mustn't be protected
by a woman, so...
As usual, you're annoying
with the man and woman stuff.
Even if you act tough, it's totally obvious
that it's bravado, you idiot!
This time you're taking sides
with the Leaf, huh?!
You guys sure are busy
all over the place!
She uses genjutsu
with the sound of her flute.
Right!
Cyclone Scythe Jutsu!
Blowing away the sounds of the flute
and being able to nail the opponent
with a physical attack.
To think she can attack and defend
with one move...
Unlike me, she has a nice jutsu.
That woman's a natural enemy to me!
Has Ukon caught him yet, like we planned?
Puppet, huh?
Behind you!
I can't... move.
What's this guy?
I leave this to you, Sakon! Do it!
Be careful!
They enter the body and start to fuse!
It's too late.
It seems like...
your jutsu doesn't work... on puppets.
This is a puppet, too?!
Let me tell you this.
We Sand ninja aren't as soft as the Leaf.
And another thing,
don't carelessly approach...
the Black Ant!
He was fearsome
when he was an enemy...
But to think he'd be this
dependable as an ally.
Ow... I got careless.
Let me rest in your body for a bit.
Good for nothing guy...
Who are these guys?
This is their ability!
Although you were caught off guard...
you getting hammered
by that puppet play...
Well...
Its power and speed
are nothing special.
I won't be beaten
by the likes of such a toy.
He's already healed.
What incredible regenerative abilities...
Ordinarily, I'm not the one
who becomes the main body,
so it's hard to move, damn it.
He's not an opponent
you can beat fighting head on!
We should retreat for now and...
We can't back down after being mocked like that.
The Black Ant isn't a mechanism
for attacking.
Primarily, it's just for capturing.
And... Crow paired up with the Black Ant
is exclusively for attacking.
Hey you! Let me out!
Black Secret Technique: Iron Maiden!
She hid, huh...?
I told you to just explain the situation.
Don't misjudge my power...
If she thinks
she's hiding from me...
yet stays close enough for the sound
of her flute to reach...
she's nave!
Summoning: Blade Dance!
Cut!
All right...
I've made it this far.
It's about time for my genjutsu...
Huh?
How about it?
It's done.
She's sure... pushy.
She's scarier than my own mom.
Pretty good, huh?
But well...
I just have to be grateful
for this time... huh?
I'll do it.
No! Please back me up.
I got sand in my mouth...
P-Please let me go!
You wouldn't be able to do
anything in your current state...
I'll do it.
Gaara of the Desert...
You use sand,
as the name implies, huh...?
Tough defense using sand...
He... isn't a close-range combat type...
Getting close would be difficult, huh.
Ten-Finger Drilling Bullets!
Attack and defense are one...
He attacks and defends
with sand, huh?
However, the amount of sand
he can control is probably...
... about the amount of sand
inside that gourd.
Going to the trouble of walking around
carrying heavy sand
is the very proof of that.
Sand Shower...
How trite...
It's easy for me to create sand
from the earth...
I get it...
With his own sand, he grinds rocks
and minerals in the earth
and makes it into sand.
So he was sending his own sand
beneath the ground
and adding new sand, huh...?
Gaara of the Desert...
His nickname isn't just for display.
Excellent!
You did it!
Not yet.
Sand Burial!
N-No way...
That's quite some pressure...
I would've been crushed flat
if I hadn't made a membrane of
bone just below the skin.
Bones... That guy's a monster, too.
It's a troublesome body, isn't it?
I underestimated you...
But, I won't be caught by
your sand anymore.
Sand Tsunami!
To think it would change
the terrain itself...
Giant Sand Burial!
H-He's so strong...
He's gotten even stronger
than when he fought me.
But... this time for sure...
He's a persistent guy...
Huh?!
I'm still... alive...
Then... There's still a reason
for me to live.
From now, we're going
to launch a night attack
on the Hidden Mist Village...
They're still in disarray
from that incident,
now is the perfect time for us
to make them realize our ferocity!
Make them realize the ferocity
of the Kaguya Clan!
- Yeah!
- Right!
What are you doing, Kimimaro?
Get going!
I don't know what to do...
You don't need to think
deeply about it.
Go down to the Hidden Mist Village
and kill every last person
you encounter!
Just act on your instincts!
Are you of the Hidden Mist Village?
No...
I-I see... Excuse me!
Haku?
Oh... no. It's nothing, Zabuza-san.
We don't have time to be stopping.
Let's hurry!
Right!
He had the same eyes as I do...
Before I met Zabuza-san...
Hold it!
You're a hasty one, aren't you?
I'm not from this village.
What you seek is over there...
Now, go.
It seems to have begun...
The Kaguya Clan...
Fools who can only find
their own path of life by fighting...
It was long ago
when a simple-minded clan that only
enjoyed slaughter was acceptable.
When facing an organized force,
they just become fools
rushing towards death
that fight only with power...
Again, I'm all alone...
Why are you blooming
in a place like this?
Why won't you answer?
You're ignoring me, too, huh?!
There's no way you'd be seen
by someone in a place like this, yet you...
That's enough...
Maybe... there's no meaning to living.
But you might be able to
discover something interesting
by continuing to live... right?
Like how you discovered that flower...
Like how I discovered you.
Okay, let's go...
The mission for me...
is to protect Lord Orochimaru
and his ambition.
What's... that?!
That form...?!
So that's the extent of your
rumored Absolute Defense?
How disappointing.
I see... You were wearing sand.
Your opponent's not just him!
That attack just now...
It would've been dangerous
had I not been protected by sand.
M-My body is still...
I'll just be a hindrance like this.
Annoying sand...
You're first, Gaara.
He yanked out his spinal column?!
Dance of the Clematis...
Vine!
Flower!
A bone of the strongest calcification...
It will pierce you,
sand defense and all...
No time... huh?
It's hard...
I gathered the hardest minerals
from the earth,
applied pressure with chakra
and mixed them into the sand.
You... that unusual jutsu...
It's a Kekkei Genkai, right?
Yes. From the Kaguya Clan...
An ability which now
only I possess.
The last one of your clan, then?
Well, it'll die out here today.
Indeed, that might happen.
Because of my sickness,
my body won't last much longer...
But, the clan will not die out.
Besides, I'm not alone.
Did you say, not alone?
That's right...
As one who plays a part in
Lord Orochimaru's ambition...
I will remain inside
Lord Orochimaru's soul...
for all eternity.
Orochimaru's brainwashing, huh...?
You're a pitiful guy.
I used my big moves too much.
I don't have much chakra.
This is the last of it.
I'll sink and confine you
200 meters into the ground.
By the pressure of the sand
stuck to your body,
you'll soon be unable to move,
not even a finger...
Dance...
of the Seedling Fern!
Thanks for saving me...
Being able to do something
like this is very impressive.
All I did was ride the sand
I was already controlling.
You just have to know how to use it.
He was a persistent guy,
but this is the end.
He won't ever come out again.
Right...
I can't go on...
We're getting off...
It's not brainwashing!
That person...
Lord Orochimaru understands me!
What do you guys know?!
He's dead...
Could it be? Has Kimimaro...?
Kimimaro's fate is of
no consequence now...
Sasuke... I can hardly wait for him.
He will come here on his own...
I would have been done for.
That's not the case.
My sensei said it often...
Luck is also a part of strength.
That meddlesome sensei of yours?
He's not meddlesome!
I'm grateful for you saving me.
But please don't talk like that
about my sensei!
You, too...?
When you feel the honor of
someone you revere has been hurt,
you take it personally
and become enraged.
The more important the person
you revere is to you,
the greater the feeling...
Fighting for the sake of someone
important to you...
He was also the same
as Naruto Uzumaki...
But... the person who is important
to oneself
isn't always a "good person."
I wonder...
There's no way someone evil
could be important to anyone.
No. Even if you know they're evil...
People cannot overcome loneliness...
Sasuke!