What do you think you're doing
with Grandpa's things?!
Honorable Grandson...
Those belong to my Grandpa!
Where are you taking them?!
Uh... you mean these?
They are no longer used,
so I was moving them
into a storage elsewhere.
No longer used, you say...
You think it's okay to take Grandpa's
things away without permission?!
The Fifth Hokage will be using
this office, you see.
The Fifth Hokage?
Y-Yes.
The next Hokage
has finally been decided.
The village can have peace of mind now.
That person apparently
doesn't smoke tobacco...
What do you mean, Fifth Hokage?!
It's too soon for that!
When you all relied on
the Old Man until just recently!
There are seven birds within 50 meters
behind me at 2 o'clock.
Tenten...?
Neji!
I just heard that Lady Tsunade
has returned!
It's really her.
Want to go see her?
Sorry.
But I'm not interested.
Huh?
So there were...
eight birds, huh...
Listen carefully, Tsunade.
We must call the feudal lords
and announce that
the Fifth Hokage has been chosen.
We will start preparations today
for the inauguration ceremony in the village.
Feudal lords and ceremonies
are just a big pain.
Tsunade!
Yes, yes, I know...
This is part of the Hokage's job, too.
- Genma!
- Here!
- Aoba!
Issue an official notice and
inform the village
within the next few days.
We must introduce the Fifth Hokage.
- Yes, ma'am!
Gimme a break,
my shoulders are so stiff.
I wish I could just down
a nice cup of hot sake and relax.
Lady Tsunade!
Wait a second!
Before you do that,
you have something else you need to do,
Old Lady Tsunade!
What was it?
I told you, didn't I?!
About Kakashi-sensei and
Sasuke and Bushy Brow!
Oh... right, right.
Hey, if it isn't Naruto!
Huh? Shikamaru?
Why are you in a place like this?
That's my question-
I have no idea why,
but my father told me
to come along with him.
What's up with that?
Long time no see, Lady Tsunade.
Oh, the kid from the Nara clan, huh...?
Are you taking proper care
of the deer?
The antlers of the deer from
that area make very good medicine.
Yes, I'm somehow managing.
Hey, Naruto, who's that person
who acts like such
a big shot when she's so young?
That's apparently the new Hokage.
Huh?!
Despite her appearance,
she's an old lady in her fifties.
Ehh?!
Well, see you again sometime.
Yes, ma'am.
All right, to the hospital!
See you later, Shikamaru.
I'll show you an awesome
new technique I learned!
That's the new Fifth Hokage...?
Hey, Shikamaru.
That person is the strongest
and most beautiful person in the world.
Huh?
I mean, she's the only woman
among the Legendary Sannin.
Huh... A woman Hokage!?
I'm not very comfortable with women...
Huh?
They're pushy, they meddle in everything,
and you can never tell what
they're really thinking.
They always think they can make
men do whatever they want.
Anyway, they're just a drag.
Hey Shikamaru...
Without women,
men wouldn't be born.
If women weren't around,
nothing good would come of men.
No matter how tough
a woman might be,
she'll show her gentle side
to the man she loves.
I can't believe Dad's saying that...
when he's so completely whipped by Mom.
You'll understand once
you reach that age.
Oh no!
Let's hurry up and
get our business done...
because Mom will chew us out
if we're late.
Hurry up, Shikamaru!
I'm coming in.
Who are you...?
What a beautiful woman...
Sakura, Sakura!
Everything will be all right now!
I brought along an awesome person.
Sasuke will be fine now!
Naruto...
Those two flowers aren't from
the same day.
So this kid is coming here
every day, huh...
I heard from Guy-sensei...
Please save Sasuke.
Okay, leave it to me.
Sasuke!
Sasuke...
Sasuke, you...!
Hmm, despite his appearance,
Naruto is pretty considerate.
Huh?
Next! Next!
How disgraceful!
To be taken down by
just two rogue ninja.
And here I thought you were a genius.
I'm sorry...
All right! Kakashi-sensei's done!
Next, Bushy Brow!
Please, hurry and examine my disciple, Lee!
Lee!
I brought Lady Tsunade here!
That's your disciple?
Yes! My beloved, beloved disciple!
I see...
Naruto.
Huh?
Should you really be wasting time here?
Uh, I almost forgot!
I had an appointment to
meet Iruka-sensei!
Go on!
Okay! I'll leave the rest in your hands!
All right!
Hey, Naruto!
You're late, Iruka-sensei!
Sorry, sorry.
There were lots of things to do
regarding the Fifth Hokage.
I guess...
I'll be straight with you.
Give up on being a shinobi.
L-Lady Tsunade...
don't joke like that.
There are numerous bone fragments
in the area around important nerves.
Moreover, they are deeply embedded.
Physically, you can no longer
function as a shinobi.
Come now, Lady Tsunade,
don't joke like that...
Even if I were to operate...
Don't be fooled, Lee!
That Lady Tsunade is an impostor!
You've used the Transformation Jutsu,
you evil woman!
Who the hell are you?!
Don't I have any... chance?
There is no one besides me
who is capable of doing the surgery
and it would take too much time.
Furthermore, there is a huge risk...
Risk?
The probability of
a successful surgery is 50% at best,
and if it fails...
You'll die.
Guy-sensei!
I'm not at all ready
to throw in the towel!
Guy-sensei, what's this god awful
bitter rice dumpling?
They are Youthful Vigor Herbal Pills.
If you eat one hundred of them,
they should heal your wound.
I see, if I don't eat
one hundred of them,
my wound won't heal, right?
N-Not in a single day!
It's better for you to give up
on being a shinobi and find another path.
Lee...
If I knew this would happen,
I never should have brought you here.
Don't say that...!
I know how painful this is for you,
but it's better to be direct.
Because it's something he'll have
to understand sooner or later.
The longer we wait...
the harder it will be for him.
I'd like to prove that
I could become a splendid ninja
even though I can't
use ninjutsu or genjutsu!
That would be the ultimate for me!
At this rate,
we will have to open it by force.
Try it! Who do you think I am?!
I am the grandson of
the Third Hokage!
If you go against me, then...
It means you're going
against the Hokage!
We need Lady Tsunade
to assume her position immediately.
Those are pepper smoke bombs!
You'll get something worse
if you come any closer!
Honorable Grandson! Even for you...
There are things that can
and cannot be forgiven!
Shut up!
What is all this commotion
so early in the morning?
It's hurting my head.
Lady Tsunade...
Just one kid...
What are you all doing?
Yes...
Get rid of him!
But it's the grandson
of the Third Hokage!
It doesn't matter if
he's the grandson or the great-grandson.
I am the granddaughter
of the First Hokage!
A good thrashing might knock
some sense into him.
Now move it!
- Yes!
Wait!
Naruto?!
Hey, hold on there.
I don't really know what's going on,
but don't be so rough with Konohamaru,
Granny Tsunade.
An acquaintance of yours?
Yes, yes...
I'll do the convincing, leave it to me.
Then get this settled by the end of the day!
Oh, Lady Tsunade... Please wait!
I would think that at least
one bar would be open.
There's no way.
What time do you think it is right now?
I can't drink sake, and I can't gamble.
The Hidden Leaf Village...
This place is no fun at all.
This place is just like the Third Hokage.
Lady Tsunade!
Oh, I'm tired.
I just want to sit down and
have a drink somewhere.
I understand.
I'll take you to a place where
you can sit and have a drink.
What?
But I will have you do your work!
Eight D-rank missions,
three C-rank missions...
I see, very much like Team Kurenai.
We can easily figure out
what the Third Hokage was thinking.
This is the same as
their parents' team.
I see.
Oh, I see. This team has its
own specialty and is well-balanced.
My shoulders are stiff.
I'm going to go get
some fresh air outside.
Success...
Oh, now I'm mad!
I could bust down a door or two
with this new technique of mine!
- Naruto!
Granny Tsunade...
Oh! Watch out!
W-Wow...
I can't believe that I let
Lady Tsunade out of my sight!
Did you find her, Tonton?
Cell Revitalization, I see.
I've found you, Lady Tsunade.
What?
Lady Tsunade is studying
Be quiet! I can't concentrate.
Concentrate?!
I've never heard you use that word
except when you're gambling.
Is that Shizune's voice?
Shizune...
Do you remember that medical ninja
by the name of Kabuto?
What about him?
His cell regeneration technique.
I was researching ways to apply
that technique to patients.
For Lee?
If I can raise that 50% chance to 51%,
it's worth trying.
It really depends on
the individual's traits.
Even for you, mastering that technique
would probably be difficult.
I'll just have to try.
I am the Fifth Hokage, after all.
It can't be helped, Konohamaru.
I am the Third Hokage, after all.
If you don't like it,
you should just quit!
Everybody from the village
is my family.
To protect the family,
that is the duty of a Hokage.
Oh! Old Man!
Just for today,
I'm making a special exception.
What's the matter, Konohamaru?
Don't you want to see
Old Lady Tsunade?
No.
I'll just have to do it.
I am the Fifth Hokage, after all.
It can't be helped, Konohamaru.
I am the Third Hokage, after all.
I guess it can't be helped.
I'm the Honorable Grandson, after all.
Huh?
I am Konohamaru of the Hidden Leaf Village,
after all!
H-Hey, Konohamaru, wait!
What's going on with him?
Hey, Konohamaru!
Lady Tsunade?
Nothing...
Clone Jutsu!
Transformation Jutsu!
Hey, young kid...
Youth is about passion
and never looking back!
Listen, if you give it your all,
you will become a splendid shinobi!
Yay!
Who is he?
He is pretty overbearing.
Son, be ambitious! Bloom of Youth...
Well then, farewell.
Here you are.
Guy-sensei?
How did you know I was here?
I know everything about you.
I heard you skipped rehabilitation
these past two days?
You can't be doing that!
When I first became a Genin...
this is where I revealed
my dream, my aspiration.
Neji laughed at me then,
but I meant what I said.
I'd like to prove that
I could become a splendid ninja
even though I can't use
ninjutsu or genjutsu!
That would be the ultimate for me!
At that time, you told me...
If you act with passion,
compete with rivals,
you can become a fine ninja.
And that...
In order to do that, it'd take "effort."
I was happy to hear that.
- Transform!
Because while at the academy...
no one, not one friend or teacher,
said that kind of thing to me.
You put me at ease...
You opened up a path
just when I was unsure of myself.
I realized all I had to do
was try my best.
And when I complained that
all my efforts couldn't match
the others' natural talents,
you told me that I had
a natural talent for effort.
That was when I learned the importance
of believing in my own strength.
The chance of a successful surgery
is probably 50%, at best.
But... this is one time...
even if I try my best...!
And even if I believe in myself,
there's nothing in the world I can do!
Guy-sensei... Please tell me...!
Please tell me.
Can I become like you?
Why did this kind of thing
happen only to me?
Because I have my own
Ninja Way to follow.
I have my own dreams I have to protect,
and I will prove them,
even if it means dying!
What should I do?!
The Eight Inner Gates...
The Forbidden Jutsu that destroys
the user's body?
Please tell me!
I'm prepared for the worst.
Please teach me that Forbidden Jutsu!
Everything is... for my dream!
That means everything to me!
The time is right...
Head for the Leaf Village, now!
But thank goodness
your injury wasn't serious.
Naruto was relieved, too...
Sasuke, you must be hungry.
Is there something you want to eat?
I'll go buy something for you.
To be honest,
I really don't understand.
It seems there were opinions that,
with the final round of the exams being suspended,
no one should pass this time around.
But I hear the late Third Hokage
highly praised your match.
It seems he intended to recommend you
for Chunin.
The lords of other lands
who observed the fight
and the proctors were of
the same opinion as well...
In that case, it's not my place to object.
From now on,
strive to perform in a manner
that is worthy of that headband...
Congratulations!
As of today, you're a Chunin!
- Wow...
- Wow!
Even someone as lazy as you
looks respectable for once.
It doesn't suit you.
Hey, don't laugh...
For the time being,
let's have a toast to celebrate
Shikamaru's promotion to Chunin!
Let's eat!
Oh! Choji!
Don't eat the meat before the toast!
But, it'd be a waste if it got burned, so...
There's a lot of meat. Eat up!
All right!
You'll end up in the hospital again, Choji.
Don't you know how to savor the taste?
Never mind!
Even if I eat a lot,
I know how to savor properly.
Hey! Choji, that's the last piece of meat
that I've been grilling!
The last bite!
This is the conclusion and
will become the meat with
the greatest value that should be savored!
I won't hand over
this last bite to anyone!
What are you acting cool for,
you idiot?!
Everyone makes fun of you
because you're like this!
- You're just a fat-
- Ino!
That's a taboo word!
But really, Choji...
A meal isn't a battle.
You need to relax sometimes.
What a drag.
Foul-mouthed... Gluttonous...
Too lazy...
I wonder if these guys
will be okay from now on.
In particular...
Choji. With you, it's nothing but food.
Do a little training sometime!
Right now,
I have no interest in you...
So your target is Naruto, after all.
Hey, Sakura!
Naruto!
It's a tranquil village as always...
The security sucks.
Humph!
We should just slaughter everyone
in this pathetic village.
Calm down, Sakon.
We haven't come here to fight.
Shut up, you coward.
If you're scared,
you should just go home
and go to bed already.
I'm telling you to calm down, Tayuya.
You understand what
our job is this time, right?
I got some apples...
You like them, right?
Here, doesn't it look good?
Huh...? I wonder where I put the knife...
It's right there in front of you.
It's so lame, you're getting all scatterbrained
just because you're in front of Sasuke.
I'd take "lame" from anyone but you...
Naruto...
U-zu-ma-ki!
Naruto 2K Barrage!
Knock it off already!
Summoning Jutsu!
I will... protect Sakura!
I-I give up...
Sasuke... Thank you.
You rescued me from
those Sand shinobi, right?
No...
The person who rescued you...
was Naruto.
You are weak.
Why are you weak...?
It's because you don't have enough...
... hate.
Good. I peeled it nicely.
I'll cut it to make it easy to eat, and...
Here, Sasuke.
Ow! What happened?
S-Sasuke?
Huh? What's going on?
Hey, Naruto...
What is it?
Fight me... Right now!
What?!
Granny Tsunade just finished treating you!
What are you saying?
Just fight!
Sasuke...
You think you saved me?
I don't care if she's the Fifth Hokage
or whatever, but...
she should've just minded
her own business!
What?!
You said you wanted to fight me, right?
I'm saying let's do it now!
Or have you chickened out?
S-Sasuke. Hey...
What's going on?!
Naruto, you say something too!
What's this all of a sudden?
This is perfect!
I was just thinking
I wanted to fight you!
Come with me!
What's... this feeling?
My stomach's all tingly...
I want to fight you, too.
And... I feel a thrill.
What's so funny?
Nothing's funny! I'm just happy!
Because I'm thinking
I can finally beat you here!
What was that? Don't get cocky, you loser!
I'm not going to be
a failure forever!
Right now,
I have no interest in you...
You... A loser like you shouldn't be
acting all high and mighty!
Hah! It's unlike you to lose
your cool and raise a fuss.
So uncharacteristic.
It couldn't be that you picked a fight
and then got scared, could it, Sasuke?
Just bring it, now!
Put on your headband before that!
I'll wait.
I don't need such a thing...
Just do it!
You couldn't even put a scratch on my forehead!
You're wrong!
This is the symbol of our fight as equals,
as shinobi of the Leaf!
And I'm saying stuff like that
is acting high and mighty!
Do you think that we're equal?!
Yeah, I do! I've never once
thought that I'm inferior to you!
You're an eyesore!
That's because you're still weak,
little Sasuke!
Naruto!
Sasuke!
Don't be getting carried away!
That's enough!
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
U-zu-ma-ki!
Naruto Barrage!
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
N-Naruto!
Wh-What is that jutsu?!
Damn it!
S-Stop...
I'll win no matter what!
Don't flatter yourself!
Stop it!
Damn.
I can't stop completely.
What are you guys doing
on top of the hospital?
You went a bit too far
for just a fight, you two.
Were you going to kill Naruto, Sasuke?
A Chidori of that size wasn't to be aimed
at a comrade from your own village.
Why are you acting like such a child...?
Sure enough, his reunion with Itachi...
Damn it!
Naruto, how far will you go?
Was it you who taught him
that technique?
Even if it were a means
to resist the Akatsuki,
to think that you would
teach Naruto the Rasengan.
If he slipped up,
he would have killed Sasuke.
Right back at you...
That Chidori was also
considerably risky.
But I didn't think
Naruto was the kind of kid
who would use that jutsu on a comrade.
To Naruto, Sasuke is a comrade
and a rival at the same time.
Well, someone he considers an equal.
He probably fell for
Sasuke's cheap provocations.
He's been chasing him
since the Academy days.
For him, it's neither
you nor me now.
More than anyone,
he wants to be recognized by Sasuke.
On the other side of the coin,
Sasuke feels the speed of
Naruto's growth at close range
and feels inferior.
Naruto has gotten strong.
So strong that he feels like
he isn't growing at all.
Revenge, huh?
I wonder if Itachi is
the one frustrating him.
That's why Sasuke doesn't
want to acknowledge Naruto.
If he acknowledges him,
he might end up denying
his own path up to this point...
Rivalry is a difficult thing.
This isn't a very good development...
Maybe I’ll give him a little lecture.
Then I’ll leave Naruto to you.
I’ve got a mission coming up...
and there’s also the matter of the Chidori.
Sakura.
It's okay. Things can go back to
how they used to be.
Cheer up.
See ya.
Naruto...
Sakura.
Don't interfere with us!
You are weak.
Why are you weak?
It's because you don't have enough...
... hate.
Now that's a good look in his eyes.
What do you think you're doing?
If I don't do this,
you'll run away, right?
You're not the type
to listen quietly to lectures.
Sasuke... Forget about revenge.
What?
Well, in this line of work,
I've seen plenty of guys like you.
Those who live for revenge
always meet...
a tragic end.
You'll only hurt yourself and
agonize more than now.
Even if you succeed in revenge,
all that will remain is emptiness.
Shut up!
What do you know?
Don't talk to me as if you know!
Well, calm down...
What if...
I were to kill the one you love most...
would that make you understand
how wrong you really are—
about everything you just said?
Well, I wouldn't mind if you'd do that.
Unfortunately, I don't even have
one person like that.
Everyone's already been killed.
I've lived longer than you have...
It hasn't all been good things for me either.
I know all too well
the agony of losing those I care about.
Well, both you and I
aren't the lucky ones...
That's for sure.
But we're not the worst off, either.
You and I,
we've both found precious comrades,
haven't we?
It's because I've lost people too
that I understand.
The Chidori is a power...
I gave to you because you now
have someone important to protect.
You should know that
it's not a power
to be used on your comrades
or for revenge.
I'm sure you know
what it should be used for.
Think carefully about whether
what I'm saying is wrong.
As I recall,
that's Kakashi the Copy Ninja.
So let's wait a bit.
Maybe you scum couldn't do it,
but I can.
I wonder. Two should be ample
to rip him apart.
Stay out of it, you moron.
Tayuya, women shouldn't
use words like that...
Shut up, you fatso.
- More, please!
Want to head back?
Sure!
We both made it
to the top of the tree.
Sakura.
I have something to talk
to you about.
I'll go out on a date with you,
so come along.
Damn it...
Damn it!
We are the Sound Four.
We're here on orders
from Lord Orochimaru.
I'm in a bad mood right now.
If you want to fight, just know
that I won't go easy on you.
Stop your babbling, weakling.
He called me... weak?
Hey, come over here.
I'm going to play do-re-mi-fa-so-la-ti-do
on your ribs until they crack.
Are you saying that Orochimaru
left a Curse Mark on Sasuke's body?
Yes.
He said, "Sasuke will come to me
without fail, in search of power."
I see. I didn't know such
a thing happened.
Orochimaru... I ran into him again
a little while back.
What?!
He was one of the Sannin
and he's ridiculously strong
and dangerous.
But, everything will be okay!
Sasuke wouldn't be tempted
by a guy like that!
He's already super strong,
so he doesn't need to do
that kind of thing!
Come with us.
If you do,
Lord Orochimaru will give you power.
What is your goal?
Are you and your comrades
just going to comfort each other
in a peaceful village like this,
trying to forget all about Itachi Uchiha?
Don't forget your goal.
A village like this does nothing
more than shackle you!
Just cut your worthless bonds
with this place.
If you do that, you'll be able
to obtain amazing power.
Don't forget your goal.
Why are you hanging around in a place
like this in the middle of the night?
You have to take this road
to leave the village...
Go home and sleep.
Why...
Why won't you tell me anything?
Why are you always silent like that?
You won't tell me one single thing.
Why should I have to tell you anything?!
I'm telling you to keep your nose
out of my business.
Stop bothering me
over everything I do.
I... I'm always just causing trouble,
aren't I?
Do you remember?
We just became Genin and
the three-man squads were assigned...
Yeah, I guess...
that was long ago, after all...
But it all began that day.
Sasuke and me...
And also Naruto and Kakashi-sensei...
The four of us went
on various missions, didn't we?
Those were tough and
difficult times, but...
But...
more than anything...
It was so much fun!
I know about your family, Sasuke...
But revenge...
that won't bring anyone happiness.
No one...
Neither you...
nor I.
As I expected...
I'm different from you guys...
I'm walking my own path.
The four of us worked together...
and it's true that there was a time
when I thought that was my road.
The four of us have worked together,
but in the end,
I decided on revenge.
That's been my reason for living.
I can't become like
you and Naruto.
Are you going to isolate
yourself again...?!
Sasuke, you're the one who taught me
how painful it is to be alone!
Now I know exactly how that feels.
I have both family and friends...
But if you were no longer here, Sasuke...
for me...
for me, it would be the same as being all alone.
From here on...
we're going to start walking
our new paths individually.
I...!
I love you so very, very much, Sasuke!
If you would only be with me, Sasuke,
I won't let you regret it,
no matter what!
I'll make it fun every day and
you will definitely find happiness!
I'll do anything for you, Sasuke!
So... I'm begging you,
please stay here!
I'll even help you with your revenge!
I'll make it happen somehow,
I promise you...!
So stay here... with me...!
If that doesn't work for you...
Then take me with you...
You really are... annoying.
Don't go!
If you go, I'll scream and...
Sakura...
Thank you...
Sasuke...
We were waiting for you, Lord Sasuke.
What's this all about?
It was already decided that
you would be our leader
the moment you left the village.
Please forgive our rudeness
up to now.
I don't care about any of that.
Let's go.
This is the beginning!
It's already four o'clock
in the morning...
The Fifth Hokage is such a slave driver.
She ought to retrieve
the documents she forgot herself...
Huh... What's the matter?
Hey! Wake up!
You'll catch cold if you sleep
in a place like this.
Huh!
Sasuke!
What did you just say?!
Is that true?!
Yes...
According to Sakura Haruno,
it appears that there's no mistake...
So what that freak wants...
is the Uchiha's power, huh...
Izumo! Kotetsu!
There's somebody
I want you to bring here!
Hurry up and eat, Shikamaru!
Your Dad's mission starts today, too!
There's not that much time
for morning training!
Okay, Okay.
One "Okay" is enough!
Nag, nag, nag from early
in the morning...
I wonder who it could be
so early in the morning?
Hey... Dad...
What is it?
Why did you marry
a tough woman like Mom?
Let's see now...
Even though Mom's like that,
she smiles gently sometimes...
Maybe that's why...
Is that the only reason?
Shikamaru!
A messenger from the Fifth Hokage
is here.
Sasuke Uchiha apparently slipped out
of the village late last night.
And... it's almost certain
that he is headed for
the Hidden Sound Village.
Slipped out?! Why...
Because he was enticed by
that Orochimaru!
W-W-Wait a minute!
Why would Sasuke get tempted
by a creep like that?!
The reason doesn't matter.
In any case, there's no time.
You will perform your first mission
as a Chunin...
So all I have to do
is bring Sasuke back?
As long as there aren't
any enemies around,
that shouldn't be too much of a drag...
Yes... However, not only is time
of the essence on this mission,
but it may turn into something
quite difficult.
Huh?!
There is a strong possibility that
those under the control of Orochimaru
are guiding Sasuke.
This is turning into a real drag.
That guy... I actually respected him
in a lot of ways...
In that case, please give me
a four-man team
composed only of Jonin and Chunin.
I'm afraid I can't do that...
Huh! Why?!
You already know
the answer to that...
Right now, only the barest minimum
number of Jonin have been left behind
and the others have all
left the village on missions.
Within the next 30 minutes,
Gather the best available Genin
and leave the village!
There's one guy I want to recommend.
What! You've have to be kidding!
You're so damn loud this early
in the morning...
But why this guy?
That jerk!
Hey, just wait here!
I'll change my clothes immediately!
So, do you have your eye...
on any other awesome guys besides me?
Yeah...
Wake up! Hey!
You said excellent guys, right...
Can't be helped...
Potato chips?
They're barbecue flavor...
you want to help out too, right?
Huh?!
Here he comes!
Even if it is just potato chips,
I won't give the last chip to anyone,
I don't care who it is!
Choji and I have worked as
a team for many years,
so coordinating with him
is easiest for me.
I understand that,
but in this kind of situation,
you'd normally ask Shino first!
Oh, shut up.
Fat chance!
Shino is on a special mission
with his father.
Hey... don't tell me...
Right. He's in.
No way!
I see... Sounds interesting...
It looks like it was worth getting up early
and going for a walk, doesn't it?
Shikamaru, is there anyone else?
I'd like to take my time to look for more,
but we're pressed for time.
If we don't find anybody else
by the time we leave the village,
it will be just us!
I see...
It's a drag,
but the more people we have, the better...
Damn... At a time like this, I...
Lee! Do what you need to do.
All right!
Everybody, follow me!
Hey...
Hey, Naruto...
I'm supposed to be the squad leader.
Though it sure is a drag...
You really think everything will be okay
if things are left in your hands?
You don't seem very reliable...
What's up with you acting
like the boss, Naruto?
Although being ordered about by
some unmotivated guy like Shikamaru
doesn't sit right with me either...
But Shikamaru is already a Chunin!
We have to follow his orders.
It means the village elders recognized him
as capable of being a leader.
Since that's the case,
come up with some strategy and plan.
From what I heard,
there are enemies
and there's a strong possibility
that they'll ambush us.
For a start,
as this is a rescue operation,
we will be in the position
of pursuit.
In other words,
the enemy can easily gain the initiative.
Therefore, I will decide
on a deployment formation
that will respond quickly
to any assault by the enemy.
If you ignore my orders and
act on your own,
we will all die.
We will go in a single file formation.
First,
the all-important spearhead will be...
Kiba, that's you!
You and Akamaru go on
walks year-round
and are therefore well versed in the
terrain and geography of the Land of Fire.
And since your nose is
very sensitive,
you can track Sasuke
with your sense of smell and,
you can distinguish booby traps
that carry the enemy's scent
which makes them
easy to find...
And moreover, you and Akamaru as
a pair will be extremely efficient
in compensating for the single file
formation's vulnerability to assault.
And... second in line will be me,
the squad leader.
I can give orders
as required in any situation
from my position
directly behind Kiba
and can give orders to those behind me
using only hand signals.
And in the middle...
in the number three position is Naruto.
The middle position is
the best for you,
since you're capable
of executing quick moves
and are able to respond immediately
to anything in front or behind.
You're our key player...
And you have your Shadow Clones.
And fourth in line is Choji.
You. You don't have speed,
but your ability to strike is the best
among the squad members.
Kiba, our point man, along with me and Naruto
can launch a surprise attack,
and I'm saving you for the final strike.
In other words, your role is
to attack the routed enemy.
And last, bringing up the rear,
is you, Neji...
You are assigned to
the most difficult position: rear lookout.
You'll use your Byakugan
to constantly check
that there are no blind spots
in our formation.
Got it? Take a careful look at this.
Use this diagram to verify
the radius of your assigned watch.
Kiba watches the front,
I'm responsible for
a wide forward view,
Naruto watches left, Choji right,
and Neji...
Using your Byakugan,
you'll cover our entire rear flank.
I want to get a handle on our current
combat capabilities.
Let me check all the ninja equipment
each of you currently has...
I will commit that
to memory straight away.
Any questions?
Even though he just assembled
this team a short while ago,
he's already created
the best possible formation...
If not, I want to tell you
the most important thing last.
Sasuke isn't a close friend,
and I don't even particularly like him.
However, he is also a shinobi belonging
to the Hidden Leaf Village.
He is a comrade!
Therefore, I will put my life
on the line to help him!
That's the way
of the Leaf Village.
In this case, even I can't just sit back
and slack off.
Because I am responsible
for your lives.
Wow... You're actually acting like a Chunin!
Okay then, as soon as he has checked
our ninja tools, we'll depart.
Everybody, take out your ninja tools.
Sasuke wouldn't be tempted
by a guy like that...
He's already super strong,
so he wouldn't need to do
that kind of thing! I guarantee it!
Damn... Why, Sasuke...?!
All right! Let's go!
Wait!
Sakura!
I heard the whole story
from Lady Hokage.
I'm sorry, but I can't take you along
on this mission.
Even you weren't able
to convince Sasuke, right?
All that can be done now is for us
to use force to convince him...
Sakura, your role in this has ended.
Naruto... This is a...
once-in-a-lifetime request...
Please... bring Sasuke back.
I couldn't do it!
I wasn't able to stop Sasuke!
At this point, the only person
who would be able to stop Sasuke...
who would be able to save him...
is you... Naruto...
You like Sasuke so much,
don't you, Sakura?
I really understand
how painful it must be
for you right now, Sakura.
Sakura, there's one thing
I want to ask you.
Huh?
How do you feel about... Naruto?
Getting in the way of romance
just seems to be his thing.
He actually seems to be enjoying
my suffering.
Naruto doesn't understand
a single thing about me.
He's just annoying.
Naruto... thank you...
I'll bring Sasuke back without fail!
That's a promise of a lifetime!
You always understood me...
You always helped me...
Naruto...
Hey, hey, Naruto!
Are you sure it's okay to make
a promise like that?!
Sure! I never go back on my word.
That's my Ninja Way!
All right! Let's hurry up and go!
We've lost a little time...
Let's hurry!
Okay!