Huh? What's this?
A man...?
A person...?
This is... a Summoning Jutsu!
Naruto! Sakura!
Let go of the scroll!
Oh...
Wha?!
Y-You...
Hi!
It's been a long time.
Congratulations on surviving
the second test!
To celebrate your passing,
I'd like to treat you to
some Ichiraku ramen, but...
Ohh... Cool!
Uh oh...
H-Hey, Naruto!
- Listen to the end...
- Cool! Cool!
Ramen! Ramen, y'know!
I've done a great job!
I'm the greatest!
I so want to eat ramen, y'know!
He's got so much energy.
Yaaaay!
Shut up!
Man, you haven't change a bit,
still as scatterbrained as ever.
Oh yeah, Sensei!
Huh?
By the way,
what are the letters on that wall?
They're kind of squiggly and
we don't understand
their meaning at all.
Never mind, never mind!
We passed!
No... explaining that is
also part of my duties.
What, really?
That's right.
Give it a read.
These are Chunin instructions
Lord Hokage recorded.
Instructions?!
That's right!
Heaven in this text
refers to the human head.
Earth refers to the human body.
No kidding...
"If you lack Heaven,
gain knowledge and await your opportunity."
In other words...
If your weaknesses are
inside your head, Naruto...
learn various strategies to
prepare for your missions.
Huh! So troublesome!
"If you lack Earth,
run across the land
to gain your advantage."
If your weaknesses are in
your physical strength, Sakura,
it means you must not
slack off on your daily training.
And if you combine both
Heaven and Earth...
Even a perilous mission can become
manageable...
In other words...
that is how this principle
ensures a safe mission.
Then, what about
the spot with the missing letter?
The letter refers to Chunin.
The "person" character from
your scroll goes there.
These five days of survival
were to test
the candidates' fundamental
abilities as Chunin.
And you guys cleared it splendidly.
Chunin are unit leaders.
They have the responsibility
of leading a team.
Be more deeply aware of
the necessity of physical strength...
and knowledge in missions!
I want you to take on
the next step,
never forgetting these
Chunin instructions.
That is the extent of the message
I was tasked to deliver.
Got it!
But for the third and final test,
don't overdo it.
Especially you, Naruto.
You're the one I'm most worried about...
Iruka-sensei.
From when I received the
Leaf headband,
I'm not an Academy student anymore,
ya know?!
I'm now...
A ninja!
I see.
I'm sorry, Naruto.
I know their strength the best.
If it's futile anyway,
I would like to be the one
to give them the final word.
If you feel that strongly,
I can leave that team to you.
To think you'd plead
their case so strongly...
Thank you very much.
But, they are Kakashi's team,
are they not?
If he's the one who
recommended them,
I thought I could count on them.
The one who might truly understand
the strength of these kids...
is you, Kakashi.
How is it?
Does the Curse Mark still hurt?
No.
Thanks to you,
it's gotten quite a bit better.
Anyway, Orochimaru is one
of the three Legendary Sannin, right?
He's an S-rank rogue shinobi
that even the ANBU couldn't stop, right?
I heard that he'd already died, but...
Why did he come to this village now...?
He's probably after Sasuke, right?
Huh?!
Master Anko!
Twenty-one candidates have
successfully passed the second test.
As for the third test, according
to the regulations of the Chunin Exam,
For the first time in five years,
we're holding preliminaries.
The second test is over.
For the time being,
continue the exam as is,
but while keeping
an eye on his movements.
Yes...
First off, congratulations on
finishing the second test.
There were seventy-eight
test takers for the second test.
To think twenty-one have
made it this far.
I told them I'd cut the number to less than half...
but I was really aiming for single digits
I'm hungry!
There are still this many remaining?
This is such a drag.
Sasuke and his team passed, too.
Of course...
Your team didn't do too badly.
I guess they were lucky.
But as long as my team is around,
they won't get any higher.
After all, whether you
like it or not,
true ability is all that matters
from here on.
Well, youth can be bittersweet,
and can sometimes be harsh, Kakashi...
Did you say something?
Unbelievable!
Not bad, my rival Kakashi.
But that cool attitude of yours...
That's what so irritating!
So that's Guy-sensei's eternal rival, huh?
Guy-sensei really doesn't compare visually...
Guy-sensei is the coolest
of all the teachers!
He shines!
Okay!
Please watch, Guy-sensei!
I'll shine, too!
Now then, if you will,
Master Hokage.
All right.
Now then, allow me to
explain the third test.
But actually...
Please allow me, Hayate Gekko, the proctor
for this test, to have a word first.
I leave it to you...
There's something... I'd like you all
to do...
before the third test.
And that is a preliminary
to the third test,
with a spot in the final rounds
on the line.
Preliminary?
What do you mean... preliminary?!
This time around,
perhaps because the first and
second tests were easy,
there are a few too many
people left.
In accordance with the rules
of the Chunin Exam,
a preliminary will be held in order to
reduce the number advancing.
N-No way!
Many guests will be coming
to the third test.
Our time is limited, so we can't have long,
drawn-out matches.
Therefore, those of you
not in top physical condition...
Excuse me.
Those of you who wish to drop out,
please speak up now.
The preliminary will
begin immediately, so...
Immediately, you say...?!
But we finally made it through
the second test.
What a drag...
Huh? What about our meal?
Okay!
I'm going to do my best, no matter what!
I promised Kabuto, too...
Well...
Excuse me... I'll quit.
Let's see...
Kabuto Yakushi of
the Leaf Village, correct?
Then, you may step back.
Okay.
Kabuto!
Why are you quitting?!
Tell me! Why?!
I'm sorry, Naruto...
But my body is worn out.
Actually before the first test...
when I clashed with those
guys from the Sound Village,
I've had no hearing at all in my left ear.
To fight again right away...
and put my life on the line...
I just can't do it.
I've seen that face a few times.
Anko.
Uh... yes.
Kabuto Yakushi.
According to the data, he has failed
the exam six times in a row.
What about his background?
From his time at the Academy,
he was a student who did
not really stand out,
and his grades were ordinary.
He finally passed the graduation
exam on his third try.
After that, as for the missions
he carried out,
two C-rank and
fourteen D-rank missions.
It's not an impressive service record.
However...
However?
Do you remember the story...
about the boy who was brought back
from the battle of Kikyo Pass?
I remember.
As I recall, I heard that a boy, an enemy
survivor, was found at the battlefield
was taken in by a Jonin from
the medical unit.
So he's that boy...?
My information-gathering role
has served its purpose...
Master Orochimaru.
I'll save the real fun for later...
Sasuke...
And Naruto...
You too.
The waves of pain are
coming faster...
Sasuke... I knew it.
Sasuke, you should quit
the Preliminaries!
Huh?!
L-Look, you haven't been yourself
ever since you were attacked
by that Orochimaru guy!
Please...
Please, quit!
I'm... scared.
You're in no condition to
fight properly, Sasuke...!
Shut up.
I understand!
Be quiet!
But you've been enduring the pain
this whole time, right?!
Please be quiet!
No matter what you say, Sasuke...
I'm going to tell the proctor
about that mark!
If I do that...
Don't talk about this mark.
Why are you acting tough like that?!
I don't want to watch you suffer
all the time anymore!
For me, Sasuke, you are-
This has nothing to do with you!
It's none of your business.
This isn't just an exam to me.
Becoming a Chunin has nothing
to do with it for me.
"Am I strong?"
All I want is the answer to that.
I must fight the strong.
And...
And they are... here!
I will not allow even you
to take my path away from me!
Sasuke...
You!
Why are you acting so tough, you idiot?!
And Sakura's so worried about you...!
Naruto!
I want to fight you, too.
Huh?!
I knew it.
What shall we do?
We should remove him from the exam
and isolate him with an ANBU guard.
We should recommend that
he withdraw immediately.
He's not the type to
just obey like that!
After all, he's of the Uchiha clan.
What nonsense are you talking about?!
I'll make him stop, by force if needed!
I will allow Sasuke to take the test...
- and see how things go.
- Wha?!
L-Lord Hokage...!
However, if the Curse Mark activates
and the power gets even a little bit
out of control,
get in there and stop it.
All right.
Now then, we will begin the Preliminaries.
The upcoming preliminaries
will be one-on-one battles.
In other words, it will be actual combat.
There are now exactly twenty people,
so we will conduct ten battles.
The winners will be able to
advance to the third test.
There are no rules at all.
You will fight until someone dies,
collapses... or admits defeat.
And if you don't want to die,
admit defeat quickly.
However, If I judge
that a match is over...
Eh... I don't want to needlessly
increase the number of fatalities,
so I may intervene and stop the match.
What holds the key to your destinies is...
Open it.
This.
The names of two opponents will be
randomly selected and
displayed on this electronic board.
Now then, let's get right down to it
and announce the two names
for the first battle.
To think it'd be so soon...?!
I couldn't ask for more.
No way!
Why Sasuke?!
Now then, the two displayed on
the board, please come forward.
For the first battle, Yoroi Akado and
Sasuke Uchiha have been selected.
No objections, right?
- Right.
- No!
The pain won't go away!
It appears the Curse Mark hurts.
Everyone other than the two opponents,
please move to the upper area.
Hey! Kakashi-sensei!
Sasuke!
Huh?
Don't use the Sharingan.
So you knew?
If that Curse Mark on your neck
gets out of control,
it could endanger your life.
I believe it.
If that happens, the match will be stopped.
Because I'll be coming in to stop it,
so good luck.
Stopped, you say?!
It seems this Curse Mark thing
is responding to my chakra.
In other words, in this match,
I can hardly use even my regular jutsu,
not to mention the Sharingan!
However... Yoroi's ability is a
particularly bad match-up for you, Sasuke.
Now then, please begin.
Let's go!
Yeah!
Oh no!
My strength...?!
Wh-What is this?
My physical strength has suddenly...!
You... my chakra...
You just noticed now...?
Yes... Yoroi has the unique ability
to absorb chakra.
It's a magnificent art that absorbs
both spiritual and physical energy,
simply by holding his palm against
an opponent's body.
And, if all of your chakra
is absorbed, Sasuke,
you'll be forced to rely on
the power of my Curse Mark...
You little...!
To think you still have strength left...
Especially for a simple test subject.
Sasuke!
You call yourself an Uchiha with that?
Don't be looking so lame!
Do your best!
That's it!
You can't afford to let your guard down!
Is this as far as it goes...?
That's my...!
But then...
this next part is my own creation.
It's over...
I won't be swallowed up...
by this thing...
No way!
Here I go!
I'm not done, yet!
Lions Barrage!
There's no need to check.
I'm stopping the match from
going any further...
Therefore, the winner of the
first battle, Sasuke Uchiha...
passes the Preliminaries!
Yes!
Well. Good job...
Before that Lions Barrage,
your movements were that
of Guy's taijutsu...
Sasuke! You, you...
That was a pathetic way to win!
Look at you, all battered up!
You idiot!
Man, that loser...
Sasuke... Thank goodness.
Okay, I'll win, too!
For a sequence of
high-speed taijutsu like the Lotus,
it's impossible to learn this
without grueling training
that pushes one to their absolute limit.
No matter how much you
use the Sharingan,
it can't just be mastered in
such a short time...
And his idea for that
finishing move...
Kakashi... this boy reminds me
of you as a kid...
It just makes it more interesting!
Yeah! He is Sasuke after all...
This is as far as we'll go...
I'm hungry...
W-Wow!
Nothing special.
Magnificent...
Sasuke Uchiha...
The medical team will provide
the best treatment.
That won't be necessary.
Huh?!
I'll take him under my care...
Now, I'll take you into the back...
and seal the Curse Mark.
Can't it wait until
the preliminaries are over?!
I want to watch
the rest of the matches!
No!
Don't get so heated.
If we let things progress any further,
the damage might become permanent.
I won't indulge you any further.
Now then, come on...
Umm, now then...
We will get right to it and
begin the second match.
Which weakling is it?!
Both of you, come forward.
We will now begin the second match.
He's going to fight with those arms?
Now then, please begin.
Now, Zaku...
Let's see how you handle this...
If you fight here,
you'll be finished...
Withdraw!
Somehow, this one still works, so...
One arm is enough to take care of you!
You can't beat me with just one arm.
Stop pestering me!
Take this!
Slicing Sound Wave!
Okay.
Hang in there.
It'll be over right away.
Sealing Jutsu!
Next time, even if that Curse Mark
starts kicking in again...
the power of this Curse Sealing
should suppress it.
However, this Sealing Jutsu is founded
on the strength of your will.
If something happens like you're
not believing in your own strength
and your will weakens...
the Curse Mark will flare up again.
Out of character.
It appears he's quite tired...
To think you've become able to
handle Sealing Jutsu...
You've grown, huh, Kakashi...?
You...
Long time no see, Kakashi.
Orochimaru...
Sorry, but...
I have no business with you, Kakashi.
But I do have business
with the boy behind you.
Why are you after Sasuke?!
How nice. You have one as well,
don't you?
You didn't have it before, did you?
I want it, too...
The Uchiha power.
Come on. Get up.
B-Bugs?
They burst through the skin...
from inside his body?!
These things are called Parasitic Insects.
They attack their prey in groups
and devour chakra...
When they attack in these numbers...
you're finished, make no mistake.
If you use your left arm
technique on me,
I'll simultaneously have the bugs exploit
the opening from behind.
Conversely, if you use
your technique on the bugs,
I'll simultaneously exploit the opening...
Either way, you won't be able
to get through this.
An ace in the hole is something
you set aside.
Man, what a pigheaded kid.
You have potential, boy.
If you come with me,
you can become strong.
Follow me.
If you come with me,
you can become strong.
No longer...
can I afford
to mess this up!
Don't... underestimate me!
An ace in the hole is something
you keep hidden, is it not?!
So the first half of the battle
was a strategic move
to make us think he couldn't
use his right arm.
Not bad... Zaku.
What's your purpose?
The recently built Sound Village.
That's my village.
And I need various pawns
who will obey my every whim.
Take this!
So Sasuke is one of those pieces?
No. Sasuke is an exceptional piece.
And the ones who are taking
the exams now...
are mere throwaway pieces.
My arms!
Earlier when I recommended
that you give up...
as a precaution, I instructed the bugs...
to block those troublesome air tubes
with their bodies and remain still.
This is what a real ace in the hole is.
Punk!
Don't... come any closer... to Sasuke!
Even if you're one of
the Three Sannin...
at the very least,
I'll take you down with me!
What's funny?
You don't truly mean that.
What?
There's no point at all in
attempting such a seal.
You understand, don't you?
The will to relentlessly
pursue a goal,
regardless of any obstacle...
He is the possessor of that quality.
He's an avenger...
So you took advantage of that, huh?
However, Sasuke is...
At some point,
he will definitely seek me out...
in search of power.
Oh, and, you're going to kill me?
Why don't you try?
That is, if you can...
Take him down with me?!
Am I an idiot?
It seems... it's over.
The winner! Shino Aburame!
Wh-What is he, Neji?!
Byakugan!
He's something else!
I can understand him calling bugs
with a Summoning Jutsu...
but he harbors bugs all over his body.
S-Say what?!
He's from the Leaf Village's clan
of insect users.
Speaking of which, I've heard of it...
The story of a clan that,
from the moment they are born,
offers their bodies to insects
as a nest as part of a secret pact.
They also fight using these bugs.
So he's... the successor?
The mission was the only thing
that tied us together.
However, I'll even the score for you.
Whew. He gives me a chill, indeed...
What?! What?!
So Shino, you were that strong,
weren't you?! Damn it!
I always thought he was
a creepy guy, but...
S-Shino, good... work...
Hey, you did it!
Yes... I'm counting on you guys, too.
He walks back in here acting like he's
the team leader or something! Damn it!
Umm, now then, I would like to
get right to the next match.
Kakashi-sensei!
Yo!
Don't just say "Yo," Kakashi-sensei!
What about Sasuke? Is he okay?
Well, he's fine.
He's sleeping soundly in the infirmary.
However, the ANBU are
standing guard...
It's finally my turn.
Kankuro, he's totally
underestimating this...
Humph. Idiot...
It's him!
Unlike Yoroi,
I don't underestimate kids.
Let me tell you, once I use my jutsu...
you'd better just give up...
I'll bring it to an end swiftly.
If so, I'll also...
First move, a surefire victory!
I dislocate every joint
and with chakra, I can control
my softened body at will.
I'll just keep tightening as long
as you refuse to give up.
I don't know what kind of
ninja tool you'll use...
but if I keep this up,
none of your tools will work.
I can break your neck right now.
So hurry up and give up.
No.
Do you want to die?!
Idiot. You're the one who's
going to die.
His neck is broken.
What?
I went a little overboard and
ended up killing you.
Wh-What?
Okay, now it's my turn.
T-This is a Puppet!
T-That's the real body?
He's... a Puppet Master...
G-Give up!
If I crush your bones,
you'll be able to bend even more.
For once, I was close to stopping
the match in the middle.
The winner, due to the opponent's
inability to continue,
is Kankuro.
Two against one, that's
totally unfair!
Is that fair, Kakashi-sensei?!
It's not really against the rules.
It's a puppet, after all.
That's the Puppet Master Jutsu.
He's controlling the puppet with chakra.
It's the same as using
a ninja tool like shuriken.
Now then, to continue,
we will begin the fourth battle.
Man, nothing but
weirdos all over the place!
Don't you say that!
You've got a point.
You, too, Sakura?!
This isn't the time to be laughing.
I never thought...
I'd be fighting you, Sakura.
And what's more, so soon.
Ino was a standout
among the rookie Kunoichi.
With Sakura as her opponent,
will she... no.
Can she bring herself to fight seriously?
To think it would be those
two of all people.
Things have gotten gloomy.
I wonder if Ino'll be okay.
That's for sure.
What are you going to do, Ino?
Sakura! Good luck! Don't lose!
Begin!
There!
I'm... not good at stuff like this.
What about you, Ino?
That's no good, considering
your name's Sakura.
Listen. There are tricks
to things like this.
You know, as for flower arranging,
after you've decided on a main flower,
you add other flowers to decorate.
Not every flower can be the main focus.
For example... look.
You can see those cosmos
flowers over there, right?
If they were the main flowers...
the thoroughwort flowers
you picked are throwaways!
As contrasted with
spring cherry blossoms,
cosmos flowers are also known
as autumn cherry blossoms
and are the prettiest flowers of the fall.
Also, they're flowers with
the original meaning of "harmony",
So any autumn grass would
go perfectly with them.
So? Do I look as nice
as the cosmos flowers?
Hey, hey, am I cute?
Uh... yeah.
Say. What's with the pause?
You look like you're having
so much fun.
Billboard Brow!
Getting a little full of yourself,
aren't you?
Don't let it go to your head!
Ami!
Sorry, your head looked so empty,
I mistook you for a vase
and stuck flowers in it.
Ino!
The shinobi flower, aconite.
It's mildly poisonous,
so you should spit it out.
Sensei!
Only the root is poisonous, though.
Ino is great.
She knows everything,
is stylish, and is cute.
And her skill with shuriken...
Even her ninjutsu is great.
Compared to her, I...
Sakura?
If you're a cosmos flower...
then am I a thoroughwort?
What are you saying?!
What?
Let me see...
You're not a flower yet,
you're still just a bud!
You're right.
Say, Ino...
Why... did you give this ribbon to me?
I thought it'd be a waste for
you to wilt away as a bud.
A flower is meaningless until it blooms.
Thank you...
Ino!
Ino...
I've always believed in what
you told me back then.
I really hoped it could be true.
That I could become
a beautiful flower...
I always looked up to you
because I wanted to be just like you.
Thanks to that, I'm here now.
So, Ino, I want to fight you seriously.
Wh-What's with Sakura?
Hmm.
Why are those two getting so worked up?!
Honestly, he doesn't realize why
he's always challenging Sasuke.
Well, rivals are mysterious things.
Huh?
Oh, hi...
My rival from youth, Kakashi...
Oh, how that nonchalant attitude of his
is so infuriatingly cool!
I understand... Sakura.
- This time for sure...
- with full strength...
- a fair... fight!
Just a Clone Jutsu?!
This isn't a ninja Academy's
graduation exam!
You think you can beat me...
with a basic ninja art?!
If you still think
I'm the same old crybaby Sakura,
you've got another thing coming!
However, her opponent is good too.
This evenly matched battle looks
like it's going to take a while!
Since when did she get this strong?!
I can make it, too!
You little!
Whoa!
This is long...
They've been going at it
for ten minutes, at the least.
You shouldn't be evenly
matched with me!
What makes you think
I'm evenly matched with you...
who only cares about her looks
and her precious long hair?!
You!
You take that back!
Idiot.
She's going for the bait.
Who knows what Ino will do!
I don't like Ino when she's that way!
You're simple-minded...
Uh oh.
She's totally lost it!
- This is!
- This is...
- the end!
Both parties are unable
to continue the match!
By double knockout,
no one advances from
the fourth preliminary match!
- What?!
- Huh?!
Now then...
Good grief.
Hey, Ino!
Sakura!
A-Are you okay?!
Seeing that made me all fired up, too!
Now...
The second one from the Sand...
- This should be an interesting match.
- Do your best, Tenten!
The fifth battle...
Tenten, Temari...
come forward!
It looks like you finally
woke up, huh... Sakura.
Huh?!
Tenten, power of youth!
Go, Go!
There is no limit to your youth!
Our match is already over.
To think I tied with somebody like you...
Huh?
Here!
Your own flower bloomed, didn't it?
A beautiful flower!
Ino...
However...
the next time we fight,
it won't end with you
getting knocked out!
Hm?!
And... I won't hand over
Sasuke to you!
Right back at you!
- Humph!
T-That's awful.
Tenten!
How boring... really.
Temari wins the fifth battle.
Oh no!
Nice catch.
What are you doing?!
Is that how you treat an opponent
who gave it their all?!
You're annoying!
Take that trash away already!
Stop! Lee!
Leaf Hurricane!
What?!
You're just like you look...
Stop! Lee!
Guy-sensei!
Temari.
Come up quick, you've been
declared the winner.
Don't waste your time with
that fool and his master.
What?!
You ninja of the Sand...
Allow me to give you a word of warning.
This kid is strong.
You should prepare yourselves.
Picking a fight with the Sand...
I definitely wouldn't want
to fight those guys.
T-They're all terrifying...
Don't lose to those guys!
Naruto!
S-Sakura.
Sakura... Are you okay?
Never mind that,
you should worry about yourself!
Huh? Me? I'm not injured or anything.
That's not what I mean.
If you lose here,
it'll be a disgrace.
You'd be ashamed to face Sasuke!
Y-Yeah.
Okay, hurry, hurry!
Me next!
Next! It's my turn!
Damn!
It's me.
That guy manipulates shadows.
Be careful of the shadows...
I won't lose to a stupid jutsu like that.
Shikamaru!
Wipe the floor with her!
And while you're at it...
Ugh, what a drag.
Plus, my opponent's a woman...
Makes it even more of a drag.
If that's what you think,
I'll end this quickly.
Go, go! Shikamaru!
Well, you could say that
I know these guys' raw power
from that incident from
the second test...
I don't know anything about
this one's jutsu.
On top of that, she's seen my jutsu...
- The sixth battle.
- That being said, for me...
Shikamaru versus Kin!
Begin!
Ninja Art: Shadow Possession Jutsu!
That jutsu!
It's useless as long as I watch
your shadow's movements!
Bells?
Heh, that's a classic.
Next, you'll throw senbons with bells
and senbons without bells
at the same time, right?
You're a chatty guy!
So in order to not get caught
by the shadow senbons...
I'm alert to the trick
and look closely...
What?!
Behind?!
String?
Too late!
Shikamaru!
He took that pretty bad.
It wasn't that bad, look closely.
M-My body...
Shadow Possession Jutsu, success.
Wh-What are you saying?
No way!
Your shadow isn't anywhere...
You don't realize it yet?
I-It can't be...
That's exactly it, you idiot!
A thread at this height
won't cast a shadow.
I can stretch and shrink
my own shadow.
But... How do you win with that?
I'm just going to move
the same way as you.
What a drag.
No way! You're...
We're going to throw shuriken
at each other.
How far will we go?
Fool, stop it!
You're only talk...
And that's checkmate.
If you're a shinobi,
you have to understand the situation
and the surroundings when you fight.
Even though we made
the same movements...
Winner! Shikamaru Nara.
Good job Shikamaru!
Cool!
And the next match.
The people left are that Sound guy,
me, Hinata, Naruto, Choji, Neji and Lee.
And that Sand guy...
Just please don't make me fight that guy.
This year's rookies are pretty impressive...
It's here, it's here, it's here!
What we've been waiting for!
It's finally my turn!
Yeah! Lucky us!
If it's this guy, it's an easy win, Akamaru!
Yahoo!
- If I'm not next, Sakura will be so disappointed.
- I'm going to do it!
- She'll just think I'm "Bushy Brow".
- I'm going to go for it!
- If I'm not next... Sakura...
- Just watch me! Yay!
This Lee kid, he's just like
Guy was in the past...
Do your best, Naruto.
Leave it to me.
Well Naruto, show us...
how much you've grown.
I'm going to do it!
The seventh battle,
Naruto Uzumaki versus Kiba Inuzuka.
I got sick of waiting!
It's finally time for me to shine!
That's my line!
With you as my opponent,
victory is in the bag!
Right, Akamaru?
Don't get excited!
You won't be able to beat me!
Why you little...!
Hey! Don't bring your puppy!
He'll get in the way of the match!
You fool!
Akamaru's going to fight with me.
Hey, hey! Is that okay?
Yes.
Animals and insects are treated
the same as ninja tools.
There's no problem.
Well, that's fine!
It's a perfect handicap!
Talking tough!
Then...
Akamaru, stay out of this one.
I'll fight him by myself!
Naruto! Don't lose to a guy like this!
Naruto, huh?
I'm sorry, but he can't beat Kiba...
Kakashi.
Naruto...
I-I want to support you, but...
Kiba's on my team...
Kiba's lucky.
Hah!
Well then. Please begin!
Ninja Art of Beast Mimicry: All Four Jutsu!
Here I come!
It'll be a while
until he opens his eyes, Proctor.
Just as I thought.
That Naruto is no match for Kiba.
Naruto...
That was too embarrassing to watch.
See...
What was that?
That guy is weak.
Don't...
underestimate me!
Yeah!
He seems to have grown,
to say things like that.
What are you talking about,
bleeding like that?
Your tough talk has gone too far!
I didn't use my full power...
I wanted to observe your strength first!
You too, cut out the tough talk
and use the dog or whatever you want!
You'll regret this...
Let's go Akamaru!
Smoke bomb?
Take this!
I can't see!
This is bad!
I have to get out of the smoke...
or I'll be done for.
Yeah! We did it!
Yay! Good job, Akama-
A-Akamaru...
Why?
Y-You!
Transformation Jutsu?!
Ouch! Damn!
Let go!
You smell like a dog!
Wh-Where's Akamaru?!
Over here!
Akamaru! Damn!
Applying Shadow Clone Jutsu to
a Transformation Jutsu, that's a clever trick.
Naruto shouldn't be able to do that...
His timing with his jutsu is very good.
What? He's better than I thought.
N-Naruto... you're amazing!
That's amazing, Naruto!
You got a little bit stronger.
But it's over.
Next, I'll attack you seriously.
Oh really?!
But you will absolutely not beat me!
Wh-What's this?!
What did you feed him?
His fur turned red!
That's why "Aka" is in his name
it means red.
Soldier pills huh...?
That Kiba...
He intends to end it with this.
Here we go, Akamaru!
Ninja Art of Beast Mimicry:
Man Beast Clone!
T-There's something wrong
with their eyes!
He's using some weird pills.
Isn't this doping?
Is this okay?!
Yes. Food pills are considered a
type of ninja tool.
Is that all you ever say?!
Let's go!
This isn't good...
There's no way to counterattack...
All I can do is gather all
the chakra in my legs
and do my best to escape...!
At this rate...
Take this!
Man Beast Taijutsu Technique:
Fang Over Fang
This is the difference in
our true powers.
I'm going...
to become the Hokage...
I can't lose here!
You? Hokage?!
When you're weaker than me?
I'll become Hokage... in your place!
Transform!
Hey, hey, are you serious?
You've been here three years
and you can't even do
a proper Transformation?!
All of you watch now!
I will definitely, someday,
become a true Hokage!
Lame! Him, Hokage?!
You know deep down inside that
you can't become the Hokage.
So quit acting tough!
You're wrong Kiba...
I'll just make it so
you won't stand up again!
Let's go, Akamaru!
You think you can get me with
that same technique again?!
Damn!
I have to counterattack somehow.
Even if I do, it has to get Kiba
or there's no point!
But which is which...?
T-That's it!
Transform!
I see how it is...
I see, so that's your move...
But...
But the Transformation Jutsu
is useless now!
Why, you ask?
Yeah!
I can smell you.
Don't mess with our
sense of smell, Naruto.
Damn! What in the world is going on...?!
So you're the real Naruto!
Messing with me!
What?!
He did it!
You little...!
Think hard about your jutsu
before you use them!
Because they'll be used
against you, stupid!
He's using my line, word for word...
Arguing with this guy is only
a waste of time!
Don't go at Naruto's pace...
Calm down.
Calm down!
He can't actually keep up with
my movements yet...
I still have the advantage!
Look closely at Naruto's movements
and if there's an opening...
I can definitely get him
from behind with the All Fours Jutsu.
So you've finally gotten serious, Kiba?
Well then... I'll end this...
with a new special move I've been saving!
What new special move?!
That's obviously a bluff!
You can test out whether
it's a bluff or not!
I won't let you!
You're slow!
Take this!
Oops!
Right now, Kiba's sense of smell
is tens of thousands of times
more powerful than normal...
Naruto!
Now's your chance!
Damn!
I was straining too much...
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Okay! The way you've torn me
apart up until now,
I'll give it back all at once!
U-!
Zu-! Ma-! Ki-!
Naruto Barrage!
The winner is Naruto Uzumaki.
Ohhhh!
Cha!
Nice one!
You did it!
That Naruto beat Kiba!
Never thought he had it in him...
Yup!
Yes!
That was easy!
Wh-What to do?
What should I do...?
N-Naruto...
Huh? Hinata?
Did you say something?
Ah, ah, ah...
Umm...
Huh?
Hinata...?
What's this?
It's an ointment.
Why for me?
Just take it, Naruto.
Hmmm. Okay!
Thank you! You're nice, Hinata!
Kiba, it's nothing to be
embarrassed about...
This kid was a really
strong opponent.
You seem quite carefree, Lady Hinata...
This medicine works really well!
Here, Sakura. Do you want to
use some too?
Only your wounds heal
with such speed... Naruto.
The power of Nine-Tails is
truly something else.
U-Umm...
T-This is...
ointment for your wound,
for you, Kiba, and for Akamaru.
Rather than worrying about others,
it's about time you worried
about yourself!
There are only 6 people left...
you, Choji, Neji, Lee, that Sound guy,
and that Sand guy.
Listen, Hinata...
If you get matched with that Sand guy,
withdraw immediately.
And there's one more...
Hinata...
This is going to be an interesting match...
I never thought that I would
have a fight with you...
Lady Hinata.
Brother Neji...
Brother?
They're descended from
one of the most noble clans
in the Hidden Leaf Village...
The Hyuga Clan.
But, they're not siblings.
Then, how are they related?
Yes!
Hinata is from the Head Family.
In other words, a person from
the main household.
And Neji, he's from a Branch Family
that is descended from the main one.
In other words,
it's a fight between relatives.
It must be uneasy for both of them...
I've heard that from long ago,
there've been various incidents between
the Head Family and Branch Family,
and now their relationship
isn't on very good terms.
Start the battle please!
Just one thing before we square off
against each other in the fight...
I should advise you, Lady Hinata.
Withdraw!
You're not suited to being a shinobi.
You're too nice.
And, you have no confidence
in yourself.
You're always feeling inferior...
You'd rather just stay a Genin,
wouldn't you?
However, you can't register for
the Chunin Exam without three members...
So you couldn't refuse when Kiba
and the others proposed it,
the truth is, you entered
the exam reluctantly.
Is that wrong?!
T-That's wrong...
That's not true...
I...
I only...
I wanted to change that about myself...
So I proposed it myself...
People can never change!
A failure will always be a failure...
That personality and strength
won't change.
I've seen everything with
this Byakugan.
That's why I understand!
You're just talking tough.
You're really thinking that you'd
like to run away from this place...
T-That's wrong...
I really...
Byakugan?
The Byakugan is one of the
Hyuga clan's Kekkei Genkai,
a visual jutsu similar to the Sharingan...
Byakugan!
Just now from my pressure,
your line of sight was pushed
to the upper left.
This is the sign that you're recalling
your past experience...
your bitter past.
And soon after that, your line of sight
moved to the bottom right...
This is the sign that you're imagining
physical and mental suffering.
That means...
you're picturing your old self,
and from all of your experiences
up until now,
you're imagining the result
of this battle...
The image of you losing!
Even the act of propping your arms
in front of your body...
It's a gesture that means
you want to build a wall
between us and keep distant.
Furthermore...
Laying a finger on your lips,
that's also a self-soothing gesture
that reveals your panic.
It represents a defense instinct
you want to alleviate the tension
and unease.
Changing yourself is something
you absolutely can't-
Sure, she can!
You don't get to decide that for her,
you idiot!
Give it to him, Hinata!
Don't just take it!
Argue back!
I'm getting irritated watching this!
What an annoying guy!
Naruto...
Thank you!
The expression of her eyes
has changed...
So you're not going to withdraw?
I'm not taking responsibility
for what happens!
I... don't...
I don't go back on my word...
That's my Ninja Way!
I don't want to run anymore!
Byakugan!
Fine...
The man who is most likely
the strongest Genin in the Leaf
is on my team.
That's...
That guy, Neji Hyuga.
Did it go in?!
No... it was shallow!
No. Even a graze works
That's the reason that the Hyuga clan
is called the Hidden Leaf's
distinguished family.
Huh? What do you mean?
The Hyuga has a unique taijutsu style
passed down for generations.
It's not like the kind of taijutsu that
Lee and I are good at...
Our fighting style, the Strong Fist (Gken),
is mainly to inflict external damage
on our enemy,
like broken bones and surface wounds.
In contrast, the Hyuga's taijutsu
inflict damage
on the chakra network through
which chakra flows through the body,
and damaging the insides. In other words,
it destroys internal organs.
They possess the Gentle Fist (Jken).
It's not spectacular to watch...
but later it slowly takes effect.
Sensei...
But, how can they do that?
After all, the chakra network
isn't visible to the eyes.
How do they attack the chakra
lines inside the body?
No.
The eyes of those two...
They can see it with
their Byakugan.
And a Gentle Fist attack is a little
different from a regular attack.
They release their own chakra
from a chakra points in their hands
and inject it into their opponent's body.
It directly inflicts damage on
your enemy's chakra network.
All right!
As I thought, this is the extent of...
the Head Family's power!
What the?!
But Hinata landed a perfect strike!
N-Not yet...
What's with this guy...!
Y-You mean... All this time...?
That's right. I can see all
your tenketsu.
Wh-What is he talking about?!
On the chakra network...
there are 361 pressure points,
also known as chakra points,
each about the size of a pinhead.
They are the tenketsu.
Theoretically, hitting one directly
can halt or increase chakra flow,
enabling one to gain complete control
over an opponent's flow of chakra.
Just so you know,
not even my Sharingan
can see the chakra points!
Having the penetrating eye
is one thing,
but to hit it so accurately like
that during a match,
well, that's just...
Lady Hinata...
What we have here is an unchangeable
difference in abilities.
It is a cruel, unchangeable fact.
You were destined to regret saying
that you don't want to run away,
from the moment you said it.
Withdraw!
I-I...
am... sticking by...
every word...
I said!
I'm not going to run away!
Because that's... my Ninja Way!
I had no idea... Hinata was this tough.
She's a lot like you.
Come to think of it...
She's always watching you.
Huh?
Hinata...
She has reached her limit.
One more blow and...
Go, Hinata!
Naruto...
Strength is back in her eyes...
I've been watching you...
I've been watching you closely
for many years now!
Why I wonder...?
I can feel courage welling up.
I feel that I can hang on,
that I can do it...
that I too am worth something!
Oh!
No!
Hinata!
Hinata...
At some point, Hinata, who was
in the habit of just giving up,
made up her mind to change.
I have never...
seen... that look in her eyes before.
Naruto.
Up until now,
I've always been the one watching,
but now...
finally, I am...
Your strikes were ineffective
from the very first.
It's the end.
Hinata... That's enough.
You lost the match,
but you've changed in the process.
You did well.
Neji's final blow went
straight for the heart.
I feel sorry for her,
but she won't be standing
again now.
Since further fighting is impossible
under these conditions...
Don't stop it!
Don't stop the match, y'know!
Naruto, stop!
What on earth are you saying, you idiot!
She's done for.
Can't you see she's unconscious...?
Huh?
Why do you stand up?
If you continue like this,
you'll really die!
He's finally...
truly seeing me for the first time.
I will not be caught looking bad...
In front of...
the person I admire most.
I-I'm not finished yet!
Stop the tough act...
I can tell you're just
barely standing.
You bear the burden of having been born
to the Head Family of the Hyuga clan.
You're wrong... Brother Neji.
Because I can tell...
that you are suffering
much more than I am.
What?!
You are the one who is torn up
over the fate of the Head
and Branch Families.
Neji, the match has been called!
Neji, get a hold of yourself!
You promised me
you wouldn't let this Head Family
business get to you!
Why are all the other Jonin
butting in?!
The Head Family always gets
special treatment, is that it?!
Hinata?!
Hinata!
Hinata! Are you okay?!
Hey!
Naruto...
Do you think...
Did I... change, even a little?
Hey you, failure!
I have two pieces of advice for you.
First, if you intend to
call yourself a shinobi,
stop that pathetic cheering.
And the second...
a failure will always be a failure.
There's no changing that!
Do you want to see about that?
You!
Naruto, I understand how you feel.
But all fighting must be
done officially in a match!
The failure beats the gifted genius
through sheer effort...
That would make for one exciting
final round, wouldn't it?
Though, I will probably be the one
to fight Neji...
All right already.
Oh, no! She's gone into
ventricular fibrillation.
Was he trying to kill her?!
The precious little time you have
would be better spent
seeing to her than glaring at me.
Medics!
Hurry! What's taking so long?!
S-Sorry.
Get her on the stretcher.
One, two, three.
This is serious! She only has about
10 minutes, at most!
Get her to the emergency room, now!
Out of the way!
Hinata...
I promise you.
I will win, no matter what!
Hey, Choji!
You're in trouble.
Only the strong ones are left.
I-I don't care!
I plan to forfeit right away
if that happens...
So that means...
Huh?
... then you plan on skipping
all-you-can-eat BBQ, too, huh?
What? Come on!
Don't worry.
If things start getting ugly,
I'll step in and stop the fight,
like I did for Hinata. Okay?
Prime beef tongue, short ribs...
- It'll be...
- Don't motivate him with food!
Besides, he didn't even...
- ... all-you-can-eat!
- step in to stop Hinata's fight.
B-B-Q! All right, BBQ! All-you-can-eat!
I'm curious about that guy, Neji, too...
I have an idea.
Kankuro?
Just a little information-gathering.
Hey!
Huh?
What are you doing here
all by yourself?
Shouldn't you be with your friends?
I-It's none of your business, is it?!
Hmmm. Well, well...
That guy... Neji Hyuga, right?
Well, it seems to me that
he didn't reveal the true extent
of his power in that last match.
What's his deal?
I'm going to crush him!
You seem like a fun guy.
I quite like you.
You're boring.
And I don't like you at all!
I'm going to waste this guy!
We will now resume the battle.
Okay!
You'll be up this time for sure.
Go for it, Lee!
No!
- Huh?
- What?
Seeing as I've come this far,
I'd rather be the last!
Hurry up and get down here...
Safe!
It worked!
If you say you want to go last, you won't.
It's an application of the same law:
If you aim to hit a telephone pole
with a rock, you'll miss...
But if you throw it to miss,
you'll hit it dead-on!
Right! That's my student!
I absolutely did not
want to go last!
I fooled them brilliantly!
Who exactly fell for it?
Okay, so let me give you
a nice little piece of advice.
Right!
Probably no one has noticed yet, but...
That gourd is suspicious!
I see!
Enough with the notes!
You're not going to have time to
read them during the match, you fool!
I see!
He didn't realize that?
Wow, is Lee going to be all right?
All right!
Go! Lee!
Yeah!
I am honored to face an opponent
like you so early on.
Please don't be in such a hurry.
Now then... The 9th match...
Begin!
Leaf Hurricane!
A sand-manipulation jutsu?
Sounds like trouble.
But let's give it a go!
Even that Lee's fast strikes...
have no effect at all!
What's the deal, y'know?!
No physical attack will have
any effect on him.
What?
The Sand shields and protects Gaara
independently of his will.
That's why... no one has been able
to do it so far...
to injure Gaara...
Curses! He's not moving
a muscle and still...!
Is that it?
Entertain me a bit more...
There's not enough...
Blood!
Why is Lee only using taijutsu?
He'll never be able to get close
enough for that!
Why doesn't he step back a bit and
use ninjutsu or something?
It's not that he doesn't use it.
He can't use it.
Huh?
Lee has almost no ninjutsu
or genjutsu skills.
N-No way!
When I first met Lee,
he was completely inept.
He had no talent whatsoever.
What? I can't believe that!
Lee, take them off!
B-But Guy-sensei!
You told me I should only take them off
to protect someone very precious!
It's fine!
I give you permission!
Weights?
That's such an old-school
training method...
All right, now I can
move easily!
Hmph! Does he think
taking off some little weights
will let him to outmaneuver Gaara's sand...?
A bit extreme, I'd say, Guy.
Go, Lee!
Right!
Go!
Very close!
Because he can't use
ninjutsu or genjutsu...
Therefore, he channeled all
of his time,
all of his energy and...
all of his being into taijutsu.
Though he can't do any other jutsu...
He won't lose to anyone...
He is a taijutsu specialist!
I can't believe it!
Gaara's been injured!
No way...!
Bushy Brow is even faster than before!
Was he this strong?!
Youth itself is... an explosion!
Right!
Over here!
Good!
I got him good!
I can't even track him
with my eyes!
Uh oh...
Uh oh is right!
That guy with the black circles under
his eyes is taking some serious hits!
That's not what I meant.
Huh?
Sure enough, he was
encased in sand, huh.
But, it's been a long time since
I've seen that expression
on Gaara's face.
So Gaara's other self has
been awakened, huh?
But what an incredible
defense he has...
no amount of speed is going
to let me get a strike through.
I'll have to inflict major damage
even through his sand armor.
The Lotus is the only way!
Yes.
Be ready!
A thin sand guard like that
won't be enough
in the face of Lee's high speed
Lotus slamming down from above.
Hurry up and bring it on!
You asked for it!
Not just yet!
What an amazing series of kicks!
Even an ordinary Lotus has
a tremendous strain on the body...!
Lee, let this be the finishing blow!
Take this!
Primary Lotus!
I got him...
good!
Right on!
I-It's over!
Wh-What? This can't be!
He did it! Lee's won!
Hey, he isn't dead, is he?
Wha?!
What?!
When did that...?!
That's impossible!
While you were closing your eyes
in anticipation.
What?
That bowl-cut guy is totally exhausted...
Gaara is toying with him.
Lee...
Idiot! There's no way
you'll become a ninja.
Yes, I can.
There's no way a loser who can't
even use ninjutsu can become a ninja!
Yes, I can!
Whatever, but the fact that a guy like
you without ninjutsu or genjutsu
and with taijutsu worse than
an average person,
you have no place in this ninja academy,
it's nonsense!
Do you know what you're called here?
Hot-Blooded!
Hot-Blooded loser-
Hey, get in line, Lee!
Hey Lee!
So that's the hot-blooded loser
everyone's talking about.
Doesn't he look like
someone we know?
Huh?
In particular... his eyebrows.
Hmm...
Rock Lee...
The loser who can only perform
under average taijutsu...
But you...
You practiced your less
than average taijutsu...
You practiced it over and
over again like crazy...
All right, you've all become
Genin as of today,
so I'd like to know what
it is you're all aiming for!
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
Tenten.
I want to become a powerful ninja
like the legendary Kunoichi Tsunade!
Hmm...
I...!
I want to prove that I can become
a splendid ninja
even though I can't use
ninjutsu or genjutsu!
That is my ultimate goal!
I know you won't give in, Lee...
You... continued to make effort.
If I can't jump rope 1,200 times,
I'll do 2,000 log kicks!
1,116... 1,117!
1,118... 1,119-
Huh?!
Lee!
Are you taking a break already?
Guy-sensei...
What is it that you want?
If this is about my mistake on
the recent assignment,
I believe I already apologized.
Lee...
It's true you're different from Neji.
You have no ninjutsu or genjutsu skills,
and you're not a taijutsu genius either...
But Lee...
you have powers that exceed Neji...
you're a genius with hidden potential.
If you're trying to make me feel better,
please stop!
Idiot!
I'm not trying to make you feel better
or anything!
The reason is that you are...
a genius of effort!
I wonder if...
If that's true...?
I've... I've believed that to be true...
That if I trained harder than Neji...
2 or 3 times as much...
that I'd surely become stronger.
But...
I've recently begun to think that...
I can't beat a real genius.
Is effort really rewarded...?
I've wanted to know this and
so I've challenged Neji again and again,
but it's always been the same result...!
I'm no match for him at all!
Even when I'm on a mission...
My legs still tremble even now...
I think that no matter how hard I try,
I'll never become stronger...
I'm so afraid, I can barely stand it!
What am I to do...?
There's no point in making the effort
if you don't believe in yourself!
Lee, you're very similar to me.
Do you mean our eyebrows?
No, not just our eyebrows...
I was actually a failure once too...
You were, Sensei?
But now, I can even win against
the genius elite Kakashi,
because of my efforts...
"I'd like to prove that I can become
a respectable ninja
even if I can't use ninjutsu
or genjutsu," you said.
That's your nindoyour ninja way, right?
That's a fine goal...
It's a fine goal worth sticking to!
That's why you must believe in
your path and forge straight ahead!
Become a man so powerful that I can
proudly watch you succeed with a smile!
Understand, Lee?!
Yes!
Thank you... Guy-sensei...!
Sensei is smiling and watching me...
And just because of that,
I can come back stronger!
Stronger... stronger still!
Lee's smiling... even though
he's been driven into a corner.
No.
It's his turn to do the driving.
Huh?
The Lotus of the Leaf blooms twice.
No, Guy!
You haven't?!
It's exactly as you imagine.
So that Genin...
that boy can open some of the
Eight Inner Gates to use the Hidden Lotus...
That's right...
This is incredible...
What exactly is it?
These Eight Inner Gates and
that Hidden Lotus?
Alright...
In the chakra network where chakra flows,
there are eight specific points, or gates,
that regulate the flow of chakra,
starting from the head and located
sequentially in various parts of the body...
The Gate of Opening, the Gate of Healing,
the Gate of Life, the Gate of Pain,
the Gate of Limit, the Gate of View,
the Gate of Wonder, and the Gate of Death.
These are called the Eight Inner Gates.
These eight gates continually "limit"
the amount of chakra flowing
through the body...
However, the essence of the Lotus is
to force these gates open.
and bring out tens of times
the body's normal strength.
The Primary Lotus...
opens the first gate,
the Gate of Opening,
No way!
Even after using just the Primary Lotus,
his body was in shambles.
So if he uses a technique beyond that...
That's right.
Huh?
By opening all the 8 gates,
one can attain power surpassing
even the Hokage, but in exchange...
one dies.
I don't intend to question what that
boy means to you,
or to tell you not to bring
your personal feelings into play...
But there is a limit!
I've misjudged you, Guy!
What do you know... about that boy?!
That boy has something important
he's willing to protect
even if it costs him his life.
There is no way that I alone can
lose in a place like this!
Guy-sensei... please allow it.
It is now...
He's opened the third gate,
the Gate of Life...
He's going to make his move!
No, not yet!
What?!
And also,
the fourth gate, the Gate of Pain...
Open!
He's fast!
Gaara!
Where are they?!
He's above!
What...?!
The Sand Armor is...
You're a stubborn one.
Since it comes to this...
The muscles have torn...
Is that really Lee...?
When did he become like this...?
This is the end!
The fifth gate, the Gate of Limit...
Open!
I can't defend myself...
Is this the movement of
a human being?!
Neji...
This technique was my ace in
the hole to take you down...
but now, I'll have to use it here!
Huh?!
The Sand Shield can't keep up!
Most of the armor has also
been peeled off...
He's done for!
Hidden Lotus!
I can't see anything, it's too fast...
He's done it this time!
Gaara!
Lee...
Oh!
What's... that?
He protects himself...
using a gourd made of sand?!
No way!
He got hit by the Hidden Lotus
and he's still able to use
a jutsu...!
Sand Burial!
Die!
Why...?
Why... save him?
He's...
He's my precious student!
Those words are definitely
not understandable to Gaara...
I quit...
- Wha...?
- Huh?
Wha?!
That's impossible...
Having opened the fifth gate...
And his arm and leg are crushed...
There's no way he should
be able to stand...!
Lee...
It's all right.
It's over!
You're in no condition to stand...!
Lee...
Y-You...
You are...
So he had already...
Lost consciousness...
You are a splendid ninja...!
The winner...
Gaara.
Naruto...
Bushy Brow lost
to a guy like this...!
Medics, please hurry.
You are the Jonin in charge of him,
aren't you?
Y-Yes.
Please come with me
for a minute.
Careful...
Don't shake him.
There is faint breathing...
but due to the comminuted fractures
and muscle tears throughout his body,
recovery will likely take
a considerable amount of time...
If that was all,
it wouldn't be so bad, but...
The damage to the left arm and leg
which received the attack is severe...
It's too severe...
I don't want to say this,
but he will likely never...
be able to fight as a shinobi again.
Lee...
I didn't want to think... that you'd lose.
Please forgive me for not...
stopping it...!
Lee...
It's not true... it's not true.
After hearing that, what's
Bushy Brow supposed to do now...?!
This guy...
He said the failure would take
down a genius with effort!
Calm down, Naruto.
B-But... Kakashi-sensei!
He kept saying he wanted
to fight Sasuke and Neji!
Perhaps... that very desire led to his downfall.
That boy...
Sasuke and Neji...
and you...
he was driven by an unspoken promise.
He risked his life...
so that he might have
a chance to battle you guys...
Don't forget that...
Heaven does not permit it.
One who tries to move ahead
while achieving victory
through methods that invite mutual destruction.
So, it ended without incident...
Welcome back Gaara.
Guy...
Well...
I may have spoken harshly earlier, but...
I've thought about it and
had I been in your position...
I probably... wouldn't have
been able to stop him either.
Guy.
We're in the way of the
next match... let's head up.
All right...
Then, for the tenth and final round,
will both contestants please come forward!
So it's finally my turn...
I'm going to win and have
some barbecued beef!
Either way, I need to make it
to the main tournament and fight Sasuke.
Or I will not have met your expectations,
Lord Orochimaru...
I can almost see through it...
The reason that you went to the trouble
of getting to Sasuke before us and...
putting a Curse Mark on him
without killing him...
In other words,
we were just guinea pigs to measure
Sasuke's abilities during these tests.
What you wanted isn't Sasuke's life,
but Sasuke himself...
I was also taken for a fool...
Now, let the tenth round begin.
Do your best!
Fatso!
Damn it!
Those two better watch out!
I'll end this match quickly and
turn you into mincemeat!
Then let's not play around...
I'll finish you off quickly, Mr. Fatso.
You bandaged mummy!
Ninja Art:
Ninja Art: Expansion Jutsu!
Followed by the
Hidden Leaf-style taijutsu!
All I have to do is to prevent him
from aiming at my ears!
Human Boulder!
Yeah! Take that, Human Boulder style!
The way you are...
you can barely move, can you?
That's where I attack!
It's no use, I'm wearing ear plugs.
No, this is the end!
Oh?!
The human body is made up of 70% water,
and water is able to transmit sound waves.
In other words, your whole body is like
one big ear.
And the winner is, Dosu Kinuta!
Lord Orochimaru... no, Orochimaru!
I'll show you...
I'm more than just a guinea pig.
Are you all right?
I-I want some BBQ meat...
Oh man...
And the guy went easy on him, too.
Even though he lost, the least we can do
is take him for that BBQ.
It's finally over.
At long last, the Final Round...
With that, the preliminaries for
the third test are complete.