What did you say?!
You're telling me only rookies
went after Sasuke?!
It really couldn't be helped...
Given the village's situation...
Hey, hey!
Your mission has already
been assigned!
Well, I'm just running an errand.
I'll be right back.
Don't worry.
Honestly...
Summoning Jutsu!
First, fan out in every direction...
and track Naruto and Sasuke's scent.
Did you say Naruto and Sasuke?
Did something happen
to the two of them?
I'll explain later...
We're short on time.
Okay.
As soon as you confirm that
you've detected the scent,
signal me, and I'll come right away.
All right! Scatter!
Well, she saw them fight
with her own eyes...
telling her not to worry is useless.
Please, let me make it in time!
Sasuke!
Are you going to
run away from me?!
Yo... loser.
It's you this time, huh?
I couldn't do it.
I couldn't stop Sasuke...
I think...
the one who can stop Sasuke...
the one who can save Sasuke is...
Naruto... you are the only one.
Naruto... This is a...
once-in-a-lifetime request...
Please... bring Sasuke back.
What's with that face?
So, you asked Sakura for a hint
the other day, what did she tell you?
Shall we go?
Yup.
Why...?
Who knows?
My body moved on its own.
You rescue Sakura, no matter what!
Sasuke... You...
I could still distract him
for a little while.
I lost everything once.
I refuse to watch my precious comrades
die in front of me again.
Why...?
Why, Sasuke?
Why did you become like this?!
You!
What does it matter to you
what happens to me?
I have my own way.
No matter who it is,
nobody has the right
to tell me what to do.
Let me be clear.
I'm done playing ninja with you guys
from the Leaf.
Go home.
Everyone...
Everyone risked their lives
to come after you!
So what?
Lastly, I will tell you
the most important thing.
Sasuke isn't a close friend,
and I don't even particularly like him.
But Sasuke is a shinobi of
the Hidden Leaf Village...
A comrade.
That's why we will rescue him
by risking our lives.
That's the way of the Leaf.
What do our comrades from the Leaf
mean to you?!
Snap out of it!
Did I get any stronger by staying
with all of you?
I'm going to Orochimaru.
Orochimaru is the person who killed
the Third Hokage
and tried to crush the Leaf Village!
Do you think he'll give you
that power for free?
He just wants your body
as a vessel!
You might not be able to come back.
You might get killed.
You think I'd just let you
go to a place like that?!
That doesn't matter to me...
If my goal is accomplished,
then that's all that matters.
If you intend to get in my way...
Then it can't be helped...
I won't let you go! I'll drag you back,
even if I have to break every bone in your body!
Why are you laughing?!
You were laughing at that time too.
That time...?
You wanted to fight me then, right?
That was...
That was not the kind of fight I wanted.
Even now... this is not...
I don't care about your circumstances.
What... is this power?
If it's like this now...
If I release this curse mark...
I wonder how much power...
I awakened long ago...
From the fool I was,
dreaming of a peaceful future...
Wasting time with my comrades.
That's why I left the village.
That's why I sought power!
My dream is not in the future.
My dream is in the past...
That's the only place it exists.
Wow, Big Brother!
You hit the target right in the middle,
even the one behind the rock!
All right, me too!
Sasuke, let's go home.
Come on... You promised
you'd teach me a new shuriken jutsu.
I have an important mission tomorrow
and I need to prepare.
Liar...
Forgive me, Sasuke...
Maybe next time.
Big Brother, watch me!
Hey! If you push yourself...
Why is the one who twisted
his ankle laughing?
Were you being careless?
That's not it...
Because....
I'm finally starting
at the Academy tomorrow!
Oh...
What's up?
This is the place...
where Father works, right?
Yeah... The headquarters
of the Leaf Police Force.
I was curious about it before,
but why is the Uchiha Clan crest
the mark of the Police Force?
Oh... so you noticed, huh?
Of course...
Yeah... Let me see...
To put it simply...
It seems the previous generations
of the Uchiha Clan
set up and established the Police Force.
So they used their clan crest as
the organization's symbol.
From olden times,
the Uchiha Clan has always been
in charge of protecting
the public and the peace of this village.
The Uchiha crest is the symbol
of our proud clan.
The Uchiha Clan has grown smaller now.
But even now, nearly all members
belong to the Police Force here.
And contribute to maintaining
peace in the village.
Only exceptional shinobi
can handle crimes
committed by shinobi, so...
Father is so awesome!
Are you going to enter
the Police Force, too?
Well... I'm not sure...
Why not?!
When I grow up, I'm also going
to enter the Police Force!
Father's also coming to
tomorrow's entrance ceremony.
It's the first step to my dream.
That's right.
You're late... What were you doing?
Father...
I have something to talk to you about.
Come quickly.
About tomorrow's special mission...
I've decided to go with you, too.
Tomorrow?
If you complete this mission, Itachi...
your place in the ANBU Black Ops
will be guaranteed!
You understand, right?
You don't have to be so worried.
More importantly...
Umm... Father...
Tomorrow's my...
Tomorrow's mission will be
a very important mission not just for you,
but for the Uchiha Clan!
I'm withdrawing from tomorrow's mission.
What are you talking about?!
You should know how important
a day tomorrow is!
I'm going to Sasuke's Academy
entrance ceremony tomorrow...
Relatives are supposed to attend
the Academy entrance ceremony.
There was a notice,
wasn't there... Father?
I get it already.
I'll go to the Academy...
Your left leg...
Be sure to ice it.
Right...
Everyone! Congratulations
on your entrance!
From this day forward, I expect you to
work hard on the path of the shinobi.
I'd like you to bring further prosperity
to the Hidden Leaf Village.
Oh! I remember
the time when Itachi entered.
As expected of his brother.
Thank you for your help with both boys.
Oh, it's nothing like that.
A prodigy, the likes of which
the Academy has never seen...
There were no students
as exceptional as that boy.
That's a bit too much praise.
Not at all...
I'm hopeful for you, too.
Become a fine shinobi
just like your brother.
Yes.
Hey... That's Uchiha, right?
Yeah.
I wonder... if he's awesome, too.
Hmm... Must be.
Recess at last! What a drag.
I'm still not used to this place...
You want some too, Shikamaru?
I mean, you spend
every recess eating.
That's my boy...
I'm confident you'll do great
in the ANBU.
This won't do!
Won't do!
Really...
You should rest your body
on your days off at least.
You don't have to push it.
I heard... that big brother graduated
from the Academy in just one year.
Times were different back then.
Besides, he's a bit special...
Now, I'm going to hand out
the report cards for the first half.
Do as well as your brother did.
Father... I wanted you to say,
"That's my boy," to me, too...
What did you say?
What do you mean you can't attend
the clan meeting tomorrow?!
You don't understand your own position!
I'm setting out on a mission tomorrow.
What are they doing this late
at night with the lights off?
What mission?!
I can't say...
It's a top secret mission.
Itachi... You are the link that
connects our clan
with the village higher-ups.
You know that, don't you?
Yeah...
Keep that well in mind!
And come to tomorrow's assembly!
Sasuke...
Get to bed after
you've gone to the bathroom.
Right...
What are you doing hanging around
this late at night?
Get to bed!
Okay.
Father only ever thinks about you,
Big Brother.
Do you hate me?
It's okay.
It's natural for a shinobi to be hated.
That's not how I feel...
Brother's right.
I really do... think ill of him...
Excellence is not easy at all.
Power isolates you, and it makes
you arrogant.
Even if you're coveted
and sought after at first.
But, we're the only brothers
we have.
I will always be the wall
you must overcome.
Even if it means you end up hating me...
That's what big brothers are for.
Is Itachi home?!
I need to talk. Come out!
Why's everyone gathered here?
Two people were absent
from yesterday's assembly.
Why didn't you come?!
He didn't go to the assembly father
was talking about last night, after all.
I understand that when you enter ANBU,
you get caught up in all sorts
of trouble.
Your father said something
like that in your defense.
But as far as we're concerned,
you get no special treatment.
Understood. I shall be careful next time.
Now I'm going to have
to ask you to leave.
Right... But before that,
there's a little more I want to ask you...
It's about Shisui Uchiha, who committed suicide
by throwing himself into the Nakano River...
Suicide?!
The other person who didn't come
to the assembly was Shisui.
As I recall, you adored him
like a real older brother.
I see... I hadn't seen him at all recently.
That's too bad.
And we, the Police Force, have decided
to launch an all-out investigation.
Investigation?!
This is the will Shisui wrote.
The analysis of the handwriting
has been completed.
No mistake, he did indeed write it.
If there's no sign of murder,
what is there to investigate?
It would be easy for a Sharingan user
to forge the handwriting.
The most adept Uchiha.
The man feared as
Shisui of the Body Flicker.
He was a man who would take
the lead, no matter the mission,
if it was for the sake of the clan.
It's tough to think that
such a man would leave something
like this and kill himself.
You shouldn't judge people based on
appearances and assumptions alone.
For the time being,
I leave the will with you.
Take this and request cooperation
from ANBU Black Ops in the investigation.
Understood...
I hope we get a lead.
Also, we have our own connection
to ANBU Black Ops.
We'll know right away if you try
to bury the investigation request.
Why don't you just come right out
and say it?
You suspect me, don't you?
That's right, you brat...
Listen up, Itachi.
Just try to do something
like betraying the clan and...
it'll cost you!
I told you before.
You shouldn't judge people
only on looks and speculation.
You judged me as patient
and took me lightly.
Clan... Clan...
You foolishly overestimate
your own abilities...
and you underestimate my own.
That's why you are cowering before me.
I've never seen him like this...
Half a year after entering ANBU...
the strangeness of your behavior
couldn't be overlooked.
What the hell are you thinking?
Fixated on the organization,
fixated on the clan,
fixated on the name.
This obsession is what constrains
you and limits your own potential.
And it's a foolish thing...
to fear and hate
what one has never seen or known...
Stop, Itachi!
What the hell's the matter
with you?!
Itachi...
You've been a little strange lately.
My potential is being stifled
by this foolish clan!
Because you're fixated
on insignificant things like clans...
you lose sight of what's truly important.
True change cannot be made if stuck
within the restrictions of regulations,
and constrained predictions
and imagination...
Such arrogance!
Enough! Any more of this foolishness,
and you'll be imprisoned.
Why... Big Brother?
What was that?!
I've had enough! Captain,
order his imprisonment!
Big Brother! Stop it already!
I'm not the one who killed Shisui.
But I apologize for
my numerous slips of the tongue.
I'm very sorry...
Recently, it seems he's been up
to his ears in ANBU Black Ops missions
and is a little tired...
Captain!
The ANBU Black Ops is under
the direct control of Lord Hokage...
Even the Police Force can't arrest him
without a warrant.
I will take the responsibility
and monitor him.
Please...
Understood...
What was that...
in my brother's eyes?
That wasn't...
just an ordinary Sharingan.
And... quite a bit of time's
passed since then...
but things are still awkward
between him and Father.
Good morning, father...
Yeah, good morning.
How have things been
going at the Academy lately?
My classes at the Academy are boring.
I'm always at the top of the class, so...
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
W-Wow...
This is the fundamental
jutsu of the Uchiha.
The sign is as I taught you earlier.
You build up chakra,
and pool it in your chest,
and spew it out at once after that.
Try it.
Okay!
Father... is teaching me jutsu himself.
Finally... father has also recognized me!
I must live up to his expectations!
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
I suppose it's not like with Itachi.
It might've still been
too soon for you.
A member of the Uchiha Clan
is not recognized as full-fledged
until they've mastered
this Fire Style.
The Uchiha crest...
symbolizes the Uchiha
who controls fire.
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
Today for sure!
Sasuke...!
Wait a minute.
What is it?
What...?
Oh... Don't move.
Okay, finished!
Mother...
Hmm?
No... It's nothing.
Okay...
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
I'm just... getting started.
Damn it! One more time!
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
Father!
Hmm?
One more time...
Please watch me.
It's still too soon for you.
Even if I were to teach you
for another week...
It's not that...
I've gotten... the hang of the jutsu.
So I want you to see it.
Failure is not an option!
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
That's my boy.
You've done well.
From now on, train hard
and aim even higher,
and don't bring shame to the crest
on your back.
Right!
And... let me say one thing.
Don't follow in your
big brother's footsteps.
Mother...?
Hmm?
What does Father really think
about me and Big Brother?
What is it all of a sudden?
the other day, Father said to me,
"That's my boy."
He'd always said that only
to Big Brother.
So I was really happy.
I see... Good for you.
But lately, Father and Big Brother
haven't been getting along, so...
I was thinking...
that maybe I'm just a substitute
for Big Brother.
Your older brother's your older brother.
And you are you.
Your father cares deeply
about you both.
Then why does he only think
about Big Brother?!
That's not it...
Your father has to protect
the Uchiha Clan
as a representative of the clan.
What about it?!
Itachi is just bigger than you
and is your elder.
He'll naturally be entrusted
with that much more work
for the clan, right?
Your father is the supervisor
of the work, so...
it's natural that his attention
is on your older brother.
But, this is just between us.
When he's with me,
your father does nothing
but talk about you.
He's just always sullen
and awkward, so...
Big Brother!
Today...
after school, can you help me
with my shuriken training?
I'm busy... Have father teach you.
But you're better at shuriken jutsu,
Big Brother...
Even I can see that.
Why do you always treat me
like such a nuisance?
Forgive me Sasuke...
Maybe next time, okay?
I don't have time to
pay attention to you today.
You always poke my forehead
and say, "Forgive me, Sasuke."
You always say, "Maybe next time,"
but "next time" never comes.
Father.
Huh?
Why doesn't Big Brother
pay any attention to me?
That guy's a little strange...
He's the type who doesn't like
to get close to people.
Why?
I don't know.
Even as his father,
I still can't read that boy...
Here!
Your boxed lunch, Sasuke!
If you're worried about doing
shuriken jutsu practice,
I will watch you when you get home.
It's not practice,
it's training.
See you later!
Sasuke, are you on
your way to school?
Yes.
I saw Itachi earlier on.
He's really become a man.
He's already a top-notch shinobi.
He graduated at the head of his class
at the Academy at the age of seven,
and became a Chunin at the age of ten,
right?
He became adept at using
Sharingan at the age of eight.
Yes, I remember.
That boy is truly
the pride of the Uchiha clan.
By the way,
how old are you now, Sasuke?
I'm the same age as
when Big Brother graduated,
but I can't...
What's the matter?
Hey!
Stop talking nonsense!
Oh my, dear.
Sasuke, both you and Itachi
come from the Uchiha clan,
the most elite clan in
the Hidden Leaf Village.
Have confidence!
You'll be an amazing
shinobi just like Itachi one day.
Yeah!
See you later!
Do your best!
Study hard!
I won't lose to Big Brother!
I'm pretty late...
What was that?
I had the feeling
there was someone there...
Wh-What's this?!
What in the world is this?!
Uncle... Auntie...
Father... Mother...
There's somebody here!
Move!
Father! Mother!
Big brother!
Father and Mother are...!
Why? For what reason?!
Who in the world would do
something like this...?
What are you doing, Big Brother?!
My foolish little brother...
Mangekyo Sharingan!
My legs...!
Stop!
Big Brother!
Don't make me see this!
Why...?
Why did you, Big Brother...?!
No!
No...
Auntie! Uncle!
Father! Mother!
Stop it! Big Brother!
Don't kill Father and Mother!
Why...
Big brother... Why did you?
To test the limits of my own ability.
To measure your vessel?
Is that all?
Only for that reason...
you killed everyone...?
You have to be kidding!
I'm scared...
I'm scared!
Don't kill me...!
I don't believe it!
This is too unlike you, big brother.
I mean...
The reason I acted as the big brother
you desired was...
because I wanted to test
your own potential.
You have the potential
to become my opponent
in order to assess
my vessel.
You hated me...
and you continued to have
the desire to surpass me.
That is why I'm letting you live...
for my own benefit.
You are someone who could be able to use
Mangekyo Sharingan just like me.
However, on one condition...
You must kill
your closest friend...
Y-You've have to be kidding...
Just like I did...
Big brother... you killed Shisui?!
That's right... and because of
that I obtained these eyes.
The main hall of Nakano Shrine...
Underneath the seventh tatami mat
on the far right
is the secret gathering place
of the Clan.
There you will find the
recorded secret of...
the very purpose of the
Uchiha Clan's visual jutsu.
The real purpose of the Uchiha Clan's visual jutsu...?
If you attain these eyes,
you will become the third person
including myself
to use
the Mangekyo Sharingan.
If that happens...
then there will have been meaning
in my allowing you to live.
However... at present...
You are not worth killing.
My foolish little brother...
If you want to kill me,
then begrudge me!
Hate me!
And live on in shame.
Run... run...
and cling to your pathetic life.
And one day, when you have
the same eyes as I do...
you will come before me.
Wait!
A dream...?
Yes... that's right.
The only one who survived...
is that boy.
Didn't he have an older brother?
Yes, but he's gone missing...
It can't be true...
That elite Uchiha Clan...
Oh, Sasuke! What are you buying today?
The main hall of Nakano Shrine...
Under the seventh tatami mat
from the right...
is our clan's secret gathering place...
I see... So that's what it is...
Hey, Shikamaru...
Want to go to the candy shop
after school?
Huh... No way.
You can get away with that
'cause your mom's nice,
but if my mother found out that I bought
myself a snack before going home,
I'd be in big trouble.
Did you hear the news...
that entire Uchiha Clan
was apparently murdered?
Yeah, my dad told me.
Apparently he's the only one
who survived...
That's my boy.
When we're alone, all
your father talks about is you...
I wonder... what kind of things
father was saying to mother...
If you want to kill me...
Begrudge me! Hate me!
If it's for the purpose of killing you,
I will plunge into any darkness
that lies ahead!
I will obtain that power no matter what!
From now on, I am an avenger!
Sasuke is now in depths of darkness...
If you stop in a place like this...
you won't be able to catch up
with Sasuke.
Neji, it's just like you said.
Sasuke's in the depths
of darkness right now...
He really hit me with
his full strength! Damn it!
Don't you consider me...
your comrade any longer?!
Don't all the things we did together
on Team 7 mean anything to you?!
It wasn't meaningless...
To me, you became my... closest friend.
We've become... friends?
Then... why?!
All the more reason why...
I have to defeat you.
I don't fully understand but...
I get that you want to fight me for real!
Sasuke...!
Like I said...
In truth, you were waiting
for this too, weren't you?
Kakashi and Sakura aren't here.
So there's nobody here
to stop us like before.
You...!
Chidori!
You idiot...
I'll do the same!
I'm going to knock you out...
and drag you back to the village
if I have to!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Rasengan!
Damn...
He was able to counter
my full-power Chidori to that extent...
Naruto...!
Well, your limit is two blows...
that's about it.
And if I try to use more than that...
what will happen?
The third blow won't initiate.
Remember that well.
If you try to initiate
the jutsu forcibly...
not only will it not
initiate properly,
but your chakra will become zero...
Worst-case scenario,
it'll cost you your life!
Damn... I can't waste a blow...
It wouldn't serve any purpose
if we cancel each other like earlier.
There's... no longer
any mistake about this.
You... really intended...
You really intended to...
I will use high-speed techniques
and jutsu to create an opening.
And then... I'll land a Chidori.
Sasuke...
Did you know, Naruto...
Top-class ninja should be
able to read each other's hearts
simply by an exchange of fists.
How about it?
Were you really able
to read inside...
my own heart?
Fire Style: Phoenix Flower Jutsu!
Sasuke... I knew that you were always alone.
At first, I was relieved when I found out
that there was someone else just like me.
And it also made me happy...
Truth is, I wanted to talk to you right away.
But... I couldn't do it.
- Awesome...
- You're incredible...
You were always able
to do everything.
And moreover, you were always
being praised by everyone.
Because you and I
were so different...
Because I was jealous,
I decided you were my rival.
I didn't want to lose to you...
and I felt that even more strongly...
because I was called a loser.
Even when we were on Team 7,
I continued to feel
the same way the whole time.
I'm stubborn...
And wasn't able to express
what I really felt...
What I really wanted was
to become like you.
You were my goal...
You are one of the ones
I want to fight.
I was really happy when
you said that!
Those were your first words...
acknowledging me...
You and I both knew,
without us even having to
have an exchange of fists!
From that time on...
Even without saying anything...
To me, you're...
my closest friend.
However... you're trying to
take me down for real.
Right now, I don't really know
whether you really meant
what you said earlier or not.
Thinking that we were friends...
That might have been...
That might have been just me...
It's too late now!
Naruto!
If that's the case... I'm...
I'm so pathetic, aren't I...
I don't know why but...
I don't know why...
But I...
I...
don't want you...
to be taken away
by someone like Orochimaru!
You managed to divert it
with your left hand,
but it's meaningless.
You can't make hand signs...
or use that jutsu of yours anymore.
This is the end!
That's Naruto?
What is this intimidating power?
And what was that
red chakra earlier on?
Is this guy a monster?
What the hell are you?!
Your friend!
That's why I'm telling you
I'm not going to let someone like
Orochimaru get their hands on you!
I'm telling you, I'll stop you...
even if I have to break every bone in your body!
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
Come on! Snap out of it!
If you don't come to your senses,
I'll have to break your bones
so that you can't move
and I'll take you home that way, Sasuke!
Shut up...
What the hell do you,
who has neither parents nor brothers,
think you understand?
What makes you think that you,
who's been all alone from the start,
could possibly understand
how I feel?!
It's because I had those bonds
that I suffer like this!
How could you possibly understand...
what it feels like to lose all that!
It's true that I can't understand...
how it feels to really
have parents or brothers...
However...
It's my treat today...
Eat your fill!
Yippee!
When I'm with Iruka-sensei,
I imagine...
- Dig in!
Ninja, first, need to
warm their inner man.
Hey! Hey! Don't get too carried away
and overeat!
Maybe this is...
what it feels like to have a dad.
When I'm with you...
Idiot, idiot, idiot...
What was that, you loser?!
I'm not going to lose to you,
no matter what!
Go ahead and say
whatever you want.
How about this?
Better not start feeling
too comfortable.
Maybe...
this is what it's like to have a brother.
Why is it, Naruto...?
Why do you go so far for me?
Because for me, this is the first
real bond I've ever had!
That's why I'm going to stop you.
It's too late, Naruto...
It's already too late.
I can't go back anymore.
Come, Naruto!
Then, I will sever that bond.
Sever that bond...?
Then why are you wearing that headband?
I'll acknowledge you... You're strong.
And the reason for that is
you know the same pain
of loneliness that I do.
And that pain makes people stronger.
That's why, by severing that bond,
I will be able to obtain
even greater strength.
I will fight you now on equal terms.
However...
You won't even be able to put
a scratch on my forehead.
That's something that
won't change in the least.
It seems that whatever I say
won't have any effect anymore, huh?
Sasuke!
I'm done with talking...
From here on, it's only fighting.
Come!
I'm able to see...
I'm now able to see
this guy's movements...
which I wasn't able to see before.
I'm able to see them!
Damn it!
When he moves...
from the subtle shifts in
how he exerts his strength...
I can vividly see
an image of his next move.
With my level of eyes,
I don't need to use unnecessary chakra
and can instead preserve it.
The Curse Mark takes
too much chakra.
If I can see this much...
I can time my attacks to the images of
Naruto's movements as I foresee them.
This is no good...
He's totally reading my movements.
Damn it!
Sasuke!
Fire Style: Dragon Flame Jutsu!
Sa-su-ke...
It's too late, Naruto.
It's too late now! Naruto!
You're weak, aren't you, boy?
You better be grateful to me...
and to the Fourth Hokage
who sealed me inside
a brat like you!
What's going on?
What was that just now?
Even if I'm able to read
Naruto's movements completely...
his chakra makes
a separate move of its own.
It's as if the chakra itself
has a will of its own...
Even with my eyes
I'm unable to read it completely.
That red chakra...
that's not an ordinary chakra!
Your target is Naruto, after all.
Capturing Naruto is the primary mission
assigned to us by the Akatsuki.
I see...
It appears that you have
some kind of special power.
Now I understand!
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
That chakra is protecting him?!
Calm down.
I won't get caught as long as
I fight from a distance.
Damn it... This is incredible!
All I can do is dodge...
Damn it, gimme a break...
If I get tainted by this power...
I don't even know what
will happen to me in the end...
But, I have no other choice,
do I, Naruto?
It is certainly true
that you're special...
However...
I'm more special than you are.
Sasuke!
By special...
By special, you meant that?!
I don't feel like I can lose.
Sasuke... you...
This body...
It looks like there's no time to waste.
I don't have any feeling
in my left arm...
That power you have...
seems to involve
some risks too, huh?
Did you know?
That this place...
is called the Valley of the End.
This is a fitting stage,
don't you think, Naruto?
Oh yeah...
I said there'd be
no more talking, didn't I?
Well, in that case,
how about we bring it to a close...?
This battle...
All our battles up to now!
- Rasengan!
- Chidori!
It's started to rain!
Will it erase the scent?
No problem.
We're already close.
This way.
Am I too late...?
Naruto!
Why did things come to this?!
This is Sasuke's...
I didn't make it in time...
please forgive me.
Naruto...
I know the kind of person you are...
You must have fought desperately.
Sasuke...
The Valley of the End...
To think that Sasuke and Naruto
would battle it out here...
How ironic...
Yeah...
When I look at
the flow of this water,
it's as if I'm being confronted
by an eternal battle...
Just like the fate of the two people
depicted in these statues here
who founded the Hidden Leaf Village...
As long as Naruto and Sasuke both live...
You have to kill...
your closest friend!
I'm not going to...
do everything you say!
I will obtain power my own way!
I will surpass you
doing it my own way!
Without fail!
The rain's... let up, hasn't it?
Yeah.
With that much rain,
I won't be able to pursue
the scent anymore.
Naruto is more important now
than pursuing Sasuke.
Yeah.
Kakashi-sensei...
Where's Sasuke?
Kakashi!
What's Naruto Uzumaki's condition?
He's okay.
What about Sasuke?
Where's Sasuke Uchiha?!
How are the other Genin?
Yes! By the Hokage's order,
the first and second medical corps
have been dispatched...
The wounded from all areas have
already been gathered.
They were transported after
receiving emergency treatment.
How are their conditions?
Yes! Shikamaru Nara has minor injuries...
Kiba Inuzuka has serious injuries,
but it's not life-threatening.
Neji Hyuga and Choji Akimichi
are in critical condition.
At this point,
there's no telling what will happen.
Everyone...
The ingredients and
effects of the medicine
have been thoroughly researched.
Excellent...
Now bring the deer antler!
Yes, ma'am!
How is he, Sis?
No walks for him for quite a while...
The muscles of his limbs
have been severely damaged.
You're a vet, right, Sis?
Can you do something...?
It'll be okay.
It'll take time. But there's no threat
to his life, so rest easy.
Walks for you are out of the question
for quite a while, too!
Yeah, I know...
It's almost been three hours...
Please take over.
All right!
We are using our chakra as a medium
to regenerate the cells,
so don't miscalculate the
regeneration rate for the damaged areas!
Right!
As for the chakra control, handle it
as if we're threading a needle!
Understood!
There's no point in
you getting frustrated, right?
Missions come with sacrifice...
You took the mental training, right?
Training and a real battle
are two different things.
I know what missions are about...
And I thought I knew what
the shinobi world is like.
I became a squad leader
for the first time on this mission.
With that, I understood...
I'm not cut out to be a shinobi.
Surprisingly fragile... for a man.
This time...
The only thing I was able to do
as squad leader...
was to believe in everyone.
I was nave...
I didn't have enough power...
It's all my fault!
Are you afraid of getting hurt?
Shikamaru...
Are you going to let a girl
talk you down and just run away?
I don't want to argue.
It's a drag, and besides, I'm not a woman.
Yeah... But you're not a man, either.
You're just a coward!
Even if you quit being a shinobi,
the missions will still go on.
Someone has to do it.
Your comrades will just
be dispatched again...
under a different squad leader.
And your comrades might die there.
But if you were
the squad leader...
your comrades might be saved
from that happening to them.
If you reflect on this time,
make use of the experience and learn,
you might be able to carry out
missions more perfectly.
If you really think your comrades
are important to you,
before you think about running away...
think about how to become
a leader they need!
That's what real comrades are,
you coward!
He's okay, now!
The antidote has stopped
the cellular necrosis
caused by the side effects of the pills.
You were a huge help this time, Shikaku.
The Nara Clan's secret medicinal
preparation manual was very useful.
It must've been tough to
make something like that...
It's the result of daily study.
Thanks...
Lady Tsunade!
Neji Hyuga...
His life is no longer in danger.
And, there's some information...
Kakashi Hatake and Naruto Uzumaki
have just now returned.
Although seriously injured,
it seems it's not life-threatening.
Two, huh?
Shikamaru...
It seems the mission was a failure.
But, everyone is alive!
That's the most important thing.
Next time for sure...
I'll carry out the mission perfectly!
Sasuke... You're the chosen one.
Whatever... Just give me power.
Even though he looks different,
it's still Lord Orochimaru.
If you don't want to die,
be more careful how you speak.
Wh-What? This chakra...
Yes...
My future lies within this boy...
Oh... You were awake, huh?
Shikamaru!
I'm going on ahead to Choji!
What about you?
I'm going to see... Naruto and Sasuke!
I see... So everyone's okay.
That's good.
Then, Sasuke...
Yeah... he's gone.
Then, I still can't see him...?
Yeah... But Lady Tsunade said that
he should regain consciousness soon.
Thank goodness...
It's really a great help that
Lady Tsunade returned
to the Leaf Village.
If she hadn't, right about now,
Choji would be...
The Fifth Hokage...
You've come to visit?
Information sure travels fast.
Sakura...
Naruto...
I heard you suffered
quite a serious injury...
But you look well, considering...
I'm sorry... Sakura...
Why do you apologize?
You went and got yourself hurt
again, didn't you?!
Honestly, you look like a mummy...
I'm sorry... I...
Hey... The weather's nice today.
So open the curtains.
Sakura! I...
I'll keep my promise, no matter what!
I promised on my life.
That's what I said, so I...!
It's okay, Naruto...
Sakura! He...
I've always...
said that... I...
I don't go back on my word!
That's my Ninja Way!
Naruto...
Thanks, Naruto...
I'll get right to healing this injury
and then I'll bring Sasuke back!
Wh-What was that?!
P-Pervy Sage?!
Yo!
I've come today to tell you
something important.
From here on,
as my official disciple,
I'll train you to become
a full-fledged shinobi in three years.
Three years...?
I've received some credible
information concerning the Akatsuki.
Akatsuki...
It seems that it will be
three or four years
before they come after you next.
I don't care about that!
Talking about stuff that's
so far down the road...
I don't have time for slow-paced training!
What do you mean?
If I don't go after Sasuke immediately,
he might be killed by Orochimaru!
It seems you've learned
of the true purpose
for Orochimaru seeking Sasuke...
Huh?! So you knew too, Pervy Sage?
I was looking into
Orochimaru's Immortality Jutsu.
It seems with that jutsu,
he can't transfer to a new vessel
for another three years.
And, unable to wait for Sasuke,
he had to transfer to a new vessel recently.
He'll be okay for another three years...
There is time.
That's not a lie, is it?!
Not a lie, is it?!
Nope.
However...
Forget about Sasuke...
Sasuke went to Orochimaru
on his own free will.
No matter what you do,
he won't change.
I've seen many shinobi, so I know...
Sasuke is just like Orochimaru.
If you're thinking about bringing him back
just forget it.
Trying to do that is just
arrogant and foolish!
He may be nothing to you,
but he's my friend!
Would a friend hurt his comrade?!
Take a look at your current condition!
This is...!
Why? Why would you...?
We were called Sannin together...
Weren't we comrades
since we were kids?!
In every regard,
you're a foolish guy, Jiraiya...
You're reckless and
never think things through.
That's why you didn't notice
what I was doing.
Won't you reconsider, Orochimaru?
Absurd!
How can you be so stupid?!
No matter how much I wanted it...
in the end, there was no way
he would come back.
After the agony, all that was left was
my own powerlessness and regret.
I don't want you to go through
the same thing...
If you're going to go after Sasuke,
then there'll be no training.
I'll get ANBU Black Ops to watch you
and depending on the case,
prohibit you from leaving the village.
You're not just an ordinary kid...
You possess the Nine-Tailed Fox,
which the Akatsuki is after!
This is serious.
I'll just have to do that...
if you're going to act on your own
without listening to what I say.
Eventually, you're going to have to deal
with guys more troublesome
than Orochimaru.
Give up on Sasuke.
Sooner or later this was
going to happen.
Stop suffering over him.
Just let him go.
It's not just jutsu or power...
A shinobi needs the insight
to make the right call.
And if you're going to live
as a shinobi, become wise.
If you remain a fool...
the reality is that it will be tough
living in this world.
Fine.
If that's what being wise is...
Then I'll gladly be a fool
for the rest of my life!
Even if by myself,
I'll create an even more awesome jutsu
and bring Sasuke back, no matter what!
And I'll kick the Akatsuki's ass, too!
If someone like you
were to do it alone...
the best you'd be able
to come up with
would be a new version of
your Sexy Jutsu, anyway.
It might somehow work out
if you're a hopeless fool and not
just an ordinary one...
Be prepared once
you're out of the hospital,
you big fool.
See you then.
Yes!
It's gotten interesting, hasn't it?
Yeah...