Sasuke, at Point B!
Sakura, at Point C!
Naruto, at Point A!
You're slow, Naruto!
Okay, Team 7...
Hm?!
The target has moved!
Follow it!
What's your distance to the target?
Five meters! I'm ready to go!
I'm ready too!
Me too...!
Okay...
Do it!
Uryaaah!
I got him!
Does he have the ribbon
on his right ear...?
Is that our target, Tora?
It's the target, no mistake.
Alright, the mission to capture the
lost pet, Tora, is complete!
Ohhh! My cute Tora!
I was worried to death!
Serves that stupid cat right!
No wonder he ran away...
Now, then!
The next mission for
Kakashi's Team 7 is...
An errand in the neighboring town...
babysitting the Chief Councilor's son...
Helping dig up potatoes...
Nooooo!
No! No, thank you!
As for me,
I want to do a much cooler mission!
Give us something else!
He's got a point...
Man... He's such a pain!
I figured it was about time
for him to get worked up.
You idiot! You're still rookies!
Every ninja starts...
with these simple missions
to gain experience
and work their way up!
B-But!
But we've only had a bunch
of lame missions so far!
Knock it off!
Naruto!
Let me explain to you
how missions work.
Listen to me!
Requests pour into the village
every day.
They range from babysitting
to assassinations...
A wide spectrum of requests
are compiled into a list...
They're classified into Ranks
A, B, C, and D based on difficulty.
All the ninja in our village...
are ranked by ability:
Jonin, Chunin, and Genin.
We, the higher-ups,
assign these requests as missions
to ninja of the appropriate
skill level.
And, upon a mission's success,
we receive payment from the client.
Since you have just become Genin...
D-Rank missions are all
you can handle for now.
Hm?!
Yesterday's lunch was pork-
bone ramen,
so today, it's miso ramen...
Listen!
I-I'm sorry.
Ah! You're always lecturing me,
Old Man!
But I'm not the little troublemaker
I used to be!
Hmph!
Man,
I'm going to get scolded later...
Okay, fine!
Huh?!
If you insist...
I will assign you a C-Rank mission.
You will be bodyguards.
Really?!
Ah ha!
Who is it? Who is it?
A feudal lord?!
Or a princess?!
Don't get so hasty.
I'll introduce you now!
Could you please come in...?
What's this?
A bunch of snot-nosed kids!
Huh?
Especially you, the short one
with the stupid face.
Are you really a ninja?
Who's the short one with
the stupid-looking face?
Huh?
I'll kill him!!
You can't kill the client
you're supposed to be
protecting, you idiot?!
I am Tazuna,
a master bridge builder.
You'll be guarding me with
your lives
until I return to my land and
complete the bridge!
We're off!!
What are you so excited about?!
You see, I've never been outside
the village before!
Hey! You expect me to believe
this little runt can protect me?!
I'm a Jonin, so I'll be in charge.
There's no need to worry.
This little runt?!
Hey, Old Man!
Don't you dare mock ninja!
I'm awesome, you see!
And I'm a super-elite ninja who
is going to be Hokage someday!
My name's Naruto Uzumaki.
Don't you forget it!
The Hokage's the top ninja
in the village, right?
You sure don't look like
Hokage material to me...
Aaah! Shut up!
I'm prepared to do whatever
it takes to become the Hokage!
Then, you're going to have to
acknowledge my strength!
I'll never acknowledge you, runt...
Even if you become the Hokage!
What?! I'll kill you!
I told you to stop that, you idiot!
C'mon! Just let me at him!
Just one punch!
Say... Mr. Tazuna...?
What is it?
Your country is
the Land of Waves, right?
What of it?
Say, Kakashi-sensei...
Are there ninja in that land, too?
No, there aren't ninja in
the Land of Waves...
But in other nations, while cultures
and customs are different,
Hidden Villages exist,
and there are ninja there.
For most nations on the continent,
Hidden Villages are a measure
of their nation's military strength.
In other words,
that's how nations maintain
relations with their neighbors.
However, a Hiden Village is not
subservient to its nation.
They hold equal standing.
On a small island like
the Land of Waves,
where it is difficult to be
influenced by other nations,
there is no need
for a Hidden Village.
Among the respective nations
that possess a Hidden Village,
the nations of Fire, Water,
Lightning, Wind, and Earth
are known as the
Five Great Shinobi Nations.
They are recognized for
their large territories and vast power.
The Hidden Leaf Village
of the Land of Fire.
The Village Hidden in the Mist
of the Land of Water.
The Village Hidden in the Clouds
of the Land of Lightning.
The Village Hidden in the Sand
of the Land of Wind.
The Village Hidden in the Stone
of the Land of Earth.
Only the leaders of
each of these Hidden Villages
are permitted the title of
"Kage", meaning Shadow.
"Hokage" (Fire Shadow),
"Mizukage" (Water Shadow),
"Raikage" (Lightning Shadow),
"Kazekage" (Wind Shadow),
"Tsuchikage" (Earth Shadow).
The five Kage (Five Shadows),
they reign supreme over
tens of thousands of shinobi
in each nation across the world.
Well... don't worry.
It's not likely there'll be any
ninja battles on a C-Rank mission.
So, we don't have to worry about
fighting any enemy ninja, right?
Of course not.
What?!
Huh?!
Wh-What?
The first one!
K-Kakashi-sensei!
Hm?!
It won't come off!
W-Wow!!
Whoa!
Ugh!!
They're coming!
I have to do something...
I have to!!
Get back!
Yo...
Kakashi-sensei! He's alive!
Hmph. Show-off.
What?!
Then, what was that...?
Naruto, sorry I didn't help you
right away.
You got hurt.
I didn't expect you to freeze up like that.
Anyway, good job, Sasuke.
You too, Sakura.
I... couldn't do anything...
but Sasuke...
It was his first real battle...
Didn't he feel scared, at all?
He saved me like it was nothing...
and didn't even get his clothes dirty.
Hey...
Huh?!
Are you hurt...
Scaredy-cat?
Sasuke!
Naruto!
These guys have poison
on their claws.
You need to
extract the poison quickly.
What?!
You have to open the wound and
drain the poisoned blood.
Try not to move around.
The poison will spread.
By the way, Mr. Tazuna...
Wh-What is it...?!
I need to speak with you.
Chunin from the
Village Hidden in the Mist...
These ninja are known to continue
fighting, no matter the cost.
How were you able
to detect our movements?
There probably wouldn't be
puddles of water
on a clear day like this, when
it hasn't rained in days.
If you knew, why did you let
the kids engage them first?
If I wanted to, I could have
kill them in an instant...
But...
I had to know...
who their target was...
Hm?! What do you mean?
What I mean is,
I had to know if
their target was you,
or if they were after us shinobi.
We didn't hear anything about
you being targeted by ninja.
The extent of your request was
supposed to be
protection from
ordinary thugs and thieves...
Our mission was to guard you
until the bridge is completed...
But if our enemies were to be ninja,
this mission would be B-Rank or higher,
which is more expensive.
You may have had your reasons...
but lying on a mission request
is unacceptable.
This is beyond the scope
of our mission.
This mission is too difficult for us...
We should call it off!
We need an anesthetic
for Naruto's wound
and to drain the poisoned blood...
Hm? What?!
This is a problem!
Since we need to treat Naruto's wound,
shall we go back to the village...?
Huh!
Oh!
Why am I so different?!
Why's it always me...
Damn it!
Naruto! What are you doing?!
I should be getting stronger...
I've been steadily carrying
out missions and
doing my own special training
every day...
I'll never let anyone
have to save me again!
I'll never freeze up,
or run away...
I won't lose to Sasuke...
I swear on the pain in this hand!
Believe it!
I'll protect you with this kunai, Old Man!
The mission continues!
Naruto...
Getting the poison out is one thing,
but if you keep that up,
you'll bleed to death.
You're going to bleed to death
if you don't stop that... Seriously!
Argh! No! No!
I don't want to die like this, y'know!
Show me your hand.
Nooo! Help me!!
Naruto!
You're so reckless,
aren't you!
You're unbelievable!
The wound is...
already starting to heal...
Did you say you failed?!
I paid a lot of money to hire
you guys
because you said
you were elite ninja!
Stop your damn grumbling...
Next time, I'll kill him myself...
I-It's really okay, right?!
It seems that the enemy
has hired some good ninja...
Now that the Demon Brothers have failed,
our target will be on high alert.
It won't be easy...
Just who do you think I am?!
I am Zabuza Momochi,
the Demon of the Hidden Mist.
This is quite some fog.
I can't see ahead.
The bridge should be visible soon.
When we reach the other side of the
bridge, we'll be in the Land of Waves.
Wooow!
It's huge!
H-Hey!
Please keep it down.
The fog is the only reason
we've made it this far undetected.
Engine’s off—been rowing to stay quiet.
If they find us now,
we'll be in deep trouble.
Mr. Tazuna.
I want to ask you something
before we arrive at the pier.
Who is after you?
And why are they targeting you?
If you don't tell us...
this mission may end the moment
we reach the shore.
It appears I have no choice
but to tell you.
No, I'd like you to know.
Just as you said,
this is probably beyond
the scope of your mission.
I am being targeted
by a terrifying man.
Who?
You guys have probably heard
of him before.
A shipping magnate
by the name of Gato.
What? Gato... of the Gato Company?
One of the world's richest men?
On the surface, he's the chief executive
of a shipping company...
But underneath, he's
involved in drug trafficking
and contraband, using gangs
and ninja to do his dirty work.
He runs a despicable business,
and ruthlessly takes over businesses
and even entire nations.
It was about one year ago...
when that man first set his eyes on
the Land of Waves...
He used his wealth and violence
to enter this country,
and before anyone knew it,
he'd taken complete control of the
island's shipping and transport.
In an island nation like the Land of Waves,
controlling the seas...
means having control of finance,
the government, the people... everything.
The one thing Gato fears...
is the completion of the bridge.
But I don't understand.
Your opponent is a dangerous man,
who even uses ninja.
Why did you hide that fact from us
when you made your request?
The Land of Waves...
is a very poor nation.
Even our feudal lord has no money.
We can't afford a B-Rank mission
or higher.
Well, if you pull out
of the mission when I land ashore,
I will, no doubt, be killed.
Killed before I even make it home.
But there's no need for concern!
Should I die, my cute grandchild,
who will turn eight...
will only cry his heart out!
Oh!
And... my daughter will only blame
the Hidden Leaf ninja
for the rest of her life
and live in sorrow!
Well...
I guess we have no choice.
Let's continue as his bodyguards.
I won!
We'll be arriving soon.
Tazuna.
It appears we haven't been noticed yet...
Thanks.
This is as far as I go.
See you around.
Yeah. You've been a big help.
Be careful.
Okay!
Get me home safely.
Right.
The next one won't be a Chunin.
It'll be a Jonin.
Damn!
I'm not going to let this guy
get all the action!
There!
Heh... Just a mouse.
Quit trying to show off!
There was nothing there
in the first place!
Please, Naruto.
Don't use kunai recklessly.
They're really dangerous.
Hey, brat!
Stop messing around!
Huh? I sense a presence there!
There!
Stop it, already!
S-Someone's really been targeting us
the whole time!
Yeah, right!
Knock it off, you!
Naruto!
What have you done?!
It's a bunny!
I-I didn't mean to...
Sorry, bunny.
It's just a rabbit, huh.
That's a snow rabbit.
But that doesn't explain
its fur color...
The coat turns white only during winter
when there is little sunlight.
Which means...
that this Snow Rabbit was raised
to be used as a substitution.
Guess they're already here...
I see... The Demon Brothers wouldn't
be enough to take on these guys.
The Copy Ninja of the
Hidden Leaf Village...
Sharingan Kakashi is with them...
If I'm not mistaken, he's...
I'm going to do it this time...
I won't lose to Sasuke!
Well, well...
If it isn't Zabuza Momochi,
the Rogue Ninja of the Hidden Mist!
Ready...
Go!
Get back, you guys.
He's on a completely different level
than the ones we fought before.
If he's our opponent, then...
Huh?
Oh.
This is going to be tough.
Sharingan Kakashi, I presume?
Sorry, but...
Could you hand over the old man?
H-Huh? Sharingan?
What's that?
Form the Manji Formation...
Protect Tazuna.
Stay out of this fight.
That's the teamwork
this situation demands.
Huh?!
Fight me.
Wh-What's up with his eye...?
Well now...
I never expected to see
the legendary Sharingan this soon...
This is an honor.
Everyone's been saying Sharingan...
What is it?!
... Sharingan.
It's a special power that can see
through movements and copies techniques.
The Sharingan is a dojutsu—a type of
visual jutsu that manifests in the eyes.
However, that is not the only power
the Sharingan has...
Well said.
There is indeed more...
When I was in the ANBU Black Ops
of the Hidden Mist,
I had a shinobi Bingo Book...
You were among those I had intel on.
You have quite an impressive record...
The man who has copied
over one thousand jutsu...
Kakashi, the Copy Ninja.
What? Kakashi-sensei
is really that incredible?
W-Wow!
The Sharingan... is a special trait
that appears in only a select few
among the Uchiha clan.
Could he be...
Let's end the talking here.
I must kill that old man immediately.
But, Kakashi, it seems
I have to defeat you first.
Over there!
And he's on the water?
He's building up quite a bit of chakra!
Ninja Art: Hidden Mist Jutsu.
He vanished?!
He'll probably come to kill me first...
What is he?
Zabuza Momochi.
He's an ANBU Black Ops member
of the Hidden Mist
and he's an expert of the
Silent Killing technique.
So don't lower your guard, you guys.
The mist is steadily getting thicker!
The Land of Waves
is surrounded by ocean.
The mist builds up quickly here.
Sensei!
Eight spots.
Huh? What?
The larynx, the spine,
the lungs, the liver...
the jugular, the subclavian veins,
the kidneys, and the heart...
Now then, which vital spot
should I choose?
What an intense killing intent!
If I take even one breath,
or move my eyes,
I will be marked and killed...
That's what I'm feeling.
I can't! I'd rather die
than face this feeling!
Sasuke.
Calm down.
I'll protect you with my life.
I will not allow
my comrades to be killed.
I wonder about that...
It's over.
Sensei!
Behind you!
Die!
A Water Clone Jutsu?
It can't be!
Don't move.
It's over.
Wow!
Did you say it's over?
You don't understand, do you?
You'll never defeat me with
such a cheap imitation.
No chance.
But, I must say you're good.
You had already copied my
Water Clone Jutsu back then, huh?
I will not allow
my comrades to be killed.
You used the clone to take your place,
and create a diversion.
While you used the Hidden Mist Jutsu
to hide yourself and watch me...
But...
I'm not a fool.
Now!
Makibishi spikes.
How foolish!
Wh-What's with this water...?
It's awfully heavy.
Hmph... Fool!
Water Prison Jutsu!
Damn!
My escape into the water...
was a huge mistake!
You're caught...
This prison is special.
There's no escaping it!
I'll settle things
with you later.
After I finish those guys off.
Water Clone Jutsu!
I didn't expect this level of skill...
Acting all tough with that
headband...
But... a true ninja is one
who has danced on the edge of death
countless times.
In other words,
only those whose names are worthy
of being listed in my Bingo Book,
deserve to be called ninja.
You brats don't even deserve
to be called ninja.
He disappeared again!
You're just a kid!
Naruto!
You three!
Take Tazuna and run!
You have no chance
against this guy!
As long as he has me trapped
in this Water Prison,
he can't leave this spot.
The Water Clone also can't stray too far
from the user's real body.
So just run for now!
Sasuke!
Sasuke...
T-This is a Jonin-level...
A real ninja...
Seriously! Seriously!
We're going to be killed!!
Ow!
Naruto, come over here.
I'd like to give you something.
Congratulations on your graduation.
On top of having a hostage taken,
you're faced with two impossible choices
and end up being killed.
On every mission,
you're putting your life on the line.
You pass!
I'm not the little prankster
you think I am anymore!
I'm going to surpass the Hokage!
And then the entire Village
will have to acknowledge my existence!
That's right...
I'm a ninja now. And...
I decided that I was not going
to freeze up!
That I wouldn't run away!
Hmph! Idiot...
What are you thinking...
charging off on your own?!
Even Sasuke is no match for him...
No matter how hard we try,
we Genin are no match for him...
Huh?!
The headband...?!
Hey, No-Brows!
Make a record in your Bingo Book...
a man who will one day be Hokage
of the Hidden Leaf Village.
The Hidden Leaf Village's very own...
Naruto Uzumaki!
When I first saw that little kid,
he seemed so unreliable...
Sasuke! I have a plan!
What is it?
I have a plan.
Hmph! Teamwork, you say?
Wh-What is this feeling?
Was Naruto always so...?
Now...
Let's do this!
Big words for a brat.
Let's see if you can back them up.
T-This isn't good...
What are you guys doing!
I told you to run!
It was obvious what was going to happen
once I was caught!
Hurry! Run!
Listen to me!
Our mission is to protect Tazuna!
Have you forgotten that?!
Old Man...
Well...
I got you into this...
And it would be wrong to let
you four get killed trying to save me.
Sorry, you guys...
Fight as much as you want!
You hear that?
Are you ready?
You guys really haven't learned
anything, have you?
Wh-What?!
You're still playing at being ninja.
When I was your age,
these hands were already
stained with blood!
Zabuza, the Demon!
Ohh? So you've heard...?
Long ago, the Hidden Mist Village was
known as the "Village of the Bloody Mist."
Ninja candidates faced
their greatest challenge.
You even know about
the graduation exam...?
The graduation exam?
What is it?
This graduation exam
that you're talking about...
The students killed each other.
What?
Classmates who had shared rice
from the same pot
formed pairs and tried
to kill each other.
It didn't end
until one of them died.
Friends who used to talk about
each other's dreams and aspirations...
How cruel...
Ten years ago,
the Mist Village's graduation exam
was forced to undergo drastic reform.
Because an evil demon had appeared
on the scene the previous year.
What about the reform?
What had that evil demon done?
With no scruples or hesitation...
a young boy who hadn't even
yet qualified as a ninja,
butchered more than one hundred
of his fellow students.
That sure was... fun...
Sasuke!
Die!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Ah... Shadow Clone Jutsu,
and so many of them.
Here I go!
It's impossible, after all...
There's only one way left
to defeat this guy!
Sasuke!
I see!
So that's your plan, Naruto!
That's pretty good for you!
Demon Wind Shuriken
A shuriken won't work on me.
I see.
This time you're
aiming for my real body...
But...
It's not so easy!
A second shuriken hidden
in the shadow of the first one!
But...
Still too naïve.
Gotcha!
You little brat!
Kakashi-sensei!
Naruto...
Your strategy was outstanding.
You've grown up...
Both of you.
The purpose of the Shadow Clones
was not to take down Zabuza,
but to hide me, transformed
into a Demon Wind Shuriken!
That was just luck...
It was just luck, huh!
Still, they performed flawlessly
as a team...
in this desperate situation.
Despite the fact...
that those two always
fight like cats and dogs.
Hmph...
I got distracted and
released my Water Prison Jutsu...
That's not it!
You didn't drop the jutsu...
They forced you to break it.
I'll say this once: the same
jutsu won't work on me twice.
So what will you do?
Ox, Monkey, Hare.
Rat, Boar, Bird, Ox.
Hand sign: Bird
Water Style: Water Dragon Jutsu!
He copied all that in seconds...
and so perfectly...!
Strange...
We performed the jutsu
at the exact same time!
He couldn't be...
This guy...
My movements...!
He's perfectly...
Reading them.
What?
He's reading my mind?!
Blast him! He's...
You're trying to intimidate me
with that cold stare... Right?
Hah! You're just copying...
You're a pale imitation.
- You won't be able to beat me!
- You!
I'll shut that copycat
monkey mouth permanently!
Wh-What's that!
Me?
R-Ridiculous!
Is this genjutsu?
Water Style: Giant Vortex Jutsu!
Wh-What!
No way!
I was just about to
use that jutsu...
I can't keep up with...
his jutsu!
It's over...
Why...?
Are you able to see into the future...?
Yeah...
I see...
Your death!
You were right. He is dead.
He's definitely dead.
I thank you.
I have been waiting for the chance
to kill Zabuza.
By the looks of that mask...
You're a Tracker Ninja from
the Village Hidden in the Mist.
Impressive.
You're very knowledgeable.
Judging by his build and voice,
he can't be much older than Naruto...
And he's a Tracker Ninja...?
He's not an ordinary kid...
What are you?!
Hey you!
Relax, Naruto.
He's not an enemy.
That's not what I'm asking!
I...
I mean!
That Zabuza...
That Zabuza was killed!
That guy who was so strong...
And he was killed so easily
by a kid no older than me!
I won't accept it!
Well,
I understand your disbelief.
But... this, too, is reality.
In this world, there are kids
who are younger than you...
and stronger than me.
Your battle is over for now.
I must dispose of this body...
It holds many secrets.
Now then, please excuse me.
He disappeared!
Our mission hasn't ended yet.
We must get Tazuna safely to his home.
So sorry, everyone!
You can rest at my house!
Okay!
Let's perk up and go!
Wh-What!
What happened!
Kakashi-sensei!
It seems I've overused
my Sharingan...
Are you alright, Sensei?
I overdid it... I won't be able
to move properly for about a week.
Well...
Then you shouldn't move at all.
O-Okay...
Hey! Sensei's awake.
Come on!
Your Sharingan is fantastic,
but if it puts that much strain
on your body, is it really worth it?
S-Sorry...
But you know...
He took down a powerful ninja!
We probably don't need to
worry for a while.
Anyway, that kid with the mask...
What was he?
He was an ANBU Black Ops
from the Hidden Mist Village.
Only elite Tracker Ninja
wear masks like that.
Tracker Ninja?
Well, they're commonly known as
"Corpse Disposal Unit,"
and their duty is to erase every trace
of a ninja's existence.
The body of a ninja reveals
a variety of things...
Ninjutsu secrets and chakra
characteristics of their village...
the composition of secret medicines
used on a ninja's body, for example.
For instance, if I were to die,
every secret about my Sharingan
would be investigated thoroughly,
and in the worst case scenario,
all of my jutsu could be stolen.
In other words,
Tracker Ninja are specialists
who prevent village secrets
from leaking out
by hunting down rogue ninja
who've fled their village,
and completely eliminating
their bodies.
What is this?
This must mean something...
I have a feeling
I've overlooked something.
What's going on?!
Sensei?
Tracker Ninja...
dispose of corpses,
immediately, on the spot.
So what?
How did that kid in the mask
dispose of Zabuza's body?
How should we know?!
That masked guy
took Zabuza away!
That's right...
If he needed proof he'd killed Zabuza,
he could simply have taken the head...
And then there's...
the weapon that Tracker Ninja
used to kill Zabuza...
With just a Senbon...
That's impossible...
Yeah... that's impossible!
What have you guys
been going on and on about?!
It's likely that...
Zabuza is still alive!
What the hell do you mean?!
But Kakashi-sensei,
you confirmed that he was dead!
I did confirm it, but...
he was probably just in
a death-like state.
The senbon that the Tracker Ninja used
has a very low chance of killing...
unless it hits a vital spot.
It's something that was originally
used for medical treatments,
such as acupuncture therapy.
Tracker Ninja know all about
the structure of the human body...
Putting people into a near-death
state is probably simple for them.
First, he took the trouble
to carry away Zabuza's body
which was probably heavier than he is.
Second, he used senbon, a weapon
with a low probability of being fatal.
From these two factors,
it's more likely that the kid's goal
wasn't to kill Zabuza, but to save him.
Aren't you reading
way too much into it?
No...
When something feels wrong,
prepare for the worst.
For a shinobi, that is an ironclad rule.
Hmph... To hear that Zabuza
may be alive and to be pleased...
Sensei, what can we do to prepare?
You won't even be able
to move for a while...
I'm going to have you train!
W-Wait a minute! Even with training,
we're not going to be that strong!
Our opponent is a ninja that even you
had trouble with, despite your Sharingan!
Are you trying to get us killed?!
Sakura...
Who was it that saved me
during my difficult battle?
You've all quickly grown...
especially Naruto!
You've grown the most!
So you noticed, Kakashi-sensei!
Now this is getting interesting!
It's not interesting at all...
Who the hell are you?
Hey, Inari!
Where have you been?!
Welcome back... Grandpa...
Inari, what sort of greeting is that?!
These are the ninja
who escorted your grandpa!
It's okay, it's okay.
Right, Inari?
But mom, these guys will die...
They can't win against Gato
and his men.
What did you say, you little brat?!
Now listen up!
I'm a superhero who's going to become
an awesome ninja,
the one who'll become the Hokage!
I don't care if his name is Gato or
Bonito or whatever...
I'm not worried
about those guys at all!
Huh! A hero? How stupid.
There's no such thing!
What was that?!
Stop that!
If you don't want to die,
you'd better hurry up and go home...
Inari, where are you going?
To the sea...
I'm going to look at the sea...
I apologize.
That brat... I'll teach him
a thing or two!
Huh?
Is he crying?!
Dad...
So, now the training begins!
Yes, sir!
But... before that, let's go over the
basics of chakra, a ninja's power.
Now then...
We already know all about that!
"Chatora", right?
It's chakra...
Go ahead, Sakura.
Pay attention, Naruto...
Chakra is the energy
a ninja needs to perform jutsu!
It's made up of two energies:
First, physical energy gathered
from each and every cell in the body
Second, spiritual energy accumulated
with years of training and experience!
In other words, jutsu draws out
and combines these two energies
from within the body,
and this is called
"combining chakra."
Then chakra is activated
by forming hand signs.
That's exactly right!
Iruka-sensei has certainly raised
some fine students.
Whatever! I may not understand
difficult explanations,
but I'll just learn it with my body!
Naruto is absolutely right...
We all are
already able to use jutsu...
No! None of you are using
your chakra efficiently yet.
What?!
Just listen...
As Sakura explained earlier,
combining chakra means taking
both physical and spiritual energies
and mixing them together
within the body.
And the amount of each energy needed
changes based on
the jutsu you want to activate...
Right now, none of you are
using your chakra efficiently!
Even if you're able to summon
a lot of chakra,
if you're not able to control it
in a balanced way
not only will the effectiveness
of the jutsu be cut in half
but it may not even
be activated at all.
Wasting energy will leave you
unable to fight for long.
These are some of
the weaknesses that can occur.
Wh-What should we do...?
You need to learn to control
chakra with your body!
It's difficult training that requires you
to put your life on the line to master!
Wh-What will we do?
Hm?
Tree climbing...
Tree climbing?!
That's right.
But this isn't just ordinary
tree climbing!
You will climb
without using your hands.
What? How?
Well, just watch.
He's climbing...
Straight up the tree,
and just with his feet!
So see, kind of like this...
Focus chakra to the soles of your
feet and use it to stick to the tree.
If you use chakra well,
you can do things like this.
Wait a minute!
How does something like that
make you strong?
I was just about to get to that...
The purpose of this training is
to build up
the required amount of chakra
at a precise spot...
This is surprisingly difficult,
even for an expert ninja.
The amount of chakra needed
for tree climbing is very subtle.
And the soles of the feet are the
hardest part of the body to gather chakra.
In other words,
if you master the control needed for this,
it will be possible to master
any jutsu. In theory, that is!
The second aim is to maintain
that combined chakra.
Ninja combine the most chakra
during battles.
Under such circumstances,
controlling and maintaining your
chakra becomes the most difficult challenge.
But anyway, just talking about it
won't accomplish anything...
You'll need to learn it with your bodies
Use the kunai to
mark the highest spot
that you can climb up to
with your current strength.
Then, you'll work to make
a new mark even higher.
You aren't good enough to
walk up from the start,
so run and use your momentum
to get used to it... Got it?
This training is nothing!
Hah! It'll be a piece of cake!
After all, I'm the guy
who's grown the most!
Enough with the talk...
Now get to it. Try climbing any tree.
Ok, so first I need to gather
chakra at the bottom of my feet...
Ready!! Here I go!
I didn't think it'd be this difficult to
maintain a constant amount of chakra...
If the chakra is too strong
you get pushed back...
But if it's too weak,
you'll lose your grip and fall.
Well...!
The difference between Naruto and Sasuke
seems about right.
This is pretty easy!
What?
S-Sakura!
Wow! Way to go, Sakura!
Just what I'd expect from
someone as awesome as her!
But it does sort of tick me off!
Whatever!
I wanted Sasuke to notice me...
Why does this always happen?!
Well, not only does Sakura have
knowledge about chakra,
her control and stamina
are pretty good.
It looks like...
Looks like she has the best chance of
becoming Hokage... unlike a certain someone.
And the Uchiha Clan
doesn't seem that impressive, either.
Shut up, Sensei!
Now Sasuke's going to hate me!
Having said that...
Naruto and Sasuke...
Those two have an incredible amount
of chakra hidden in them...
that Sakura can't hope to match!
If this training goes well,
this will become an asset to them...
Okay! First I'll catch up to Sasuke!
I'll do it... for sure!
Whatever!
They're just wasting their
time with that...
Ohhhhh...
Ow!
I'm totally worn out!
How much stamina
do those two have?
But Naruto isn't getting
any better at all.
He'll give up soon and
start throwing a tantrum.
Damn!
See! He sure is
an easy one to figure out!
Hey, Sakura!
Can you give me some tips?
What?
But keep it a secret from Sasuke!
Come on, come on.
He's getting stronger and stronger...
How strong will he get?
At any rate, Naruto...
the amount of dormant chakra you have
is probably far more than Sasuke's.
It's probably even more than mine!
I look forward to
watching you grow... I really do.
It looks like you've got some time
to kill there, all by yourself.
What about the blond brat
and the stuck-up one?
They're in the middle of
the tree-climbing training.
You don't have to do that?
I mastered it quickly, so Kakashi-sensei
has me on guard duty.
Really?
What?!
Can I have a word, Tazuna?
Huh? What is it, Giichi?
Uh, actually...
I've been thinking things over...
Building this bridge...
I want to quit!
What? So suddenly? Not you too?!
Tazuna, we go back quite awhile.
I'd like to help,
but if we push it too far,
Gato will set his sights
on us, too.
And... if they kill you,
it's all for nothing!
Why don't you just
stop building the bridge?
This is our bridge.
This is the bridge that
everyone in town has built
believing that it will bring
distribution and transportation
to our land once more.
But we're talking about our lives...
It's already afternoon...
Let's call it a day.
Tazuna!
Giichi... you don't have to
come back tomorrow.
Damn it!
What is going on?!
Why can't I do this?!
I won't lose to you!
Say, where are we going?
I was asked to pick some things up
for dinner on the way home...
Thief!
What's up with... this town?
We're here...
Welcome...
There's hardly anything here...
You pervert!
Man, I was really surprised earlier.
What's going on with this town?!
Again?
Hey, you...
What?
Gimme some!
Oh... here...
Yaaay!
Thank you.
This is how it's been ever
since Gato showed up.
Here, all the adults
have turned into cowards.
That's why the bridge
is necessary...
It's a symbol of courage...
to restore their spirits and
stop them from giving up.
For the people of this land...
who have set their minds
on remaining passive...
If we can just...
complete that bridge...
This town will return to
how it once was...
and everyone will come back.
Damn it! Damn it!
Are you telling me that
Sasuke's still climbing?!
Crap...
He's catching up...
Damn it! No! No!
If I let myself get distracted by Sasuke,
my concentration will break!
Concentrate!
Okay... I think I'm getting
the hang of this, y'know!
Okay! This is it!
Hey... Naruto!
Hey! What the hell is
wrong with you?!
I'm trying to concentrate,
so don't get in my way!
U... Uh... Well...
Wh-What is it?!
Y-You asked Sakura to give
you some tips before...
What did she say to you?
I'm not telling!
Man!
This is really fun!
It's been a long time since we've had
a meal with this many people!
Seconds please!
Stop eating if you're going to vomit!
No, I'll eat.
I have to eat, even
if I have to force it down.
I have to get strong
as quickly as possible, so...
Mm-hmm.
But vomiting it all back up is
just a waste.
Excuse me, why is there
a torn picture hanging here?
It's my husband...
He was a man this town
once called a hero...
Dad!
I keep telling you not to
talk about him in front of Inari!
Why does talking about his
father make Inari upset?
There's a story behind that,
isn't there?
Inari wasn't related to that
man by blood,
but they were like a real father
and son who got along really well...
Back then, Inari was a child
who laughed all the time...
However...
Inari changed... after the
incident involving his father.
Poochie!
Wrong!
His name's Shooting Star...
As of today, he's my dog!
He's not Shooting Star!
He's my Poochie! Give him back!
Poochie's my friend!
Why would we give him to a
crybaby like you?!
Shut up!
Poochie!
That's what you get for not
handing him over quietly...
I couldn't care less
about that dog!
Hey, let him go!
What have you done?!
Are you trying to kill Poochie?
Heh! He's your special mutt, right?
Then save him, quickly.
What's the matter?
Is it okay with you if he dies?!
- But...
- Look! He can't even dog paddle,
- even though he's a dog!
- But...
I'm sorry, Poochie...
I can't swim...
Hey! If you're his owner,
dive in after him!
This is bad, Akane.
What if he can't swim?
S-Save me!
Leave him be.
B-But...
Then why don't you go save him?
I-I don't want to die...
Somebody save me!
P-Poochie!
Poochie!
Shooting Star escaped. Get him!
Ohhh... I can't breathe...
This... is it...
Are you awake, boy?
I gave those kids
a good scolding.
Here, eat!
Is this real? Oh...
Did you... save me?
Just eat! Start with that.
I see. You were betrayed
by your dog, too...
In my country, dogs are creatures
that have a keen sense of loyalty...
Well, you betrayed
your dog's trust first,
so there's nothing
you can do about that.
I was scared and couldn't move.
I wanted to save him...
But... I have no guts, so...
That's right.
Of course, a kid your age
would be scared.
But you know... boy.
Just remember this.
Huh?
A man should live his life without regrets.
For the things I truly
hold dear,
I'll protect them to the very end
with these two arms.
No matter how hard or painful it is...
even if it costs me my life!
We... we've got trouble, Kaiza!
The river dam broke
from all this rain!
At this rate,
District D will be flooded!
What?!
Dad!
Inari, go out back and
get some rope!
Okay!
It's no use!
The only thing we can do is
attach a rope and pull...
Don't talk nonsense!
How are we going to attach a rope?!
We'd die if we were to go
into such a furious current!
But if we wait, everyone in
District D will be wiped out!
What should we do?
I'll do it.
Kaiza!
Don't be foolish!
Even you wouldn't be able to!
Dad!
Don't worry...
Your dad's unmatched.
Your dad loves the town
you're from, so...
For things I truly hold dear...
He did it!
The rope... the rope's attached!
Okay, everybody pull!
Yeah!
From that day on... the people
of this town called Kaiza their hero.
And he became a father
that Inari could be proud of.
It was around that time when Gato
set his sights on this land.
And then, one night...
I heard...
That you're going to protect
this town with those arms...
I dare you to try!
Listen up!
This man committed acts of violence
against the Gato Corporation,
and disrupted the order of
this island.
Therefore, he will now be executed!
I just hope that such trivial matters
will never occur again.
Dad!
Stop, Inari...
Do it...
Dad...
Dad!
Ever since then,
Inari has changed...
as well as Tsunami...
and the townspeople...
What are you doing, Naruto?
You've had enough training for today.
You've used too much chakra.
You'll die if you use
any more than that.
I'll prove it.
Prove what?
I'll prove that...
there are heroes...
in this world!
Good morning!
Here.
Thank you.
Naruto didn't come back
last night?
He's such a fool,
he's been out every night,
climbing trees.
He might be dead already
from using up too much chakra.
I wonder if Naruto's okay.
To think a child's out in
the middle of the night.
Well, you don't need to worry.
Although he may not seem like it,
he's a full-fledged ninja.
I wonder...
That idiot's probably
all pooped out right about now.
You'll catch a cold if
you keep sleeping here.
Who are you?
Huh... Did you wake me up, miss?
I mean... what are you doing out here?
I'm gathering medicinal herbs.
Herbs?
Yes. For healing injuries,
sickness and the like.
You're up early, miss.
You, too.
What've you been doing
in a place like this so early?
Training!
Could it be that...
you're a ninja or something?
What with that headband and...
Is that what I look like? Is it?
Yup! I'm a ninja!
Oh really?
That's admirable.
But... why are you training?
I want to get stronger!
But, you already look
strong enough.
No, no! I want to get
even stronger!
What for?
To become the greatest ninja
in my village!
I'm going to get everyone
to recognize my strength!
And I have to prove something
to a certain person!
Are you doing this for someone else?
Or are you doing it for yourself?
Huh?
Wh-What's so funny?!
Do you have someone
precious to you?
Precious?
What are you trying to say, miss?
What is it?
When a person has something
precious they want to protect...
that's when they can truly
become strong.
If you ever lay a hand on Iruka-sensei,
I'll kill you!
Yeah! I know all about that!
You'll get strong.
Yeah!
I hope we meet again somewhere.
Oh... and...
I'm a boy!
No way!
He's even cuter than Sakura!
Why? That's strange.
This world is full of mystery...
Ouch.
Hey! What are you doing?!
Did you forget to eat, you blockhead?
Naruto?
What in the world is Naruto doing?
And Sasuke hasn't come back
from his walk either...
No way...
Naruto can climb that high now?
Wow!
How'bout that, how'bout that?!
I can climb this high now!
Whoa!
Oh, you idiot!
This is bad!
Gotcha!
You fell for it, you fell for it!
Don't scare us like that!
I'll get him for that! Cha!
He's grown a little, hmm.
You fool.
Sasuke...?
Nice, Sasuke.
You're awesome!
These kids are really growing.
Naruto, huh?
Let's go back.
Okay!
They're late.
Not just Naruto, but Sasuke too.
What happened to you guys?
You're both muddy and exhausted.
We both... made it to the very top.
Good.
Naruto, Sasuke, starting tomorrow,
you'll both be guarding Tazuna as well.
Got it! Whoa!
You idiot!
Just a little longer,
and the bridge will be complete.
It's thanks to you guys.
Even so, don't let your guard down...
I've really wanted to ask
you for a long time now...
But why are you still here
even though I lied about the mission?
To abandon a just cause
is the mark of a coward.
It's an old saying I happen to like.
Why are you pushing yourself so hard
that you're about to collapse?!
There's no way you'll be a match for
Gato's men, no matter how hard you train!
Shut up. I'm not like you.
Shut up!
Just looking at you makes me sick!
Stop sticking your nose in our business!
You don't know anything about this land!
I'm not like you—always
acting so carefree and oblivious,
someone who doesn't know
what it's like to truly suffer!
An idiot like you can cry all you want!
You crybaby!
Naruto! That's too harsh!
Naruto...
Got a minute?
Naruto didn't mean any harm
with what he said...
He's just uncouth, so...
We heard the story
about your father from Tazuna.
Like you, Naruto also grew up
without a father...
In fact, he never knew either
of his parents.
Not only that.
He didn't have a single friend.
What?
However...
I've never once seen him
complain or cry.
He's always trying so hard,
just wanting to be acknowledged.
He always puts his life on the line
for that dream.
He's probably tired of crying.
That's why Naruto understands
how you feel, probably more than anyone.
What Naruto said earlier...
I'm sure it's something he's been
telling himself over and over again.
You've recovered considerably.
All right...
Just a little more, Haku.
Yes.