Sasuke, Lord Orochimaru has
given us one important task.
You will need to die once.
Die once, you said?
Mind Awakening Pills.
Please take these.
And after I die?
You don't need to worry.
That is why we are here.
We will use our barrier ninjutsu
to suppress the side effects,
to guide you from the brink of death
into a state of suspended animation.
No matter what happens,
I cannot afford to die yet.
I'm in your hands...
– Four Black Mists Formation!
Black Seal!
All right, we're done with
the first part.
You are weak.
D-Damn it!
I see... You've made up your mind, huh?
Yes!
I'm doing fitness training
to get ready for the surgery.
I want to return as soon as
I can after the surgery, so...
Oww!
Ow ow...
Lee...
Yes?! What is it?
You won't die
if you give up being a shinobi.
Why are you so fixated
on being a shinobi?
Proving that even I can become
a fine ninja... That's my everything!
You might die. Even if you succeed...
Even so...
I promise you!
That's my dream, so...
Why... do you react so strongly
to the name "Hokage"
Unlike you...
I will be the next
Hokage, no matter what!
Because Hokage is my dream!
In this village, promising children
are being brought up.
Sarutobi-sensei... Just as I thought,
you were a wonderful Hokage.
The surgery is in the afternoon.
Get ready!
Let's go, Lee! Are you prepared?!
Yes!
Man, I'm exhausted.
I didn't think this mission
would drag on this long.
I'll go check out the situation.
Let's go, Raido!
Right.
Damn. This has sure gotten troublesome.
There's one...
No, two of them.
Here they come!
You guys are Orochimaru's...
Judging from the direction
you came from,
it seems you're on your way back
from the Hidden Leaf...
What's in that barrel?
Having two Jonin as opponents...
That's a tough one.
Every one of them
has a Curse Mark...
You refuse to answer?
his isn't going to play out
like your ambush last time.
Shut up, you scum!
Just drop dead!
Orochimaru's toys...
Don't you dare mess with Leaf shinobi.
Those two are really late, aren't they?
What should we do, Shizune?
Let's go see!
Right!
Shikamaru!
What's the matter?
There's a smell of blood nearby.
Wh-What's this?!
Raido! Genma!
This isn't good!
Right now, all I can do is provide
emergency first aid...
Shizune...
I'm going to hunt those guys down!
No!
B-But...
W-Wait... Iwashi.
The jutsu those guys are using...
it's not something an ordinary shinobi can do.
If you pursue them alone,
you'll just get yourself killed.
Genma... don't talk anymore!
The other two's scent is mixed
with the five others, including Sasuke...
But the five are moving away
from the smell of the blood!
What should we do?!
Just as I thought.
He has guides.
This has really turned into
a pain in the neck.
Let's hurry and go after Sasuke!
Shut up, Naruto!
That's for Shikamaru to decide!
Stop acting like the boss!
Shikamaru?
The smell of blood probably means
that a battle occurred somewhere.
If we go to that location we should
be able to gather some information...
We'll have to be careful
as we near the location,
so we'll have to switch to
a reconnaissance formation
and approach cautiously...
While all that's going on
Sasuke will cross
the Land of Fire border!
What are we going to do, Shikamaru?!
All right! Let's pursue Sasuke!
All right! That's what I was waiting for!
However...
Since there was a battle,
they'll have their guard up.
They'll certainly be aware
that there might be ninja on their tail.
In other words,
the odds are high that
there will be traps or an ambush.
Listen carefully...
From now on, use your eyes
and ears to the fullest!
We need to locate those guys before
we get caught in an ambush!
And if we come across
anything suspicious,
don't just dodge it,
figure out what it means!
All right!
When we find them,
I'm going to use my new jutsu
to knock them out!
That Naruto...
Each time I see him
he's added a new jutsu to his arsenal.
Damn! Just when I thought
I had caught up with him...
Hey! The enemy's smell is everywhere!
Everybody! Stop!
Take a careful look above you.
Paper bombs...
And in five other places too!
It's a perimeter barrier formation.
Perimeter barrier?
It's one type of booby trap ninjutsu!
Perimeter-type traps have a time lag
and are activated
when someone enters the designated area.
It's an advanced jutsu...
It was in one of the books that
my father made me read.
Damn! Our only choice
is to make a detour...
Damn! Nothing but traps!
Yeah, but the enemy seems
pressed for time.
The traps have noticeable flaws.
Hey, hey, Naruto!
There's wire at your feet!
Don't trip on it!
I know that already!
Wait, Naruto!
Shadow Possession Jutsu...
M-Made it... just in the nick of time.
Naruto! I told you to be careful!
I see... One wire is easy to see
because it reflects light.
The other wire has been coated
with a matte green.
So it's very difficult to see
with the naked eye.
It's a double trap, huh.
Even though they're in a hurry,
that's a pretty elaborate trap.
Which means that...
They're resting.
They could be injured,
or this itself might be the trap...
Byakugan!
I've found them!
All right! All right!
I'll drag Sasuke back without fail!
Naruto! Hate to tell you this,
but I'm going to demonstrate
my new jutsu right here!
Me too!
Don't be so hasty.
As soon as preparations for
my strategy are complete...
we'll make direct contact
with the target!
Damn! When we're in a hurry,
having to take a damn break...
It can't be helped.
Fighting in State 2
drains your body drastically.
More than that,
and being immobilized for a while
afterward is an ordeal...
We had no choice against
two Jonin-level opponents.
If we'd held back,
we would've been done for.
Kiba...
In that case,
don't mess up the timing
of the smoke bombs.
Got it!
Now then...
we'll split up into two teams.
- Right!
- Okay!
It looks like they haven't noticed us yet.
Hey, Sasuke's not around.
It appears that...
He's inside that barrel.
Is he dead?!
That barrel is secured with barriers.
I can't see through it.
I wouldn't think that the guys
who wanted Sasuke
would kill him that easily.
You might be right about that.
What's this?
I poked the bush for kicks
and out come not even a snake,
just two little bugs.
Hey, wait a minute! Wait!
We didn't come here to fight.
We just came here to negotiate!
Huh, then...
What are they?!
There's no point
to that smoke bomb.
You can't run away from me.
It's a nearly invisible string,
thinner and stronger than wire.
I've placed my string all over this area.
Damn.
Those two types of wires
on the trap were on purpose...
It was actually a triple trap.
Damn.
Didn't think they had someone with
that kind of ability in their group...
You will be...!
What's going on...? My body...
Nice! Kiba, Shikamaru!
Shadow Possession Jutsu succeeded!
But... so they have someone with
this kind of ability too.
Thanks for getting caught so nicely
in my strategy.
Damn... But...
I have this kind of ability, too.
Where did it come from?
Earth Style Barrier:
Earth Dome Prison!
These guys are mine.
I need to feed to recover my strength.
Once you're done eating,
catch up with us,
we're going ahead.
Come quickly.
Let us out! You!
Be quiet, Naruto!
Fang Over Fang!
The wall is repairing itself...
Hey...
I saw that.
Let us out!
Byakugan!
Th-This is...
What is it? What's happening?
This is bad.
Our chakra's getting sucked out...
Damn... I didn't expect them
to just keep us in this barrier,
but I never predicted
they would drain our chakra either.
Man. How dare they!
Let us out of here already!
I feel like my body energy
is being sucked out.
Shikamaru, it won't be good if
we stay in here like this.
It was careless to get caught
before we even figured out
our enemy's powers.
On top of all that... inside here.
Damn! I'm going to make a hole
before all my chakra is gone!
Akamaru!
The food pills!
Ninja Art: Human Beast Mimicry
And for me,
Ninja Art: Beast Human Mimicry
Fang Over Fang!
All right! Good going, Kiba.
It's useless...
Damn! It starts to repair itself
the moment it's hit.
Same with the ground.
At this rate, we won't last
another ten minutes.
We'll lose all our chakra
and be totally annihilated...
I can't use the Rasengan, it
requires extremely difficult chakra control
especially in a place like this
that's draining our chakra.
Hey, I want you to listen to me!
I want to talk to your leader.
We won't go after Sasuke anymore,
so let us out of here!
Hey...
Shikamaru, what are you saying?
Pleading for your life,
how interesting...
But you guys are my prey,
I can't let you out.
Then... just let me out by myself.
This battle...
is such a drag.
You! Do you know
what you're saying?
Shut up, Kiba. Just be quiet.
What?!
A split in the group, huh?
Seems like you're the leader, but...
I didn't think you would be
the only one begging for your life!
You really see a human's true nature
when they're pushed to the edge of death.
You're such a lowlife.
You're not qualified to be responsible
for the lives of your squad members.
To abandon Sasuke and
even betray your own squad...
Is that what it means
to be a Chunin of the Leaf?
Someone like you deserves to die...
I won't let you out.
Shikamaru! I believed in you,
but now I've lost confidence in you!
Let's take this outside!
Hey, we can't get out!
You fool!
That's why we're in this situation!
What do you mean by "fool"?
I'm just speaking the truth, fool!
Oh! You said "fool" again!
Everybody, be quiet for a second!
Choji?
Neji... I'm sorry, but can you use
the rest of the chakra you have
to observe the wall behind you
and the wall behind Choji?
Understood.
Shikamaru! You be quiet!
Naruto!
You still don't understand?!
Remember what Shikamaru said
when he gathered everyone!
Even I can't just sit back
and slack off.
Because I'm responsible
for your lives.
Choji, don't raise your voice
too much from here.
Kiba, dent that wall
behind Neji and Choji again!
Y-Yeah...
Fang Over Fang!
Huh! No matter how hard you try,
it's useless!
Huh, I see...
It's over there.
Neji...
Mark that spot with the kunai.
Choji, are you ready?!
Okay! Any time!
All right, let's do this.
What's happening?!
As I said earlier,
the wall's surface is infused with chakra.
But even this tough wall could have
an area with a thinner layer of chakra.
That is what Shikamaru speculated.
How... How did you figure all that out?
Think about what happened earlier.
He noticed that
some areas repaired themselves quickly
and others more slowly,
when Kiba and Akamaru attacked the wall.
In other words, he guessed that
the areas that didn't repair quickly
probably have a thinner layer of chakra.
On top of all that,
by cleverly talking to the enemy,
he figured out the position
of the enemy outside the wall.
He guessed that
the wall furthest from the enemy
probably had the thinnest chakra
reinforcement,
so that's what he wanted to confirm.
That's what it is, correct?
I see, in order to trick the enemy,
you must trick your friends first.
I didn't see that there was
such a plan behind that conversation.
I'm depending on you, Choji.
Yeah!
Expansion Jutsu!
All right, let's go!
Human Boulder!
What?!
Choji... You are awesome, after all!
Everybody, you did well...
for some losers.
What?!
Who are you calling losers?!
Once we're out, we'll win this fight!
I will do it!
Wait, you two!
It's dangerous to fight him
head-on right now!
We tore through the barrier!
We can do this!
Earth Style: Sphere of Graves!
He's nuts!
You are the squad leader,
if I'm not mistaken.
You sure do suffer
when you have a stupid leader.
You underlings!
A stupid leader like this...
I'll get rid of him for you!
Expansion Jutsu! Human Boulder!
Thanks! Choji...
Why? Wasting my good intentions...
If the leader is stupid,
then I guess the subordinates are losers.
Well... I'll kill you losers
before you suffer
working under a gloomy shadow-user
like him!
Damn, damn! Babbling on like that!
I will!
He's mine!
I will... take care of him!
Choji...
What are you saying?!
He's not the kind of guy
you can handle on your own!
I will do it!
Choji... you...
Shikamaru...
Take these food pills for everyone...
Choji... Don't tell me you're going to...
That's right.
I have that secret weapon of mine.
But Choji, those are...!
Huh... Losers, I won't let you
have your way!
He's coming!
I'll get rid of you all here!
Go, everyone!
The Tri-Colored Pills?
Those aren't food pills.
What are they?
First... the Green Pill!
Get out of the way! Loser!
Impossible... He stopped me?!
Shikamaru, take everyone and go!
Choji...
What did we form this team for?
If we lose Sasuke,
then we will end up like he said...
The stupid leader and his losers!
You better catch up with us, Choji!
Yeah.
Everybody, go!
All right! Let's go, everyone!
- Yeah!
- Right!
Choji...
I'm going to get rid of you quickly,
and then get rid of those guys too!
It won't be that easy...
What?!
I will...
... stop you!
A parting gift from Choji...
Eat it!
Yeah!
Thanks, Choji...
Kiba!
Thanks!
Shikamaru...
That pill that Choji took earlier...
It seemed like some sort
of trump card,
but does he have a chance to win?
He said that he has a secret weapon.
He brought the Akimichi clan's
ultimate secret pills on this mission...
These are the Tri-Colored Pills:
green, yellow, and red.
If you take them,
you can gain explosive power.
The energy that each pill
contains is enormous!
I see! I see!
So that's why he was so confident!
But... there's always a side effect
to any pills that work too well.
Damn... I didn't think it would hurt
so much with just the Green Pill.
I hope that Choji can settle it
with just the Green Pill.
Don't take the red one,
no matter what, Choji.
I'm going to finish you off at once!
Expansion Jutsu!
Spiky Human Boulder!
He raised the rotational
and destructive power
by using the kunai as spikes.
Earth Style: Terra Shield!
What?!
Don't get carried away, loser!
Slamming Palm!
Did you know?
When there's a group of, say, five people,
there's always one loser.
That person is always made fun of...
and when it comes down to it,
they'll just toss that person
aside like a pawn.
I'm talking about you!
Choji. All you do is eat.
You should train sometimes, at least!
You get teased because you're like that.
You're just a fa—
You said somebody exceptional, right?
Shouldn't we ask Shino or somebody?!
That is true...
No matter how hard I try on my own...
I...
Seems like I hit it right on the nose.
Seems like the Leaf is lacking in people,
seeing that they picked a loser
like you for the pursuit team.
But...
Choji and I have worked as a team
for many years,
so coordinating with him
is easiest for me.
But Shikamaru...
But, if we fight against each other,
you might be stronger.
I might have given up fighting
against you too.
And you're you...
But...
Shikamaru... has always...
Shikamaru has always
believed in me...
Choji... are you ready?!
He believed that I was really strong!
That's why he entrusted this to me alone!
Oh? Pretty impressive chakra.
But... it's a far cry
from being a main dish...
Let's go, fatso!
Don't YOU say that!
Partial Expansion Jutsu:
Arm!
Leg!
Partial Expansion Jutsu:
Arm!
Don't mess with me! Scum!
Eat this!
What?!
Super Expansion Jutsu!
I did it... Shikamaru...
What?!
I can't believe I had to go to
State 2
for an opponent like this one...
Slamming Palm
What... What is that appearance?!
Now that it's come to this, it's over.
In State 2, I can put out ten times
more power than before.
I'm invincible.
It's too painful to move...
Who knew that the side effects
of the Yellow Pill would be this intense.
This is what happens...
to powerless scum for butting in!
Go back to just playing ninja!
Because he... promised...
He's definitely going to defeat
the opponent and come after us!
Yep!
That's right... he can do it.
Okay! While I'm here...
Me too...
All right, everyone,
we get Sasuke back
before Choji catches up!
Wait!
All right! Here we come!
He's late... that Jirobo...
He's greedy and eats so much...
He's probably squeezing out chakra
even from the marrow of their bones.
I wish he had switched
with me already...
I need a lot of chakra
for State 2.
I'll take whatever chakra
you have left!
Well then, I'll take it now.
There's not much left...
You're empty!
I haven't had nearly enough to eat...
I said I haven't had enough to eat!
Huh?
What, just one last piece, huh...
When I said I haven't had
enough to eat...
Just as I thought, you're the scum
used as a sacrificial pawn.
Die... you pitiful fatso,
you're just the leftover.
I won't let you play ninja with us!
Why?
Because if we let you play,
we'll lose.
You're slow.
Yeah, but... then the number
of people won't be even.
Japanese chess is fun
because the number of pieces are even.
A useless piece is the same
as not having one at all!
Yeah, that's right!
We're the ones with fewer players,
and we're not complaining.
Hurry up, let's do it!
If it's okay with you, then it's fine...
Okay, it's settled!
We can win it!
Yes!
Where are we going to hide this time?
And um, the whole Akimichi Clan
is fat and slow...
That's what everyone says.
Really...
But Choji, you have a kinder heart
than anyone I know.
One day, you'll surely make friends
who'll see that quality of yours.
And then you should cherish
those friends
and become a friend they can trust,
just as much as you trust them.
Oh! You...
You... were there just now...
What about playing ninja?
It was a drag, so I left.
Huh?
By the way, that's my special seat.
Your special seat?
I like to lie on my back and
look at the clouds on a nice day like this.
You've come to look at clouds?
Mind if I sit there?
Oh... sure!
This is a good place.
You can see the clouds well.
Yeah...
Why don't you...?
What?
Watch the clouds with me
and lounge around?
Okay!
You know! I brought snacks.
Want some?
Oh, that'd be great!
Thanks.
Eating potato chips
while watching clouds... this is the best.
Yep!
My name is Shikamaru...
from the Nara Clan.
You... What's your name?
It's Choji! Choji Akimichi
of the Akimichi Clan!
Choji, huh...
I think I'll get along with you.
Me, too!
Shikamaru... Sorry... I can't go...
It's over...
But, this guy...
I have to beat him...
even if it means death.
No matter what you do now,
it's too late!
Slamming Palm!
Wh-What's that...?
But...
Boulder Slam!
It's no good!
I'm 100 times stronger than before!
They say that food
can be a reason
for people to hold a horrible grudge
against someone.
The blow just now...
was for eating my last chip...
No way!
This guy has so much chakra that
his body has changed physically!
And this is...
for making fun of me by calling me
a sacrificial pawn and fat!
But what I can't forgive you for
more than anything else...
You insulted my best friend!
More than mocking me
by calling me fat,
and for stealing the last chip
out of the bag...
I can't forgive you for that!
All of my chakra... to my left hand!
This is bad!
This blow... is heavier than my life!
W-Wait! Don't be hasty!
I... I won.
Me... I won!
Everyone...
Dad...
I've made... a lot of friends...
What's wrong?
It's close.
That's strange.
There hasn't been even
one trap set for a while...
Shikamaru, what do you think?
We're being underestimated.
They think the only one
following them is that big guy.
They don't need to set
traps for one of their own.
How dare they underestimate us!
It seems you're right.
We are being
completely underestimated.
However, this is our chance.
Yeah... We'll take them by surprise.
That Jirobo is late.
No, he's already here.
Aw, c'mon, what took you so long?
Sorry.
It took time to eat those scum's chakra.
Hey fatso, don't drag your feet!
Hurry up and carry that coffin...
That's your job, you foul-mouthed woman.
I know.
What, Jirobo...
You're awfully easygoing today.
What do you mean?
I'm just saying I'm not handing you
the coffin.
Because you're not Jirobo!
This time let me do it.
Sakon, Tayuya, you guys go ahead!
Jirobo always corrects
Tayuya's choice of words.
Heh, I see.
Ninja Art: Spider Web Net
You!
Ninja Art: Spiral Spider Web
Fang Over Fang!
I won't let you get away!
That's my line.
Look at your feet.
You!
It's way too early to think you've got us
trapped with something like this!
Shut up!
Got it.
- Neji!
- What?!
Me, Naruto, Kiba and Neji...
Even though we've followed the plan,
it's no good.
I'm going to cocoon you.
Damn!
Damn it! Damn it!
What's with this thread?! It won't cut.
It's useless.
My thread is so strong that
even if two elephants pulled at it,
it wouldn't break.
Shadow Clone... Interesting.
This thread is sticky...
This stickiness is probably made
by mixing chakra with
his special body fluid.
Moreover, this strength. Even after
it's been released from his hands...
chakra's continuously flowing
in the thread.
It's impossible...
The level of this jutsu is incredible.
Calm down... Just calm down...
My chakra...
Ninja Art: Spider Sticky Gold
It's a different color than
the thread from before.
What's he going to do?
It's quickly solidifying, huh...
You are the first one,
so it's like a little entertainment.
Now I'll play a game to see
which of you is the real one.
What did you say?!
First is... you at the end.
What a lucky guy.
Next, I'll take two at once.
The odds are now two to one.
This guy's really lucky,
but it's one of these two now!
Turns out he made it to the last.
Well, it was fun as a game,
but now the game's over.
Die!
The first one is done.
What?!
I see, the real body made
its shadow clones get caught,
and hid himself and
waited for a chance, huh.
For a grunt like him to come up with
such a plan in this situation...
You're not too bad... but...
You're at the end of the line. Die!
What?!
Naruto, the time you bought was helpful.
Neji!
You... How...?!
Chakra-based substances...
are meaningless against Gentle Fist
which destroys by injecting
chakra directly.
That guy's jutsu...
Evidently I'm the only one
who can fight it.
Go!
I'll take care of this.
The reason we're doing this
is because of the mission
to bring back Sasuke.
But that's not all.
What we are after and trying
to protect is the bond
of the shinobi of
the Hidden Leaf Village.
Look, Sasuke is heading
towards Orochimaru.
We can't let Orochimaru get
his hands on someone from our village.
Absolutely not.
And...
Naruto...
Your eyes are better than mine.
Right now, Sasuke is...
in the darkness.
Hurry up and go!
I'll catch up with you!
Mmh!
Okay! Let's go!
You and Choji,
make sure to catch up!
Yeah...
Heh... think I'll let them get away?!
Byakugan!
This guy's pretty good...
Neji!
That's Neji all right!
Well, that's fine.
It seems you're the strongest
out of the lot.
For starters, I'll play with you...
and kill you in three minutes.
I got you.
You're pretty good at handling chakra
and you've got sharp eyes.
You release chakra from
the chakra points in your hands
like a sharp needle.
You see the weak points in the thread
where chakra flows, and attack them.
I see, I've heard from Lord Orochimaru...
This is the Gentle Fist, isn't it?
But if you can't use
those annoying hands,
they can't cut my threads either.
Man, games. The instant you know
the rules of engagement,
they're no longer interesting.
It's only been a minute,
but I'm already tired of you.
Die!
Ninja Art: Spider Sticky Gold
What?!
How did he...?!
I'll explain, especially for you.
It's not just my hands
I can release chakra from
all the chakra points on my body.
And it's game over.
Gentle Fist: 8 Trigrams, 64 Palms!
Uh oh!
2 Palms!
4 Palms!
8 Palms!
16 Palms!
32 Palms!
64 Palms!
What's going on?!
A golden surface on his body...?
It's the same material as the weapon
he spit out of his mouth earlier...
That was close.
I hear that if you're hit straight on
with Gentle Fist,
your chakra network gets damaged
and you become unable
to build up chakra...
That was close.
Are you a monster?
It seems to come
not just from your mouth.
Gum Style Spider Thread...
is a metal that hardens
the instant it leaves my body.
Moreover, it doesn't let chakra through.
And... it can be secreted
not just from my mouth,
but also from the sweat glands
throughout my body.
Attacks on chakra points won't work.
Now it makes sense...
The Spider Web Net won't work
on him up close.
And there'll be no close range
combat against the Gentle Fist.
In other words,
I just have to attack the blind side
from long distance.
The kunai is a fake!
8 Trigrams, Palm...
Rotation!
Wha—?! What is that?!
Does he... have eyes behind him?!
And the defense just now...
He repelled physical attacks
with chakra?!
Can he see me?!
What the hell is he?!
I know you're there.
Come out.
Those eyes...
It seems they can do more
than just see chakra flow...
So he's an extraordinary
visual jutsu user...
A long range battle
is unfavorable...
I must bring this to
close combat by all means.
Very well.
I'll acknowledge that this game has
a somewhat high level of difficulty!
I'm going to get serious now.
It's like he's a totally different person
from before...
His chakra activity is overwhelming.
And those markings...
His move earlier...
He dodged an attack aimed
from behind
and was able to see me hiding
in the shadows.
In other words,
he has a combined wide range
of sight and X-ray vision.
And what's more, that jutsu...
If so...
Summoning Jutsu!
If he defends
against physical attacks
with a large emission
of chakra and its Rotation...
all I need to do then is to stop
that chakra Rotation!
Scatter!
Rotation!
It's starting to stop.
Here!
Die!
He released chakra just in time
and repelled the kunai!
To think he'd stop my chakra Rotation
by binding it with chakra threads...
These things...
I just have to cut them for now.
If the Rotation doesn't work,
then I'll just have to dodge
them all.
This guy uses
close range taijutsu style combat.
There will be no problem
if I fight him from afar.
In that way...
I'll have a good long look at your ability.
8 Trigrams, 64 Palms!
What a number!
Hm?! His stance changed?!
8 Trigrams,
128 Palms!
He's fast!
The number of strikes has doubled...!
If I get nailed by that straight on,
it'll be the end for me.
If that's the case on his end,
then it'll be a battle of numbers
on this end, too!
The number's too great!
I won't have enough time!
The Rotation's no good,
just as I thought...
It seems he has 360 degree vision.
And it seems he deals
with enemy attacks
by combining his X-ray vision ability
for seeing through things
and his telescopic vision ability
for long distance sight.
Furthermore, although
he's got 360 degree vision,
that vision has a formidable extent...
If I were to determine the range
from his reaction before...
he almost unfailingly detected
the kunai
that entered the 50-meter radius
around him.
But for some reason,
there are kunai
he can't evade completely.
If so...
8 Trigrams, Sixty...
I see...
This time, there'll be even more.
This time, two will hit...
I've found the perfect way
to counter your ability!
It seems that defense technique
was something to compensate
for this weak point!
In other words...
Your visual jutsu isn't perfect!
Why even bother?!
I've won the game!
You can't beat me!
This is the end...
Gentle Fist!
Small fry number one...
Annihilation complete.
Well, for a crummy game,
I was entertained...
Heh... I missed the fatal spot?
I suppose he wouldn't die so easily
from a kunai at 50 meters.
I see...
He's still going to entertain me, huh?
Here's my thanks for that.
Maximum destructive power...
with 100% accuracy!
Die!
Heh! It's over...
What?!
Just barely...
That was a close one.
But... I was able to throw it off
just a little.
There's no mistake.
He's now realized the secret
of the Byakugan.
What's the meaning of this?
How?!
How was he able to throw it
that far off from his vital point?!
I see... That chakra!
He was emitting chakra
the whole time
and covered the area surrounding him!
And over such a wide range, too.
No wonder he was able
to detect the arrow and
throw off the trajectory of it.
But constantly emitting that
much chakra is a desperate gamble...
If he doesn't go that far,
he can't dodge.
In other words, there's no mistake.
It's as I hypothesized...
The arrow earlier was
totally invisible to him!
He doesn't carry out useless attacks...
And from the results,
he accurately examines the information.
And... he's also discovered
the weakness of my eyes...
Impressive.
Of all the enemies
I've fought until now,
this guy's the strongest!
Right behind his first thoracic vertebra...
there exists a blind spot expanding
from a very small point.
Indeed, if he moves and fails
to stabilize the blind spot,
aiming an arrow at it
becomes difficult.
But such a trick... doesn't fool me!
Gentle Fist is pointless if
you don't come close to your enemy.
And you can't afford to think about
approaching me at this point.
It's about how to escape now...
Though whether you struggle or not,
you're going to die anyway.
It's useless!
A thread?!
I see, with this thread...
This time, the trajectory was thrown off
slightly by the trees, huh?
If that's the case...
I'll add some rotation this time.
So even if it hits a tree,
it'll just cut through and the trajectory
won't be thrown off.
And as before...
I'll control the arrow up until
150 feet away from him
using a thread with chakra
flowing through.
I'll take aim at the moving target...
and plunge the arrow into
the blind spot with a pinpoint attack!
He's still standing up?
He's strong...
He's much stronger than me.
I hardly have any chakra left now.
I probably won't be able to evade
his next attack completely.
Is this it?
I'll win no matter what!
Naruto... I wonder what you'd do.
He's stopped moving...
Has he given up?
But just to make doubly sure...
Maximum destructive power
with 120% accuracy.
I've got him!
This is it.
Gentle Fist!
Wh-What? He still...?!
No! My attack just now
should have killed him.
Chakra-based substances...
are meaningless against Gentle Fist.
Gentle Fist...
I see...
In his final moments he funneled
the last of his chakra through the thread!
Eight crows...
Again I couldn't see one of them.
He damaged several of
my internal organs.
But... I can still move.
You're not a failure.
Naruto...
Now it's just the three of us...
Don't worry about such things.
Both Choji and Neji will
catch up right away.
Choji had the trump card.
And I fought Neji
in the Chunin Exam, so I know...
Know what?
That he's... a true genius. Believe it!
I cannot lose...
Whether he's an enemy
much stronger than me...
or even if this body should fail me...
I cannot lose!
I have a reason why I cannot lose!
I've had a hard time of it this time.
I played too long...
Huh?
I can't build up chakra...
How? You should've
been instantly killed!
How come you're alive?!
I couldn't completely
evade it anyway.
So I was prepared to deliberately
take the hit.
So you took the hit deliberately...?
It doesn't change the fact
that you're going to die here.
How can you go that far?!
Of all the enemies,
you're the strongest I've ever fought...
But, there's a reason why I cannot lose.
Of all those I've ever fought,
the strongest one said this to me...
- Unlike me... you are not a failure.
- "Unlike me... you are not a failure."
He said that.
I've been called a genius all along.
So I cannot lose.
And for the sake of those guys
who believe
that someone like me is a genius!
Even if you act tough,
you can't stop what's happening...
Sasuke ran to the Hidden Sound Village
of his own free will.
No...
There's a person who can find him
in the darkness and save him.
Sasuke belongs to Lord Orochimaru.
No matter who it may be,
they can't save...
He can save him!
Because... Naruto...
You saved me from the darkness!
Talking rubbish until the end...
But...
I haven't been pushed this far
since Kimimaro.
Damn it...