Oh, another shooting star!
Did you make a wish this time?
Oh, I forgot.
What do you mean,
"going out now"?
Well, the guys are getting together.
I have to go out sometimes!
"Sometimes"?
It's been every night lately!
I'll be sure to come home early.
Thank you!
Thanks, I'll come again!
Hey! Watch where you're walking.
Why don't we just do
Rock-Paper-Scissors again tonight?
Not that again!
Think of something more exciting!
And you call yourself my rival?
We have an early start tomorrow,
so let's skip it tonight.
Don't use a mission
as an excuse!
I've got all this pent-up energy
inside me!
Now is the time for diligent training!
True discipline and hard work
is what leads to success on missions!
Are you listening to me?!
Hey Guy...
Do you sense anything weird?
There's a chill in the air.
That's because of your
unenthusiastic attitude!
We're only young once!
There's a full moon out tonight, Sasuke.
What...?
What is this sensation?
There, there...
Don't cry, Sasuke.
No matter what happens, your big brother
will always protect you...
It can't be...
– What happened?
– Is it an accident?
That's...!
N-No way!
The Nine-Tails!
– Run!
– It's the Nine-Tails!
– Help!
– We're done for!
It's okay. There, there!
It's the Nine-Tails!
The Demon Fox is loose!
What's going on?!
Just run, you idiot!
Sasuke!
It's okay.
You got a little scared, huh?
Lord Third Hokage!
The Nine-Tails is...!
The Nine-Tails suddenly
appeared in the village!
I know. I'll deal with it.
You and the others protect
the civilians!
Yes sir!
Has Kushina's seal broken?
Despite all the precautions,
did we fail?
Biwako...
Damn you, Nine-Tails!
This is the moment
I release my pent-up power!
Don't be hasty, Guy!
Come on! I'll be your opponent!
– Wait!
– Huh?
Gather immediately in the guardroom!
Why?
It's the Third Hokage's orders!
Lord Hiruzen?
You heard. Let's go, Guy!
Now's our chance!
Evacuate the civilians!
Are we ready?
Yes!
Over here, Nine-Tails!
Where are you looking?!
Over here.
Do not falter!
Even if we can't defeat the Nine-Tails,
we must concentrate on
evacuating the villagers!
Do not take action on your own!
Assemble before Lord Hiruzen!
Carry out the orders!
As Hokage,
I will protect the village...
my family...
I must do it now.
– Run!
– Help!
Iruka, are you all right?
Mom!
Dad! Mom's...!
Why didn't you stay
at the shelter?
I'll take care of Mom,
so hurry up and get out of here!
No, I won't!
I won't leave you
and Mom behind and run away!
I'll protect Mom!
Don't get ahead of yourself,
you're just a kid!
It's a parent's duty to
protect their children!
You must avoid damage
to the village!
Chase the Nine-Tails
outside the village walls!
Yes sir!
Buy me time
to prepare my jutsu!
Do not slow down the attack!
Right! Let's go!
Ninja Art: Summoning!
Come forth... Monkey King Enma!
The Nine-Tails, huh.
So the seal was broken?
We'll chase it out of the village
with the Adamantine Staff!
Got it!
Transform!
Let's go, Enma!
Right!
Extend!
I've chased it out of the village.
Don't let up! Keep the pressure on him!
Keep him occupied until
the Fourth Hokage arrives!
Iruka...
Let go of me!
My dad and my mom are...
still fighting!
The barrier has disappeared!
Lord Fourth!
Lady Kushina!
Take her to the Leaf Village Hospital
immediately!
Summon the Medical Ninja!
Lord Third...
Kushina...!
Please take care...
of our child.
Of course, you don't need to worry.
His name is...
Naruto...
Minato and I...
picked it from...
Jiraiya-sensei's novel...
Naruto, is it? A fine name.
I'll take full responsibility.
So, for the child's sake,
you must rest!
Kushina! I promise...
Wha—?!
What is this?!
How terrible!
Who did this?!
Naruto Uzumaki has arrived!
I'm going to be Hokage,
believe it!
Hey!
Come back!
You won't get away with this!
Damn it!
It was him again!
He's made a big mess.
Even if we want to file a complaint,
he has no parents
to complain to!
What will we do?
Who's going to pay for all this damage?
Who do we complain to?
Was it him again?
Yes, the one
we're not allowed to speak of.
What a nuisance.
– He's so unpleasant.
– Tell me about it.
He's such a pain.
I'm leaving!
You forgot something!
Oops! What'd you make us
for lunch?
Did you put in omelets?
Yes, I put in lots.
– Yes!
Be careful now!
– Okay!
Can I come in?
This is for this month's living expenses.
Spend it wisely now.
Hey...
Hmm?
Why don't I have a mom and dad?
Didn't I tell you before?
Although it was
quite some time ago...
That's not what I want to hear!
You're talking about
when that beast called
the Nine-Tailed Demon Fox
went on a rampage, right?
And that a lot of people
in the village were killed,
including my mom and dad...
Well, that's not
what I'm asking about!
I just want to know...
Who were my parents?
What kind of people were they?
There's no use asking about that.
It won't bring the dead back.
I hear it's true.
That boy, huh?
Look, isn't that the boy?
He gives me the creeps.
Hey, don't play with him.
You don't know what he'll do.
Is that right?
Man, that looks good!
Pops, one order of fried rice
and dumplings!
Got it! Coming right up!
Dumplings for me!
Gotcha!
What a weird kid.
He's the kid...
Did you hear the rumor that
the Fourth Hokage died because of him?
Oh...
I'm home...
Oww...
Oh!
Wow!
Seconds please, Mom!
Of course.
Big Brother said
you're going somewhere.
When is that?
Yes...
We're going to visit
your mother's family.
Oh...
So he told you, did he?
I thought we'd go
on my next day off.
Would you like to come?
Big Brother's going to
teach me all kinds of stuff.
He said... he'd teach you?
Yeah! He promised.
Itachi did?
That's unusual!
Here's your rice!
– Oh, can I trouble you for some tea?
– Sure!
Here, Gramps, eat this.
Oh, thank you.
Oh, this looks so good.
Well, I caught it.
So of course
it's going to taste good!
Is that so?
H-Hot!
Look at those stars.
Each one of those stars
is like our world's sun.
What do you think?
So many of them... Incredible, isn't it?
The sun? That giant thing that
shines in the sky during the day?
Yes. This world is boundless.
Yeah? You sure know a lot, Gramps!
Compared to the vastness of the world,
man's existence is very insignificant.
Compared to that, the worries
of us humans are so trivial.
No kidding. The world is big, huh.
It goes on and on...
Want some mushroom soup, Gramps?
Are you sure
you can spare me some?
Sure! You tell great stories, Gramps!
I see!
Are you sure these mushrooms
are safe?
We won't know until we eat 'em!
Now you try it, just like that.
You've improved, Sasuke!
I can throw better than Mom now.
All right, then how about this?
Huh?
You're amazing, Big Brother!
How did you do that?
You'll start throwing
like that very soon.
You're a lot like me.
Big Brother... Can you teach me
again sometime, like today?
Sure, when I have the time.
Promise?
Yeah.
Do you know how
the Uchiha Clan came about?
What?
I haven't really learned about it
in depth yet.
The Uchiha crest is the symbol
and proof of our prestigious clan.
An image of a fan... is prestigious?
You need wind
to start a fire, right?
You produce wind with a fan.
Is that... a great thing?
Well, you'll understand in time.
Big Brother...
Do you fight for
the sake of the clan?
I wonder...
I'm not sure
about that either just yet.
All right!
I'm going to make us a feast tonight!
Ouch! Hot!
You made all of this?
Yeah...
Maybe I went a little overboard.
A little, huh?
I'm stuffed!
Hey, Sasuke...
Want to sleep outside tonight?
Are you sure it's okay to do that?
Hey, don't rush!
Oww!
Are you cold?
Nope... It feels great.
I want to become
a skilled shinobi like you,
and win Father's approval.
What? Like me?
You will surpass me.
Impossible.
No way. I mean, you're gifted.
Everyone says so.
You're a lot like me.
You've got the potential.
Okay then, I'll surpass you!
Sasuke...
Sasuke?
Hey, Sakura.
Sakura, aren't those bangs
getting in your way?
You should just cut them!
Oh, don't start, dear!
Girls have their reasons...
If you say things like that,
Sakura will start hating you!
Oh... You like flowers?
Who's there?
Oh, it's you, Ino.
You like cosmos?
Oh...
Uh...
Yeah.
Take a look!
Ta-dah!
Oh, it's so pretty!
Isn't it?
I'll tie your hair up with this.
Huh? My hair?
You're cute, Sakura, so...
There!
This is way better!
But...
my forehead is...
"Billboard Brow"...
People tease you
because you try to cover it up.
Just show it off.
Then the people around you
will change.
But Ino, you're so strong...
Well, I think this is much better.
You've got good style...
I think you should
have more confidence...
I...
I made a friend.
Her name's Ino Yamanaka,
and she's cute, strong,
fashionable, and kind...
I see.
You made a friend, Sakura?
If she's cute,
I'd like to meet her too.
Oh, dear...
What are you saying!
I'm happy for you, Sakura.
You must cherish your friends.
Friends are precious
assets in life.
Okay!
Ino gave me this ribbon.
It looks great on you.
You're as cute as Mom was
when she was young.
Oh dear... You said I'm cute?
Sakura... while you're at it,
you should find a boyfriend.
Come on, Dad!
Wow... That's amazing.
You did this all by yourself?
It's nothing at all!
I'm not creative like you.
See this cosmos?
To bring out its beauty,
the things around it
should complement it,
so that they don't clash.
All right...
I'm going to rearrange them a bit.
Umm, I'll do this...
And do this...
You know...
... there's a boy I like.
Really? I didn't know.
Who is it?
Is that why you've been
more cheerful lately?
Okay, all done!
Not really...
but Sasuke...
I see...
It's Sasuke?
I heard Sasuke likes girls
with long hair.
So I was...
Oh, sorry.
I just remembered something.
I'll come again later.
Huh? Ino...
Thank you for today.
All right, that will do for today.
No, Father...
I can still continue!
Neji...
You mustn't push yourself too hard.
But considering your age,
you've certainly gotten strong.
Father...
Thank you for sparring with me.
Oh, Father...
I've heard that your older brother
has a child about my age.
Yes... A girl, one year younger than you.
A girl...
We will be going to a celebration
tomorrow for her third birthday.
I wonder what she's like...
Father, it's snowing!
The first snow...
It's going to turn into
a heavy snowfall.
Lady Hinata...
Congratulations
on your third birthday.
Lady Hinata...
is a cute child.
Neji...
It is your destiny to protect her,
and to protect
the Hyuga bloodline.
The Hyuga... bloodline?
Father!
Neji is very strong.
When we were young...
Neji exists to protect Lady Hinata.
That is the Hyuga destiny.
All right, that will do for today.
Neji, you are strong indeed.
Hinata, you still have a ways to go.
No, my father's daily lessons are...
I... don't like...
to practice taijutsu.
What are you saying?
You are the heir of the Hyuga clan.
You must be more positive
and confident.
I wish I could switch places with you,
Big Brother Neji...
You are very strong, after all.
No, you must never say
such a thing.
I will make you strong!
When you are in danger,
I will give my life to protect you!
Big Brother Neji!
Lady Hinata, it's snowing!
I had a snowball fight with my father
this morning, and I hit him twice!
Um... um...
Of those three symbols, the one on the
right belongs to the Akimichi Clan, right?
The rest are, um...
The one in the middle
signifies the Nara Clan.
The one on the left
is the Yamanaka Clan.
Three clans that use
highly unusual Secret Jutsu.
We've been combining our
powers for many generations
and our three clans share
a special relationship.
To strengthen unity
and protect our clans,
the esteemed Sarutobi Clan bestows
ear piercings upon all three of our clans.
Generation upon generation has sworn
an oath of loyalty on these earrings.
This is it, right?
The other clan heads wear one too.
Piercing your ear must hurt, though.
The ear is pierced so that
the message goes deep down.
So that one never forgets the oath.
In time, you will also pierce your ear.
What?! Why?
When a child becomes a Genin,
it is customary for the parent to
pass on his earring to the child
until he attains Chunin rank.
It's a ritual to teach one's child
about weight of those oaths!
I don't like pain...
Hizashi!
He's only four...
It's such a pity...
Big Brother Neji...
What are you doing?!
What are you doing here?
If you keep crying,
how am I supposed to find out?
I... I...
Where's your house?
Oh well, come on.
Let's go.
You live in a big house like this,
and you're crying?
Even though I'm all alone, I'd never cry!
Never!
Later!
Hinata!
You are the precious heir
to the Head Family!
What do you think you're doing?!
I...
For your sake, and for the sake
of the Head Family,
many people have made
the ultimate sacrifice.
It's about time you learned
about these things...
Here I go!
Bombs away!
Bull's eye!
Red-Nosed Hokage, complete!
He is incorrigible.
Lord Third,
please let me think about this.
About becoming
Naruto's homeroom teacher.
As you can see, Iruka,
everyone is troubled by
Naruto's mischief.
And his pranks are
getting worse each day.
No one wants to take him.
I believe a teacher's job is
to enhance a student's virtues.
If Naruto does not graduate
from the Academy,
he will not be able to
become a ninja.
He will remain an outcast in
this village for the rest of his life.
Just a minute... I'm sure there's
someone else better suited for Naruto.
If Naruto cannot get a teacher,
then I have no choice
but to have him leave
the Academy.
Don't let it bother you.
No one can blame you.
And even if that happens,
it certainly isn't your fault.
Please wait.
What? Then you'll accept?
Uh... Err... Yes.
Oh... Is that so?
This is a lifesaver for Naruto.
Keep wiping until every speck
of graffiti is gone!
Oh look... It's that thing.
Why do we let that boy
stay in this village?
I wish Lord Hokage would have
more consideration for us.
Shut up!
Hey! Come back!
I'm not "that thing"!
I'm Naruto Uzumaki!
I'm going to be Hokage someday!
It's just a dream...
That's right!
I'm supposed to get
a new homeroom teacher today.
The first impression is important.
I should give him a proper greeting.
- 'Morning!
- Hi!
Who did this?!
Of all the mischief...
Gotcha! Gotcha!
The eraser was just a decoy.
Naruto!
I know, I know.
I'll go stand in the hallway.
No, go and take your seat.
Huh?
What a letdown.
I was looking forward to
seeing Naruto get yelled at.
Sheesh! How boring...
'Morning!
First, let me introduce myself!
I'll be your homeroom teacher
starting today.
I'm Iruka Umino.
My favorite food is Ichiraku Ramen.
My least favorite food
is mixed rice.
My birthday is May 26th.
My hobbies include
going to the hot springs...
Therefore, one's chakra
is greatly influenced
by their mental energy.
Huh?
Sensei... Class time is over.
See? Look.
Oh, it's that time already.
Well then, that's all for today.
How's that for Naruto's third prank?
See!
Owww...
You found out already?
Return to your seat.
Let's continue the lesson.
Okay then...
Instead of self-introductions,
I want each of you to demonstrate
your ninjutsu skill!
You're not going to be graded.
This is just so I can assess how
to proceed with our lessons.
So... We'll do a basic jutsu:
the Clone Jutsu.
Umm... First up is Sasuke Uchiha.
- Go ahead and try it.
- Sasuke!
Clone Jutsu is child's play.
You always act so smug!
Shut up, idiot.
Don't interrupt Sasuke's focus!
That's right! You're in the way!
Not you too, Sakura.
Okay, Sasuke. Try it.
Clone Jutsu!
Hmm...
Amazing!
That was a perfect Clone Jutsu.
I can't tell which one is real.
It's so obvious to me!
This one!
Wrong.
H-Huh?!
- Stupid! Hey, that's the real one.
- What are you doing?!
Wrong again.
Sasuke!
Amazing, two clones in an instant
while the real one moved elsewhere.
Humph! I can do Clone Jutsu too!
Clone Jutsu!
This guy's such an idiot!
Damn it...
I don't know what your problem is,
but stop lunging at me.
He's right.
I say that because every time
you do something,
you hold up our lesson.
And that is an annoyance.
What?!
Yeah, you're an annoyance!
You're a germ just for being alive!
That's cruel, Hibachi.
But he's right!
What?!
Everyone! Quit making fun of Naruto!
Sensei!
Don't bother... with this kid.
Huh?
C'mon, everyone.
Let's continue our lesson.
- Okay.
- Let's go.
- I'm going to do my best.
Big Sister Hinata!
I've been waiting for you!
Let's play ninja!
I'm sorry, Hanabi.
I can't right now.
Huh? Come on,
just for a little while!
That will not do, Lady Hanabi.
Lady Hinata must train
with Lord Hiashi.
I will play with you.
Please be on your way.
I'll see you later, Hanabi.
No, no! Big Sister!
It's so boring...
It can't be helped.
Her ladyship is the heir
of the Head Family.
But just a little can't hurt...
We Hyuga are an illustrious clan
within the Hidden Leaf,
who possess the Byakugan,
the most renowned of all Kekkei Genkai.
As the leader of the clan,
there is a mountain of knowledge
that Lady Hinata must learn.
Here you go.
Lady Hanabi!
Now where did she run off to?
I found Big Sister!
I didn't get to play
with Big Sister today...
Big Sister Hinata!
Sorry I'm late.
No problem!
Huh?
Damn it!
I'm going to pulverize him today
for sure...
Y'know!
Damn it! Damn it!
Damn it! Damn it! Damn it!
Oh man! Oh man!
Even Choji?!
Damn it!
Definitely today!
It'll be Naruto Uzumaki
versus Sasuke Uchiha.
Come on, you idiot!
Naruto! Make the proper sign for sparring!
It's part of the etiquette!
Who cares about that!
Hurry up and
let me beat this guy!
I'm finally going to become popular!
What a waste of time...
I'll make it quick,
just like you want.
Hold on, you two!
For crying out loud...
Shinobi hand-to-hand combat
is a traditional training method
passed down through
the generations.
It might be stuffy etiquette,
but here at the Academy
we start with the basics.
It matters!
You always start by showing
your opponent a one-handed sign,
which represents half of the two hands
used when unleashing a jutsu,
and displays your
intention to fight!
This is called the
"Seal of Confrontation".
After the sparring is done
and the victor is decided,
both partners present
the Seal of Confrontation again,
then bring their hands together to form the
"Seal of Reconciliation" as a show of friendship.
This is the etiquette of
hand-to-hand combat.
Are you listening, Naruto?!
This is the second time
I've explained it to you!
Yeah, yeah.
One "yes" is sufficient, you idiot.
I get it.
N-Naru—
Pound him, Sasuke!
Start!
Amazing! He's so cool!
Sasuke, you're terrific!
This guy...
That look in his eyes...
It's the same look that
everyone gives me.
No...
It's stronger than that.
But...
But it's not for me...
He pisses me off!
I'm going to show all of them!
I swear!
Clone Jutsu!
Wha—?
Damn it! Once more!
N-Naruto...
What's the matter, Naruto?
Nothing...
Want some ramen?
No thanks... I got no money.
You can pay me back
when you're rich.
Besides, the grill's still hot.
Really?
Yeah...
All right!
You seem depressed.
Something wrong?
No, it's nothing!
I'm my usual self!
All right. Today, we'll do hands-on
practice of Shuriken Jutsu.
Let's have someone
demonstrate it for us first.
Let's see...
- Me! Me! Me!
- I can do it!
- Leave it to me.
- I'll do it in one try!
- Me! Me! Me!
- I can do it!
Shino, go ahead!
Iruka-sensei,
you chose the wrong person.
The reason is, for all forms of warfare,
the Aburame Clan relies greatly
on the parasitic insects
we house in our bodies.
And the Shuriken Jutsu
is simply not in our...
Okay, enough!
Sasuke, show us the basics.
- Sasuke!
- Do your best! Go for it!
Sheesh! That Sasuke is always
so arrogant!
So how come he's so popular?!
Hmm... Well done, Sasuke.
- All right, Sasuke!
- You're so cool!
Hmph! Show-off! I can do that too!
Then Naruto, you're next.
All right!
I'll show you!
I'll nail this in one shot, and make
everyone acknowledge me.
Go!
Are you kidding me?
Every single one missed!
I was just fooling around!
Sensei! One more time!
Please, just let try one more time!
I'll get serious this time.
No, that's enough.
Okay, who's next?
Hey!
It's that kid again!
That brat!
Damn it, where did he go?!
Over there!
Serves you right!
Did you hear?
The entire Uchiha Clan was wiped out.
Yeah, I know.
I heard my dad talking about it.
He's the only one who survived.
- Let's go!
- Okay!
Hey guys. What are you all doing?
What? Stay away, Naruto.
Why? Why can't I?
Let me play with you guys too.
Why should we?!
There's no way you're coming with us
for tonight's test of courage.
Test of courage?
Ow!
What are you babbling about?
Wow, sounds like fun!
I'm coming too!
We told you, you can't!
Get this!
Don't you dare follow us!
Come on!
Get this! You better not follow us!
Hey, is that the boy?
Yes... That's the one.
You brat!
Huh?
Go away!
Big Sister came yesterday.
She must have been exhausted
from all that training.
Did you thank her properly?
Well... She was already asleep,
so I'll thank her next time!
Yes, please do that.
What's the big idea?!
What are you doing here?!
You're nothing but a pest!
What? I was only...
I was only looking at the masks!
You want this?
You little brat!
You disgust me.
Just take it!
You can have it.
Now get lost!
Hey, Natsu, who is that boy?
Well...
It's as the shopkeeper said.
What?!
Why does everyone look at me like that?
You must never approach him.
You're going to your studies?
Yeah!
I can write my name now.
I even know some kanji!
Actually lots!
Really?
Lady Hinata, you mustn't keep
Lord Hiashi waiting.
Right.
I'll see you later, Hanabi.
Okay!
Training, huh...
Please focus.
You can't go out to play
unless you finish.
Done! Here!
My, my...
So strong... yet so kind.
I want to be like her...
I want to be more like my sister,
even just a little.
Big Brother Neji?
Her sparring partner
doesn't have to be me.
Please let me do my own training.
No, not yet. Continue.
Please, let's continue, Neji.
Understood.
That guy's different today...
What's wrong, Lady Hinata?
This isn't a game.
Hang in there, Big Sister!
That's so...
That was nothing...
And with this, you expect to fulfill
your destiny...
As the leader of the Hyuga Clan?
What?
Argh... My head... My head...!
The fool...
What's... going on?
What was that?
What is she doing
in a place like this...?
Clone Jutsu!
Isn't that the boy...?
Why is Big Sister watching him?
Big Sister?
I'm entering.
Sheesh, you're all wimps.
No one's brave enough
to go all the way in?
Don't say that...
Well then, I'll go.
This is easy.
All I have to do is take that branch.
A fox demon!
Huh? What's going on?!
What?!
Serves them right.
Everyone got scared and ran off.
You better run, Sensei,
or I'll eat you up!
Bad news! The advance team
has been defeated!
What?! Then the advance team
is... wiped out?!
The advance team... All of them?
It can't be true...
My mom and dad...
they wouldn't die!
Huh? What's up, Sensei?
Naruto... Do you realize
what you're doing?
Why? Why?!
Why does everyone, even you,
my teacher...?
Why do you all look at me like that?!
I'm not a pest and I'm not some germ!
I'm... I'm Naruto Uzumaki!
Hey!
Good morning, everyone!
- Good morning!
All right, let me take attendance.
Naruto's not here?
Sakura.
Do you know?
Oh... I didn't notice.
Oh yeah, I don't think
I saw him this morning.
Kiba, have you seen him?
Huh? Nope.
Besides, I have no interest in him.
Right, Akamaru?
Fine then.
Let's begin our class.
But, why?
Lord Hokage is performing
official duties right now.
Why won't the Third Hokage
agree to see me?
That's not our concern.
We have our orders.
No one is permitted to enter.
Hey, hey!
You know, this is my special seat.
I can't concentrate on my reading
when someone's sighing
that loudly next to me.
Oh... I'm sorry. I'll move away now.
No, wait. I was just about to leave.
Be seeing you...
What's wrong?
You look so depressed.
If you feel like talking, I'll listen.
- Kakashi...
- Hmm?
That's your name, right?
Well, I happen to be Naruto's...
you know the one...
I'm Naruto Uzumaki's homeroom teacher.
I see...
But I went to ask
the Third Hokage to relieve me
as his homeroom teacher.
Lord Hokage wouldn't see me.
I just don't know how...
I don't know how to deal with Naruto.
I'm not qualified to teach Naruto!
Perhaps you've forgotten
a basic rule of teaching.
"One cannot open the hearts of
others if one's own heart is closed."
Or perhaps you're trying to forget.
The Nine-Tails sealed inside
of Naruto is responsible
for the death of my parents.
I'm fully aware that Naruto
is not to blame.
But whenever I see him,
I can't help but see
the Nine-Tails sealed inside of him.
I don't think Naruto would
open up to someone like me.
You are the only one
who can open Naruto's heart.
That...
That is your ordeal.
Trial?!
Yes, one that Lord Hokage
has given you.
Just hang in there a little longer,
and you will find the way.
Rise up to his expectations.
See you.
Third Hokage sure made
a bold decision.
Koji! Time to go home!
- Daichi! Dinnertime!
- Okay.
Let's go home, everyone.
Mom!
What are you doing?
I told you not to play with that boy.
Come on, let's go!
Shikamaru, let's go!
Oh, Dad...
Choji's with you?
We'll walk him home. Let's go.
- See you, Naruto.
- Bye.
Y-Yeah.
Dad! Let go of my hand!
What's there to be embarrassed about?
Thank you for the food.
Let me go! My Mom and Dad
are still out there fighting!
Damn it!
Ow...
Who is it... so early in the morning?
What?! Iruka-sensei?!
What's he doing here?!
Naruto!
Naruto! I'm coming in.
This is all he eats?
Thank you for the food.
You're going to stop at
Choji's house, aren't you?
Hurry up and eat, then.
Yeah...
Say Dad? Can I ask you something?
What is it?
Why does everyone avoid Naruto
like he has the plague?
Did he do something wrong?
Shikamaru... How do you feel
about that boy?
H-How do I feel?
Well, I never thought about it.
He's an idiot, but he's a funny guy.
It's not like I want to be his best friend,
but I don't avoid him either.
I see...
Then you should do what
you want to do.
Yeah, I guess so.
I knew I'd find you here.
Hey, Shikamaru.
Can you lend me some money?
Why? Snacks again?
Yeah!
I mean... what else is there
to buy besides snacks?
Aw man, what a drag.
You're one in a million.
What's with your eyes?
So creepy!
Don't look at us!
You're weird.
C'mon, cut it out!
What'd she do to you anyway?!
What? Trying to act like a hero?
Stop bullying someone weaker
than you!
Shut up!
Humph! This is boring!
Let's go, guys.
So boring.
– Let's go.
– Yeah, let's go.
Man, what a drag.
Getting involved in stuff like that.
Instead of butting into
other people's business,
he should polish his skills.
Stupid Naruto.
Don't call him "stupid."
Huh? What?
Naruto is not stupid.
Even you said before, Shikamaru...
You said all shogi pieces
are necessary.
You said that about me.
Huh?! What are you talking about?
You're just mad at me
from earlier
because I wouldn't lend you
any money.
You're wrong.
Naruto is...
Naruto is like you, Shikamaru!
So don't call him "stupid"!
Take it back!
Sheesh!
What a drag!
Then speak in a way
I can understand!
Don't...
Don't order me around!
Hey, hey!
What are you guys doing?!
You're friends, aren't you?
Why are you fighting?!
Hey!
This...
This fatso started it!
It's because you're blind!
I'm not a fatso!
I'm just big-boned!
All right!
Then, let me in on this fight.
Huh...?
– What are you talking about?
Oh! Then I'll use the money
you pay me to buy snacks!
– What?
– Huh?
What did you just say?
I did that...
and then, I went
to the usual spot.
Huh, so that's what happened.
Naruto, want some snacks?
Oh, thank you!
Hey, look!
What? Seriously?
What a drag!
– Nope, nope.
– No girls for me!
– She's after us!
Over here!
You wait!
I can't go any further!
Ino's coming! Keep running!
I can't!
That Ino...
She's terrible when she gets mad!
I swear she's going to end up
an old maid.
See ya later, Naruto.
Your Sexy Jutsu was awesome!
Bye-bye, Naruto!
Hey, hey, Shikamaru.
It's curry night at my house tonight.
That sounds good!
I'm getting tired of
my mom's cooking.
See you tomorrow!
Yeah!
See ya tomorrow!
Hey, Naruto!
Why would you do such a thing?!
You're really going to get it this time!
I don't care!
You know your problem?
You can't do the things I do!
Only I can do this!
I'm better than all of you!
Believe it!
There's a problem, sir!
Lord Hokage!
What is it?
Did that Naruto do something again?
Yes. He climbed onto
the mountainside images...
And he vandalized them!
He graffitied all over them!
Wait!
Ha ha...
Why should I?
Hey, Naruto!
How did you suddenly get here,
Iruka-sensei?
The question is what are you doing here
when you should be in class now?
We are now about to begin
the graduation test.
When your name is called,
proceed to the next classroom.
The test is on the Clone Jutsu.
Oh no...
Of all the jutsus...! That's
the my worst one!
But still...
I will do it no matter what!
Clone Jutsu!
Disqualified!
Iruka-sensei.
His physical coordination
and stamina are excellent.
And he managed to come up
with something.
Isn't that enough
for him to pass?
Mizuki-sensei... All the others
created three or more clones.
Naruto created just one.
And it's completely useless.
I can't give him a passing mark.
I'm a ninja now!
You did well. That's my son.
Congratulations on your graduation!
I'll cook something good tonight!
Look at that one.
It's that boy.
I hear he's the only one who failed.
Serves him right.
Imagine what would happen
if he became a ninja.
Isn't that boy actually...
Hey! We're not supposed to
talk about that...
Iruka.
We need to talk later.
Yes, sir.
Iruka-sensei isn't trying
to be mean to you.
Then why just me?
He says he wants you to become strong
from the bottom of his heart.
You both don't have parents.
But I really wanted to graduate.
Well... I guess I have no other choice...
I'll let you in on a big secret.
Secret?
Iruka.
What is it, Lord Hokage?
I know how you feel. But...
Naruto also grew up without knowing
the love of his parents... like you.
Let me go!
My mom and dad are
still out there fighting!
Wake up, Iruka-sensei!
What's the matter?
Come to Lord Hokage's immediately!
Naruto... he stole the Scroll of Sealing.
The Scroll of Sealing?!
Let's see...
The first Jutsu is...
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu?
Seriously?! The first one's a jutsu I'm no good at?
Lord Hokage!
We can't just forgive him this time!
This is not just a prank!
The Scroll is a dangerous item
that the First Hokage sealed!
Depending on its use...
It will be a major disaster if
it is taken out of the village!
Yes. Bring Naruto here at once!
Yes, sir!
Where did you go... Naruto?
I will tell everyone in the village
about this and eliminate Naruto...
Then the Scroll of Sealing
will be mine!
Found you, Naruto!
You found me...
And I've only managed to learn one jutsu.
He's been practicing his jutsu...
until he's this exhausted?
Listen, listen!
I'm going to show you this amazing jutsu!
And if I do it,
you'll let me graduate, right?!
If I can do one of the jutsu in here,
I graduate, right?
Who told you that?
Mizuki-sensei! He told me
about this scroll, and this place...
Mizuki did?!
I'm impressed you found this place.
I see... now I get it.
Naruto, give me that scroll.
Wait, wait...
What's going on here?
Naruto! Do not give him that scroll!
It's a dangerous object
that contains Forbidden Jutsu.
Mizuki used you in order to
get it for himself!
Wha?
Naruto, Iruka's just scared of
you getting that power!
Huh?
What are you saying, Mizuki?!
Don't let him fool you, Naruto!
I will tell you the truth.
Idiot! Don't do that!
After the incident 12 years ago,
a rule was created.
A rule?
It's a rule everyone in the village knows, Naruto...
everyone but you.
Except me?!
What is it?
Stop it, Mizuki!
The rule forbids anyone from revealing
that the Nine-Tails is inside you!
Huh?
That's right...
The Nine-Tailed Demon Fox
that killed Iruka's parents and
destroyed our village!
Stop it!
Everyone has been
deceiving you this whole time.
Didn't you find it strange?
Why everyone hated you so much?
Damn! Damn! Damn! Damn! Damn!
Naruto...
No one will ever accept you!
That's why Iruka hates your guts!
Die, Naruto!
Naruto!
Get down!
Wh-Why...?
Because you and I are the same.
After my parents died,
nobody paid attention to me
or gave me any support.
I wasn't a good student in school.
I became the class clown...
because I wanted people to notice me.
I couldn't get noticed through excellence,
so I kept doing stupid things.
It hurt so much.
Isn't that right, Naruto?
You must have been so lonely...
I'm sorry I was so hard on you.
I'm sorry, Naruto...
If I had been a better teacher,
maybe you wouldn't have suffered so much.
Naruto!
Narutoooooo!
He's not the type of kid
to change his mind.
He's going to use the scroll
to take revenge on the village!
Did you see the look in his eyes?
Those were the eyes of a monster.
No...
Naruto... isn't... like that at all!
All I want is to kill Naruto
and get the scroll.
I'll take care of you later!
Naruto!
Everything that Mizuki said
was a lie!
Give me that scroll, quick!
That's what Mizuki is after!
It can't be...
Why is it, Naruto?
How...
did you know I wasn't Iruka?
Because I'm Iruka.
I see.
Why bother try to protect
the thing that killed your family?
I'm won't let a fool
like you have the scroll!
You're the idiot.
Naruto is the same as me.
Same?
Anyone with that scroll
would have limitless power.
There's no way that that monster...
that Demon Fox, won't take advantage
of the power of that scroll!
You're right...
I guess it was true all along!
Iruka-sensei never really
cared about me... at all!
... if he were the Demon Fox.
But Naruto is different!
He's... He's an excellent student.
He works very hard...
Despite that, he's clumsy and...
No one would accept him... So he already
understands the pain in people's hearts.
He is no longer the Demon Fox.
He's a member of the Hidden Leaf Village...
He's Naruto Uzumaki!
You're so gullible, Iruka.
I was going to take you down later,
but I've changed my mind.
Die!
Naruto?!
You surprised me there, freak.
If you ever lay a hand on Iruka-sensei,
I'll kill you!
Shut up! I can kill a brat
like you with a single blow!
Try it!
And I'll return it a thousand times over!
Let's see you try!
Show me what you can do, Demon Fox!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Naruto! You've...
Those aren't illusions, they're solid clones!
That's a high-level ninjutsu!
What's this...?
What's the matter?
C'mon!
Weren't you going to kill me
in one blow? Well, here I am!
In that case...
I'm coming for you!
I kinda got carried away.
Iruka-sensei, are you okay?
Yeah.
Naruto, come over here.
I'd like to give you something.
Has anyone found Naruto yet?
No.
Damn, this is bad...
There's no need to worry anymore.
Lord Hokage!
He'll be back soon.
Sensei, how much longer?
Alright, open your eyes now.
Congratulations on graduating.
To celebrate, we'll have ramen tonight!
Iruka-sensei!
That hurts!
Naruto...
I was going to lecture you...
that the road gets more difficult
now that you're a ninja.
But I guess it can wait
until we're at Ichiraku Ramen...
Even if it was a coincidence,
it seems Naruto's recklessness
saved the village.
You may leave.
Yes, sir.
What's wrong?
Lord Hokage... Umm...
Thank you for placing me
in charge of Naruto.
Because of that, I remembered
why I wanted to become a teacher.
Lord Hokage...
It was because of something
you told me long ago.
It's already been a year, huh?
Smiling while hiding
your sadness isn't easy, is it?
I heard from your teacher that
you're the center of laughter.
I'm not sad!
It's an honor for a ninja
to die on a mission!
Mom and dad sacrificed their lives
to protect the village
from the Nine-Tailed Demon Fox.
They're heroes!
I'm the son of heroes,
so I'm not sad!
These are tears of joy!
That's enough.
I know that you crawl into
a ball when you're by yourself.
But you are not alone.
The ninja of the Hidden Leaf
carry the Will of Fire in them.
Will of Fire?
It's the strong will to
protect this village.
As long as you have
the Will of Fire in you,
everyone in the village
is your family.
Iruka... Do you have that?
Yes!
I want to pass on your Will of Fire
to the next generation of children, and to Naruto.