Captain Kakashi...
What's the enemy up to?
There are no signs of life,
even the enemy's.
It's completely silent.
What's going on?
I don't think they would just give up.
The key to a shinobi battle is
psychological warfare.
I don't like doing what
the enemy wants us to do,
but we should use this as
a chance to rest.
Everyone, rest up and
recover your chakra!
But be on your guard!
We'll scout the area
every half an hour!
We must be ready to resume fighting
at a moment's notice!
That is all!
Guy, you should rest a little too.
Did you think that I could sleep
at a time like this?!
I understand how you feel, but...
Captain Kakashi...
We've received that item from HQ.
Reanimation...
This jutsu is unforgivable!
Sai, use the Foundation's
Sealing Jutsu.
Follow my lead!
But I still can't use that jutsu...
Danzo thought highly of you,
didn't he?
There's no need to suppress
your emotions anymore!
Hey, Sai, sorry to bother you
while you're resting.
That's okay.
This just came from headquarters.
You need this for
your Sealing Jutsu, right?
Lee...
Is it the enemy?!
It looks like you can still fight.
Yes, sir!
I, Rock Lee, the Blue Beast,
do not know the meaning
of the word "exhaustion"!
I want you to be Sai's bodyguard.
He won't be able to
defend himself well
while he's preparing
his Sealing Jutsu.
Leave it to me!
I will risk my life for him!
I leave it to you, Sai.
It's time to change shifts.
Okay.
How are things?
There's been no change.
It's morning and
they still haven't shown up.
It sure is quiet.
It's like the calm
before the storm.
I hope it means
the festival's over.
Enemy attack!
They're here!
This way!
He ran away?
Damn it! Is he over here?!
Hey... Where did everyone go?
There he is! This way!
Even though he's cornered,
he doesn't look like
he's going to fight us.
The enemy sent
their weaker forces into battle.
It seems like hiding in the trees
and using guerrilla warfare
is their main tactic.
They want us to become bold and pursue
our targets, and once we've scattered,
they'll destroy
the Shinobi Alliance one by one.
I hate to admit it,
but they wanted us
to become overconfident
after defeating Zabuza!
What are we going to do?!
Things are going downhill!
We need to regroup.
Send a message to each team
telling them to work with
at least two other teams!
Okay, got it! And what will you do?
I'm worried about
the squads behind us.
If I were the enemy,
I would use this confusion to
cut off our support squads!
The rear guards are tough and
have the restraints and seals
to fight against Reanimation.
Well, I don't understand!
I'll just let you handle it!
You heard us, right?!
Send a message to all teams!
Do not pursue the enemy
if you see them!
Try to stick together and
we'll destroy them one by one!
Yes, sir!
Guy-sensei!
Sorry I'm late!
Hey!
Sai! Lee!
Perfect timing. Follow me!
We're going to prepare a seal!
Yes, sir!
You can count on me!
We won't let them get their way!
Earth Style:
Rampart of Flowing Soil!
Ensui, prepare
the Shadow Paralysis!
Got it!
I found you...
One more time!
Defending against the Blunt Blade,
Kabutowari, is futile!
Form a line of defense...
Trying to block me is meaningless.
You still don't seem to understand!
This next attack will be your last!
It's not over yet!
That's...
Captain Kakashi!
I hope you don't think
this will be over soon!
Sai, please begin!
Okay...
Let's see what
your Sealing Jutsu can do!
I've made up my mind.
But I've been told to suppress
my emotions
ever since I was little.
Is it really possible for me to
master this Sealing Jutsu?
You're back...
Lord Danzo... What is this?
You must assimilate the mass
of negative feelings
you hold deep within you
and train diligently.
This jutsu is the reason why
I raised you all from the time
you were young.
Try to gain complete control
over your emotions.
Release your negative feelings
and restrain them.
I couldn't suppress
my emotions that time...
Can I suppress my emotions now
better than I could then?
If anything, it's even harder now!
I see there's still someone who's
a bit of a challenge in this world.
Even if you're one of the Seven
Ninja Swordsmen of the Mist,
we're not going to let you
win so easily.
Shut up!
That eye looks dangerous, but...
If I thrust my sword
towards you, I can win!
There's no way to block
my Helmet Splitter.
Who said anything about blocking?
Your defense is weak!
Ensui!
Yes, sir!
Hold him with Shadow Paralysis
until the seal is ready.
Understood.
The rest of you, group up with
the squad in front. Follow me!
Shadow Stitching Jutsu!
Impossible...
Run away, little brother.
Our bodies are indestructible.
There's no way you can win!
Shin...
Brother, snap out of it!
Secret Black Technique:
Salamander!
Brother!
Sai...
I heard it was difficult,
but he really looks
like he's suffering.
Someone's coming!
An Explosive Style User!
This is not good!
Sai!
Hurry up with the seal!
Lee can't handle this by himself.
I need to assist him!
There's no need to worry!
I won't forgive the Akatsuki!
They're controlling the dead
using Reanimation.
I'm seriously mad.
Is there any reason
why I would lose?
No! There isn't!
How?
I don't sense any negative feelings
coming from Lee's anger.
Why? Doesn't anger come
from negative feelings?
This is bad!
How dare you...
How dare you harm my friend!
I see...
I see... The source of Lee's anger
is his feelings for his friends.
But I can't do that...
No!
I'm different from how I was then.
I have friends now.
And now, I have a lot of
feelings towards those friends.
A Sealing Jutsu that becomes more
powerful when I release my emotions.
But those emotions don't have
to be negative ones
that come from anger or sorrow!
Sai!
Lee...
I still haven't given you
a nickname, have I?
I'll think of one,
once this war is over.
Sai! Do it.
Sealing Jutsu:
Crouched Tiger Bullet.
Okay! We caught him!
Return!
Whatever the defense...
Wait! Don't go after him!
Sai!
Ninja Art: Needle Senbon!
Weaklings!
Captain...
Wait, don't do anything until
we can get a handle on the situation.
Captain Monga!
The enemy isn't attacking
in large squads...
but they are using
guerrilla tactics.
We're facing the Seven Ninja
Swordsmen of the Mist.
He's strong even without
a ninja blade!
But there's only one of him.
If we surround him with more people
and attack in waves...
that should create
an opportunity for us...
Seems like it's a tough fight.
It is him we're fighting...
Hey, Maki, why aren't they attacking
with a large squad?
I don't know...
Anyway, we need to figure out
what the enemy is going to do
and put together a strategy.
How many enemies are there?
I don't know.
They just suddenly appeared.
Maki, Ruka! Fall back!
Perhaps you should tell them
to run as fast as they can...
If they don't, they'll go boom.
Gari of the Explosion Style...
I never expected to face you...
Yeah, you don't have
enough men to take me on.
That's exactly what
we want you to think...
I get it! The flashy guerrilla tactics are
just to scatter our forces.
You were targeting the support squads
in the rear from the beginning, huh?
That's the quickest way
to end the battle, isn't it?
Besides, I've been brought
back to life and
I can't stand being immobile
because of a Sealing Jutsu.
I never expected someone
like you to be satisfied
with being just a puppet...
You've never been dead,
so you wouldn't understand.
Death isn't something
to take lightly!
Earth Style: Mud Slide!
Don't get near him!
Sorry, your advice has
fallen on deaf ears...
Captain Monga, I...
You guys stay there!
I can handle this by myself.
How fun...
But you can't stop me
with just spirit!
Can you defend yourself against
Explosion Style with just that?
Maki, seal him away right away.
Captain!
This jutsu is...
Pakura-sensei...
Sai of the Hidden Leaf sealed away
one of the Ninja Swordsmen!
Looks like you did well, Sai.
I just hope we can
keep morale high.
Help me!
What's wrong?
Strings are controlling my body...
He's crucifying them alive and
taking pleasure in their suffering...
Stop!
Is this some kind of game for you?
Ran!
You are unforgivable!
I feel sorry for the legends
of past generations
who are being forced to fight
against their will.
It pains me...
You revel in killing.
I hate to think that
we're both called shinobi...
Stop being so full of yourself.
Who do you think
you're pointing that at?!
That belongs to the Seven Ninja
Swordsmen of the Mist!
An outsider wielding
the Executioner's Blade?
I don't like it one bit!
He's mine!
I'm going to kill you and take back
the Executioner's Blade!
No, I will.
I'll kill you if you get in my way!
I'm already dead.
Going up against these two alone
is going to be rough, but...
Looks like you're backed up
against a wall, buddy!
Severe...
Leaf Hurricane!
I'm Might Guy,
the Hidden Leaf's Noble Blue Beast!
Sorry I'm late, Kakashi.
Thanks, Guy.
You're the one who wanted us
to regroup
because it was dangerous
to work in squads.
So why are you doing this
by yourself?
Furthermore, you're fighting two of
the Seven Ninja Swordsmen
of the Mist.
I wanted to save as many people
as I could and got in over my head.
I figured that was the case.
Anyway, we should get her away
from here while we can.
Yeah, thanks.
It's kind of creepy to see you
being so grateful.
But... I guess your opponents were
just strong enough
to make you feel that way.
Where am I?
He... He killed my comrades!
I know.
We're going to defeat the enemy,
so you go regroup with
the main regiment.
B-But...
When we fight them,
you'll only get in our way.
Be careful.
Now then...
How dare you treat our comrades
like they were your toys.
Be careful, Guy.
Kushimaru Kuriarare, who wields
the Long Blade the Sewing Needle...
And Jinpachi Nanashi, who wields
the Explosive Blade, the Splatter...
One killed his master and
the other killed his older brother.
Aside from that, they've committed
countless acts of cruelty.
If you get in my way,
I'll kill you too!
I guess you could call them
the cold-blooded combo.
We've got to stay focused!
That's no problem!
They may be the cold-blooded combo,
but we're the comrade combo!
No one is a match for the Hidden Leaf's
invincible comrade combo!
They're open to attack.
They've underestimated my speed.
His swings are big because
of that gimmick. But...
He doesn't have his Long Blade!
Be careful, Guy!
Ninja Art Long Blade:
Stitching Spider!
This thing!
Explosive Blade Jutsu:
Multiple Explosions of Death!
You saved me again, Kakashi.
Earth Style: Multi Mud Wall!
I was naïve.
I thought I had all the data on the
Seven Ninja Swordsmen of the Mist...
But I never expected them to take
advantage of being reanimated that well.
Kakashi? Did they...
Yeah... They got my eye.
I think it's temporary,
but this is bad.
I've survived many
tough situations like this.
There's something
I remember every time...
This is bad! Guy!
Stone shinobi...
They use jutsu formulas
that cover a wide area.
D-Didn't you run out of chakra?
Chidori!
He cut through a lightning bolt
with Chidori?
I thought he was out of chakra!
Are you all right, Kakashi?
How strange...
I thought I was out of chakra...
But when I thought about saving
my friends, it came out of nowhere.
You should rest, Kakashi.
I'll handle the rest.
But you can't run on those legs...
If I can't use my legs,
I'll use my arms.
If I can't use that,
I'll use my fingers or my mouth...
and struggle all the way until
the end to save my friends.
Just like you did now...
Friend, huh?
You can't see.
Don't push yourself, Kakashi.
If I can't see,
I'll sense things by sound.
If I can't do that,
I'll use smell or even my skin...
and struggle all the way
until the end to save my friends.
You remember that time too...
Let's go!
Yeah!
C'mon!
Let's do this!
Don't underestimate me!
It seems like repeating
our rival challenge
wasn't a waste of time, after all.
Even if I can't see you,
I know exactly where you are!
By matching your movements...
I can even tell where the enemy is.
It's as if I can see.
You're in the way!
You should disappear!
I'll deal with you first!
You don't think of your comrades
as comrades...
You were never a match for us!
Shut up!
Substitution Jutsu?
You idiot!
I can't dodge it!
Did we succeed?
Damn it...
I'm done with this stupid fight!
Get back, Kakashi!
I'll use my Explosion Blade
to blow up this whole area.
Shadow Stitching Jutsu!
I-I can't move!
Captain Kakashi!
I've brought the Sealing Team!
You can see again, Kakashi?
Yeah...
Seal these two away.
Yes, sir!
Stop hiding!
Isn't there anyone here that can send
shockwaves through my heart?
Lightning Style: Lighting Fang!
Cowards aren't my type!
Where are the reinforcements?!
As punishment...
I'm going to burn you to a crisp!
Lighting Style: Thunder Gate!
Hang on, Yurui!
It's over...
Everything's... going dark...
Don't give up, Yurui!
Help is on the way!
Nurui... It's in...
your hands now...
Damn it! I've had it with this!
How many have died already?
Is this what war is?!
Are we the only survivors?
It looks that way.
I'll take command from now on.
I have seniority here.
Ameyuri Ringo went after the
other squad in the other direction.
But she'll be back.
We have to decide
what to do quickly.
It's obvious. We retreat.
Are we running away?
Just because she's one of
the Seven Ninja Swordsmen?
Are you suggesting we take on
Ameyuri Ringo?
Well...
That's not like you, Omoi.
I thought you were
the cautious type, just like me.
War is not the place
for revenge.
And besides, we don't have a chance
against someone with a Ninja Blade.
They are like elephants or tigers...
And we're just mere ants.
Then why the hell are we here?!
Don't get full of yourself, Omoi.
Are you trying to be a hero now?
We'll create a diversion for
Ameyuri Ringo and make our escape.
How boring... Not a single soul
to give me a thrill.
Oh, that's right.
There were two or three
more back there.
Maybe they're more my type.
Damn it... If we keep running
and running...
Pretty soon,
we'll circle the globe.
And if we keep circling
the globe over and over again,
we'll forget why the hell
we're fighting.
And no one will think
that I'm still alive.
I'll keep running and
running until I die.
If that's the case, then...
Captain! Are we still going to
keep running away?
If we keep running,
maybe the reinforcements will arrive
and take care of that bitch.
Waiting for others to bail us out?!
What are you doing?
We have to make it look
like we put up a fight...
Otherwise, who knows what
they'll say after the war.
How stupid. Talk about ego...
And this trap is so obvious!
It's like telling the enemy exactly
which way we're running.
Nothing good's going to come
from following this guy!
You can't run away from me.
They call this a trap?
They must think I'm stupid.
I'm never going to let you go!
Just who is
this Ameyuri Ringo anyway?
A woman known to be an exceptional user
of the Lightning Style.
Although she died young
from an incurable disease,
it's said she never lost her prey.
There's no escaping her?
That's enough, Kayui!
Nurui!
You knew this, and still...
Here she comes!
Damn it!
She's faster than I thought.
Of course, she's going to catch up!
This is such a lame strategy!
We can't outrun her!
Let's fight!
No! It's no use!
How far can we run?!
She always gets her prey, right?!
I know!
Well, do you know that our lives
are in your hands?!
That's why we're retreating!
How can you call yourself
a shinobi?!
Have you even thought about
our fallen comrades?!
Omoi! You don't understand Nurui!
And Nurui, you too!
Why don't...?!
Shut up, Kayui!
I've...
had enough of running!
Omoi...
I know... about your reputation
in the village, Nurui.
Omoi! That's enough!
That your caution is just
a cover for your cowardice!
Well, I'm a cautious guy,
but I'm no coward!
Stop it, Omoi!
Fighting is useless right now!
We can't be heroes!
The thought didn't even
cross my mind!
I just keep seeing Yurui's face
as he was dying!
And even if we escape somehow,
I can't go on living with that image
constantly flashing through my mind.
Looks like Ameyuri Ringo is
still in pursuit of someone.
This isn't good...
There aren't any Allied Shinobi
units beyond this point.
The pursued are only making
themselves more isolated.
Let's hurry!
Oh, here's one.
Someone who's willing to face me!
I'm avenging Yurui!
What? Running away so soon?
Fooled ya!
Cloud Style: Deception Slice!
No one tricks me!
Lightning Sword Style: Thunderbolt!
She's strong...
If I'm going to beat her,
I have to use the one
Bee taught me!
Hidden Mist Slice.
Still not giving up?
At least you have some backbone.
This sword style makes it difficult
to read the path of the blade!
I'm just beginning to
execute this jutsu!
My personal style...
Hidden Mist Slice, Kai!
Let's see you counter this!
Huh? They're all decoys?!
Gotcha!
Lightning Style: Depth Charge!
You're not bad at all.
Most guys would be dead.
Sorry, but I'm really strong.
Omoi!
I won't kill you just yet.
Because I'm the type of person
who saves the things
I like to eat for last.
Don't come!
Nurui! Kayui!
Nurui...
Nurui!
Are you all right, Nurui?!
Did you have to act so foolishly?
I'm sorry... For my sake...
Damn right. Everything's ruined.
Now listen carefully...
Omoi...
Found you!
I won't let you get away.
Are you all right, Kayui?!
Yes...
Is there anyone else with you?
Nurui and Omoi are up ahead...
Ameyuri Ringo is there too, huh?
And they're going to
bring her down.
Now then, are you prepared?
Fine... You want me to fight?
I'll fight then.
You're determined.
I'll give you that.
Please let us get there in time!
I have to, I mean,
we have to bring her down.
Nurui... Yurui...
Bring me down?
Are you still talking nonsense?
I planned to devour you
from the beginning!
Since 'Ringo' means apple,
and today's flavor is apple candy!
Bring it on with
your strongest jutsu!
Too bad!
And you were my type too.
Lightning Style: Thunder Gate!
What is this?!
You trapped me?!
This is actually a bottomless marsh.
Once you're stuck,
you'll never get out.
And you're coming with me?
What a gentleman!
Yurui was my friend.
I'm the one who let
personal feelings interfere.
I wanted to avenge Yurui...
There was only one way
for us to beat her.
There is a bottomless marsh
up ahead.
It's been covered with
an Earth Style lid.
If she uses her Lightning Style there,
she'll sink into
this bottomless marsh.
I planned to lure her there.
Yurui, Kayui and I had made
a number of traps
in preparation for a big battle.
So you... weren't running away?
Omoi, I know the limits
of my strength.
But my plan won't work.
You must run away.
I'll stop Ameyuri Ringo here.
You can't in your condition!
And besides, there's no
running away from her, right?!
Stop... Omoi...
Omoi!
Kakashi! Guy!
We made it in time.
Pull him out.
Weren't you going to
come with me?
Sorry, maybe another time.
In my next life, I'll remember
to eat what I like first.
You won't be
reincarnated anymore.
Here's a farewell gift from me...
Thank you.
Omoi... My name's Omoi.
Omoi...
That's a thank-you gift from me.
I'll be waiting for you
on the other side.
You did well, Omoi.
You're a hero.
The real hero... is you.
So there are new heroes,
after all.
It's always a heartwarming sight...
This deep bond between men.
Kakashi, Guy... Listen up.
I wanted to give you a heads-up.
Naruto and Bee are heading
to the battlefront.
It seems nothing worked
to convince Naruto.
So, we're going to use
this opportunity to turn this war around!
Over and out!
Did you hear that, Kakashi?
Yeah... They're finally on the move.
The heroes we've waited
so long for.
No one is allowed near
Lady Shizune's tent!
Anyone making a move will
be considered an enemy!
So, just stay put!
Sakura, take a look at
this genetic sequence data!
It's finally done?!
It has changed and become
even more like Captain Yamato's
than it was at
the Five Kage Summit!
In other words,
there's very little difference from
the First Hokage's genetic data.
So it was true.
What are you saying?!
What's this about the white creature
and the First Hokage?
Essentially, this white creature is
a clone of the First Hokage.
Or rather, judging from
how many there are,
the First Hokage's cells
were cultivated and
using living plants as a medium,
mobile clones were created.
They are diluted in strength,
but they still use the Wood Style.
Looking at this data,
I'm sure Captain Yamato
is being used to make
these clones stronger.
I'll notify HQ immediately!
I'm back!
I got word that those white beings
are transforming,
and are causing havoc
on the battlefield.
Perhaps it's too much
of a coincidence,
but letting Naruto go
couldn't have been timed better.
I agree.
Sorry to interrupt,
but we just got a report
from the medical team.
It's data about those white creatures.
Give it to me!
Who would have thought that
Madara and Orochimaru's fixation
on the First Hokage
would create this?
Plant clones created
from Grandfather's body.
This is proof that
Madara has possession of
the First Hokage's cells!
He's cultivated them
and developed a way
to replicate them.
Including his own body.
No wonder he's been
able to live this long.
Well? Do we have an idea
of how to destroy him?
No... Just the opposite...
Now, we don't even know
what will kill him.
It seems Madara is really... immortal!
An immortal leader and
his mobile plants...
Reanimation zombies...
Not a normal human among them.
The white creatures are using
Transformation Justu...
Warn Naruto and Bee immediately!
Naruto, please listen carefully.
You too, Lord Bee.
I am transmitting this message
directly into your minds.
Let me explain the enemy's battle jutsu
and their objective.
Pay close attention.
That explains all the weird,
fuzzy sensations I've been having.
I guess I have no choice,
but to step up.
Yeah!
But remember, I mentioned
that Madara's Project Tsuki no Me
won't work without
your Tailed Beasts...
That means you two are his targets.
I know that!
As if I'd sit still and
let them capture me!
Then this time, don't even think
about negotiating with him, Naruto.
Madara is different from
Pain and Nagato.
He has no interest in peace.
He's a truly evil man
who covets the entire world.
And with Project Tsuki no Me,
he'll be able to completely control
humans through genjutsu...
That's about it.
So don't let down your guard!
I once talked to Madara
in the Land of Iron.
He told me about
the Uchiha Clan's destiny.
He knows all about hatred,
and took advantage of Nagato.
He's the one fueling
Sasuke's hatred too.
I know how evil he is.
He doesn't act out of hatred.
He simply exploits hatred.
He's unlike any other foe
you've faced, so be careful!
In any case, I'm going to
pulverize Madara
and bring this war to an end!
Only then can we talk.
I don't know about Kabuto,
but Madara is supposedly immortal.
Furthermore, those mobile plants
that were restructured
with the First Hokage's cells...
You know,
those otherworldly zombies...
Nothing works against them
except by sealing.
It's truly an undead army.
Beware of them too!
That's the only piece of
good news.
I don't have to worry
about holding back!
That's...
It's chaos out there
in the battlefield!
We've got to get back and
shore up HQ's defense!
Rasengan!
Naruto?!
Leave it all to Naruto here.
Those he gives his stamp of approval.
Are the only ones I'll give an ear.
They're all enemies!
Let's do this, Octopops!
Rasenrangan!
Rasenkyugan!
Naruto's attack is affecting
the Wood Style,
and turning them back into wood?
It's just like before...
This way, we won't be so vulnerable
to the effects of his attack.
Mini-Rasen Shuriken...
Summoning, Mayhem Jutsu!
All right!
Yay!
The fruits of training.
Thanks to my mentoring.
Yay...
I'll leave my Shadow Clones and
Mr. Gamahiro to keep an eye here.
Let's go!
I'm going to hit all the battlefields
at the same time!
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
It's no good. He caught up to us!
H-He's...?!
He's a Cloud ninja with
a Kekkei Genkai!
Toroi of the Magnet Style!
The Hidden Cloud has
a Magnet Style user too?
When he attacks, you must always...
You Idiot! I said you always
have to dodge it!
Huh? You didn't say that!
His Magnet Style magnetizes
any object that he touches.
And subsequently, anything those
things touch becomes magnetized...
although the effect is not
as strong.
You are the first conductor
to have touched the shuriken,
so the magnetic power
in your body is...
Huh? What exactly do you mean?
Right now, your body is infused
with magnetic power
since his shuriken is magnetic.
Which means,
your body and his shuriken
are going to be
drawn to each other.
Which means, in his second attack,
you won't be able to dodge it!
That means I'm going to die!
I'm going to die!
Rasengan!
What is all this ruckus?
Lord Bee!
What are you doing here?
Are you okay?
You shouldn't be here!
Those white beings are disguising
themselves as our comrades.
I know that.
So this is one of the zombies
controlled by
the Reanimation Jutsu...
Looks like sealing them like this
is the only way to stop them.
We were rushing back to
Headquarters with Eff
to tighten the security there,
but got separated...
Eff was actually a white creature.
Huh?!
Things here have gone awry.
Octopops, we have to catch up
with everyone else.
Yeah!
Hang on!
Bring me a hemostat! Quickly.
Sakura...
Yugao, take her away.
All right.
I've compiled a preliminary report on
the status of each company.
Casualties spiked up during the night.
I hesitate to bring this up, but...
The bodies of the shinobi are
full of secret information.
If those bodies get into
the hands of the enemy,
DNA data could be taken...
In a worst-case scenario,
the enemy will use their jutsu to
turn them into military weapons.
There's no need to worry
about that!
I've taken care of it.
But there are many corpses
on the battlefield
that cannot be recovered...
These three are the bodies
of elite shinobi. I'm certain.
Then I'll place them into
safekeeping immediately.
Thank you.
This one too. He's an elite.
All right.
Please line him up over there.
The ones with Kekkei Genkai
and their relatives,
and those families with
special ninjutsu abilities,
are being given the highest priority
in handling and safekeeping.
When everything is over,
we'll send them back to their villages
with the rest of the deceased.
I'll be returning.
Thank you very much.
She's very skillful and efficient.
Well, word is that Miss Yugao used
to belong to the ANBU Black Ops.
A former ANBU?
Why's someone like that here?
I don't know. But it helps.
May I ask you a question?
I'm just a little curious...
If it's a simple question.
I understand you were once
a member of the ANBU Black Ops.
With such skill, what are you
doing helping in the medical camp?
Every company is shorthanded now.
Someone like you...
I... I can't fight anymore.
Yugao...
I'll be right there!
Please wait.
Right now,
this work is what's best for me.
You should return to
your station quickly too—
What was that?!
That explosion...
It was from the vault!
That man is...
Hayate?!
Yugao!
The scroll he has is the KIA list!
The bodies of the elite shinobi
have been taken!
Get them back!
– Right!
Do not flinch!
Not!
Get a taste of this!
This is fun!
That's enough. Let's go!
Where's Shizune?
She just went into surgery.
All right.
Notify HQ about this immediately.
And get the wounded inside the tent!
Right!
As for the scrolls
with the bodies of the elite...
I saw the faces of the assailants.
I believe one of them
was a Hidden Leaf Special Jonin...
Hayate Gekko.
I see...
This medical tent
must be guarded too.
Looking at the situation,
we can't spare many people.
We'll have to contact HQ
and ask them to send reinforcements.
But Iou, Yokaze, will you two go?
– Yes.
I'll go too.
My battle and healing skills
will increase
the odds of success for this mission.
Thanks. Also, Yugao...
I want you to go too.
Huh?!
I know that you are not part
of the combat force.
But a Sensory-type is essential
in order to track the enemy.
You're the only one available now—
That's impossible! I can't...
Yugao?
This is an emergency.
State your reason!
That man...
Hayate Gekko...
was my lover.
You've improved.
Not bad, huh?
I can get one out of two now.
Get real. It's more like
one out of three.
That's because
you can use the Transparency Style.
But just you wait,
I'll catch up in no time.
Then I just have to
work harder so you can't.
You're wide open!
My mistake.
I won't let you
surpass me that easily.
Since I'm going to protect you.
Okay, before the fighting starts...
We should know about
who we're fighting.
Hayate Gekko is an expert
in the Hidden Leaf Sword Style.
He specializes in
the Transparency Jutsu.
He's highly skilled.
You want to avoid close combat.
Let's hurry!
That was boring.
I wanted to do more damage.
Are you kidding?
I'm sick of being used like this.
But we got to come back to life.
We should enjoy ourselves, right?
To meet again like this...
But you could...
Hey, I'm talking to you.
Are you dissing me, you bastard?!
They're coming.
Oh, I see...
This is what it means to
have a body that can't die.
This is pretty convenient.
Don't talk too soon!
A posse, eh?
That's more like it!
Two left...
I wish we could have stopped
at least one more.
That one disappeared quick...
This is perfect though.
Let's share the prey, fifty-fifty!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Please take care of that one!
Right!
You've come...
Get back.
Sorry, but you'll be going up
against me!
Earth Style: Flying Stones!
You're mine!
Please get back.
Then return that scroll!
What?!
Iou!
You should pay attention!
Go after him too.
I'm sorry.
I am now an enemy of the Leaf...
and yours as well.
So I want you to stop me.
I don't want to hurt you... Please!
Yugao! Take this!
Kill me, Yugao!
I can't...
I just can't!
If you don't...
Yugao!
Cha!
That's all you got?
You're the only one left.
I have to go.
Wait!
Damn it!
Iou!
This is...!
Please bear with the pain.
I'm going to close the wound.
Iou can't continue on with the pursuit.
That goes for you too...
I'm sorry. It's my fault.
No.
But it was true then?
That... you can't fight.
I'm sorry.
I always dreamed of joining
the ANBU Black Ops,
so I lost my head earlier...
I'm going to get some water.
Where are you going?
Hayate hasn't changed his course.
So you don't need my help
in pursuing him.
There's nothing I can do
even if I remained.
Why did you leave
the ANBU Black Ops?
Hayate was my lover.
At the time, we were training partners
in the Leaf Sword Style.
We honed our skills together.
There!
Impressive.
The Hokage himself certified
my Transparency Style.
Well, with my Sensory skills and
swordsmanship, I was chosen for the ANBU.
But you're still lacking.
I'm almost there!
Hayate?
I suppose I should be happy
that your strength has
been acknowledged.
But the missions are risky,
far more dangerous than before.
Please, I want you to be careful.
I heard that...
members of the ANBU Black Ops
died at Hidden Leaf Hospital...!
I'll be fine. But...
They were killed by Kabuto Yakushi.
It seems he was Orochimaru's spy.
The one who was taking part
in the Chunin Exam?
He had us completely fooled.
But going after Sasuke
doesn't explain their actions.
Without a doubt,
they're up to no good.
So we must learn more
about their movements.
It's too dangerous.
He held his own against Kakashi.
But someone has to go.
And with my Tracking Jutsu,
I'm the ideal candidate.
But...
I'm off.
Hayate Gekko has been killed.
– What?!
– Oh no...
No...
Not Hayate?
He was found on the outskirts
of Kikyo Castle.
That's...
The destruction of the Leaf Village
happened a month later...
Hayate, I'll avenge you.
It was my way of memorializing Hayate...
So I fought and I fought...
But when the fighting ended...
My emotions that had been stretched
so thin... just snapped.
I couldn't even hold
a sword anymore.
Hayate and I were connected
through fencing.
Inevitably, a sword reminds me
of his death.
Yugao...
How can I kill him?
How can I go through his death
all over again?
Still, I cannot let you go...
and leave behind the injured.
Am I right?
I understand a little of
what you're going through...
I couldn't fight the one I loved.
But you must see this through.
Sakura...
Kakashi-sensei told us...
"This jutsu is unforgivable."
To trample on a person's death...
to trample on our memories of them...
I feel the same way!
I'll be fine. Our reinforcements
will be here shortly.
Please stop, Hayate Gekko.
You're... Sakura Haruno, right?
You've become a fine shinobi.
I don't want to kill you.
And I can't let you go.
I can't let you have that scroll!
I won't get into your line of attack!
Right there!
Where'd he go?
Please run away!
I'm here.
I'm sorry I'm late.
Thank you.
I'll assist.
No, call the Sealing Corps.
Killing him won't stop him.
Right!
– Dance of the Crescent Moon!
Yugao...
Hayate...
Moonlit Night...
Secret Sword: Tsukikage!
Like you said, you've gotten better.
It wasn't for something like this.
I regret...
making that promise.
You're wrong.
I wondered what was taking
so long.
Hurry up and do your work,
will you?
I'm being called...
Is he taking my consciousness too?!
Hayate...
This is pitiful, but...
I'm really doing my best.
Yugao!
Goodbye, Yugao.
Yokaze and Iou
have been rescued.
I see. That's good.
Yugao...
In the end...
he protected me.
Thank you... and...
goodbye...
Hayate.
You don't think it's...
Are they close?
It feels familiar, nostalgic...
Itachi Uchiha... and Nagato!
You know these guys, Naruto?
Yeah, I know both of them.
I never imagined I'd be forced
into fighting you again, Naruto.
It's probably been
a while since we last met.
But since I've been dead, it feels
like it's only been a moment.
You've changed a bit, Naruto.
Oh, you mean this?
I've mastered the Nine-Tails' chakra now.
This is my Chakra Mode!
What?
I see...
No wonder you look different.
It's your face.
You now command
the power of the Nine-Tails?
I'm impressed with your development!
He and I are fellow disciples.
I'm not surprised!
For that, it's me he owes...
Before I came along, he was
pretty much in the shadows.
That's so not true!
So you've overcome hatred, Naruto?
Oh yeah! As my senior,
you taught me about pain.
The training I did at the Waterfall
of Truth with Octopops...
My mom and dad...
I have all of you to thank
for where I am now!
I see...
Naruto, I must ask you...
That reminds me—
I have a question for you,
as well.
Seems like I found you first...
Eight-Tails and Nine-Tails.
With these two cards,
he'll fall right into my hands.
Too bad I won't be able to see
the frustrated look on
his face under that mask...
when he realizes!
Yo?!
Oops, was that hot?
Sorry for not giving it all I got.
Samehada...
So Kisame is dead...
He was still talking...
He's under a spell...
Even if he cuts you off,
what the hell?
Okay?
Above you!
I see him!
What happened to Sasuke?
He says he's going to take
revenge on the Leaf Village!
He joined the Akatsuki!
Why won't Sasuke return
to the village?
He found out about
your top-secret mission,
and chose to destroy the village!
Top-secret mission?
Don't tell me Madara...?
Madara told me the truth too.
So that's how it was...
So Madara was telling the truth!
The Uchiha Clan tried to
take over the village and...
You've said enough, Naruto.
Is that true, Itachi?
Itachi...
You died playing the villain in order
to protect the village and Sasuke!
Sasuke surely understands
your pain and resolve!
But instead of seeing
your wishes through,
Sasuke is trying to
destroy the village.
This is his way of avenging
the pain the village caused
his beloved older brother!
Damn Madara,
he knew the truth about me...
Do the villagers know about this?
Kakashi-sensei and
Captain Yamato were there too.
But there was nothing to prove
what Madara said,
so Kakashi-sensei is keeping
everyone tight-lipped.
I don't think anyone else knows.
Then don't ever tell
the village about this!
You can't let the Uchiha Clan's
reputation change!
And one more thing...
Damn! My body is moving
on its own!
Universal Pull!
Nicely dodged, Naruto!
I'm stronger now than
when Pain and I fought.
I'll let you deal with Sasuke.
That was my plan from the start!
Entrusting it to you was
the right thing to do, after all.
Okay, Naruto, pull me away!
I can't move by myself.
Summoning Jutsu!
What?!
Or maybe I can...
Since when can you do that?!
Behind you!
I got it! Okay!
Fire Style: Phoenix Flower jutsu!
Hot! Hot! Hot!
Caught you! Ya fool, ya fool!
For someone so big,
that was easy!
Keep your guard up, Naruto!
What the hell's happening?!
Genjutsu!
Don't look at my eyes!
Ouch!
Wake up!
Samehada!
Killer Bee the Eight-Tails!
That's me!
Yay!
This'll go on forever!
He multiplies every time
you hit him!
Knock me down first!
Watch yourself, Octopops!
If you get struck by Amaterasu or
Tsukuyomi, it'll be the end of you!
He's got the Mangekyo Sharingan!
It's out.
You just said you consider
Sasuke to be like a brother...
What if Sasuke were to attack
the Leaf Village?
What would you do then?
What?
Why would Sasuke...?
There's no way he'd do
something like that!
Sasuke is still naïve.
He can easily be influenced.
In such a case,
can you stop him?
Even if you have to kill Sasuke?
I have shared some of
my power with you.
Though I hope the day never comes
when you'll have to use it.
This feeling!
Naruto! It's Amaterasu!
Almighty Push!
Damn it! My body's moving
by itself again!
What was that?!
What's going on?!
It's not Amaterasu?
So that's how it is...
How what is...?
Amaterasu...
That crow... It's yours, isn't it?
What did you do with that crow?
I underestimated him...
Amaterasu!
You!
Relax...
I'm no longer being controlled.
I used a new genjutsu against
the enemy's jutsu.
A genjutsu that orders me
to protect the Leaf Village.
It erased the Reanimation Jutsu.
I prepared that crow to respond
to my Mangekyo Sharingan.
Just in case, for times like this.
What are you talking about?
It's implanted in that crow's left eye.
It's his eye!
There's only one genjutsu
that can do that.
Shisui Uchiha's...
The strnogest Mangekyo Sharingan
genjutsu:
Koto Amatsukami.
Using that genjutsu,
I was able to restore myself.
It appears Shisui's Mangekyo
had already worn off, though.
Shisui Uchiha?
The Uchiha's most powerful
genjutsu user...
Shisui of the Body Flicker?
Shisui's Visual Prowess creates
a powerful genjutsu
that allows you to control someone
without them ever realizing it.
I programmed the genjutsu,
to protect the Leaf, into Shisui's eye.
Then I put it into the crow's left eye,
and after that,
I implanted the crow in you, Naruto.
I never realized that I'd be
using it on myself someday.
Why did you have that eye,
and why did you give it to me?
Self-sacrifice...
The mark of a true shinobi is
that they do not seek glory.
They protect from the shadows.
Shisui taught me that.
Shisui anticipated that a battle
would ensue for his eyes.
He faked his own death and made
it seem like his eyes were destroyed.
I helped him by becoming
the target of suspicion in the village.
When I last saw Shisui,
Danzo had managed to
steal his right eye.
He bequeathed his remaining
left eye to me,
telling me to use it to protect
the village, and disappeared.
I gave that eye to you,
because you share Shisui's feelings.
If Sasuke, whom I left behind,
ever became a threat to the village...
then I would have violated all
that Shisui entrusted me to do.
You are the only one
who can make it right.
You said you consider
Sasuke a brother.
That's why I felt that you, Naruto,
were the only one
who could stop him.
True power...
In his quest for
the Eternal Mangekyo,
Sasuke planned on transplanting
my eyes into himself.
If that ever happened,
that crow was supposed
to emerge from you,
in response to your coming into
contact with my transplanted eyes,
and cast the Koto Amatsukami on Sasuke,
compelling him to to protect the Leaf.
That was my plan.
Why didn't you cast that jutsu
on Sasuke from the start,
using Shisui's eye?
It's not that I didn't, I couldn't.
Not at that time...
Shisui's Mangekyo would take
decades to reactivate,
unless you had
Hashirama Senju's chakra.
Also, there were many things
Sasuke wanted to
use my death for.
Itachi...
Thank you for trusting me.
You don't have to worry anymore.
You've done more than
enough for the village.
Let me take care of the rest.
My little brother is lucky...
to have a friend like you.
Even Shisui's eye...
Luck just keeps coming my way!
Almighty Push!
Where did he go?!
It isn't going to be that easy.
Fool, ya fool!
Lariat!
Gakido!
Are you absorbing chakra?
Octopops, you okay?
Ningendo!
You have all of Pain's jutsu!
But I'm... not familiar with this one!
Oh, right!
I just confirmed that he can absorb
ninjutsu a minute ago!
I'm so stupid!
Nagato! What the hell is
that jutsu anyway?!
Tell me!
No good!
He's completely being controlled...
Jigokudo!
Hey, wait... This is...
It's the reviver Pain's jutsu!
What are you after?!
Use Ningendo to extract
their souls and kill them.
Hide their bodies and souls
with Jigokudo...
and bring them back to me,
so that I can revive them.
I can make the Jinchuriki mine
without Madara finding out.
Now then, what else could he do?
Damn it! So you're not going to
give me any answers, after all?!
How does that reviving jutsu work again?
This stuff...
It's like my soul's coming out!
And I'm losing strength...
I'm getting a bad feeling about this!
Shurado!
What did he summon? Strange armor?
Octopops!
He sure uses a lot of hands.
To change tactics and his stance.
Naruto, remember when you had
that tug-of-war with the Nine-Tails!
Susano'o!
You're a lifesaver! Thanks, Itachi!
What kind of ninja is he?!
Damn, he's strong! Fool, ya fool!
He's known as Pain,
and has the strength of
the Sage of Six Paths.
So, of course he's strong!
And this time, we're facing him,
not his corpse puppets!
So his power and moves are
in a different league.
Planetary Devastation.
Here it comes!
What is that?!
That black sphere looks like
it has enormous gravitational pull!
He got me with this jutsu once!
It's really bad, it's really bad!
If you get caught in it, it's over!
Hey, Naruto...
What?!
If it's a sure death,
how come you're still alive?
Well then, no need to worry,
about our victory.
This is no time to be laughing!
How can you be so easygoing
when we're in a bind like this?!
If we're caught,
we'll never be able to get out!
Its gravitational power is awesome!
I got out only because
of Nine-Tails' rampage...
It's not about being easygoing.
Analysis requires calm.
It's safe to assume that the mass
that Nagato threw earlier
is the central core of gravity.
We need to destroy it.
We'll attack the center simultaneously,
each of us using our strongest
long-range ninjutsu!
We can't aim properly under
these conditions!
Our jutsu will make contact,
even if we don't aim correctly.
This tactic takes advantage of
the core's powerful gravitational pull.
Every jutsu has a weakness!
Okay.
That was fast!
All right... Me too!
Yasaka Beads!
Tailed Beast Bomb!
Wind Style: Rasen Shuriken!
Forgive me... Itachi.
You're back.
This is the Totsuka Blade...
It's a sword that possesses
a sealing jutsu.
You will be sealed away soon.
Do you have any last words?
Naruto, I'm going back to where our
master is to watch your story unfold.
If you ask me, you are
the final volume of the trilogy.
Jiraiya was the perfect first volume.
But the second volume
was a failure... me.
One that our master
would not acknowledge.
You must make it
a masterpiece...
One that will completely overshadow
the failure of the middle volume, Naruto!
Farewell.
This Reanimation Jutsu or
whatever they call it stinks!
Guys are forced to fight,
even when they don't want to.
This is happening at
other battlegrounds too, right?
I will put a stop to
the Reanimation Jutsu.
I leave Madara to you two.
We fought with a Reanimated ninja
on the way here.
The Sand shinobi sealed him...
But it seems he can't be killed, okay?
This is a perfect jutsu that
has no weaknesses, okay?
I told you earlier.
There is a weakness in every jutsu.
I wonder about that...
No, I'll stop him!
Like I said...
Leave the rest to me!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
You've used Nine-Tails
Chakra Mode too much.
No more clones right now, Naruto!
Don't try to do everything yourself.
I am the best one to put
an end to the Reanimation Jutsu.
I also have an idea.
I'll put an end to this war...
It's my responsibility!
I'll admit that you're stronger
than before.
But because of that,
you seem to have lost sight
of what's truly important.
Now listen carefully.
The villagers, who once shunned you,
have begun to admire you.
They think of you as a comrade.
It's because you fought hard
for their acceptance.
You once said it was
everyone who cares about you
who helped you get
where you are now.
If you forget others because
you now have power,
and become arrogant...
you'll eventually become
just like Madara.
No matter how powerful
you become,
do not try to shoulder
everything alone.
If you do, you will surely fail.
Your father, Minato, was able to
fulfill his duty as the Hokage
because he had your mother, Kushina,
and his comrades at his side.
You share your father's dream,
don't you?
Then don't ever forget...
Becoming the Hokage doesn't mean
people will acknowledge you.
But when the people
acknowledge you,
you can become the Hokage.
Never forget your friends!
Naruto...
I promised that Iruka guy
that I'd keep you safe, no lie!
I won't let you go alone, bro!
Cuz' I'm still alive, and rarin' to go.
Don't act like a spoiled brat!
To me, you are...
An important student.
And... I think of you as
my little brother.
The enemy leader is targeting you
with everything he's got.
How can we allow you
to face such danger?
And besides, there is no reason for you
to shoulder that burden alone.
You're right. I forgot.
I thought I had to do it all alone.
Wh-Why?!
Shisui's eye won't reactivate for
another decade or so.
You won't be able to use it against Sasuke.
But you possess something
far greater than Shisui's eye.
You have the same soul as Shisui.
That is what Shisui really
wanted to pass on.
You don't need his eye anymore.
As you are now,
you can stop Sasuke without
something like this.
You can stand before Sasuke now.
This time, you can...
No.
I tried to do everything myself
and I failed.
This time, I will leave it
to my comrades.
You're not just a powerful shinobi.
Killer Bee...
Take care of Naruto.
For sure!
Let's go, Octopops!
Stop! Why did you do that?!
Let's test these outside,
shall we?
These eyes...
see the darkness
quite well...