This is the form,
the body I needed!
It's not a battle without raging blood...
and a pounding heart!
Ancient relics...
should just stay out of this!
A brat who doesn't even
come close to my level.
You stole my line.
Why did he close his eyes?
Sasuke!
It's pointless to just
throw attacks at him.
This guy can absorb ninjutsu!
When these two polar opposites
work together,
it gives rise to all things
in this universe...
Hashirama, do you remember me
telling you this long ago
in front of the Uchiha Stone Tablet?
That the inscription
on the stone says,
when two opposite sides cooperate,
you have true happiness.
But I also told you it could
be interpreted differently.
That's...
The one who obtains
both Uchiha and Senju powers
can attain true happiness.
Don't you think it could be read
that way as well?
Hashirama?
It seems you've been doing
a lot of plotting
since you left the village.
No... Actually, this is something
a comrade of my subordinate came up
with by coincidence.
Seems there was a fellow
who thought a lot like me.
However...
Me coming back to life
was exactly as planned!
Damn it... I can't move!
Though things did happen
out of order.
Oh well.
So this is Sage Art chakra...
Is that all there is to it?
Seems like this will
be easy to control.
This is the perfect chance now
that you are flesh and blood.
This time I'll kill you for good,
and send you back
to the afterlife!
Curse your fate for being
a reanimation...
as you go to your death!
I can feel it...
Your Mangekyo are Choku Tomoe,
a straight pattern.
No wonder you have fine moves.
It might be a good idea
to take your eyes
until I get my Rinnegan back.
But killing you would be such
a waste with an eye like that.
How about it?
You're a survivor of
the Uchiha like me.
Want to join forces?
Make no mistake.
You're a dead man.
Fine then...
In any case,
you don't have much time left.
Fire Style:
Hiding in Ash Jutsu!
Madara is regaining his past strength.
Not good. His next target is...
I'll be taking you all next...
you filthy beasts!
Obito... Your usefulness is over.
What did you do?
Madara...
has come back to life!
You performed the Rinne Rebirth,
so you will die.
This is the last step.
I'm taking back that left eye.
He'll last a little while longer
while I'm attached to him.
Just what are you?
You're not human.
I am Madara's will incarnate.
I will eliminate anyone
who gets in Madara's way.
Black Zetsu.
I thought you'd been captured...
All of you, including Obito, greatly
underestimated Madara's plan.
You underestimated me as well.
I-I can't move now...
I can't believe he's able
to transform his blade so much
in such an instant!
Then that's perfect.
You'll go to Obito and
bide your time until
I give you the order.
I'm going to play a little here,
then head over.
I just want to gauge
the present Kage's strength.
I got it.
He's a useless traitor
who went against Madara's plan.
Until Obito dies,
I'll use his body to fight you.
I've got to get some use
out of him,
at least at the end.
You know, staying here...
Yeah... isn't wise.
Get away from here!
Shukaku! Get ready!
Let's go wild!
Wind Style:
Sand Bomb! Salvo!
Nice jutsu.
But it lacks in finishing power...
So you implant your sand with
this jutsu to stifle movement...
Now, Shukaku!
Grand Sand Mausoleum Seal!
He'll never take another
breath of fresh air again!
I'll be putting collars
on all of you shortly.
Not one of you will
be able to get away.
I won't let you!
No one here's going to wag
his tail for you!
Sorry we're late!
We were moving the injured.
Don't worry!
There won't be any more wounded.
We're ending this now!
Stack tails!
You were close,
you damned raccoon!
Quit ordering us around,
you dumb fox!
But this should...
Persistent bastard!
But he's already taken a beating.
All right! One more blast!
Yeah, let's go, Naruto!
Sorry I'm late, Lord Madara.
You're finally here.
Do you have it?
Of course.
This should make things
a little more fun...
Finally... I can fully
savor battle again!
Summoning Jutsu!
He's going to fight us using that?
Kakashi, can you manage?
Yes, in one way or another...
Kamui!
Did it work?
I think...
it failed...
Not that thing again!
Seems the right arm's been wrenched off.
Seems there's someone left with
good eyes on the other side.
Well, it's not much of an impediment.
And now, I've got a pen for them.
All I need to do is
shove them in there.
A fake Rinnegan from a reanimation
can summon that thing?
He's bleeding and wounded.
In other words, he's not
a reanimation anymore.
He possesses a real Rinnegan.
How did he come back to life?!
Naruto, I'm grateful to you.
You even extracted
the Tailed Beasts from Obito,
saving me the trouble
of weakening him.
Then Obito's...!
You're stubborn,
for someone near death.
This left eye came to you
through Nagato,
but it's time for it to return
to its rightful owner.
The only ones who have awakened
the Rinnegan in this world
are the Sage of Six Paths
and Madara Uchiha.
It's not a mere thing to
be hoarded by the likes of you.
I've hidden the right eye...
And I'm going to have Kakashi
destroy the left eye right now.
White Zetsu found
the right eye a while ago
and turned it over to Lord Madara.
You're a useless fool
who refuses to die...
So stop resisting.
You'd be dead already
if I wasn't sticking to you.
Then detach from me and
take the Rinnegan after I die.
The instant I detach from you,
these two will kill me.
Before I can take the Rinnegan.
Have you forgotten that I was the
one who gathered intel for Akatsuki?
I've already analyzed these two
and their strength.
It's going to take a bit longer
for the left eye.
Seems like it.
This also looks like it's going
to take a bit longer too.
Don't compare me to that brat who
took years to get back those pets.
You're covered in blood.
Knowing that I possess
Hashirama's healing powers
might cause me to fight crudely.
I'll proceed more carefully.
If I use the Rinnegan's true powers, we
should see a more sophisticated battle.
It will only be a few seconds.
So watch closely!
Limbo...
Hengoku!
He might try something...
So be careful...
What is this?
What just happened?!
Damn you...
That ought to have tamed you a bit.
Now I can put on your collars!
Eight-o!
Kurama!
First, I'll rip the Eight and
Nine-Tails from their Jinchuriki!
Eight-o!
Damn it!
That's right...
If I just undo
this Kurama Mode...!
It's useless.
Once I catch them,
I won't let them go.
It's not working!
Kurama's not going
back inside me...!
Damn it, I'm being pulled backwards!
Lord Madara, you must take them
in order starting with the One-Tail.
I know that.
Since you need to rip out
the last two Tailed Beasts,
Eight and Nine-Tails,
from the Jinchuriki,
why not pull in the others,
the One-Tail through Seven-Tails
for the time being?
You bastard! I'm not letting you
take Kurama!
You're right, it looks like this will
take longer than I expected.
So let's start... with this one!
Desert Hands!
You can't have Shukaku!
Gaara, don't lose!
Until now, I've always
considered you unpleasant.
But it was because
I was a Jinchuriki,
that I was able to meet Naruto...
So there's one thing
I'm grateful to you for now.
You Sand brat!
Are you really that happy
to have your old pet back?
To think you'd interfere, even though
you're no longer a Jinchuriki!
My motto is absolute defense!
I've still got my pride as Shukaku!
I know...
No... you know nothing at all.
Gaara... Don't overexert yourself!
I'm no longer a Jinchuriki...
So...
I can finally talk to you
on equal terms!
Gaara... You...
Damn it!
Hey, Kazekage brat!
Do me a favor!
All right...
You got that... Gaara?!
Naruto!
Shukaku!
Sorry... Bee!
I'm counting on you...
Kazekage brat!
I don't believe it...
They've all been sucked in!
Well, I guess...
that's about all I can expect
from my current strength.
It took more than a few seconds...
But you were faster than Obito.
You really do talk too much.
You're all failed experiments of mine...
Always finding fault with me.
Black Zetsu is nicknamed
"Wicked Tongue"
and they call us White Zetsu,
"Wagging Tongues".
I hope the other battle
is going well.
Don't worry!
After all, the base is good.
Flying Raijin Slice!
You're mine!
This is my chance!
I swear I will not let you die!
Like I'd let you die!
It's your M. O. to strike an opponent
when he's convinced of victory...
Making the brats do the work...
You still tend to leave things to
others, don't you, Tobirama?
The same goes for you.
However, heaven is on my side.
Look at you, the one touted
as the fastest shinobi ever.
There's a reason why you two
brothers can't regain your former speed.
Whether it's coincidence or if it's
inevitable... I've got the edge now.
Plus I'm nurturing a new eye.
Though it's unclear which side
they'll end up on...
Wait!
Uchiha lad...
Let me give you a jutsu.
A jutsu?
Yes...
Madara stole my Sage chakra...
This jutsu will respond to
the Sage chakra and bind him.
I will give you all of
my remaining chakra.
You must stop Madara...
Why ask me, an Uchiha?
You're a lot like him...
Madara's younger brother...
Izuna Uchiha.
So? What does that have to do
with stopping him?
Madara's fundamentally
a kind man.
He was a man of deep love
who cherished his siblings.
That's why he gave you
a chance at redemption.
You might be able to stop Madara
without using force.
Now... come stand before me.
To be honest...
I've wanted to do this
to you for a long time.
Since you're...
the one who killed Izuna!
But you're just a moving corpse,
so it's hardly fulfilling.
Madara... What is it that you
desire so badly
that you'd come back to life for?
Our era, our time ended...
ages ago!
I just want to build the nation
that Hashirama couldn't.
But this world belongs to Hashirama,
my predecessor who failed.
Drastic measures are needed
to save the dying patient.
I'm going on ahead!
So this thing called
the Infinite Tsukuyomi was your idea?
This is your idea of a cure?
Yes. Hashirama's nation-building
bore a paradox.
People desire peace...
And yet, on the other hand,
crave conflict as well.
That duality is mankind.
To only want peace
and to discard conflict...
would cause people
to stop being people.
And those two things stand
together side by side.
Be they a friend... sibling...
or even my own child...
I will not forgive anyone
who threatens the village.
People will sacrifice something in order
to protect something else.
Except in a true dream world.
You've got a point.
But... it's not a dream
that you should interfere with!
Now.
You could say that this world is
Hashirama's paradox world.
Damn it!
What is this?!
In order to protect something...
one must sacrifice something else.
Stop, Madara!
Don't go any further...
"Be they a friend... sibling..."
"or even my own child..."
I gave you plenty of time.
And I warned you...
that there wasn't much time left.
How unfortunate.
Madara!
What kind of man are you?!
It's coming again!
My jutsu won't activate!
My chakra is—!
I can't believe we've been stopped
by the likes of him...
This strange thing...
It's blocking our way!
It's using the Wood Style...
What is it?
I told you, I wouldn't let you
pass so easily.
By the way, isn't there anyone
who can give me
a serious answer to my question?
I asked you, what does
it feel like to take a dump?
Well... I'm thinking it's like
the refreshing feeling you get
after killing someone.
All five elements at once?!
How do we counter that?
Impressive...
Using the same jutsu simultaneously
to cancel them out...
We're saved.
Don't underestimate Lord Third!
That said, everyone's exhausted
most of their chakra.
Which leaves only a reanimated
Lord Third to fight back.
If Lord Third should fall,
we're done for...
Forget Madara. We need to do
something about him.
To be honest...
Everyone needs to
start fighting as if
Lady Tsunade, Shizune and I aren't able
to use medical ninjutsu anymore.
This large-scale battle using
big attacks is taking too long!
And we haven't had
a chance to regroup.
We'll just have to trust young Naruto
to take care of Madara.
This is our chance, Lord Orochimaru!
Not yet.
This foe...
No way!
Shh! Be quiet!
No way! This is—!
What is it?
S-Sa...
Did something happen to Sasuke?
It seems I should do it
sooner than later, after all...
What is it, Ino?
Naruto!
What?
What is that?!
That's Lord Gaara's...!
Over there!
Naruto!
There's no time to explain.
Hokage! Come with me!
Heal Naruto as much you can
while we're en route.
I've depleted my chakra.
I can't use medical ninjutsu anymore.
Take Sakura.
She can still help a little.
How did Naruto
end up like this?!
What happened over there?!
Just come!
Don't waste time! I'll explain later!
Quickly, Sakura, get on the sand!
Right!
How could this happen?!
Is Naruto there?
Yeah! Over there!
Can't you use your Byakugan?
Did he bring down Madara?
Naruto's heartbeat...
is getting weaker and weaker!
Naruto!
Naruto Uzumaki...
We're talking about the Uzumaki Clan,
so I'm sure he's tenacious...
But trying to do anything
for him is useless.
A Jinchuriki dies when
the Tailed Beast is extracted.
– That's an absolute rule!
The fact that you possess
such eyes proves
that you've continued to seek
something despite many great losses.
But it all ends here.
You will lose your very self.
It's what they call a true ending.
I'm not dying.
I... can't... die.
I can't let Itachi's life... be in vain!
No matter what darkness or
contradictions lie within the village...
I am still Itachi Uchiha
of the Leaf!
Not yet... not here...
Until I build a true village...
and become a true Kage.
I'm...
not going to die!
Hang in there! Don't give up!
You are strong! You will make it!
My chakra's almost all...!
S-Sasuke is—!
What's wrong, Karin?
Sasuke is really going to—!
At this rate...
At this rate, Naruto's going to...
– ... die!
The Nine-Tails' chakra...
No heartbeat or pulse...
No way!
Hang in there, Naruto!
What's going on?!
My medical ninjutsu isn't
working on him!
It's probably because the Nine-Tails
has been extracted from him!
That's impossible!
Madara got him.
But there's a way to save him!
That's why we're hurrying!
To where?!
To where the Fourth Hokage is.
Hey, kid! Kazekage! Do me a favor!
His father...
One-half of me is sealed inside
the Fourth Hokage, Minato.
So transplant that other half
into Naruto. That will save him.
Hurry to the Fourth Hokage!
He has the Teleportation Jutsu.
Can't we just contact him over there
somehow and have him come here?
That won't work!
His Teleportation Jutsu is written
into my Sealing Formula.
Once I'm extracted,
it will disappear...
Just rush Naruto over
to the Fourth Hokage.
Got that, Gaara?!
That's what Nine-Tails told me.
Right now, there's no other way
to save Naruto!
How much longer 'til
we get there?
Several kilometers!
I'll do whatever it takes
with what little chakra I have left!
All right!
As long as I'm here,
I am not going to let you die!
I'm going to go at full speed!
Right!
If I could just... save his soul
with my Forbidden Jutsu...
I can't sense any chakra
in him anymore.
I can't even move my body...
let alone use Teleportation.
Damn you, Madara!
Whoa, you're not getting past me.
No one's answered my question yet.
Don't get in my way!
I'm going to Sasuke!
Move, you bastard!
You've got to be kidding!
Karin is amazing.
What is this?!
The same power as
Kushina Uzumaki's.
After all this time,
she's finally attained it...
Oh no...
You just broke my little toy!
Do not... underestimate me!
Double Blast!
Not bad.
I can't move...
A Curse Mark!
Too bad!
A-Amazing...
Orochimaru... They got past it!
It's no big deal.
It's too late even if
you go over there anyway.
Are you all right, Karin?
Yeah... But never mind me.
Sasuke! I can't sense Sasuke!
So this is Six Paths power...
Now, for that left eye.
Who's there?!
There's someone else
where Sasuke is.
Do you recognize the chakra?
No! But...
This chakra...
has a real nasty feel to it!
Let's head to the others with
the Power of Youth at full throttle!!
Lee! Tenten!
Yes, sir! But you're falling over,
Guy-sensei!
Your body isn't keeping up
with your spirit!
That's Gaara's sand...
I think I saw Sakura too...
Why are they retreating?
Kakashi hasn't overtaken
and passed us yet, has he?
No.
The Nine-Tails' chakra we got
from Naruto has disappeared.
And Sakura, a medical ninja,
is on the move...
I have a feeling something
is going down on Kakashi's side.
I feel a little heavy.
There's something catching
in my chest.
The Sage of
Six Paths' ninja Tools, eh?
Useless.
But now I'm lighter.
What will we accomplish
by returning now?
Tenten, don't grumble!
I just have this gut feeling that
some unknown horror is approaching.
Yes, sir.
Are you two all right?!
Yes...!
No way...
These are definitely the—!
You guys are stubborn too!
Obito's consciousness is
no longer stable.
Let's go, Kakashi.
Hold on, Minato!
Switch your chakra to Sensory Mode!
No way!
We were distracted by
what was happening here.
There's no mistake. My other
half has already been extracted!
Sensei?
Kakashi-sensei!
What happened?
The Nine-Tails was extracted
from Naruto!
At this rate he'll—!
Naruto...
Fourth Hokage, I bring a message
from Naruto's Nine-Tails!
He said to seal the other
half of the Nine-Tails
that you have within you into Naruto!
That will save him!
Oh...
Kakashi, he's yours.
I understand.
I'll help!
The current me can...
This time for sure!
What?
That's—!
Nine-Tails...
You're finally mine!
What happened?!
How's Naruto?!
What was that?
No way...
Lord Madara...
You're late, Black Zetsu...
I decided to come to you!
Zetsu... How long are you going
to cling to Obito?
Sorry...
But that allowed me to steal Nine-Tails'
other half from these guys.
Good. Now bring it,
and my left eye, to me.
I sense Sage Power...
And it's much stronger than
what Obito possessed.
So the Fourth Hokage's Nine-Tails
is inside that black thing!
Madara?!
How did he get Six Paths' power?
Since Lord Madara is here,
you can't do anything to me...
even if I separate myself
from Obito.
Now, Kakashi!
Why you—!
You're still—!
Not yet...
I need to
ask you something, Madara.
We need the Nine-Tails inside
that thing for Naruto.
We cannot afford to miss.
We have to wait for
the right moment.
Just what am I... to you?
You're kidding, right?
What kind of stupid question is that,
at this point in time?
You are only one thing to me...
You are Madara.
Now go...
Until the time when
I am revived...
You shall be Madara Uchiha.
Madara is he who rejects the world.
All who hold that in their heart...
and strive toward achieving
the Infinite Tsukuyomi are Madara.
I left you in charge of everything...
And let you act in my stead,
while I slept, waiting to return.
It's the path I guided you towards.
You were supposed to live out
your life as Madara
in order to achieve our goal.
As the savior who rescued this world.
This world laid out by
the Sage of the Six Paths...
has failed.
Now listen...
The chakra dispersed by the Six Paths was
originally meant to be a linking power.
The mental energies of people
would connect and feelings
would be understood without
the need for words...
That would lead to peace and stability.
The one who preached this
as Ninshu, the Ninja Creed
and sought to guide the people,
was the Sage of the Six Paths.
However...
But before long, people used chakra
not to connect with others
but only to combine the mental and
physical energies within themselves.
Through a method of infusing one's
own chakra and increasing it multifold...
they changed chakra into ninjutsu
that could be used as weapons in battle.
Ironically reverting to the way
Six Paths' mother, Kaguya,
had originally used chakra.
Just what the hell is
he talking about?!
Gaara...
I know.
All the Sage of the Six Paths did was
to further the human paradox.
And even if bonds were established...
All they learned was that
true understanding was not possible.
In any case, chakra only gives rise
to conflict and false hope.
We all know the reality all too well...
Even as we seek peace,
we seek war.
And this reality compels
infinite suffering
through the power known as chakra.
Power leads to the desire for war.
And the lack of power leads
to losing everything.
I will build a new world
that overcomes that!
Through the Infinite Tsukuyomi,
I will create a dream world
without any abominable chakra!
I, who possess the most
powerful chakra, shall lead it!
And you are not Obito,
but me... Madara himself.
Obito Uchiha with his Uchiha chakra,
challenged Kakashi Hatake,
desired the title of Hokage,
and yearned for Rin Nohara!
But because his power was false,
he ended up losing everything!
This is hell!
Have you forgotten?!
Come over here.
Yes, come, Madara!
From this day forth,
you are a savior.
You are still the savior, even now.
Sand Wave!
Kamui!
Sage Jutsu!
Rasengan!
No way...
Their combined attack...
Now...
You damned...
What are you doing?!
One who leads others...
is one who never steps
over his friends' corpses...
even if his own ends up
being stepped on.
Then in order to confirm that,
you'll have to become a corpse.
You won't be
stepping on me anymore.
I realize now that letting someone
handle everything in your name
isn't the same as truly
entrusting them with the task.
I am not you.
The current me...
is the one who wanted
to be Hokage... Obito Uchiha!
Obito...
Obito... You've finally found yourself!
I passed through you.
That's your original right eye's power.
Are you trying to weaken me
by taking away the Tailed Beasts?
Do you think you can
challenge me and win?!
So weak...
Is that all? You only tore off a mere
sliver of the One-Tail and Eight-Tails?
Kakashi!
Take Naruto into the Time-Space!
Obito plans to hand him
the Nine-Tails there!
Kamui!
I know that when you teleport
your body materializes...
If I try to teleport carelessly,
he'll come after me.
My teleportation speed is too slow.
Since he'd been in Sage mode once,
he was able to steal some
Sage Power from me too...
Madara...
could have killed me at any time...
I was so scared I forgot to breathe!
Of all the people,
he's in a different class!
All right, I transported Naruto.
All that's left is for you
to teleport yourself there
and Naruto will be saved, right, Obito?
Damn it.
You always talk down to me...
And act so superior...
Just like old times.
This time, I'll take point and
you'll be my backup, Kakashi.
It's been a while since
we were a two-man squad.
Don't stumble, Obito.
Are you prepared for this?
Yeah...
I'm glad my final op will
have been with you.
Obito... Kakashi.
Obito, I'm taking back everything
I loaned you.
Especially that left eye...
Are you worried, Madara?
You told me once that
only with both together
could the Sharingan's true power
be unleashed.
And so...
You're wrong. Those are Rinnegan,
not just Sharingan.
You're wrong.
I was talking about these eyes.
In order to resurrect Naruto,
they need the Rinnegan
and the Nine-Tails.
Obito has them both,
so as long as I don't allow him
to teleport away to his time-space...
And I've already discovered
that my attacks are faster than
their Kamui's transfer speed.
There's no doubt one of them
will try to distract me
while the other performs the Kamui.
Obito will teleport himself or
have Kakashi teleport him.
I should keep it fast and
simple with Limbo...
No... I shouldn't use that as long as
Obito still has the Rinnegan.
Then I'll attack them
both simultaneously!
Kamui!
They both released their Kamui
at the same time!
And doubled the speed of the jutsu!
Obito!
Don't worry.
I'm here to help Naruto...
Can I trust you?
Ever since I was a kid, I've never
been able to walk a straight path.
But I've finally gotten to
where I needed to go.
You actually had
perfect timing for once.
Thanks for saving Kakashi...
Guy!
Are you all right, Kakashi?!
I've seen you before.
Who is that?
Sasuke!
Who is that guy?!
Hey you!
I don't know who the hell you are,
but what are you doing to Sasuke?
Oh, so that's what's going on...
Huh?
So it was you...
... Kabuto.
I sensed a group rushing this way...
It was you, after all, Lord Orochimaru.
That's Kabuto?!
His chakra is different!
Even his appearance.
He has taken in the chakra
of many people,
even Sage Jutsu chakra.
It's no wonder even you thought
he was someone else, Karin...
I wonder if his chakra
had a nasty feel to it
because he still has
some of mine inside him?
– Or...
– Get away from Sasuke, you four-eyes!
What brings you here, Lord Orochimaru?
I should ask you the same thing.
What are you planning, Orochimaru?
Mister Kabuto...
Don't tell me you're going
to absorb Sasuke?
And would that make you
Kabuke or Sasuto?
You're the one who
did this to Sasuke?!
You bastard!
Suigetsu... I don't desire to
do that anymore.
Nor am I going to steal Sasuke, Karin.
Sasuke's chakra!
I can faintly sense it!
No way!
Kabuto... You're helping Sasuke?
Yes.
With my medical ninjutsu and
heavily modified cells of Hashirama,
along with a certain
someone's suggestion,
I managed to save his life.
He's right.
Huh?!
Well, well...
if it isn't the man I most respect...
the Second Hokage,
Lord Tobirama Senju.
However, Kabuto...
You being here means that
you were able to slip out of the
infinite loop set up by Itachi's Izanami?
You're right.
I was unable to acknowledge myself,
I didn't even know who I was.
That allowed you to give me
easy answers and use me.
Making me lose myself even more.
But with that jutsu,
Itachi made me realize...
that I am none other... than Kabuto...
... and where my home is.
Does it seem like the person inside
has changed too?
That is the jutsu known as Izanami.
The jutsu is set up so that
you cannot undo it
until you reflect upon yourself
and accept who you are.
Sasuke...
Now I wish from the bottom of my heart
to not lose my home.
And Itachi, who wanted to
protect Sasuke even unto death...
His feelings have pierced
through my heart strongly.
Hey!
Isn't it a little too late
to say things like that?
You teamed up with that fake Madara!
You guys started this war!
You're right.
Both Obito and I...
... thought we'd lost our place in this world.
And dragged everyone else into this.
But, I now know who I am.
And what I must do!
You may be reinforcements,
but you're nothing more than pebbles.
You won't make any difference
at this point.
That's Madara?!
Yes, that's him.
Kakashi, are you all right?
Yes, thanks to Guy.
I don't mean that.
I'm talking about my Sage Art
Rasengan hitting you earlier.
That was okay too.
I diverted it with my Kamui
just as it was making contact.
Kamui!
I'm glad...
Sage Art?
You mean, senjutsu?
Yes.
Only senjutsu works against him...
As well as...
physical attacks such as taijutsu.
If I recall, Sensei,
senjutsu isn't your forte...
Yes.
In all honesty, I'm weak in senjutsu.
It takes me too long to infuse the chakra
and I can't maintain it very long.
I haven't used it very much
in combat either.
Furthermore, in this state,
I can't weave signs,
so I don't think
I can even fight effectively.
So, it's showtime
for the wild blue beast, eh?
Eight Inner Gates!
Seventh Gate of Shock!
Open!
Blue vapor?
Eight Inner Gates...
One gate before the Gate of Death...
He insults me,
not bringing out the Red Vapor.
Don't let the black spheres
or rod touch you!
Take this!
Hirudora! Daytime Tiger!
Kakashi, take the kunai!
Right!
Rock Lee!
How is Tenten?
She wanted to check something out,
and made me go on ahead.
Just when I was about to catch up...
all of a sudden
the Hirudora appeared.
Are you all right, Guy?
Yeah.
Only my right arm and
a few ribs are hurt.
What are we going to do
if our last ray of hope, your taijutsu...
is no good?
He's... too strong.
Wait, Kakashi...
It's too soon to decide
my taijutsu won't work!
But...
Our youth hasn't faded yet!
Do not lose hope!
Guy-sensei...
It's true that everything we wish for
will not come to be...
But things that we must do
must always begin with a wish.
Just like the times I challenged you.
I challenge you, Kakashi!
And this is not a bluff.
Don't tell me...
you're going to—!
The end has come for
the Leaf's Blue Beast...
It's time for the Red Beast to emerge!
No way... Not the final Gate of Death!
Guy! Don't do that!
Think it over hard!
No one here wishes for that!
Not even your father would...
No!
But I wish it.
Guy-sensei!
Do you really think it's that time?
Lee, don't look at me like that.
This time, you sit back
and enjoy the show!
You remind me of myself back then,
when I was a complete failure.
Now, in matches against
that elite genius Kakashi,
we're nearly even.
"Even if I cannot do ninjutsu or genjutsu...
I want to prove that can still
become a splendid ninja?"
Isn't that your ninja way?
That's a fine goal.
It's a goal worth fighting for.
So you must believe in your path
and run hard toward it!
Become strong so I can just sit back
and enjoy the show!
Guy! You fool!
I'm sorry, Papa...
I'm already five years old,
but I can't even run 500 laps...
Do not apologize!
I'm not scolding you because of that!
Never apologize for trying hard!
It's an insult to your determination, Guy!
Then why?
You're applying your self-rule
in the wrong manner!
Doing 500 laps will qualify you
for the vacant place in the academy?
That's not a self-rule!
That's just a wish!
The kind you make a prayer for!
You see,
you impose a self-rule on yourself
to spur you on
and help you overcome
a challenge or difficult situation.
You apply a self-rule on yourself only.
Because of that rule,
you are able to gather your strength
and focus on your efforts...
So even if you fail,
applying that rule keeps you
extremely disciplined and focused.
That is the way a self-rule works.
I'm sorry, Papa...
However, no one can find fault
in your determination.
Even if you can only make it half way,
effort is effort.
And for that, you deserve a big hug!
Papa!
Guy!
Oh... there they go again,
that father and son.
Isn't that abuse?
Anyway, what's with those bodysuits?
Gross!
Thank you for your support!
Papa, I don't think that was support...
Then, encouragement.
I guess... I can't do ninjutsu or genjutsu...
so that's why I failed the test...
Listen, Guy!
Your youth has just begun!
Do not turn your back on your youth!
Just like me!
As your father,
I'm happy that ninjutsu
and genjutsu aren't your strong points!
Knowing your shortcomings
will highlight your strengths!
Your taijutsu is already
shining brilliantly!
I'm very happy!
I've discovered my own child's strengths
when he's still so young!
Papa, you're just saying that, aren't you?
Shortcomings can become strengths!
Being repetitious is just being polite!
To be loud is simply to be lively!
Obstinacy is merely earnestness!
Those who are selfish are like cats!
What about hairy people?
Mmm... Th-They're like cats too!
What about people with long torsos...?
Th-They're like cats!
Hey, Might Dai...
Are you playing "training"
with your son again?
You sure work hard for a perennial Genin!
Yeah! Thanks for your support!
Damn it! Still trying to
act young at his age.
Right?
Oww!
What?!
Aren't you Dai's kid?!
What's the big idea?
Don't you ever say anything stupid
about my papa ever again!
A fool is a fool.
I just spoke the truth.
If you say one bad word about Papa,
I'll punch you five times!
That's my self-rule!
Your self-rule? Interesting.
So I'll say it.
Your dad is a good-for-nothing
who can't do ninjutsu or genjutsu,
and can't even do taijutsu that well.
You know what they say?
He's more a comedian
than a Genin.
Yeah, a comedian who
only tells jokes about youth isn't funny!
You said two bad things!
That's ten punches!
And we'll punch you 20 times!
Damn it!
I can't believe you couldn't
return a single punch
after what they said about your father.
Guy, why did you do
such a thing?!
Papa...
Papa... How can you stay
so positive and optimistic?
When does one's youth
come to an end?
As long as you never turn your back
against youth, it never ends.
Then are you saying your youth won't come
to an end when you die, Papa?!
What are you saying, Guy?!
That is when youth climaxes!
When it burns the brightest!
There's something wrong
with you, Papa!
Youth doesn't matter
a bit when you die!
You can believe in it until you die,
but there's no guarantee you'll win
against someone strong!
Just like me...
True victory isn't about winning
against someone strong.
It's about defending
what's important to you!
I just wanted...
to protect this youth that
you always talk about!
Now pay close attention, Guy.
Father... What is this?!
The Eight Inner Gates...
A type of Forbidden Jutsu!
Father mastered such
a technique? When did he...?
As a Genin, I practiced every day,
and finally grasped this unique jutsu
after twenty years.
Twenty years!
To put it plainly,
this is the one and only jutsu that
I can pass on to you as your father.
And it shall become
a most special technique to you!
Special?
You have become
a splendid shinobi!
But I shall impose
one strict condition
upon the use of this technique.
A self-rule!
A self-rule...
Father...
His chakra is spreading toward
the Death Gate's chakra point.
Father...
The Eighth Gate... of Death!
It's no good... We're surrounded.
There's no way we can escape.
No way...
Aren't they the Seven Ninja
Swordsmen of the Mist?!
So even brats from other villages
know who we are?
We've gotten pretty famous.
What's this? It's slight,
but the blade's gotten chipped!
I have to let it suck some blood
and restore it with iron.
What'll we do? We can't take
them on by ourselves!
I made it just in time!
Father!
You're a Genin, Father!
What are you doing here?!
Never mind, just run away!
I'll buy you some time!
Run away?!
Father!
They are Jonin, and on top of that,
they're the Seven Ninja Swordsmen!
You're no match for them!
I have the Gate of Death...
the Eight Inner Gates Formation!
But that's—!
I'm going by my self-rule!
Now is the time...
Open! Eight Inner
Gates Formation!
... to protect something precious enough
to give your life for!
Guy, are you really going to—!
I can't believe this.
Red vapor...
The unique vapor of blood...
from the opening of all eight gates...
But actually seeing it
with my own eyes...
It's almost like the color
of dead autumn leaves
that have fallen off their tree...
You're right.
But they're not falling
for any reason or purpose...
They become the nutrients...
for fresh green leaves!
And the period they bridge,
until the new spring
when fresh leaves bud...
... is the climax of youth!
When it burns most crimson!
Sekizo, Evening Elephant!
First Step!
Second Step!
He stopped midway?!
The Evening Elephant is supposed
to be a continuous attack
that can be shifted up in speed
from one to five times...
I see, what unbelievable pain.
But I've acclimated.
Next time, I can keep it going without
giving him any openings.
Great stress is placed on
the body even through
the Fifth Gate, the Gate of Closing...
I bet the Gate of Death's
level of pain
is something that exceeds
my imagination!
A taijutsu move that bombards
with blows of punched air...
An air cannon, so to speak...
Taking four or five of those
would be bad.
I should definitely avoid getting hit
by the fists creating them too.
One rarely gets to fight
the Eight Inner Gates Formation!
I'm game! I'll play with you!
He's coming towards me
by kicking air!
Lee, are you—?
I am not sad!
Showing any pity or sorrow
to someone
who has resolved himself
would be an insult!
We must assist Guy.
Listen up.
Sensei...
Those black weapons of his
are troublesome...
They're not the activating-from
-Nothing type,
but an always-on-standby
type that undergo Change in Form.
Their impact points disappear,
but there is clear sensation
if they make contact with you.
Also, he can only send them
about 70 meters out.
Any further than that,
and he'll lose control over them.
Since they actually exist and
can be seen with the eye,
your Kamui should work on them.
By sending them away,
we can prevent Madara from
controlling them.
To be honest, I'm beginning
to lose sight in my left eye.
I'll have to get pretty close to
target my Kamui accurately.
Gaara, can you prepare some sand?
You want me to transport Kakashi
with my sand, right?
But my sand isn't fast enough
to avoid his attacks.
Don't worry.
That's where I come in.
I'll have Kakashi carry
one of my kunai.
Eight Inner Gates:
The Sixth Gate of Joy!
Open!
Lee!
You've mastered
the Eight Inner Gates too?!
I can only open up to
the Sixth Gate...
I've never cursed my own lack
of power as I do now!
No... That's enough, Lee.
Because you're still...
... a fresh new leaf Guy wants
to risk his life to protect!
Lee, I want you to stay here
to support and guard Gaara.
And one more thing...
Take one of my kunai.
First Step!
He is fast!
Second Step!
Third Step!
Fourth Step!
I can't move!
Fifth Step!
Just keep going, Guy!
No matter what!
Here he comes!
Great timing, Lee!
Kamui!
You're the first since Hashirama
to make me feel this excited!
Can you still dance?
Do you have any
other techniques?
Give me some more fun!
He got up from a barrage of Sekizo?
Where am I?
Did I die?
What makes thee think
that thou art dead?
Thine ethical viewpoint
on death differs much
from that which prevailed
in my time...
To so easily replace oneself
with the term "death"...
Thou must gain mettle,
oh fledgling.
Who are you?
'Tis quite a precise query
for this place, but...
I am quite uneasy over
whether thou shalt be able
to connect my name with
my actions as a herald...
I am he who shall achieve
peace and order...
My name is Hagoromo.
On the other hand...
I had foreseen
that thou wouldst end up
in such a state as that.
Uh... I don't understand
what the hell he's saying.
He seems to be one of
those lecturing geezers!
Hey, Gramps, sorry.
But, I...
Now then...
Hey! Those eyes!
Rinnegan!
Thou dost appear to
possess observant eyes.
All that remains is for thee
to pragmatically comprehend
thy circumstances.
Thou hast not died yet...
This place is within thy mind.
I understand thine haste,
– This geezer's not an enemy?
– but at this moment,
– rushing will accomplish naught.
But...
Can't you speak a little more smoothly,
using easy, normal words?
I am an anachronism.
Over the passage of much time,
cultural traditions and
notions, and ethics
have brought about
significant change.
Each occurrence where I cross
time and meet a reincarnate,
I have come to sense greatly the
differences between the other and myself...
I was also able to regulate
things systematically and
learn new mores and words, however...
Shut up already!
I don't have the time
to be sitting around
and listening to
some weird geezer!
Not just searching for words...
But there is ambiguity
in scholarship.
If communication of wills
cannot be achieved
in addition to difficulty of definition...
I see that I must speak simply...
taking into account current idealistic
and materialistic thinking.
Are you an alien or something?
I mean, you seem
super dignified, but...
Uh, that's a bit much, doncha think?
An alien? Seriously?
Well, maybe that ain't too far off.
So anyway...
Do you still fail to understand me?
To think that conversation would
pose such a complex challenge...
No! Keep talking like just now.
I finally get you!
I was just shocked because
your speaking style
changed so drastically, ya know?
Oh, for real?
Then I'll keep going like this.
I appreciate it!
Uh, yeah.
Oh but, those words don't match up
with your face at all,
so it's kind of super-scary...
And he loses all dignity too.
You should be just a bit more formal.
Otherwise, you come off
kind of dumb.
Now you're going too far, no?
What do you mean by dumb?!
Well, considering how
I was talking before,
I guess I can't blame you for that.
So how's this then?
That's it! All right!
That's perfect!
Indeed. I'm getting
the hang of it too.
Finally, I can talk with you.
So anyway, Gramps, who are you?
If you know a lot about this place,
tell me how to get out of here!
Don't ask so many questions
all at once!
I am a person of the past,
someone long dead.
A monk who wanders through
this world as chakra,
crossing generations, ascertaining
the course of Ninshu, the Ninja Creed.
My name is Hagoromo,
the founder of the Ninja Creed.
I'm also known as
the Sage of Six Paths.
What?! The Sage of Six Paths?!
The sage from the legends that
Pervy Sage and Nagato talked about?
Oh, so you know about me?
Of course, I do!
You're the one who
created ninjutsu, right?
Not ninjutsu...
Ninshu, the Ninja Creed.
My Ninja Creed was something
meant to inspire hope.
Do not confuse it with ninjutsu
which breeds conflict!
In any case, if you're the sage,
I've got tons of things
I want to ask you.
But first, right now...
Anyway, the conditions are
all in place now.
Quit speaking in riddles and
let me out of here!
Forgive me... That is something I have
no influence over.
That depends on the actions
of those outside.
I can only relay things to you.
I'm not getting what
you're saying again!
It means right now,
trying to rush won't make
any difference.
So I want you to listen for a bit...
No, you must listen...
First, about my mother and sons.
My mother, Kaguya Otsutsuki,
came to this land of yours
from a faraway place.
She came in search of
the fruit of the Divine Tree.
The chakra fruit of
that same Divine Tree,
that you have seen in this war.
Kaguya consumed the fruit,
attained power, and subdued this land.
Where'd Kaguya come from?
Is she stronger than you,
Sage of Six Paths?
I guess all moms are scary
when they're mad, huh?
It matters not where
she came from.
Mother was powerful...
More powerful than any other.
Some called my mother
the Rabbit Goddess
and others considered her
a demon...
They both worshiped her
and feared her.
Later, Kaguya would birth two sons.
I was one of them.
We brothers, to atone for
the crimes mother left behind,
battled Ten-Tails, an incarnation
of the Divine Tree,
and sealed it inside me.
The Divine Tree,
robbed of its Chakra Fruit,
went on a rampage in
an attempt to recover it.
Much, much later,
I had two sons of my own.
I named the elder, Indra,
and the younger, Ashura,
and I taught them
the Ninja Creed.
But there was a huge difference
between the two.
One possessed genes containing my
powerful chakra and the other did not.
And this difference manifested
itself extremely.
It's getting complicated again,
ya know?
What does this all mean?
In short...
There was the exceptional
older brother, Indra...
and the dunce
younger brother, Ashura.
A dunce, huh?
Even though his dad's
the Sage of Six Paths?
Perhaps there's no need
to say this to you, but...
No matter how exceptional
both parents may be,
there's no guarantee one will inherit
either of their abilities outright.
Sound familiar?
Just as it seems to have been
in your case, Naruto.
For some reason,
I understand that completely.
And you are truly similar
to Ashura, in your actions as well.
Huh? My actions?
Indra and Ashura walked
different paths in life.
Elder brother, Indra, possessed
strong visual prowess
and senses from birth,
and was called a genius.
He always did everything alone,
leaning only on his own strength
and came to understand that his powers
were different and special.
He perceived that power could
achieve everything.
On the other hand, nothing ever went well
for the younger brother, Ashura,
from the time he was young.
And he couldn't do anything
on his own.
In order to attain the same power
as his older brother,
he needed the cooperation of others
in addition to his own effort.
While struggling through training,
the power of bodily chakra awakened
within Ashura
and he attained power
rivaling his brother's.
He came to understand that
he was able to become strong,
thanks to the cooperation and
help of those around him.
He learned of the love for others that
arises from thinking about others...
And perceived that it was love
that can achieve everything.
In the way that the younger one
chose to live his life...
I thought I caught a glimpse
of new possibilities.
I partitioned the power of
the Ten-Tails inside of me,
and named each of the pieces...
And believed that the bond known
as "cooperation" was true power.
I then named
the younger brother, Ashura,
the leader and guardian
of the Ninja Creed,
believing that his elder brother, Indra,
would cooperate with his younger brother.
However...
Indra did not accept my decision.
And thus from that day on,
... interminable conflict began.
Even after their flesh perished,
the chakra the two honed
continued to reincarnate across time,
without vanishing...
over and over.
It kind of sounds like being
haunted by a ghost. It's creepy.
So, is it still possessing
someone even now?
It's you, Naruto.
The younger brother Ashura has
reincarnated as you.
You don't seem too surprised.
Perhaps, you have sensed
Ashura's presence inside you already?
I thought as much.
Then you must know already...
who is the reincarnate
of the older one, Indra...
Sasuke...
Yes. You sensed it, after all.
It seems that there were
other reincarnates
besides Sasuke and me...
Who were the others?
The first generation of reincarnates
were Hashirama Senju and Madara Uchiha.
Hashirama was Ashura.
Madara was Indra.
You know how they ended up.
However, before Madara could end
his life as a reincarnate,
he created a certain problem.
Madara was so obsessed with power
that he stole some of Hashirama's cells.
Which, in short, caused the merging
of a portion of Ashura's chakra
with Indra's chakra...
And the result was that
it essentially became my own chakra.
That's right,
he awakened the Rinnegan.
I always thought that someone
like that would appear
among either Indra
or his reincarnates.
Hence, I left behind
the stone tablet
that contained my writings
on how to deal with this.
Although, it seems no one could
understand its meaning...
So, Six Paths Gramps, you've been watching
your kids' sibling rivalry
all this time?
Yes, I suppose you could say that.
I see...
Through Ninshu,
I preached that chakra is the power
that links individuals.
I strongly believe that chakra
should not be something
that amplifies the strength
of one person alone.
Even after my mother, Kaguya,
put an end to chaotic times,
she ruled with her power alone.
However, my mother's power
bred arrogance within her.
And mankind began to dread
the existence of that power.
That is why my mother,
once known as the Rabbit Goddess,
became feared as a demon.
When power is concentrated
in one person,
that power runs rampant and
in time, it possesses the person.
The current Madara is
a prime example of that...
He's become just like
my mother, Kaguya.
Now, he's no longer
Indra's incarnate.
He's obtained Ten-Tails' power
and is getting close to me.
And he is trying to obtain even
my mother Kaguya's power.
The Infinite Tsukuyomi doesn't
just cast genjutsu over you.
It keeps you trapped
inside genjutsu dreams,
so that the caster can use your
individual power while keeping you alive.
You're attached to the roots of the
Divine Tree, and turned into living slaves.
Mother possessed the power
of Sharingan as well as Byakugan.
She used her visual prowess to cast
that jutsu upon the populace.
It was a ghastly jutsu.
If all chakra were to
be reunited into one again,
a new Chakra Fruit
would take shape.
That must be prevented
at all costs...
or this world will end.
I would like you to stop Madara.
Unlike the previous reincarnates,
you tend to be a little bit of a fool.
But there may be potential
in your unpredictability.
Even long after you died,
you tried to protect the world...
And even when
it's turned out like this,
you still have faith in us.
Thank you.
Don't thank me.
I don't deserve it.
If the current world desires Indra's,
or rather, my mother's way...
and if that's the natural flow...
then I'm the one who's selfishly
trying to go against it and stop it.
Even in terms of how
the Tailed Beasts are being used,
not for maintaining peace and balance,
but only as weapons...
Perhaps my way is naïve.
No!
You're not wrong, Gramps!
You're absolutely right, old man!
Oh, aren't you Gaara's?
Why are you inside of me?
You see, Obito...
Octopops!
He extracted a portion of Shukaku's
and my chakra from Madara.
He knew exactly which Tailed Beast
powers you were lacking, that guy!
Obito did that?
A lot of things happened.
He even put me inside of you.
Now you've got the chakra of all
nine Tailed Beasts within you, Naruto!
Even you?
The other half of Kurama?
The promised time has
finally come, old man Six Paths!
You're right, my dear Kurama...
Just as Gamamaru prophesied...
a blue-eyed youth who can name all
nine beasts and frolic among them.
Prophesied? You mean the prophecy
Giant Gramps Sage passed on
to the Pervy Sage?
Gamamaru is his real name?
You're pretty awesome because
you know that, Gramps!
Hey, Naruto!
You truly have the ability
to win others' cooperation.
You managed to summon my soul.
And accepted that Ashura has
reincarnated inside of you.
Shukaku.
Matatabi.
Isobu.
Son Goku.
Kokuo.
Saiken.
Chomei.
Gyuki.
Kurama.
It seems the time has come for the
child of prophecy to change the world.
My dear Naruto...
What do you want to do?
What do you seek for
the aftermath of this war?
I would like to hear
your honest thoughts and opinions.
Maybe I'm really like
this Ashura guy.
Only... unlike him,
I'm just a stupid kid
who doesn't know much
about a lot of things.
But, I do know what friends are.
And I want to protect them all.
That's it.
Is that your answer?
Yeah...
Long ago, I entrusted
everything to Ashura and
cast my attention away
from Indra.
That proved to be
the source of calamity.
Put out your dominant arm.
This time, I am also entrusting
my power to you, Indra's reincarnate.
From this point on,
Naruto and Sasuke...
What you both shall do,
and what shall transpire,
will be up to the two of you.
Naruto and I...
Sasuke and I...
... may not be real brothers,
but I really believe that
we can make peace.
Because we're pretty good friends.
Now then...
Hey, Kabuto!
Sasuke's... Sasuke's going
to be okay, right?
Hey, say something, you—!
Obito!
Is Naruto all right?
Naruto the Jinchuriki will die if
his Tailed Beast is extracted...
But I put the Tailed Beast
back inside him.
He should be okay now.
Sasuke!
Naruto!
– Time to go.
Guy-sensei!
Even that... didn't work...
Sekizo... isn't enough!
This is great!
Keep on dancing!
All that's left... is Night Guy!
That stance is not the Sekizo!
Don't tell me he has something
even greater!
Guy!
Come on, Dad, hurry!
There's no need to rush.
The Academy isn't going
to run away, is it?
There's a set time for
entrance applications.
Oh, nice to meet you!
My son will be attending
the Academy.
Dad...
I hope those two
will get along okay.
I'm afraid that will
be impossible!
Huh? What a thing to say!
Are you one of those overbearing parents?!
No, Dad... You're wrong.
He failed the Academy
entrance exam.
Oh, pardon me! I just assumed
since you were in front of the Academy.
Don't worry about it!
Uh, I don't think it's anything
to be laughing about.
Hey, Kakashi, don't be rude.
But Dad, you were a lot ruder
just a minute ago.
I mean, this guy is trying
to get into the Academy
even though he can't
use ninjutsu.
Oops, we should get going,
or we're going to be late.
Right.
Excuse me.
Your name's Kakashi Hatake, right?
Thank you for your support!
Kakashi...
Don't slack off just because
you got into the Academy.
At the rate he's training,
that boy will become
stronger than you.
He will?
They haven't announced
the alternates yet, have they?
The Academy isn't dumb.
You should ask what his name is
and remember it.
What...?
He'll be a good rival for you.
Hey, you!
What's your name?
Might Guy!
I'm going to become stronger
than anyone around!
Dad, it ended up exactly
as you predicted.
Guy!
I'll acknowledge this chakra of yours!
Of all those who have
fought me over the years,
there's no one who surpasses you in taijutsu!
I, Madara, declare you the strongest!
Flow!
He's fast!
What?!
He's bending space?
Night Guy!
Guy-sensei?
That was Guy's final move!
What happened?
I almost died, you bastard!
Your flame is about to go out...
But as a parting gift for
such a great time,
I'll finish you off...
before you turn to ash on your own!
He kicked away my Truth-Seeker Orb?!
Bushier Brow-sensei...
Naruto...?
You seem a little different
from before.
What did Obito do?
Yeah...
I'm still trying to figure it out myself.
But I think I can change
everything now!
That node's chakra hasn't gone out.
Don't tell me he stopped
the end result of the Eight Gates?!
He touched the Truth-Seeker Orb,
so how can he—?
Is it because
I haven't finished healing yet?
No!
His power is suddenly growing?!
Son!
Lend me some of your chakra, okay?
All right!
Sage Art: Lava Style Rasen Shuriken!
Th-This is bad!
Limbo!
What?! He dodged... my Limbo?!
All right!
Burst!
Take me within you.
Who is that?!
Take the Divine Tree...
Ten-Tails...
... everything, into you.
The tree disappeared!
Guy-sensei!
Bushier Brow-sensei
is going to be okay!
He's not going to die!
Naruto, you healed him?
But I thought he had activated
all Eight Gates...
I feel like I can
do all sorts of things...
the way I am right now!
He touched Madara's rods,
but he wasn't affected...
What happened to him
while he was dying?
Can you teleport, Lord Second?
I see...
Yeah... Since I'm linked to
the Fourth's markings.
But unfortunately...
At my current strength,
I can only teleport one person.
That's plenty.
I alone need to go.
Bushy Brow and Gaara,
take care of Bushier Brow-sensei.
Naruto...
Thank you for... Guy-sensei...
When you become Hokage,
let's have a drink together.
You got it!
Is that Naruto?!
Obito...
You...
You're an enemy.
You hurt and killed
many of my comrades...
I don't want to say this, but...
I'm going to consider you
an ally just this once.
Thank you for saving Naruto.
I have one final favor to ask you.
Not as an ally, but as an enemy...
I understand now...
The Divine Tree itself...
The time has come
for all to become one.
Is it because
I met the Sage Gramps
and got more power from him?
I can feel it clearly even
from here...
The other half of
Gramps' power.
You cannot take me down.
Essentially, I am completely immortal now.
I have obtained eternity!
You idiot!
I'm not taking you down...
We're going to take you down!
Your time has come, Madara.
One has awakened
the Six Paths' Senjutsu...
and the other awakened
the Rinnegan, huh?
However... I possess
both of those powers!
This is the final battle!
My powers versus yours...
Let's settle who is superior,
once and for all!
Sage Art:
Yin Style Thunder Blast!
Sasuke's gone?!
This left eye...
So that's what it can do...
Teleportation? This distance...?
No, he didn't teleport!
You should pay attention!
Limbo!
What is that?!
He did it again!
Sage Art:
Storm Style Fang of Light!
It's coming again!
Over there!
It didn't hit.
Sasuke, it's headed your way!
Something I can't see is
lurking around you.
Oh yeah? I can see it clearly!
These guys can see my Limbo...
It's... another Madara.
So he can see it with his Rinnegan...
And that one,
can't see it but senses it...
Naruto!
Looks like our physical attacks...
have no effect on
the other Madara.
Yeah!
Normally, one shouldn't be able to
sense or see it from this realm...
That "me" exists in
the invisible world of "Limbo."
How did they both obtain
such power so suddenly?
That Sasuke Uchiha...
He was the only one who
awakened the straight pattern,
Choku-Tomoe Sharingan
just like mine.
Perhaps Sasuke and I share
a bond that goes beyond blood.
Well then...
That left eye should suit me perfectly!
So, that's your left eye's
ability as well.
Then try it.
That's not enough to kill you, is it?
So the Six Paths' Sage chakra can
affect the shadow Madara too, huh?
That wound on his right arm...
is from blocking
Naruto's first attack earlier.
It seems your shadow returns to
your body after a certain amount of time.
Naruto, when his shadow
emerges again, go after it.
I'll take on the visible one. However...
I used to hate it when
you would order me around...
Some things never change, huh?
Let me finish.
This is our chance.
Madara and his shadow will probably
stay merged for a little while longer.
I don't care what it is,
but get a Sage Power Jutsu ready.
One that seals movement.
Then you should use my chakra
to build your Sealing Jutsu.
Thanks... ummm...
It's Shukaku!
He's estimating the Limbo's duration,
activation interval
and how to counter it...
He's got a sharp intuition,
calm analyzing and
judgment skills,
and a Choku-Tomoe Sharingan
just like mine.
If he had only been born
before Obito...
he would be my...
No... There's no point
in reflecting now.
No matter what's happened,
I must keep in mind that
these two aren't ordinary brats.
I need to get
my other eye back soon.
Sage Art: Magnet Style Rasengan!
And I have Six Paths Power too...
Chidori!
Naruto, shoot that towards me!
I'll take care of the rest.
It's a bit irritating,
but there's no time to argue!
Why am I here?
Naruto, the jutsu the Sage of
Six Paths gave you...
You know it, right?
Yeah, the time is now!
What?
He moved?
He substituted his shadow?
Over there!
Sasuke, I'll hold this one down,
so go after the real one!
Seems like his Rinnegan
can't reach this distance.
I'm starting to understand
your left eye's abilities, Sasuke.
Hurry, Sasuke!
Madara is heading straight for...
Kakashi-sensei!
Hurry and destroy my Rinnegan...
I can't hold off Black Zetsu any longer.
I must admit Sasuke sure is fast.
Kamui!
Damn!
Just his upper body, huh?
Hurry!
I know!
Oh no, you don't!
Kamui!
Sakura!
Kakashi-sensei.
Sasuke?!
Why did you pop up here, Sakura?
She was in the Time-Space dimension...
Sakura, what's going on
over there?
Kakashi-sensei, your left eye!
It all happened so quickly.
But I think Madara stole my Sharingan.
Let me take a look, Sensei!
Thanks.
In any case, what happened to Obito?
I'm sure Madara used the Kamui
to teleport himself there!
In a flash,
I was back out here, so...
What's wrong, Sakura?!
We're in trouble!
Obito had reached his limit
and couldn't move...
Which means Madara's going
to get Obito's Rinnegan!
The Cursed Seal Tag I placed on
your heart has disappeared.
How did you remove it?
You shouldn't have been able
to damage it yourself.
I had Kakashi stab me
and remove it.
This is all I can do right now.
Since it was in the way
of me making myself
into the Ten-Tails' Jinchuriki...
I gambled my life on it...
But I wasn't going to keep
doing what you wanted!
Actually, you did exactly
what I wanted you to do.
In fact, you exceeded my hopes.
What's so funny?
A Curse Seal Tag meant to
turn you into a puppet...
One that would restrict your movements,
should you try to remove it from
inside the body it's implanted in.
It seems you knew about it, Obito.
Regarding these Cursed Tags
I implanted in the two of you...
Naturally, you couldn't have
killed yourselves either.
Since you both were
my precious pawns.
"You both" ...?
As fate would have it...
It's ironic that both of
you ended up
getting rid of them through
the exact same method.
Rin!
Yes.
That plot to make that girl
into the Three-Tails' Jinchuriki
and have her rampage through
the Leaf Village was mine.
Not the Hidden Mist's!
That girl took advantage of
Kakashi's attack against the enemy
to avert the plot,
at the cost of her life.
But that was also part
of my plan...
In order to plunge you into darkness
and make you into my pawn.
You bastard, you deliberately
had me see all that!
I waited for the opportunity,
when Minato was away
on another mission.
And manipulated the Mist shinobi
into kidnapping Rin,
leaving Kakashi
so he would come after her.
The other purpose of that
was so I could see the extent
of your unleashed power.
Did you really think that
White Zetsu goading you on,
and you being able to get out
from underground right at that moment
was all a big coincidence?
Either way, I would have had
my Puppet Shinobi kill her.
I taught you to use the darkness
in people's hearts...
to manipulate them, didn't I, Obito?
If there isn't any darkness,
you can create some.
Don't you think it's presumptuous
to consider yourself any different?
Why? Why me?!
You were kind and cared about
people from the bottom of your heart.
Remember how great you were
at taking care of the elderly?
Your deep love for Rin...
for your comrades and friends...
for the Hokage and
all other shinobi...
Once you fell into darkness,
it would conversely transform
into an equally profound
hatred for this world.
That's the kind of guy you are.
I'll be taking back that left eye.
This should do it!
You can't move anymore.
I'm leaving him to you!
Right! You can count on me!
We don't know when Madara
might emerge. Stay alert.
What about his shadow?
I stopped him cold with
my Shadow Clones and
Six Paths' Rods!
Naruto?
Hey, Sakura...
Let me do it!
What are you trying to do, Naruto?
Hey!
It's okay, it's okay.
Kakashi-sensei,
try opening your eye.
No way! How did you do that?
It's really hard to explain in words...
But I took a part of Kakashi-sensei,
and then I kinda... um... uhh...
Hey, Naruto...
I told everyone to stay alert!
What?
But it's the first time
I'm hearing of it!
Quit talking back
for once, Naruto!
Anyway, you'll have to explain
about the eye later!
Madara stole Kakashi's eye
and went to where Obito is.
The next time he appears,
he'll have both Rinnegan!
What? Really?
Let's see, we'll start
with the introductions.
I'll go! I'll go!
I'm Naruto Uzumaki!
I love instant cup ramen.
But I really love
the ramen at Ichiraku
that Iruka-sensei treats me to
even more!
I hate having to
wait three minutes
after pouring the hot water
into the cup.
My future dream is...
to surpass the Hokage!
And that's why I'm going to
make everyone in the village...
acknowledge me!
My name is Sasuke Uchiha.
There are lots of things I hate.
And not many things I like.
Also... I have no intention of
saying I have a dream,
but I do have an ambition.
That is...
to kill a certain man one day.
I'm Sakura Haruno.
What I like... I mean,
who I like is... um...
My future dream is...
You've already surpassed
the Hokage, Naruto.
You're a hero and
everyone has acknowledged you.
But becoming Hokage
is still your dream.
And Sakura...
I bet your feelings for Sasuke
have changed from
what they were back then.
You still love him,
but on a totally different level.
He tried to kill you,
yet you still care for him.
You won't cut him off,
no matter what.
And you think it's your duty
to save him from the darkness.
That's how kind you are.
Sasuke...
Your dream was to kill Itachi.
Now that he's gone,
what do you desire?
What are you heading towards?
I was your teacher,
but it turned out that
I didn't understand you at all.
Even now...
Sasuke...
What is your dream now?
It might be fate
that reunited the old
Team 7 like this, Sasuke.
If you don't want to say what
you're thinking right now, that's fine.
But the fact that we were
once Team 7 is indisputable...
Right?
In front! He's coming!
You haven't forgotten the lesson
from the very first mission
to steal the bells, have you?
Yes!
Of course not!
The answer is teamwork!
Then dying together can also
be considered teamwork, eh?
Madara... you have both Rinnegan.
His lower body has
completely healed.
Obito!
Unfortunately, Obito is gone.
I've taken over his body now.
Seems he was hoping
to right his wrongs.
He was praying like
a child, deep inside...
so that he could leave
the future to you all.
How convenient that would
have been for him, right?
Just like a spoiled brat.
I can't blame her.
Given the power of those eyes.
I'm not retreating anymore.
I'll be the diversion.
So follow me!
Wait!
Sakura!
The same Mitotic Regeneration Jutsu
as Hashirama's granddaughter.
What?!
An invisible wall?!
I can't reach him!
What's happening?!
Sakura...
Don't worry about me, Naruto.
I'm all right, so...
Naruto!
Yeah, I know!
There are more of them, right?
That left eye is a Rinnegan!
Madara's got four shadows now.
Enough with this sideshow.
What is he up to?
Planetary Devastation!
Retreat for the time being!
What about Naruto and the others?!
They will pull through,
no matter what!
This is Six Paths' power?
He's way bigger than before
and there's more of 'em...
Stop getting distracted
by what's above!
His shadows are
on the ground with us!
They're a bit more solid and
larger than raindrops, but...
Here they come!
The shadows as well!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Leave them to me!
I guess I'll just record
their final moments!
Kurama...
Yeah!
Susano'o!
Tailed Beast Bomb Rasen Shuriken!
Damn it!
There's no end to them!
Unbelievable...
Damn you!
According to that stone tablet.
When the one who possesses
the power of the Rinne,
should draw near the moon...
the eye that can reflect off
of the moon,
and grant the infinite dream,
shall open.
Shine upon the world...
Infinite Tsukuyomi.
Wha—?!
What is this?
It's finally started...
I'm done with this!
Then we don't need these vessels
anymore either.
Again?!
What's all this shaking?
Over at 4 o'clock! Meteorites!
There are so many!
Brace for impact!
What's happening over there?!
That's not normal!
Something big is happening
over there, that's for sure.
Most likely, it's something bad.
What's the matter, Kiba?!
Shino...
The moon! Look at the moon!
This can't be!
What is happening?
This is really bad.
I'll pulverize all the meteorites
with these next, so don't worry.
You two stick close to me
and stay still!
Okay!
I have to make sure
I don't hit Sasuke!
Go!
Sasuke, don't head down here
so suddenly!
I could've hit you with
a Rasen Shuriken—!
Hey! Land more softly too!
Just shut up and stay still!
Now! Become one!
Those eyes...
Don't tell me Madara's launched
his jutsu already!
This light can penetrate and
see through even shadows...
No one can hide from it.
And now...
Divine Deep Forest Emergence!
Get a hold of yourself, Tsunade!
What is going on?
I can't move!
Naruto!
Naruto, don't do it right now!
The light can't penetrate
that Susano'o?
His Rinnegan can counter
even this jutsu?
Don't go outside right now.
Without this Susano'o
that my eye made,
you'd get bound up in
his genjutsu as well!
Also, his shadows are outside...
If you and I fall, it's all over!
We need to bide our time.
This is the Deep Forest Emergence!
He's binding people using
the Divine Tree's life energy!
Why am I not affected?!
Yamato!
What's going on?!
What's going on outside right now?
Sasuke?
What difference will it make,
knowing that?
There is nothing
you can do right now.
Sasuke... That's not the point.
Naruto and I also want to know.
In order to analyze our next move,
Sakura is...
Kakashi...
You're being just like Sakura now.
Just be quiet for a bit.
Hey, Sasuke!
We need to work as a team!
Team 7 needs to work together
to bring Madara down!
You're right.
There's nothing I can do right now...
Kakashi-sensei!
If you can analyze what's outside
with your left eye,
Sasuke...
you should be the one to lead Team 7...
Huh?!
I doubt he's better at planning
than either you or Sakura!
Although he may be
better than me...
Anyway...
Madara has activated his jutsu.
It's a powerful genjutsu.
I suspect everyone outside
has fallen under its spell.
We might be the only ones
left unaffected.
The Infinite Tsukuyomi, huh?
So right about now, everyone's...
Inside a dream.
Lord Kiba!
I think I'll start by establishing
a new holiday called Dog Day!
It's the Hokage's Decree!
Everyone will own a dog!
Go get a dog!
It's the Hokage's Decree!
I've finally found a new species!
There, there...
Wow!
What a feast! This looks so tasty!
I went all out and cooked
all this just for you, dear!
Looks like you've found a fan!
Thanks for the food!
How many times
do I have to tell you?!
If you're going to be late
coming back from a mission,
let me know!
I made dinner for nothing,
- Marriage is such a drag.
- And you kept me waiting.
I think I'll pass.
- Haven't you learned after all these years?
- Yeah.
I won't let you have Ino.
Ino is my woman... Get lost!
No, she is my woman.
Stop fighting, both of you!
My daughter's so popular.
This is such a pain!
Great Leaf Hurricane!
Youth prevails!
Oh, Lee!
I love you!
S-Sakura!
- Sai!
Oh, Sai.
Hey, Sai.
Good morning, everyone.
'Morning.
You have a really nice smile,
as usual.
Do you think so?
You really do have
a beautiful smile, Sai.
It is super cool!
Oh...
Sai! Your smile's the best
in the Hidden Leaf!
I've finally perfected it!
It flies! It moves!
My ultimate puppet!
He embodies all the dreams
of the Sand!
You will be the guardian deity
Let's go!
Elder Sister, Elder Sister!
Please help me. I need your wisdom!
Calm down. What is it?
You see...
Hold on!
Let me discuss something
with you first!
You're the Kazekage now.
Make your own decisions.
No!
I really want to hear your opinion!
Me too! Please, Elder Sister!
It just has to be you!
Elder Sister!
My little brothers are so hopeless.
And then Gaara—!
Is that so? At the Academy?
Uh-huh!
Lord Gaara.
Your friend is here to see you.
Hey!
What are we going to play today?
Let's go outside!
Gaara...
Don't stay out too late.
Uh-huh.
So when can we get outta here?
It seems the genjutsu
is cast by the moonlight.
Which will gradually wane.
But as long as there's light,
it's useless.