This is amazing.
Follow me.
These ruins seem to
be quite old.
They must have
archeological importance,
they should be restored.
No! Those stone statues were carved
without heads to begin with.
There's a reason for it.
How am I supposed to
fight the Nine-Tails here?
What's more, how am I
supposed to face him?
I hope you're not going to
do anything excessive!
Do you think it's something
that can be controlled
without going overboard?
Fool, ya fool.
Since long ago,
this has been a sacred place
where those selected as
Jinchuriki have come
to undergo
the Purification Ceremony.
It's set up here so you can talk to
your Tailed Beast in a special way.
It's right inside this building.
You hear what I say?
This is...
Only the chosen ones can enter...
To be selected.
In the statue's mouth... do as directed!
Like a man who's respected.
If your heart has no darkness inside,
the door will...
swing wide.
Hey, can you explain it normally?
I don't quite understand.
No darkness in the heart?
I see, so that's why
at the waterfall...
However...
If there's even a little darkness
in your heart, the gate will not part.
Let's start.
And the statue will bite off
your head and tear you apart.
Be smart.
All the headless statues
you saw on your way here...
are past Jinchuriki who weren't...
sincere!
This is too risky.
Naruto, use a shadow clone.
This is a sacred place,
fool, ya fool.
Generations of Hidden Cloud
ancestors guard
and protect this place.
Tricks like that won't work!
But...
Captain Yamato...
I came here to learn how
to control the Nine-Tails' power!
This is important to me.
I can't run away!
I'm going to believe in myself!
Naruto!
No! How could this happen!
You...
Just kidding!
There's just a switch in there.
It's a habit.
I couldn't help myself.
I did the same thing too.
Out of habit.
Those stone statues are
just broken. Just a bit of wit.
I thought you said this place
was sacred! Fool, ya fool!
This is...?
Go inside,
close your eyes and focus.
Just like at the waterfall.
Then you'll meet your Tailed Beast.
Before when I was training,
I was able to meet
the Nine-Tails in my mind.
Any Jinchuriki can do that.
But this is
a little different, okay?
Listen to me very carefully.
I'll give you an explanation.
Naruto, what kind of sealing jutsu
holds your Nine-Tails?
Please answer my question.
It's a Tetragram Seal.
A Tetragram Seal, huh.
That's impressive.
It's even more solid than
my Steel Shell Seal.
Do you have the key?
Yes!
You're going to undo
the seal, after all.
What if he can't
control it properly?
What if the Nine-Tails
revives completely?
We'll seal him away here.
That's what this place
is for as well.
Until we get a new Jinchuriki,
this is where we'll seal him in.
You got a problem with this?
No booin'.
– But...
– That won't happen!
Because I'm going to do this.
Okay! I'm going to shut the door.
And I'll show you how to deal
with the Nine-Tails!
Naruto, you really do impress me.
The rules are simple,
as you'll soon see.
Greet the Nine-Tails in your
subconscious mind, then undo the seal.
Hey, evil glare as usual.
Naruto...
You...
What is it?
Where'd the real you go?
I don't sense him.
I'm here... right in front of you!
You conquered hatred.
But don't relax,
do the best you can!
The Nine-Tails is
a mass of true hatred.
That's absolutely true, man!
What are you up to?
Can't you see my mouth is full?
Here I go...
When the Nine-Tails emerges
from the seal,
grab the Nine-Tails' chakra with
your own chakra, and pull it away!
Chakra can only be caught
with chakra.
It's common sense, son.
Take the Nine-Tails' chakra
away from him...
and you'll be number one.
Touch the Nine-Tails directly and
stick your chakra onto its chakra,
and it'll pull each other.
In other words, it's going to be
like a match of tug-of-war. Okay?!
I'll help you in your fight.
But unfortunately inside
your head I got no might.
He's strong!
Just a word of warning.
When you're trying to
take his chakra,
there's the risk that
he'll pull away yours.
I don't need to explain what'll
happen if all your chakra is
pulled away and
you have zero left, right?
I see. You intend to
control my power.
So you teamed up
with Eight-Tails?
You, the Jinchuriki of
the Nine-Tails? That's pitiful!
The risks are high for sure.
But if you take it away, the Nine
Tails' chakra will be yours forever!
Grab whatever chakra you can
from the Nine-Tails' will...
That's the deal!
Don't get caught in
the Nine-Tails' hatred.
Use your strong will.
That's how you'll ward him off!
Don't underestimate me!
Thank you, Octopops!
I managed to contain the explosion!
Naruto, that will be the last of
my cooperation to your operation!
Thanks!
I'm sitting still
just as I thought.
Sage Art: Super Giant Rasengan!
So fast!
Do you think you can beat me?
Why would I break
the seal otherwise?
Besides...
We gotcha!
Wind Style: Rasen Shuriken!
Do it now!
He's weakening!
Now's my chance.
Hatred...
Suffering...
I want to kill...
Help!
I hate all this!
It's not going to work anyway.
I'll get revenge!
What is this?
This is bad!
Don't give in, Naruto!
Fool, ya fool!
You cannot control my power!
You are just a small portion
of my hatred!
Is he the one?
Get lost!
No one will ever respect
someone like you!
Get lost!
Get lost! Get lost!
Just go away!
Shut up!
The Nine-Tails' hatred is greater
than I imagined.
This could get bad for real.
This is quite an ordeal!
I'll stop him.
Go away and disappear!
It's all right,
you can stay right here.
Naruto...
What? What are you doing here?
And how come you know my name?
Oh yes, that's right.
Well then, Naruto,
can you guess who I am?
No way...
Have you figured it out?
You're Nine-Tails' real form!
That's such a crude laugh!
You're trying to fool me by transforming
yourself into a woman, Nine-Tails?
You got it wrong, ya know!
Ouch!
Huh? "Ya know"?
I couldn't stop myself
from hitting you.
I was born impatient,
and I talk fast,
so I use some weird phrases.
I try to control it,
but it slips out when I get excited.
What about you?
I hope you didn't get any of
my bad speech patterns.
Then...
Minato, didn't say anything to you?
Shame on him.
Yes... I'm...
I've wanted...
I've wanted to meet you
for so long, Mom... ya know?
"Ya know," huh?
You really are my child.
The Nine-Tails transformation stopped.
Did you do something, Yamato?
No, it seems to have
stopped on its own.
What happened?
There's a ton of stuff
I wanted to ask you
when I met you!
Sure, you can ask me anything.
But first, we have to tame
the Nine-Tails.
This chakra...
Kushina, is that you?
Minato embedded my chakra
into the seal formula,
so that when the time came
for you to take control
of the Nine-Tails' power,
I could be of help.
Are you listening?
I'm glad my Mom is so beautiful!
Well, thank you!
Your hair is just like your father's,
but I'm sorry you inherited
my looks, Naruto.
Why?
If I got my pretty mom's looks,
that makes me handsome, right?
And you have nice,
straight red hair.
I wish my hair were like that too!
You're the second man to
compliment my red hair.
Really? Who was the first?
Who else? Your father.
Oh! That's right!
What is it?
Hey, hey!
I always wanted to ask you
one thing if I ever met you!
How did you and Dad
fall in love?
What an embarrassing thing
to ask, ya know!
Hey! You said, "ya know!"
You're excited!
In this case, it's more like
shaken up, ya know!
Hey, you said it again!
Let's see...
It was the first day I came
to the Hidden Leaf Village...
That's when I first met
your father, Minato.
All right. We have a new transfer student
today who will be attending our Academy.
I'm Kushina Uzumaki, ya know!
Oh!
Look at the color of her hair.
How can anyone have
hair like that?
How do you get it that red?
Her hair's really weird!
– I wouldn't go out with hair like that.
– Hey! Be quiet! Settle down!
I'm...
I'm going to become
the village's first female Hokage!
I want to become a great Hokage
who will be admired by everyone
in the village too!
A Hokage who is admired
by everyone in the village, huh.
Back then, he wasn't very manly
and didn't look too dependable.
So I didn't take Minato seriously
or believe for a minute that
he could become a Hokage.
Why not? Dad looked so strong.
You're right.
But back then,
I was young and very ignorant.
But I sure was arrogant,
having moved from another village
and announcing that I was going
to become the Hokage.
After that, I started getting
teased by the boys.
They nicknamed me...
Tomato!
From today, we're going
to call you Tomato!
You have a fat, round face
with red hair.
Just like a tomato!
As if a tomato can become
the Hokage!
I hate tomatoes!
Me too!
I never eat it in my salad!
A tomato that everyone hates
could never be accepted
as the Hokage!
So that's it!
I'll bet it was Dad who
protected you from those bullies!
No, you're dead wrong!
Tomato...
I grudgingly accepted being
called that name.
It was embarrassing,
but it fit me perfectly.
You're getting redder and riper!
It's the Tomato Festival!
It's time to harvest!
Who are you calling Tomato?
Now you listen...
I hate tomatoes too, ya know!
Keep calling me Tomato
and you're going to get it,
ya know!
What are you laughing at?
I always beat those bullies
at their own game
and turned them into
smashed tomatoes.
The girl with the long red hair
who beat the boys half to death.
As expected,
I was stuck with a new nickname...
The Red-Hot Habanero!
Kiba and Shikamaru were
always saying
that mothers are really scary.
Always fighting.
Naturally, I always won these fights
as the Red-Hot Habanero.
But...
I used to hate my hair.
But a certain incident changed
the way I felt about my red hair.
A certain incident?
I'm home!
I'm home.
Is...
Is anyone home?
Someone!
Help me!
I have a special kind of chakra.
Because of that,
the Hidden Cloud kidnapped me.
At that time, in order to
leave a trail behind
as I was being taken away,
I cut off pieces of my hair
and dropped it...
without the enemy knowing.
But since I was an outsider,
I didn't hold out hope that
anyone would come to rescue me.
We had come to the edge
of the border
and I thought it was all over...
I came to save you.
You'll be all right now.
Hey, wait a minute!
That's...
Your hair is beautiful.
So I noticed it right away.
But you've always ignored me.
Because I know that
you're strong,
in body and in spirit.
But this is a fight between
two villages.
It's different from
your other fights, so...
So?
I didn't want to lose you.
Even if I'm an outsider?
Why do you say that?
You live in Hidden Leaf Village.
so you're one of us.
At that moment,
Minato was a great ninja
in my eyes.
He was the man of my dreams.
He changed me.
This red hair that I used to hate
brought me
the man of my destiny.
And it became
the "red thread of fate."
After that, I learned to
love my hair.
And...
I fell in love with Minato.
Only men who compliment my hair
get to hear these precious words
from me.
Naruto, will you accept them?
Uh-huh!
I love you.
What is this?
I feel so calm...
I love you.
I feel so happy.
Damn you, Kushina!
What is this?
This is real nice!
For now,
keeping watch will suffice!
My chakra that's suppressing
the Nine-Tails won't last much longer!
This is your chance to do it!
All right!
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
You brat!
Just as I thought.
He's really strong!
Take this!
Rasengan Super Barrage!
Don't underestimate me!
I can keep going, ya know!
Here!
That's...
Sage Mode!
Sage Art!
Massive...
Rasengan Barrage!
One more round!
What kind of power is this?
Pull!
Get out!
You did it! You pulled
the Nine-Tails' chakra out!
This is...
This is the Nine-Tails'...
Naruto...
You...
You have infuriated me, Naruto!
You still have that much power...
You really are amazing.
This is the Six Paths...?!
You watch out, Naruto.
I'm sorry... Nine-Tails.
But I'll make it up to you.
So just hang in there
for a little while.
You did it, Naruto!
Yeah.
Mom, where are you going now?
I can finally go and join Minato.
There's something
I must tell you before I go.
Naruto...
It's about when you were born
16 years ago.
I'll tell you what really happened.
What really happened...
16 years ago?
I was the Nine-Tails' Jinchuriki
before you were.
Let's start from there.
You were the Nine-Tails' Jinchuriki, Mom?
I was chosen as the second
Jinchuriki host of Nine-Tails.
Truth be told, I was brought here for
the express purpose
of being the Nine-Tails' Jinchuriki...
from the Land of Whirlpools.
Why?
Why did they have to choose
someone from another land?!
You're right. I'm from
a different land, and village.
But the Land of Fire and
the Land of Whirlpools,
as well as Hidden Leaf Village
and Hidden Whirlpool Village,
share a deep bond.
The shinobi of the Senju Clan
of the Hidden Leaf
and the shinobi of the Uzumaki Clan
of the Hidden Whirlpool
were distant blood relatives.
Our people lived long.
So the Hidden Whirlpool Village was
also known as the Village of Longevity.
And we specialized in sealing jutsu.
We were also a rowdy bunch.
The Tetragram Seal on
your abdomen is based
on a jutsu from our village.
And Minato, your father, learned
various sealing jutsu from my mother.
Naruto, the symbol on your back...
That is the symbol
of the Hidden Whirlpool.
Even today in Hidden Leaf Village
that symbol is a symbol
of friendship, isn't it?
So the Hidden Whirlpool Village...?
It no longer exists.
During the era of war, our sealing
jutsu abilities were greatly feared,
so the village was targeted
and destroyed.
Those who survived feared
for their safety,
so they hid their identities and
scattered throughout the region.
But still... why were you chosen?!
It seems that even within my village,
I was born with powerful chakra
able to suppress the Nine-Tails.
Do you know about the battle...
between the First Hokage,
Hashirama Senju, and Madara Uchiha?
Mm-hm.
The Jinchuriki who came before me...
was the First Hokage's wife.
Her name was Mito Uzumaki.
In order to help Lord First Hokage
who had obtained the Nine-Tails
in his battle with Madara,
Lady Mito sealed the Nine-Tails
inside her body
with a Sealing Jutsu and
became its Jinchuriki.
From then on, the Hidden Leaf
maintained possession of the Nine-Tails.
But when Lady Mito's days
were coming to an end,
I was brought to Hidden Leaf
as the vessel for the Nine-Tails.
They just used you!
When I was first brought to the village,
I wasn't told a thing.
It was quite a shock
when I was told why I was there.
This was a closely guarded secret.
And the only ones who knew
were the Third Hokage and
a few of the top officials.
Not even the Legendary Sannin
were told about this.
I was nearly overwhelmed by
the pressure of being the Jinchuriki
and the loneliness I felt.
But Lady Mito, the previous Jinchuriki,
summoned me...
Like you, I was brought here
to become the vessel
for the Nine-Tails.
I can imagine your shock
when you learned of this.
How sad you must have been.
How you have suffered.
You can tell me the truth.
Yes...
Now listen carefully.
It's true, we are the vessels
for the Nine-Tails.
However, there is a way
to find happiness
even if you must live as a Jinchuriki.
First...
we must fill ourselves up.
If I filled myself with love first,
I would be able to live a happy life
despite being
the Nine-Tails' Jinchuriki.
That is what Lady Mito taught me.
So you were happy even as
a Jinchuriki, Mom?
Yes.
Naruto... Now why are you crying?
Wait...
What is it?
That time 16 years ago
when the Nine-Tails attacked
Hidden Leaf Village...
Dad said a man wearing
an Akatsuki mask was behind it.
So how come you had
the Nine-Tails, Mom?
I see that your father didn't
tell you all the details.
Of course.
Back then,
there was so much going on
and Minato didn't have much time.
It's true. The fact is that,
16 years ago,
a masked man controlled
the Nine-Tails to
attack the village.
But moments earlier,
I had the Nine-Tails sealed
and in my possession.
Then why?
That masked man...
He knew about the one chance
he had to weaken the seal,
which kept the Tailed Beast
locked inside the Jinchuriki.
He waited for that moment
to steal the Nine-Tails.
The one chance to weaken the seal?!
What was it?
It was childbirth.
During the approximately
ten months from the time
a female Jinchuriki gets pregnant
and gives birth,
the Tailed Beast Seal
weakens proportionally
as the energy normally
used to maintain the seal
is diverted to the growing baby.
Then...
Sixteen years ago... on October 10...
Kushina, there is something
I must explain to you
about giving birth.
It happened to Lady Mito,
the previous Jinchuriki, as well.
During her labor,
the Nine-Tails' seal was nearly broken.
I'm sorry,
but as a precautionary measure,
we're going to ask you
to deliver the child
somewhere away from the village,
inside a barrier.
We have the seal to think of,
so I will be accompanying you.
Minato and Taji from
the ANBU Black Ops.
Also, I will send my wife, Biwako,
to be with you.
This is to be done in utmost secrecy.
Naturally, I will assign bodyguards,
but they will be ANBU Black Ops
under my direct orders.
I'll go on ahead and
prepare everything.
All right.
I will take you there.
Kushina!
Oh, yes.
I appreciate it.
We should go soon.
Yes.
Oh!
Oh my...
Is it a girl?
It's a boy.
So cute...
What's your name?
It's Sasuke.
Oh, so he was named after
the Third Hokage's father!
Yes, so that he will grow up
to be a strong and fine shinobi.
You will be giving birth
soon too, right, Kushina?
You should pick a name
in advance.
I already have.
His name will be Naruto.
You'll be classmates, Sasuke,
so be friends, okay?
By the way, does it really hurt?
So there's actually something
that scares you, Kushina!
I'm surprised!
Let's go, Kushina!
Oh, yes!
See you again!
The details of your birthing
are supposed to be top secret.
Until we get to our location, you must
avoid any contact, even with your friends.
Yes, I'm sorry.
Also, we are leaving
the village secretly.
If your labor pains begin,
try not to cry out loud!
Oh... right.
It hurts, ya know!
I've never seen Kushina
in so much pain.
Is she... all right?
She's all right!
Never mind that.
Just stay focused
on the Nine-Tails' seal!
But she's...
You are the Fourth Hokage!
Act like one!
A man would have dropped dead
from such pain long ago.
But women are strong!
He's so strong!
The Nine-Tails is struggling
to get out!
Hang in there, Kushina!
Hang in there, Naruto!
I can see his head!
You're almost there, Kushina!
Hang on, Kushina!
Naruto! Come out quickly!
Nine-Tails, you stay put!
Hot water!
Right!
He's born!
I'm a father today!
He's a healthy baby boy.
Naruto!
Don't touch him!
The mother sees him first.
Naruto...
I finally get to see you.
You'll have lots more time later.
There, there.
How are you feeling, Kushina?
Okay.
Thank you.
Minato...
All right!
I know you've gone
through childbirth,
but I'm going to completely
seal the Nine-Tails!
Lady Biwako!
Taji!
Fourth Hokage Minato,
get away from the Jinchuriki.
Otherwise, this child's life
will end in one minute.
How did he get past the barrier?
This guy...
Who the hell is he?
Kushina!
The Nine-Tails Seal is still...
Get away from the Jinchuriki.
Don't you care
what happens to your kid?
Wait! Calm down!
Speak for yourself, Minato.
I'm as cool as can be.
Naruto!
Well, I must hand it to
the Yellow Flash.
But I wonder about this next one.
Minato!
Naruto!
Thank goodness...
Naruto isn't hurt.
I was forced to use
the Flying Raijin Jutsu.
His target is Kushina...
and he succeeded in separating us.
I must hurry.
Just what... do you want?
I'm going to pull the Nine-Tails
out from you
and destroy the Hidden Leaf.
What?
Minato's Teleportation Jutsu
allows him to move instantly
between locations marked
with jutsu Formulas.
He made sure to mark
your Sealing Formula too...
in order to protect you.
However, I managed to put
a distance between you.
Furthermore, the Nine-Tails' Seal
has been weakened from childbirth.
Do you know how long
I've waited for this moment?
You'll be safe here.
Naruto, just wait awhile.
I have to go and save your mother.
You are...
Now then, come out Nine-Tails!
Good.
Now I'll go straight
to Hidden Leaf Village.
Hold it.
The Uzumaki Clan is amazing.
You don't die right away after
the Tailed Beast is extracted.
You were the Jinchuriki
of the Nine-Tails.
I'll use him to kill you.
I must say,
you really live up to your nickname.
But you are too late.
Minato...
Is Naruto... Is he safe?
Yes, he's fine.
He's in a safe place for now.
Thank goodness.
Minato, you must stop that man
and the Nine-Tails right now.
He's heading for Hidden Leaf Village.
Why?
Never mind that.
Just stay with Naruto.
Naruto...
Minato... Thank you.
Good luck.
I'll be right back.
What is this feeling?
There, there...
It's a strange feeling.
Of all times for Mom
and Dad to be out.
Don't cry, Sasuke.
No matter what happens,
your big brother will
definitely protect you.
It can't be...
Summoning Jutsu!
– What happened?
– Is it an accident?
That's...!
N-No way...!
The Nine-Tails!
– Run!
– It's the Nine-Tails!
– Help!
– We're done for!
Go, Nine-Tails!
As Hokage,
I will protect the village,
my family, right now.
This is what I need to do.
I won't allow it to do
as it pleases anymore!
So you've taken notice of me.
You won't get your way here!
For this large a scale,
I'll have to be careful
where I send it.
The jutsu that stopped
the Nine-Tails' attack
must be the Teleportation Barrier!
It's Minato?
All right! We're going too!
Right!
I must report all that's happened
to Lord Third immediately.
I'm your opponent...
and it's all over.
He flew away. He's fast.
Next time, I'll get him faster.
The instant we make contact.
My attack missed.
But he materialized and
instantly tried to drag me in.
What is that jutsu?
I won't let you get away.
He uses the Teleportation Jutsu too?
Is that how he took Kushina
and moved away so quickly?
A shinobi who outmaneuvered the ANBU
assigned under Lord Third's direct control...
who slipped through
a top-secret barrier...
and who knew that the Nine-Tails'
Seal would weaken during childbirth.
Furthermore, he undid the
Nine-Tails' Seal, controlled it and...
went in and out of the barrier set up
by the Hidden Leaf without being caught.
I know of only one shinobi
capable of this.
Are you Madara Uchiha?
No, that's impossible.
He's dead.
I wonder about that.
At this point,
it doesn't matter who you are.
But why are you targeting
the Hidden Leaf?
I could say I did it on a whim,
or that I planned it,
or that it's war,
or that it's for peace.
Whatever the case,
he's no ordinary man!
He can control the Nine-Tails
and his Teleportation Jutsu surpasses
both Lord Second's and mine.
And he has some
dangerous ideology.
I must deal with him now
or he'll be even more trouble
than the Nine-Tails!
If I transport myself to
the village now,
he will follow and the battlefield
will become even more chaotic.
If he's anything like Madara,
he can't keep the Nine-Tails under
the summoning jutsu for too long.
I just have to entrust
the village to Lord Third.
As for me...
I must take this guy
down right here!
Now that I have freed the Nine-Tails,
you people have no hope left!
His flesh...
My physical attacks have
no effect on him,
but he makes himself materialize
to attack me.
Meaning, I can only aim for him
when we both strike blows!
But his risk lies during
the moment of attack.
And considering the time remaining
on the Nine-Tails' summoning jutsu,
he doesn't want a long battle either.
The one who attacks
an instant quicker than the other...
will win this match!
I win.
Damn it! He flew to that
kunai from earlier!
That was my Flying Raijin, Level 2.
You got me.
This is what is meant by "elusive."
I should never have let down my guard.
Flying Raijin Jutsu!
So that's it...
He marked my body somewhere!
A Contract Seal?
He intends to separate
the Nine-Tails from me?
With this, the Nine-Tails
is no longer yours!
I must hand it to
the Fourth Hokage.
You wounded me and managed
to pull out the Nine-Tails.
However, the Nine-Tails will
be mine eventually.
I am going to rule the world...
And there are so many ways
to go about doing that.
That tone...
He's not joking around.
Keep him occupied until
the Fourth Hokage arrives!
This is terrible.
He's going to do that again?
Lord Third!
Summoning Jutsu!
This is...
It's the Fourth Hokage!
Hold down the Nine-Tails
for just a while!
That's going to be tough...
even for me!
In order to transport
something this big,
I'll need just as much chakra!
Minato...
Did he fly off with the Nine-Tails?
That way!
I must put up a barrier immediately.
My chakra is almost...
I can still do it, Minato.
Kushina!
Did I wake you up?
I'm sorry, Naruto.
Kushina...
I'm going to drag the Nine-Tails
down with me to my death.
That will delay the revival
of the Nine-Tails.
I'll be able to save all of you
with what little chakra
I have left.
Thank you for everything
you've done for me.
Kushina...
You're the reason that
I became the Fourth Hokage!
You made me a man!
And you made me
this baby's father!
And yet...
Minato, don't give me that look!
I'm happy that you loved me.
And today... is this child's birthday.
If I were to imagine me alive,
and our future together,
the three of us as a family...
I can't see us having
anything but a happy life.
If I were allowed just one regret,
it's that I won't be able
to see Naruto grow up.
How I wish I could have seen that.
Kushina, there is no need for you
to die with the Nine-Tails.
Preserve what little chakra
you have left
for when you see Naruto again.
I'll seal all of your remaining
chakra inside Naruto.
It will be part of
an Eight Signed Seal.
Then I'll take the Nine-Tails
with me
with the only Sealing jutsu I can do
since I'm not a Jinchuriki,
the Reaper Death Seal!
But the user of that jutsu...!
And one more thing.
I will only seal half
of the Nine-Tails.
Sealing a power this immense
is physically impossible.
It's also strategically unwise.
If you take the Nine-Tails and
its seal with you when you die,
there won't be a Jinchuriki around
when he reemerges.
That will upset the balance of power
between the Tailed Beasts.
The Reaper Death Seal will seal
half of the Nine-Tails with me forever.
As for the other half
of the Nine-Tails...
I will seal it inside Naruto with
the Eight Signed Seal!
I know what you want to say.
But remember what Master Jiraiya
said about world upheaval.
And the calamities that would follow.
Two things were confirmed
for me today.
That masked man
who attacked you today
is a harbinger of disaster!
And the one who will
stop him is this child!
I don't know why,
but I'm convinced of this.
But Minato...!
Reaper Death Seal!
Let's put our trust in this child!
He's our son, after all!
Lord Third, what's wrong?!
It's no good.
I can't go further than
this point
because of the barrier put up to
keep Nine-Tails from escaping!
Those two are planning to take care
of Nine-Tails themselves!
Damn you, Fourth Hokage!
Seal!
My body is getting numb...
I never expected
such massive chakra...
Damn you!
All right,
next is the Eight Signed Seal.
I will seal the Nine-Tails
inside Naruto.
The Ritual Altar?
Does he intend to seal me again?
Furthermore...
Inside that baby?
Kushina! Are you all right?
Right now!
Why you—!
Okay, I understand that
you're determined to do this.
Thank you, Kushina.
Summoning Jutsu!
Nine-Tails!
What?! Lord Fourth too!
What's the meaning of this?!
Gerotora, I'm going to give you
the Sealing Formula's key.
Take it immediately to Master Jiraiya
and store it away.
Understood. I confirm the key
is in my possession.
And now, I'm off!
That should do it.
Kushina, my time is running out.
I'm going start
the Eight Signed Seal.
I want to put some of
my chakra in Naruto too.
It'll be quite a while
before we can see him.
Let's tell him what
we want to say.
Naruto...
Don't be a picky eater.
Eat lots and grow strong.
Make sure you bathe every day
and keep warm.
Also don't stay up late.
You need lots of sleep.
And make friends.
You don't need a lot of friends.
Just a few...
Ones you can really, really trust.
I wasn't very good at it,
but keep up with your studies
and practice your ninjutsu hard.
Remember that everyone has
strengths and weaknesses.
So don't get too depressed if
you can't do something well.
Respect your teachers and
upperclassmen at the Academy.
Oh, and this is important.
It's about the Three Prohibitions
for a shinobi.
Be extra careful about lending
and borrowing money.
Put your mission wages into
your savings account.
No alcohol until you're twenty.
Too much can ruin your health,
so drink in moderation.
Next is women...
I'm a woman, so I don't know
too much about this but...
All you need to remember is that
this world is made up
of men and women.
So it's only natural to take
an interest in girls...
But just don't get hooked
on bad women.
Find someone just like me.
Speaking of the Three Prohibitions,
be wary of Jiraiya-sensei, you know.
Naruto, from now on,
you're going to face
lots of pain and hardship.
Be true to yourself.
Have a dream and
have the confidence to make
that dream come true!
There's so much...
Oh, so much more that
I want to pass on to you.
I wish I could stay with you longer.
I love you.
Minato, I'm sorry I used up
your time.
Oh, it's okay.
Naruto, my message to you is...
I guess it's the same as
your nagging mother's.
Eight Signed Seal.
I'm sorry for making you
the Nine-Tails' vessel.
For putting our burden
on your shoulders...
For not being able
to live by your side...
For not being able to
shower you with love.
You don't have to apologize.
It was rough in the past
because I was a Jinchuriki.
But I never held it
against you or Dad.
I admit I didn't really know
what parental love was.
After all,
you and Dad weren't around.
I just had a feeling.
But I know now that you and Dad
gave your lives just for me.
And I realize that even more
than the Nine-Tails,
I was filled up with your love!
I'm happy!
I'm glad I'm your son,
Mom and Dad!
Minato, are you listening?
Our hopes did reach our boy!
Naruto...
Thank you for letting me
be your mom.
And thank you for letting
Minato be your dad.
Thank you for...
being born to us!
Thank you...
Thank you so much.
Mom...
From now on,
I promise I'll eat vegetables
and not just ramen.
I like taking baths,
so don't worry about that.
I go to the hot springs a lot too.
And I get lots of sleep.
In fact, I sleep too much,
ya know!
As for friends,
I have lots of good ones.
I wish you could have met them.
There's one that I'm not
getting along with though.
As for studying...
Well, you were right to worry, Mom.
But I don't let it get me down, ya know!
A lot happened with my teachers and
upperclassmen during my Academy days,
but we respect each other now.
Master Jiraiya taught me about
the Three Shinobi Prohibitions.
You were right about him, Mom!
But he's the one who taught me
how a shinobi should live!
He was a great shinobi.
I'm Naruto Uzumaki,
a ninja of the Hidden Leaf!
My dream is to become the Hokage!
And I'll surpass all the Hokage
who came before me!
And I'm going to be cooler
than Dad!
And I'm going to be
a stronger shinobi than you, Mom!