Naruto has arrived at
every battlefield!
Good.
Over there!
– The combined First and Second Companies
– And those guys too!
Have detected just about
all the enemies!
Earth Style:
They're advancing with
incredible momentum.
What was that?
Sorry, Bushy Brow!
The Third Company also
seems to be dominating!
Wind Style: Rasen Shuriken!
– This is...
– huge!
The Fifth Company has
the upper hand as well!
Cha!
The medical unit has suppressed
all their enemies.
It worked!
The tide of battle has turned
overwhelmingly in our favor.
See?
Humph!
Now we just need to stop Madara
who is approaching
with Jinchuriki in tow.
We should focus
our remaining strength there
and hit him with all we've got!
I never expected to be
at such a disadvantage.
Still, I'm glad that clone was sealed
before he could say too much.
Given Naruto and his power...
Even if it's a Reanimated body,
it will take some time to regenerate.
How naïve, Ohnoki...
You were my student.
How could you miss that
I had fragmented myself?
This is...
a violently rotating...
Rasengan!
Earth Style: Boulder Jutsu!
Be careful, I'm...
As I thought,
I can't get this tag off.
It's an impressive Sealing Jutsu.
If I remember correctly,
Mu's jutsu is not cloning,
but fission.
Because the real body
simply splits into two,
he doesn't need to make signs
and it's faster.
However, his power is halved.
Summoning Jutsu!
At last. It seems he successfully
brought that brat Nagato to maturity.
The user of this Reanimation Jutsu
has a keen understanding of war.
To think of using you...
Did you say "Reanimation"?
This is not the Rinne Rebirth Jutsu...?
J-Just a minute!
What is it?!
The enemy is resisting
Gaara's Fourth Company!
But... what is this chakra?!
Huh? What is this?!
What are you sensing?
Over there!
What is it?
Hm?
That's the Second Tsuchikage!
I thought Gaara sealed him away!
Impossible... He used
Fragmentation in that state...?
It's not him!
There's someone else!
What?!
Hey, there's one more!
H-He is...!
Who is it?
You've come at last!
Uchiha...
Madara!
That's him?
So that's what he looked
like beneath the mask.
He looks exactly the same!
What's going on?!
What do you mean?
Look closely at his eyes.
That's a Reanimation!
The Reanimation Jutsu brings
the dead back to this realm...
Which means he had been dead!
Wait a second!
I thought HQ reported
Madara elsewhere,
approaching from the other direction
with the Jinchuriki, right?
But there's no mistake...
He's Madara Uchiha!
The one I fought when I was young.
Then who's the man...
behind the mask?!
So the guy in front of us
is the real Madara.
Then the guy we thought
was Madara... isn't Madara?
So it seems...
As Tsuchikage, you've utilized
the Akatsuki in the past.
Can you speculate who
that masked man might be?
There's no one I can think of.
But it doesn't matter who he is!
We still need to stop him!
Their headbands say "Shinobi."
But I see them wearing shinobi gear
from each of
the Five Great Nations...
Is this a new allied army?
It does appear that we're at war.
Coming from him...
He must have something in mind.
But things don't seem like
they're going as planned.
Why else would he revive me
in this state?
Who is the caster of
the Reanimation Jutsu?
Who knows?
I'm Kabuto.
I am... his collaborator.
Speaking through
a Reanimation Link?
Such a sneaky one you are...
Your Reanimation is quite special.
I've fixed you up so that you're even
greater than you were in your glory days.
You know what I was like
during my "glory days"?
No.
Which is why
I want you to show me...
your legendary Uchiha power.
I guess they won't be easy
to capture.
Very well...
Here he comes!
Do not look directly into
his eyes!
You can't use the Particle Style in
your divided state right now...
Sensory Types! Watch Lord Mu!
Wait!
Gaara, you and Lord Tsuchikage
must recover first.
Naruto, instead of your clones,
go into that mode!
The truth is, I can't anymore.
I used up my chakra
in the earlier fight!
Do you want to dance too?
Don't underestimate me!
Fire Style:
Majestic Destroyer Flame!
His jutsu spans a wide area!
– Water Style: Wall of Water!
Here he comes!
This is... as far as you'll go!
Giant Rasengan!
Earth Style: Mobile Core!
A Susano'o...
He's already activated
the Mangekyo Sharingan!
How much longer, Naruto?!
Just hold on!
Sorry!
I'm ready!
Get back, everyone!
Go, Kazekage!
Earth Style:
Lightened Boulder Jutsu!
I made the surrounding
sand lighter too!
With sand this light,
I could...!
Naruto!
Yeah! Let's go!
If it's like Sasuke's,
external attacks are ineffective.
So I should use the sand
at Madara's feet!
Naruto!
Rasen Shuriken!
Too much energy...
H-He... absorbed it!
What the...?! How?
How come he's got the Rinnegan?
My guess was right.
What comes naturally after
the Sharingan is the Rinnegan.
I awakened the Rinnegan
just prior to my death.
You said your name was Kabuto?
What did you do to this body?
Like I told you.
I made you better than
you were at your peak.
You bastard...
You know the secrets of my body?
You can't even read
the Uchiha Stone Tablet!
But you still managed
to decipher it?
I just tested some hypotheses
drawn from years of data
from experiments Lord Orochimaru
and I conducted.
And now...
You are verifying my hypotheses.
You have obtained a fragment
of that God's power...
the power of the Sage of Six Paths.
Thanks to the power I built into you.
Do not misunderstand.
This is not power of your creation!
Damn!
N-No way...
What is that?
It's out of our league!
Is this the power of a god?
A meteorite? How did he...?
Is that really ninjutsu?
We can't outrun it!
This is not good...
Damn it!
It's still too early to give up!
Never give up without even trying!
Do what you can, no matter how small
the effect it may have!
Lord Tsuchikage!
Everyone, get as far away
from here as possible!
Hey!
Run!
Hurry!
You're taking us out too?
Of course.
That was the original point
of the Reanimation Jutsu...
To take others out with you.
We'll be restored shortly.
A shinobi that can fly...
Then, this must be the Both Scales brat
from the Stone.
What's Gramps Tsuchikage
trying to do?!
He's going to try to lighten
the meteorite to stop it!
Earth Style: Lightened Boulder Jutsu!
Just a tad more...
A little more... to stop it!
That Fence Sitter brat...
He's gotten a little better.
All right!
It's stopped!
We're saved...
Leave it to Lord Tsuchikage.
Well then...
What will you do about
the second one, Ohnoki?
What was that?!
Why did the masked man
specifically claim to be Madara?
The presence of Madara...
Even if he were a fraud,
if you can convince the world that
he exists, it will tremble in fear.
The name itself is power.
That name made us
cast aside our differences...
It fooled us,
then drew us all into war!
What happened?!
This is from our Relay Intel Unit.
A giant boulder big enough
to block out the sky
has been dropped onto
the Fourth Company's battlefield.
It's the source of this tremor!
Any further reports from
the Fourth Company since then?
What's going on?
So many casualties...
in just one sweep!
I'm sure of it...
It's Madara's jutsu or
something close to it!
Lady Tsunade! At this rate...!
I'll go!
What in the world...
was that?!
Rubber Pops...
I'm just a clone, so why did you...?!
I feel bad about the others.
But clone or not, you are needed here.
In order for us to win.
What about Gramps Tsuchikage?!
Gramps Tsuchikage!
It's okay.
He's alive...
But he's seriously hurt!
So this is the power of
the Sage of Six Paths...
Magnificent!
This landscape brings back memories.
It's Kabuto, right?
How much do you really know?
About me?
I venture to guess...
In that battle against
the First Hokage Hashirama,
you did not die at Valley of the End.
On that day...
though you lost to
the First Hokage Hashirama,
you gained a portion of
his power in return.
Am I wrong?
No wonder...
You're well-prepared.
You know about our plan?
Not in detail...
But I am your ally.
Although I'm not certain
if that fake Madara intends
to carry out your plan exactly...
By the way...
There are still some survivors.
The Tsuchikage and Kazekage
are especially persistent.
What should we do?
There's something I want to check first.
Summoning Jutsu!
My stomach... feels hot!
This chakra that summons me...
Is it Madara?!
It seems the Nine-Tails
hasn't been captured yet.
That's the purpose of this war.
The Nine-Tails is sealed
in a Jinchuriki.
For now...
See... He's over there.
That boy is the Nine-Tails' Jinchuriki...
His name is Naruto Uzumaki.
Uzumaki?
Of Mito's clan, eh?
He's the brat who attacked me earlier.
But he's actually quite something.
Capturing him is fine,
but that one in front of us is a clone.
Shall we go now to get the real one?
No. There's a jutsu I'd like to try out.
I think it will make a prettier picture
if I do it where there
are people around.
It's them! At four o'clock!
Wood Style:
Deep Forest Emergence!
He can do Wood Style?!
I guess this is it for us...
Naruto, this time I'll lend you
my power.
Are you going to say you want me to
surrender my body over to you again?!
No...
I'll just give you my chakra.
I don't care for Madara...
If I'm going to be controlled,
I'd rather it be you than him!
Naruto!
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Giant Rasengan!
Do it... Naruto!
Giant Rasengan Barrage Line!
As you mentioned, he's quite a guy.
Right?
I used up the chakra Nine-Tails
gave me all at once!
I'm at my limit!
I'm going to disappear
at any moment!
Naruto... Enough.
I'll take over from here.
Lord Tsuchikage,
you're in the same...
I finally have a chance
at reclaiming myself!
And I've got myself a worthy opponent!
I'd like to try out some more jutsu...
But I don't think
you can dance anymore, Ohnoki.
What's that look?
Long ago, I showed you
the difference in our strength.
Why?
That wasn't the agreement!
Lord Hashirama is...
There is no alliance...
Just submit to the power
of the Hidden Leaf!
And... never mention the name
of that shinobi in front of me!
We shinobi are weary
of all this endless fighting.
We've kept on fighting for
the sake of our nations and villages.
Without a care about other nations
and villages, we just take!
We take away, then they take away
in an endless cycle...!
Hatred has caused three wars!
That is life.
I can't believe
you've lived this long
and not learned a thing
from the pain of the past.
I've lived longer than you!
I've learned twice as much!
It's because I've experienced pain
in the past
that I can even consider
what would be best for the future!
Yet this is the fourth war!
Is this what's best?
This war is different!
Unlike the past wars where
we took from each other...
this time, we are fighting together
in order to achieve something different!
By watching them,
I've learned that time
does not simply pass by!
Though slow in pace, the world is
building upon its past experiences...
and heading towards "peace."
There's no need for the world
to mature any further.
It can slumber in the genjutsu
of the Eternal Tsukuyomi!
Long ago, you made me forsake myself.
That's why...
I will defeat you here...
and reclaim myself!
The one who will slumber shall be you!
Lord Tsuchikage!
Come... I will help you
reclaim yourself.
The elderly always complain
when young ones try to help...
I'll let you all meddle this time!
It seems they can still dance.
For myself!
For the future!
I will bring you down!
Damn it!
Lady Tsunade!
You said your name was Mabui?
Prepare to do
your Ethereal Transmission Jutsu!
Come with me!
Ethereal Transmission is
a jutsu used to transport items!
Unlike the Summoning
or Reverse Summoning Jutsu,
it's impossible to transport people!
There's no time to argue!
Unless we try, we'll never know!
I do know!
The transmission rate is so fast, the body
cannot keep up and will be torn apart.
Death is certain!
The only one who survived
Ethereal Transmission in the past
is the Third Raikage!
But that was only because
of his superhuman body.
Now I can understand the Fourth Raikage
since he is of the Third's blood...
But Lady Hokage,
it's impossible for you!
Please reconsider this!
I have an idea...
The Flying Raijin Jutsu.
We'll have Genma's squad come here.
Then if we mark
one of Katsuyu's clones,
and transmit her to the site first...
I have the ability to survive
being split into pieces...
That's not necessary!
I will use this.
But it's a risky gamble.
And you tend to be unlucky with bets...
That's only when I bet money.
It's different when I bet my life.
That's why I'm still alive.
Lord Raikage!
Please tell Lady Hokage
to think it over...
Mabui, prepare the Ethereal Transmission...
For two.
Not you too, Lord Raikage!
Shikaku!
We have no other options left.
It's time for the Supreme Commander
to make his appearance!
However, Madara belongs
to the Uchiha Clan...
If we don't do something
about his Fire Style,
we won't have a chance at winning.
Damn!
The more I cut down,
the more confidence I gain.
That's why I just have to keep slicing!
Right!
Yeah!
I thought that was a lot of chakra
he was gathering...
But I had no idea the sword
would be this huge...
I-I can't move...
I can't believe that you changed
that sword so quickly.
Genma!
Sorry, but could you please
just do as I say?
Is that you, Shikaku?
It's urgent. Do exactly as I say.
no interruptions!
First off, the real Madara
has been reanimated.
Sorry, but can I interrupt?
I said no!
Do it!
H-Here I go...
Ethereal Transmission Jutsu!
I'm surprised...
Instantaneous travel
through dimensions...
Isn't that the Fourth Hokage's jutsu?
We used to belong to a squad
assigned to protect the Fourth Hokage.
Now, it's the Fifth Hokage, but...
The Flying Raijin Jutsu
was taught to us by the Fourth.
But unlike the Fourth,
it takes the three of us for it to work.
We apologize for the tight fit.
Please get ready!
Lady Tsunade bears
the Jutsu Formula on her.
The instant she arrives
at the battlefield,
we will make the jump!
Understood!
I'm already late for marriage.
I won't be late for this.
I've relayed our coordinates to HQ!
Reserve Seal! Release!
Ninja Art of Mitotic Regeneration!
Are you all right?!
Yeah...
Granny Tsunade?!
That's her regenerating jutsu!
Since everyone is alive,
I guess we weren't late.
Finally, I'll get to see some action...
I've been bored stiff!
All right, I'm ready!
Living long was well worth it.
Imagine... Being able to see the day
when the Five Kage would be united
and fight side by side.
This is perfect.
This will make my test worthwhile.
Thank you, Princess Tsunade.
I'll heal the two of you.
Raikage, Mizukage!
Buy me some time!
Here we go, Mizukage!
Right!
Lava Style: Lava Monster Jutsu!
Jutsu this pitiful isn't even
worth absorbing!
He's fast!
Lateral Bolt of Pain! Chop!
You guys come with me...
I'm going after the other one.
Help me!
Is that him?
Follow me! Let's go!
How much longer, Hokage?!
Almost done!
Are you okay, Granny Tsunade?
Whenever you use the jutsu
from that forehead mark,
you get old and fall down!
This is different from
the time with Pain.
I only healed myself...
And besides,
it wasn't much of an injury.
I have more than enough chakra!
Then heal me too!
I may be a clone,
but I can't afford to disappear yet!
I'll join you and...
That's not necessary.
Why...?!
This is no longer just
a war to protect you.
Lightning Style Body Flicker
and Lava Style Kekkei Genkai...
Impressive attacks...
I usually like men
who are hard to melt...
But you, I want to avoid.
He counters me even
with my speed.
More speed... I need to increase
my power to crush his defense!
What about your defense?
A Stone Golem and a Sand Shield...
This war is now a battle
to protect each other!
Then, I want to fight Madara too!
A two-fold defensive wall of
Sand and Stone, huh?
Also, quite impressive!
Here he comes!
Time to go on the offensive!
Mizukage! Raikage!
Listen to me now!
Mizukage!
Water Style: Hidden Mist Jutsu!
Let's do this, Raikage!
Right!
Super Weighted Boulder Jutsu!
Granny, fix me up now!
Listen to me, Naruto...
You see... This war we're fighting...
In the beginning, I only agreed
to join the Allied Forces
to get rid of the Akatsuki.
But as I fought alongside you all,
I started feeling differently.
So now, I want to be here
as the Tsuchikage of
the Allied Shinobi Forces!
In the same manner,
shinobi villages that were once
at odds have joined together,
are changing and becoming one!
So maybe, this system of
the shinobi world
which has bred so much hatred
can change!
Naruto...
Let us deal with this Madara!
I swear we shall settle this
once and for all!
It will be our first step
in stopping the curse of hatred
we've been under until now!
Like Madara, we are similarly guilty
of stirring up hatred in the past.
It is our responsibility
to make things right!
Rest assured and leave this to us!
So...
You go take care of
the other Madara!
That will become the first step
in promoting hope for the future.
Old one, new one...
Defeating both Madaras
will bring an end to this war!
We will protect you on this battlefield!
So protect us by fighting over there!
Naruto's clone... I entrust you with
this message from the Five Kage.
We will win!
Yeah!
We'll win!
Chill out, Naruto...
You fool, ya fool.
Damn, it's so hard.
I couldn't even put a crack in it.
I could've let him pass
through me...
But to think he couldn't even
scratch this mask.
I hope that's not all the power
you can muster
to control the Nine-Tails...
Lava Style:
Scorching Rocks Jutsu!
Hot!
Water Style:
Aqua Mirror Jutsu!
These guys...
... have the same power...!
This chakra...
Utakata, you were a Jinchuriki?
You too, huh?
I heard rumors that
you had gone missing.
So the Akatsuki got you...
Yeah...
After I left you guys,
they were lying in wait for me.
Why did you go into
the forest alone?!
If you had escaped with Hotaru,
you'd still be—
The Shinobi Tracking Unit from
the village was in the forest.
I grew tired of running.
I wanted to reconcile with
the village and live in peace.
I wanted to stop living like a fugitive.
And I wanted to spare Hotaru
a life constantly on the run.
Utakata, you...
I wonder why I started
feeling that way?
Why did I wish for such a dream?
Well, it's all meaningless now.
I convinced myself that the master
I trusted had betrayed me.
And so, I closed off my heart.
I didn't know how to trust people.
And yet, Hotaru put her faith
in someone like me.
Hotaru was also burdened with
a fate she hid from others.
The same way we Jinchuriki are.
Maybe she sensed that
you and she were alike?
You have the will to
take yourself back.
This is a meaningless fight.
Naruto...
I don't know if it's because of
these circumstances or not, but...
I was able to tell you
my true feelings.
Thank you...
Naruto!
Water Style: Bubble Jutsu!
Sorry, Octopops!
Secret Tradition...
Scaled Sneak Jutsu.
My shades are the best!
This light won't put my eyes to the test!
I can still see through their evil intent!
Wasn't that Yugito just now?
These guys are former Jinchuriki.
On top of that, each of them
has a Sharingan in one eye
and a Rinnegan in the other.
Not only did they lose their lives,
their eyes were turned into
those disgusting things.
Poor Yugito...
This could have easily
happened to you.
This is no joke.
Seeing them change
fills me with grief...
But keeping my own eyes
is a huge relief!
You hide yours behind
shades anyway.
If you don't want to end up like that,
don't let your guard down!
Madara's eyes are the same.
His mask's different from
the one he used to wear before.
It's got two openings!
Unlike the previous one,
this mask was specially made.
It's battle-grade tough.
So the left eye you always kept hidden
was a Rinnegan,
just like Nagato and
that other Madara.
We're going to stop both you Madaras!
Did you just say "both"?
Summoning Jutsu:
Reanimation.
Yes. You can't refuse me.
Why you...
Where did you get that?
Don't worry.
I haven't told anyone about this.
Damn that Kabuto...
Whaddya mean by "both," fool?
Isn't this Madara, ya fool?
Well then, I don't mind using
my previous name, Tobi.
Now that the war's begun,
names don't matter.
Madara... Tobi...
Call me what you like.
Just who are you anyway?
I'm no one. I don't want to be anyone.
All I want... is the success of
Project Tsuki no Me, that's all.
You Jinchuriki had Tailed Beasts
forced into you
and you've only experienced despair.
Am I wrong?
Surely, you can understand
a little of my despair.
Who the hell are you to decide...
that having a Tailed Beast in me
makes me unhappy?!
Even if this world is worthless to you,
you really think you can get away
with starting a war
and trying to say that you're a nobody?
You piss me off.
I'm going to rip that mask off of you!
I'll go first! Wheee!
Taking this mask off of me...
won't be so easy.
Eight-Tails... Nine-Tails...
You shall be mine...
and I'll achieve
Project Tsuki no Me!
We're not going to let
you have Nine-Tails or Eight-Tails!
What's going on?
I thought their Tailed Beasts
were extracted from them?!
They were probably made back
into Jinchuriki
after they were reanimated...
I can also sense that
the Tailed Beasts are
a bit different from before too...
Be careful!
You too? Getting bad vibes?
Have to be careful with our lives
Samehada is ready to fight
That's fine with me...
'Cuz I'm raring to go...
Are ya ready?
Hold it, Octopops!
Nice moves...
OK! She didn't see my... KO!
You didn't even see me,
so how'd you dodge?! Fool, ya fool!
That's not going to work, Octopops!
It's just like the time
I fought the Six Paths of Pain.
Their eyes...
Their Rinnegan are all linked.
They're hooked up to each other!
What the hell does that mean?!
It's the same as
Nagato's Gedo Jutsu!
So they've got the eyesight...
of six guys!
Damn, I can't even talk...!
Hot!
Aw man!
It's Yugito's Mouse Hairball!
It's coming after us!
It's like a guided missile
Time to run, let's hustle
Yugito's moves are different
from before...
Half left of my expensive scarf...
What a surprise
Now it's only worth half the price
It's that Sharingan!
That's how they're able
to track us so closely!
Their Visual Prowess is
enhancing their Jinchuriki abilities!
On top of that,
with their shared vision,
the six Jinchuriki can
position themselves
and time their attacks
with more precision.
Bee! Let me talk to Naruto!
Yo!
Naruto... They're cleverly combining
the two types of Visual Prowess
and their Jinchuriki abilities.
They're probably on to us too.
What do we do?
We have no choice
but to take down
six Jinchuriki one by one!
If it's the same as
that time with Nagato,
they're all controlled by chakra.
Back then, in order to get chakra,
black receivers were stuck
to their bodies.
I see...
If we remove it or destroy it...
the Gedo Jutsu would be broken.
But that's going to be
a problem.
It's hard enough landing
a blow on them.
And we can't even pinpoint
where these black receivers are.
You mean, that thing?
Huh?
Where?!
Take a close look at Yugito's chest
and you'll see that black protrusion
At first, I thought it was her ni—!
When they're flaunted,
it's unappealing
But just a little glimpse,
it's a good feeling
This battle is going to
determine the future.
And you're only thinking about...
That's it!
I'm going to go check out
the others.
Wait, Naruto!
Our attacks don't work,
and we can't catch them...
Hot!
I'll just have to put up
with their attacks and grab them!
Rasengan!
I knew it was here!
Then... I'll just...!
Are you two all right?
Ouch...
Bee... We're at a disadvantage
fighting them in the woods.
Your field of vision is narrowed!
You get me, don't you, Bee?!
Oh... yeah...
Blow up the entire forest!
I'm Killer Bee and
Eight-Tails is here with me!
Wheee!
Don't fall off of me, Naruto.
'Cause now, the real fight's a go!
Eight-Tailed Beast Twister!
It seems Lord Bee has undergone
the Tailed Beast
transformation already!
I sense the immense chakra
of the Eight-Tails!
It feels like they're on
the defensive!
Things aren't looking
too good, are they?
Frankly...
However, the Five Kage
have Madara on the defensive!
We're doing okay for now!
The Five Kage are working together.
They have to have the edge!
What's the status of each company?!
The First and Second Companies
are on the verge of
annihilating the enemy.
The Third Company is down
to two Reanimations.
Out of all the Seven
Ninja Swordsmen of the Mist,
only Mangetsu Hozuki is left.
It appears the Fifth Company
needs a little more time...
But there's no doubt that
they have the upper hand!
All right!
Tell the First, Second, Third
and Fifth Companies
as soon as they wrap up...
They are to head over to
assist Naruto and Lord Bee!
What are their coordinates, Lord Ao?
W-Wow...
Seal them now, Bee!
Sealing Jutsu: Octopus Hold!
So that's it!
It's only one of Bee's Sealing Jutsu!
Just like that and on
a count of three...
Basically, in three seconds,
the ink will completely cover
their bodies and harden,
incapacitating them!
Once they're immobile,
we can remove the rods from their chest!
– One!
– Two!
– Three!
Go...
That masked bastard!
He was hiding underground!
Bug Bite!
Cat Claws!
Leech Slip!
Oww!
It's a strong alkaline fluid!
Your skin's melting!
Octopops!
Coral Palm!
What the hell...?!
Naruto!
Floral Mountain!
This is bad!
I didn't realize that
these guys could transform
into Tailed Beasts
just like that!
Naruto, retreat for now.
We need to regroup!
Horn Hit!
I can't move...!
Bastard!
Even if you're Jinchuriki,
six against two appears
to be bad odds, huh?
When I touch you, I win!
This isn't good!
Violent... Leaf Superhuman Hurricane!
Using Naruto as bait,
they waited for the moment
I materialized...
What a nuisance!
Kakashi-sensei and Bushier Brow-sensei!
Two more joining the party isn't going
to change anything.
Not against my Visual Prowess
and power of the Tailed Beasts.
We have Sharingan on our side too.
As well as the Noble Green Beast
of the Leaf!
You came, Kakashi-sensei!
Bushier Brow-sensei!
You know I can't just sit back
and relax
while my student from Team 7
is working hard!
Oh! Him! He's got a Sharingan
and a Rinnegan that are linked,
left eye to right eye... and...!
And there's a rod sticking out of
the left side of the chest... and...!
Calm down.
You're not making sense.
The right eye is Sharingan.
The left eye is Rinnegan.
And he has the same rod
Pain had in his left chest.
So I see.
Have to hand it to you, Kakashi.
Your skills of deduction
are impressive!
Here it comes!
From the number of tails...
It's Five-Tails!
Leaf Rock Crush!
Hey, thanks!
He's after the Eight-Tails!
Sorry, Eight-o! You okay?
We share pain, remember?
What about you? You okay, Bee?
He tried to attack him?
So painful...!
Huh?!
How can I let a bastard
like him do this to me...?
Why you...!
There! He did it!
Why would he suppress
the Tailed Beast's powers?
I don't know...
He doesn't seem to
have the Tailed Beast
completely under his control.
Maybe that's why...
Hey, did you hear
that voice, Naruto?
I heard it.
That was the Tailed Beast...
Five-Tails' voice.
We Tailed Beasts have emotions.
It pisses me off to see one of
my kind treated like that!
Ouch!
Now you get mad?
It's always been the same with
every shinobi who has kept us as pets!
Eight-Tails... You and that brat Bee
are a special exception.
I wonder about that Nine-Tails...
Huh?
Nine-Tails can talk to Eight-Tails?
I know all about it, Nine-Tails.
– You...
– You talk too much!
By the way, Eight-Tails, given
the number of tails you have,
aren't you the next
most powerful after me?
Hurry up and finish this!
I'm going to take a nap!
Don't decide who's stronger
based on the tail count!
You've always been like this!
That's why that Tanuki
One Tail really hates you!
Are you even listening, you fool?!
Don't you dare play possum,
you fox!
Eight-Tails and Nine-Tails
are arguing...
Through telepathy
the Tailed Beasts speak...
It's not only rare,
but an amazing feat!
What are you mumbling about,
Naruto?!
The enemy's approaching!
Just because I'm here, it doesn't
mean you can breathe easy!
Right!
We need to confirm which one uses
which of Pain's jutsu!
Got it, Guy?
I'm not good at
remembering faces...
And they all look the same to me...
Lightning Blade!
Eight Inner Gates!
Sixth Gate of Joy, Open!
Three are headed your way, Naruto!
They're here!
Three is better than what
we faced before...
I'm serious now too, hard core!
Chakra Absorption...
Summoning...
Magnetic Pull and Repulsion...
Chakra Extraction...
Puppetry...
What's going on?
They're not using any of those!
Why?!
They're not using any
of Pain's jutsu!
Maybe... they can't.
Maybe he's shrewd enough
not to waste any chakra
on Pain's jutsu since we already
know how to counter them!
Yeah. In order to control
six Tailed Beasts
with just his Visual Prowess,
he must use an enormous amount
of chakra.
Have to hand it to you,
Kakashi-sensei!
There's your deductive skill again!
Kakashi Hatake...
He's got very discerning eyes.
Well then...
I'll just power it up a little.
Next up, two beasts.
Damn it!
I'll have to use Nine-Tails' Chakra
to make Shadow Clones for a diversion...
and attack the masked guy head on!
You can't use anymore Nine-Tails'
chakra for Shadow Clones!
Nine-Tails will take
your own chakra...
And you'll drop dead
Then you'll be seeing red!
Bee, haven't you noticed yet?
I thought you bumped fists
with him!
Given the number of clones
he's already produced,
Naruto should have been
half-dead a while back.
Seeing as he's not means that
Nine-Tails stopped taking
Naruto's chakra sometime ago.
Right, Nine-Tails?
Although I don't know
what happened between you two...
You know, Nine-Tails...
I'm coming after all that hate
inside you, too, some day!
Who the hell are you to decide...
that having a Tailed Beast
inside me makes me unhappy?!
What the hell is that?!
Whatever you do,
don't let it touch you, Guy!
Naruto!
We have to help him!
Guy, we have to deal
with this side first!
This is bad too!
We're being surrounded!
The tree wilted instantly!
Is it a corrosive gas?
I'm worried about how much chakra
I have left, but I have no choice.
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Guy...
We have to guard
each other's back
and focus only on
what's in front of us.
Any complaints?!
Nope!
Lightning Cable!
Sixth Gate of Joy, Open!
Asakujaku!
Here comes the next wave!
Same here!
Let's wrap this up and help Naruto!
Let Naruto go, you monkey!
Nine-Tails...
I think you gave some
of your chakra
to the Naruto's clone who was
fighting the other Madara.
You should lend this one
strength too before it's too late.
I'm not like you, Eight-Tails.
I won't wag my tails each and
every time for my Jinchuriki...
Don't you care what happens
to Naruto?!
Nine-Tails...
Your current form is nothing more
than a momentary construct...
You're merely a fragment of power.
Shut up.
You are just an ignorant
unstable power...
Shut up.
Those who shall guide
you are the Uchiha.
You Tailed Beasts are simply
servants of those with Visual Prowess!
Shut the hell up!
Obey!
Nine-Tails...
Your power is too great.
Regrettably, I cannot
let you run loose.
No matter what words they use...
When you exert your power,
you draw hatred to you.
Please stay quiet inside me.
Humans all say...
This is unfortunate for both of us...
You may be here to keep
the world in check,
but I'm here to watch you.
... the same thing.
And now, it's this brat?
How dare these shinobi...
I'll bet even he...
You know, Nine-Tails...
I'm coming after all that hate
inside you, too, some day!
Naruto!
What the—?!
Now you want to take my power too?
Coming all the way in here...
you obnoxious brat!
A-Are you...
Four-Tails?!
Don't call me "Four-Tails"!
I have a proper name!
I am the handsome
Monkey King of Suirendo,
the King of Sage Monkeys,
bestowed with
the priestly title "Son"
from the Sage of Six Paths!
The Great Sage
Equalling Heaven, Son Goku!
Huh? Uh...
Which one's your name?
It's Son Goku!
You humans are all stupid!
You can't even get
a name straight!
You are all lesser than apes.
I don't want to give my power
to likes of such...
So where are we?
It sorta looks like
Nine-Tails' place...
Did you hear me, kid?!
I told you my name!
Don't you dare ignore me!
You're so rude!
Huh? Oh...
S-Sorry.
You're... pretty genuine for a human.
It's the first time I've heard
someone apologize to
a Tailed Beast.
I guess you didn't come to
steal my power, eh?
You have one inside you too...
That's how you got in...
Kurama's trained
his Jinchuriki well.
Kurama?
Who's Kurama?
How can you be the Nine-Tails' Jinchuriki
and not even know his real name?!
That's why humans disgust me!
Huh?! The Nine-Tails
has a name too?!
I see, his name's Kurama!
You humans only see us
as sources of power.
You don't even care if we have
names, or care to know them.
You imprison and deny us
of our existence.
Look, it's that boy.
Ignore him and keep walking.
Who's that boy?
You don't need to know.
I think I understand a little
about how you feel.
I used to misbehave a lot.
I just wanted to be scolded.
Huh?
I'd do anything to get people
to notice me.
It was better than being invisible.
I'm a Jinchuriki...
But I have a proper name
I cherish... Naruto.
It's a memento from
my parents and master.
That's why...
I'm no one.
I don't want to be anyone.
I just want to fulfill
Project Tsuki no Me.
I can't stand a guy like that who
doesn't even care who he is...
Well then, what do you
want to do with us?
Like Octopops...
I'd like to be like Octopops
and Eight-Tails.
Huh?
When I watch him joke around
with Eight-Tails,
and fight, and console each other...
They're like friends.
And I always have this feeling...
I... I really envy them.
Aw c'mon! Don't tell me...
A human like you seriously wants
to be friends with a Tailed Beast?!
Huh?
This guy...
He's dead serious...
That's why I want to help
you too... Umm...
What was your name again?
Just call me Son...
By the way, I ate you.
What are you going to do?
Oh, yeah! What'll I do?!
Hmmm...
He seems better than
the guy in the mask...
There is a way to stop me.
Undo these chains and you'll see.
Son!
You have to tell me
how to stop you.
First, just one thing...
I don't trust Jinchuriki on principle.
Especially fools like you
who claim they want to be friends
with Tailed Beasts.
In other words...
Don't think that if you set me free,
I'll be your ally.
If you want our trust...
It's fine.
I have a pretty good idea of
what I need to do anyway.
Naruto... I've seen all
that you've done.
So you should know by now.
No matter what you say to me,
to us Tailed Beasts...
It doesn't matter.
Your true feelings won't
be transmitted to us.
Unlock the noose,
have to let Naruto loose
So you were here.
I'll drag both you and
Four-Tails into me.
This isn't good.
Open your mouth!
Naruto, get out!
I've got to get outta here!
It's not opening.
It's not going to work like this.
Umm... umm...
I have to make him throw me up...
Throw up...
From overeating...
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Didn't expect so many Naruto
on the plate
He's smart to make him regurgitate
All right! I made it out!
Now then...
Listen! Take a good look
at the base of my neck.
There's a rod stuck into it.
That's where the chakra
chain binds us.
It's the chain of the demon statue
that Rinnegan Gedo uses.
Huh? It's not on the chest?
The Jinchuriki had it
on their chests.
It's because we expand in size
when we undergo
Tailed Beast Transformation...
The rods migrate to
the base of our necks.
And being bigger makes it
difficult to find.
You just don't know
when to give up...
Just pull that rod out.
Then the chakra chain won't form!
Damn, where is it?
Found it! That's it!
And the chain binding me
should disappear.
But it won't be easy.
I'll be controlled and unable
to stop from attacking.
Yeah, I know.
Things might get rough,
but you have to bear with me.
Don't go overboard and
end up killing me!
I can't keep up this mode
much longer.
I may as well just
push it to the limits!
Here it is!
Do it, Naruto!
Why you—!
It's working!
Damn Naruto...
It's not going to go that easily.
What the hell is this...?
My power...
Those rods bind anything
that touches them.
They're stronger restraints than
Nagato, Pain's Gedo Powers!
Naruto!
One problem after another!
Ya know, Nine-Tails, I...
I'm going to come after all that
hate inside you as well some day!
That's why I want to help you too...
Naruto...
If you're absolutely serious and
truly wish to do something
for us Tailed Beasts,
keep doing what
you've been doing...
Not yet...
All right!
Hope you can sense this okay!
The real me is outside...
right about here.
I did warn you that
I might have to get rough.
Hope you understand.
We're going to push
the rod out from the inside!
Keeping doing what
you've been doing all along
and prove yourself
through your actions!
Naruto... That's who you are!
Frog Slap!
It's loose!
That's right,
that's the Naruto I know.
Damned Naruto!
He pulled out the rod!
In that case...
Rasengan!
You did it!
What?! Why are
the chains still here?!
Heh... I guess this chain through
my stomach won't disappear...
Why?! I pulled out the rod,
just like you said.
That rod just temporarily binds
my chakra to the Jinchuriki's body.
But my chakra itself is held by that
masked guy through the Gedo Statue.
You knew about that?!
Then it means that
I haven't saved you!
You... You're seriously saying
that for real...?
Of course, I am!
This kid... He really is serious...
I only told you how to stop me.
I never told you how to save me.
You should have told me
that from the beginning!
Why aren't Tailed Beasts
more straightforward?!
So what do I have to do?!
Before I tell you,
I have something to pass on to you.
What is it?
Hold out your hand...
Huh? You're giving me something?
It's something good.
It will come in handy
one of these days. Hurry up!
What?!
The statue reabsorbed Four-Tails!
I guess he's still under his control!
You look like you're
about to pass out
after stopping
just one Tailed Beast...
You can't defy me!
I'm going to take your precious
Tailed Beast with these...
What's going on?!
This is bad,
no matter how you look at it.
And you're a mess.
Idiot. Just watch me...
If you want me to lend you power,
I wouldn't mind doing it, Naruto.
You sure are talking to me a lot, lately.
I'm glad you want to lend me power,
but before you do,
there's something I have to say.
Thanks for helping me with
the other Madara back there.
That extra power really saved me!
Don't thank me!
It's creeping me out!
I just did that because I'd rather
deal with you than Madara!
Besides, I could only give you a
tiny bit of chakra because of this cage!
I just wanted to see you fight
a little more!
That's right...
Just to pass the time!
Hey! Why do have to get mad
when I just thanked you?
You don't have to
stop glaring at me,
but you could at least work
on your attitude!
You're always like—?!
Meld your chakra with mine...
Are we going to play chakra
tug-of-war again?
You idiot...
We don't need to do that this time!
It's not like I have
anything else to do.
So we could if
you really wanted to.
Let's do this, Octopops!
We fight as a two-man team
with me taking the lead.
Naruto, you just be
my backup, agreed?
Even so, we're going up
against five Tailed Beasts.
You can't be on the front lines if you can't
do a Tailed Beast Transformation!
Both you and Eight-o are hurt,
so there isn't going to be
any leading or backing up!
We're going in together!
Hey... Naruto!
Especially since we're both already
in two-man teams...
Hold on, Naruto... Don't tell me...
You and the Nine-Tails...
I've still got tons
of reserve power!
I guess it was true all along!
Yeah... if he were the Demon Fox.
But Naruto is different!
He's... He's an excellent student...
that I have acknowledged!
He works very hard...
Despite that, he's clumsy and
no one would accept him...
So he already understands the pain
in people's hearts.
He is no longer the Demon Fox.
He's a member of the Hidden Leaf Village...
He's Naruto Uzumaki!
You're no longer the Demon Fox...
You are a member of the Hidden Leaf
and my partner...
Kurama!
Come on, let's do this!
Naruto... Don't tell me you...
Th-This is really bad!
Guy, don't move!
I'm going to blow them away
with my left eye's Kamui!
There's so many of them!
It's impossible with
Visual Prowess alone!
In that case,
I'll open the Eighth Gate...
You idiot!
You'll die after you do that!
But still...
Naruto! Looks like they're
in trouble over there!
There are five Tailed Beast Bombs
aimed right at them!
I know about it... y'know!
What was that?! So fast!
S-Sensei?!
I-Is that, Naruto?!
The mountain...
So this is the power of
the Tailed Beasts!
He deflected them all?!
In that case...
Here they come!
Let's go, Kurama!
Was Naruto able to do
Tailed Beast Transformation?
That Nine-Tails...
What's going on?!
Are we inside
the Nine-Tails' chakra?!
First, we have to figure out
where all of their rods are!
Just to let you know,
we don't have much time here.
This is our first Tailed Beast
Transformation, so our link isn't perfect.
We can only keep this up
for about five minutes!
That's more than enough time.
There are more of you,
so I can't be as gentle
as I was with Son.
So just grit your teeth!
I'm not falling for that same trick twice!
Take this!
All right! I found out where they all are!
This is like an all-out monster
smack down!
He exceeded my expectations.
I'll have to go after him
with intent to kill.
Hey... Don't you think that's pretty big
for one of those things?
Are they pooling their power
into a single point?!
Naruto, what now?!
Is he going to cancel it out
with equal force?!
But Naruto's never succeeded
at that before...
He managed to do it
by accident during training,
but this time, he'll do it for sure.
– Tailed Beast Bomb!
He aimed it low, so it would
bounce them upwards.
That was good...
but it was really big!
Nine-Tails sure is strong...
I've got all their rods!
Let's do this, Kurama!
We're going to pull them out
all at once!
We're going to free them all!
And definitely save everyone!
We've been waiting for you.
Huh?
The same thing happened with Son.
You did get all the way to this dimension...
just as Four-Tails said.
This isn't where Four-Tails was...
Now that we're fully linked,
you're able to enter deeper into
the Tailed Beast Psyche Dimension.
Look! There are Jinchuriki here too!
Also, Four-Tails was bound
by chakra chains.
I don't really get it,
but everyone's here and
there aren't any chains.
It's not as crazy as last time!
That jerk in the mask cannot
penetrate this deep.
Welcome!
I thank you on behalf of all of
us Jinchuriki and Tailed Beasts.
I've wanted to meet you,
Naruto Uzumaki!
To tell you the truth... huh?
You look shorter, younger,
and weaker than me!
You must have had it rough
as a Jinchuriki.
Knowing how you went through that...
And how you've already passed on...
It's just so sad.
You never knew
the taste of good ramen...
or what it felt like to kiss a girl!
– Hey! You've never kissed a girl either!
– I'm the former Fourth Mizukage!
– I was quite distinguished!
– Actually...
– And I'm an adult!
You've only kissed Sasuke.
No! Don't make me remember that!
Hey, you're barfing way too much!
What was it like kissing that Sasuke?!
I'm talking to you!
Honestly, just as Four-Tails said,
you don't listen at all!
Four-Tails?
So, Son was here too?
That's right...
Finally...
So does that mean that
bearded old man was here too?
Yup!
Make sure to tell him...
Also, I was able to give him
just a tiny bit of my chakra.
Do you remember what Old Man
Six Paths told us at the very end?
I think this kid's it...
That's what I felt.
I wager he'll probably come here
to save all of you too.
Look after that kid when he does.
I'm being pulled back
into the statue...
Goodbye for now, guys.
Four-Tails...
This is just hypothetical, but...
Do you think we could have
traveled down a different path too?
This coming from you, who's even
more stubborn than Tsuchikage Ohnoki?
Have you gone soft after death?
Well... maybe if you had tried
to remember my name,
right when you became
my Jinchuriki...
I haven't softened enough to
start calling you by your name,
after being your Jinchuriki
for over forty years...
But I haven't forgotten it either!
In that case, say my full name,
spiel and all.
Is just "Son" good enough?
We assembled here on
Four-Tails' summons...
and hung around after promising
to tell, and give you, something.
I see... He did all that?
I'm glad that you're all gathered
together and getting along!
That only happened after
Four-Tails and Roshi left here.
It's all thanks to you, Naruto.
Naruto, step forward and
extend your hand...
We shall now fulfill our promise
to Four-Tails... rather Son Goku.
My name is Matatabi.
Yugito Ni'i...
My name is Isobu.
We've met before, huh?
I'm Yagura,
the former Fourth Mizukage.
I am Kokuo.
I'm Han.
Me, I am called Saiken.
You already know me, I'm Utakata.
I'm Lucky Seven Chomei.
I'm Fuu!
I will not live much longer...
Shukaku, Matatabi, Isobu,
Son Goku, Kokuo,
Saiken, Chomei, Gyuki, and Kurama...
Even if you are far apart,
you will always be together.
There will come a time when
you will be united again.
Each of you with a unique name...
and a different form than before.
And unlike when you were inside me,
you will be guided down
the right path.
I hope you learn what true strength is...
Before that time...
It's taken way too long, Old Man.
Don't you all agree?
That Naruto's the Old Man's...
Yes!
Yup!
Yeah!
Indeed...
For sure...
Well done, Naruto!
I never thought you'd be able to
completely control Nine-Tails.
However, it looks like you still
can't maintain it for too long.
So same old, same old.
It's not the same old, same old...
I just learned a bunch
of hard names all at once!
Difficult names?
What does that have to do
with anything?
You don't know, do you?!
I'm not going to tell you!
Naruto gaining
such experience and strength
makes me feel old and feeble.
What's the matter?
You're not being yourself!
It may sound funny
coming from me...
The springtime of our youth
is still far from over!
We still have a lot of...
Quiet! Do you want to make me
feel even worse?
That's the Guy I know!
That expression...
Huh? Am I sweating?
No, it's just rain.
These fools could never
make me sweat.
Naruto was always
merely a pawn to test Sasuke.
That brat's supposed to be
an amusement.
I knew what his limits were.
There's no way his power could be
pushing me this hard.
So what is it?!
What happened?
It doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter who
or what Naruto is now...
After this war is over,
there will be no past or future.
Nothing that exists now
will matter then!
A-Amazing...
Did you guys feel that?
I can't believe it.
There's no doubt.
That is the Nine-Tails' power!
Yeah...
But I sense something...
slightly different.
What's the current situation?
Naruto Uzumaki is holding back
the Masked Madara
with an unbelievable amount
of power.
The chakra is unbelievable!
He's keeping him at bay.
It's just the four of them!
Naruto, Bee, Kakashi and Guy!
Inoichi!
Relay Naruto's actions directly
into the minds
of the reinforcement troops
with everything you've got!
Fifteen seconds is all we need!
I want to boost everyone's morale
all at once!
Those four are giving it their all!
I want the rest of us here
to do everything we can too.
Transmit their resolve to everyone!
To everyone?!
It will overload the chakra network.
Make one mistake and...
You ask for the extreme.
Make it ten seconds!
Master Inoichi!
Sorry, but this is critical!
Make it short,
but make it count!
I'm not good with words,
but you can count on me!
Message from HQ!
We have the upper hand at
the battle reinforcement point!
Naruto Uzumaki is standing firm!
The ones we must protect at all costs,
Naruto and Bee...
are fighting with everything
they've got on the front line!
Guy and Kakashi are there too!
And I want everyone in the Alliance...
to join your strong feelings with theirs!
Because those strong feelings...
are the prophecy...
that leads to our victory!
I'm bad with words, after all.
It took me 20 seconds.
Captain...
Yeah...
That just shows how mighty
your heart is...
Naruto...
I have always... always...
always been chasing after you.
And I'm still running after you.
But when this war is over.
I'm going to stop running.
I'll stand with you.
I'll hold your hand.
And I'll walk with you by your side.
So please wait for me!
Naruto...
I marked you as
my rival ages ago.
hold out against Madara,
until I get there!
I'll support you completely
with my ninjutsu, Naruto.
As for the reason...
It is not necessary!
Naruto is doing a good job.
I can't see him being
anything other than reckless.
But despite his looks,
he's a pretty sharp guy.
People thought Naruto was dumb
and I was fat.
But that really wasn't the case!
Wait for me, smart Naruto!
A Slim Choji is coming to help you!
He's not the type to strategize calmly.
That's what I'm here for.
So you just wait, Naruto.
I'll be right there!
Thank you, Dad!
You transmitted Naruto's mighty heart
to everyone.
That promise must be fulfilled!
I wonder if Guy-sensei is all right?!
I hope he's protecting Naruto!
Kakashi-sensei is there too.
I think they'll manage, but...
If it wasn't raining,
we could have flown on
my Super Beast Scrolls.
Stop complaining, Sai.
Pick up your speed!
We must follow Guy-sensei
and Naruto's examples.
This is the time for us
to exceed ourselves!
Uh-huh...
This is camaraderie...
I think I finally understand
human bonds, Naruto.
Naruto...
You saved the Hidden Leaf.
And now, you are trying to
save the shinobi world.
And we've always, always put
the burden on your shoulders.
But this time,
no matter what you say...
you'll have help.
Not just me.
This time,
we'll all fight together!