Six Paths Gramps?
Are you by any chance
the legendary...?
I am Hagoromo Otsutsuki.
Also known as
the Sage of the Six Paths.
No wonder... you're levitating.
At this point,
nothing shocks me anymore.
It seems like everything
went well.
The shinobi world sure became
a mess while we were dead.
Damn it!
It's the first time I've seen so many
Tailed Beasts together in one place!
The Sage of the Six Paths, eh...
It feels like we've wandered
into a fairy tale!
So you are the one, after all.
Summoning the past
Five Kage here and...
being able to bring the Tailed Beasts
and us back from the other dimensions...
You're probably the only person
who could perform such godly actions.
Are you Kakashi Hatake?
Oh... yes.
Good job guiding everyone and
sealing my mother away.
That truly was the work of gods.
Oh, no.
I hardly played any part at all.
It was these three
and many comrades.
And... a former friend also
lent me strength.
That's why I said you
guided everyone well.
Despite losing your way,
you remained Naruto's teacher
and Obito's friend.
Or else, you likely wouldn't have
succeeded in stopping my mother.
Hey! Kurama!
Were you lonely being
separated from me?
I missed you!
Don't talk so loud!
I wasn't lonely.
You have half of me
inside you... remember?
Just look at Kurama,
all embarrassed and flustered!
But this is exactly
what I had once envisioned.
That there would one day
be a shinobi,
who could move even
the Tailed Beasts to cooperate.
Even Obito was Naruto's doing...
He restored Obito.
I see...
Then I shall ask Obito to tell me
that tale in the afterlife.
Is he still...?
I'm going to get going soon.
Yeah...
I really made a mess out
of the shinobi world.
So much that I don't even know
what to say to you before I go.
We're able to say goodbye
as friends, not enemies.
To the old you...
the one who was always late
because you were helping others.
That's plenty enough for me.
Thanks, Kakashi.
I'll be going then.
I've been keeping Rin waiting.
Do you have an excuse ready?
I told her beforehand
I'd be helping you.
I see...
Same here...
Thank you, Obito.
Kakashi-sensei!
Sakura... Thank you.
Kakashi-sensei, your eyes!
Yeah...
As of today, Kakashi of
the Sharingan is no more.
Madara was a Jinchuriki.
Even if it was temporary...
emptied of the Tailed Beast,
he won't last long.
It's his fault for trying
to use such things.
Sasuke, Naruto...
Behold, the end of
your predecessors.
You should watch this closely.
Is that you, Hashirama?
I guess neither you nor
I could achieve what we wanted.
It's never that easy!
Our job is to do all that we can,
while we're alive.
And then, bequeath the rest for
future generations to accomplish.
So naïve...
as usual.
You... were always... the optimist.
But perhaps...
that is the correct path.
My dream...
was squashed.
But your dream...
still lives on.
We were both too hasty.
We didn't need to fulfill
our dreams ourselves.
It was more important to cultivate
those who would come after us...
to whom we could entrust
our dreams.
Which means I would
have failed anyway.
Since I always hated someone...
standing behind me...
When we were kids...
You once said we're shinobi
and we don't know
when we'll die.
And that for neither side to die,
we'd both have to reveal
what's inside of us
and pour each other drinks
to toast like brothers.
But we're both about to die.
Right now, we can drink together,
as war buddies.
War buddies... huh?
Well...
I guess... that's fine...
then...
This is the perfect moment.
I will release the jutsu,
free the Five Kages
and those under the Reanimation.
Go.
Dad...
Oh, that's right.
I've been meaning to tell you...
Happy birthday!
You've become
a splendid young man, Naruto
Yeah... Thank you.
We're an existence outside
the rules.
We can't remain
in this world forever.
It's time to say goodbye.
I promise to tell
Kushina everything.
Tell her not to worry.
I'm eating properly!
I'm not picky and eat
lots of different stuff!
Like, tonkotsu ramen,
miso ramen, and shoyu ramen...
Oh but, not just ramen though!
I try to bathe every day!
I go to the Leaf Hot Springs
once in a while too!
Although everyone just says
I only take quick dips...
What else, what else...
I've made lots of friends!
And they're all good guys!
And...
I was really awful at school,
but I never got depressed and
had more confidence
than anyone else!
Naturally, I always obeyed
Lord Third and Kakashi-sensei.
I respect them both!
They're right here,
so you can ask them yourself!
Oh! And those
Three Prohibitions of Shinobi?
I learned a lot about that
when I was with Pervy Sage!
He was hopeless
when it came to them though...
but he was an awesome Sannin
and I respect him the most!
I just turned 17 today,
so I don't know much
about alcohol or girls...
I know Mom said to find
someone like her...
But... that's... um...
Anyway!
Not everything
Mom told me about went well,
but I'm doing the best I can!
I've got dreams too!
I'm going to become an even
greater Hokage than you, Dad!
I swear I will!
So when you see Mom over there,
please tell her...
that she doesn't have to
worry about me at all!
Tell her I'm doin' my best!
Got it...
I'll make sure
to tell her everything.
We're leaving the rest to you...
Kakashi, Sakura...
Sasuke and Naruto.
Lord Third!
Elder Brother, you finally
settled things with Madara.
As Saru said...
let's leave the rest
to the next generation.
Naruto Uzumaki...
Sasuke Uchiha...
You two will probably find
a different conclusion than we did.
No... make sure you do.
Now, we're free too!
I'm going back to Suirendo!
I'm going to seclude myself in a forest.
We can finally go back to our homes.
It's like a dream.
Eight-Tails, what are you going to do?
Me? Well...
I think I'm going to go back to Bee.
Even his annoying rap
has actually grown on me.
So, what about you?
What will you do?
I'll...
A little piece of each of your chakra...
is already within Naruto.
In short, Naruto is like
a gathering place for you.
If you want to discuss something,
you can speak to each other through
your chakra inside Naruto.
Kurama...
Hmm?
I'd like you to stay inside Naruto as
the overseer of the gathering place.
It's no longer a hardship
for you anymore, is it?
Well, if you say so, old man,
I guess have no choice.
What?!
What's so funny?
Still not upfront with your feelings...
You haven't changed at all, Kurama.
So the Great Ninja War
is finally over now.
Yes. All that's left is...
Naruto and Sasuke...
I asked you before.
After battling my mother Kaguya,
is there any change to
the answers you gave me?
My answer's the same.
And I'm sorry, Gramps,
but there is one thing I feel
strongly about after fighting Kaguya...
I'm really glad that
Kushina Uzumaki was my mom.
Kaguya was different from
anyone I've ever battled.
It's like she didn't have a heart at all.
It's said my mother Kaguya started off
as a beloved goddess of the people.
I do not know for sure what
caused her to transform
into a being that came to
be called a demon.
I suspect something was triggered
the moment she devoured
the Chakra Fruit.
In any case,
you are not like my mother.
I trust you not to become like her,
even with all the Tailed Beast
chakra within you.
Now then, all that's left is...
to undo the Infinite Tsukuyomi.
But how, specifically?
Do you need our powers?
No, you're fine.
Naruto has the chakra
of every Tailed Beast.
And Sasuke possesses the Rinnegan.
If they both weave
the sign for rat simultaneously,
the jutsu will be undone.
What? That's it? It's so simple.
I researched thoroughly how to
undo Mother's Infinite Tsukuyomi.
There's no mistake.
Now then,
the rest is up to you, Sasuke.
Yes...
But first, I'm going to execute the current
Five Kage who are trapped in the Infinite Tsukuyomi.
What did you just say, Sasuke?
What about the Five Kage?
Oh, and...
I'm putting all of you Tailed Beasts
under my control...
and eventually,
I'll get rid of you as well.
What did you say?!
Kurama!
He put the Tailed Beasts
in a genjutsu...
and with a single glance too.
Naruto, it has ended up
as I expected.
I have no choice
but to leave the rest to you.
I cannot stay in
this world any longer.
I shall soon fade away.
Yeah, and sorry for saying this,
Six Paths Gramps...
but we won't end up like your sons.
I'm not Ashura.
And Sasuke isn't Indra either.
Sasuke!
Is this what your current dream is?
Are you saying you're
still seeking vengeance?
Sasuke!
I admit, at one time,
all I wished for was destruction,
and vengeance was my goal.
But I feel differently now.
I want to destroy, and rebuild.
A village no longer
shrouded in darkness.
I'll reform the shinobi world.
What I am proposing is...
revolution!
Revolution?!
My dear Sasuke,
what do you want to do?
What is it that you seek
in the aftermath of this war?
I want to hear your honest thoughts
and opinions.
All the previous Kage created
these current circumstances.
So I will become Hokage
and change the village.
This Hokage you speak of...
What do you mean by it?
If you want to know so badly,
I'll tell you.
Planetary Devastation!
Naruto...
It's on you!
I swear I'll get you all out!
Just hang in there
a little while longer!
Because of this war,
I've become quite adept at
using my Rinnegan's abilities.
And all those who were
in my way are gone.
Except for you...
Naruto.
Things just don't go as planned.
When I bequeathed power
to just one side,
I ended up with Indra and Ashura.
This time, even after entrusting power
to both, the result is the same.
Nope... All sibling squabbling
ends right here!
Let the Tailed Beasts go.
They've finally gained freedom.
They won't cause trouble anymore.
Naruto, you don't seem to get it.
You're now the Jinchuriki
of all the Tailed Beasts.
Which means I plan to
eventually get rid of
the Tailed Beast chakra
inside of you too.
What?!
In other words,
you're going to die, Naruto.
Out of necessity.
If what the Sage said was true,
there's no need to use
the Tailed Beast power inside you
to release the Infinite Tsukuyomi.
I can take advantage of
the Tailed Beasts that I captured.
I'll let them live until then.
You know that I won't
let you do that, right?
I guess I'll have to
deal with you first, Naruto.
Let's move this elsewhere.
You know, don't you?
Wait, Sasuke!
Sensei!
The recoil of the Sharingan...
I...
I know in my heart that
there's nothing I can do!
Even though I love you.
Even though I care about you
so much, Sasuke. And yet...
I can't get close to you
or exchange blows with you.
I can only whine and beg
and cry like this again.
It's so pitiful, isn't it?
Sakura...
Thank you.
But... But Sasuke!
If there's even a little corner of
your heart that thinks about me,
please don't leave again!
If we stick together,
I know it can be like old times again...
You're...
... really annoying.
Sakura!
You didn't need to put Sakura
under genjutsu!
If I didn't,
she would've chased after us,
and gotten in the way.
Sakura... Sakura just wanted
to help you, all this time.
So you're suggesting I should play at romance?
Well, I have no reason to love her
or be loved by her.
The only time you need a reason
is when you hate someone!
And Sakura's not trying to
make you hers!
She just wants to help you!
She almost died by your hand.
But she still thinks of your welfare
and sheds tears for you...
because she suffers from loving you!
Perhaps, those are the ties
to a failed past.
Sasuke!
I made a promise.
Long ago... to Sakura.
I'll definitely bring Sasuke back!
I swear on my life!
Sensei! You know about
my ninja way, right?
I'm going to go.
Yeah... We're counting on you.
Love is a difficult thing...
I once had two sons.
I loved them both,
and they loved and revered me.
But I entrusted everything
to the younger brother.
That became the impetus
for the older brother to begin
hating his brother and me.
Love transformed into hate.
What molded the current Sasuke,
is none other than
his loss of love in the past.
Madara was the same too.
Are you saying that Sasuke shares
the same fate as Madara?
No, not at all.
I, too, want to make the future
better in my own way.
Having learned from past mistakes,
this time I gave both of them the power.
The past does not exist
to remind the present that
the future cannot change.
The past is supposed to exist
for the sake of the future.
How did you see the potential
within Naruto?
Naruto Uzumaki...
The boy was able to save
and befriend Kurama,
who had become
a concretion of hatred.
I shall let Naruto handle this.
Since I hope that hate can be
transformed into love this time.
Or rather, I have hope that
love can be regained.
Because, unlike my mother,
Naruto as well as Sasuke...
know what love is.
This place, huh?
I should've figured.
Doesn't it bring back memories,
Sasuke?
Long ago, we fought here.
And just like before,
you're going to lose.
You won't be hitting me with
that same punch as last time!
I'm not about to let you get away
with whatever you want.
I won't let you become
the Hokage, either!
You don't even understand
what it means to be Hokage!
I told you, that to me,
being Hokage means revolution.
It's totally different from what you think.
Let me tell you something
your big brother said...
It's not the one who becomes Hokage
who gets acknowledged by everyone.
It is the one acknowledged by
everyone who becomes Hokage.
I learned not from Itachi's words,
but from the way he lived his life.
You and I came up
with different answers.
Let me clarify this
before we battle...
I'll teach you exactly what being
Hokage means to me.
My explanation of
what it means to be Hokage
represents my response.
The way Itachi lived
led me to this answer.
To protect the Land of Fire
and the Leaf Village,
he sacrificed both
his clan and himself.
First, I needed to know why.
What is this Land and Village
that he would go so far to protect?
The previous Hokage said...
... that the village is a framework
created to stop the slaughter
of clans and children...
... a framework that was
supposed to lead to peace.
Itachi tried to sustain
that peace all by himself.
That's when I finally understood...
Suffering bitter experiences,
living in darkness
as a criminal and traitor
against Land and Village...
He was a shinobi
who took on all hatred
and protected the Land of Fire and
the Leaf Village from the shadows.
I feel he was the true Hokage.
It's not the one who is
acknowledged by all...
... but the one who
accepts all the hatred
that is worthy of that title.
I eventually came to understand
Itachi's feelings
for his Land and Village.
My big brother failed
in just one aspect.
He let me,
his little brother, live.
Unable to hide the truth from me,
he allowed the hatred
to disseminate.
However... I'm not like
my Big Brother anymore.
I have no father, mother, brother...
not even a single member
of my clan.
I am all alone.
I alone can bear the weight
of all the hatred now.
And I alone will deal
with everything personally.
I will handle all the
shinobi's problems.
I will also dispense
all judgment and punishment.
I'll concentrate
all hatred upon myself...
... and bring together every
single village under my control.
Hatred inside darkness
cannot be eliminated.
In which case, I'd rather...
That's right...
What the Hokage is to me...
... is someone who will sear away
the darkness of all Five Villages
with only his own flame.
And then keeps living
by eating the ashes.
And you think everyone will just
sit back and say "yes" to that?
I told you already...
I don't care what you
or anyone else thinks.
Besides, I have the power now
to control it all.
You don't have a clue
about how Itachi lived!
There are things
you can't do alone!
Just like our battle with Kaguya!
But things don't always go well...
Like with these two stone statues
And us two brothers...
With revolution...
... the villages will no longer
have to bear darkness.
And I alone
will become the darkness.
I'll dispose of the deep darkness
of the past,
and build a pure white future
from scratch.
You mean by killing
the Tailed Beasts,
and the Five Kage?!
Exactly.
I'm casting off the past.
You're saying you can pretend
nothing ever happened with Itachi?
You and Itachi were brothers,
and a lot happened between you...
That's what made you
who you are today!
Itachi is now in my past.
I'm cutting all past mistakes and
doubts here, and starting anew.
Beginning by cutting you down.
Yours will be
the last blood I shed,
in the memory of my late brother.
I won't... let you kill me.
I learned everything I know
from the people of my past!
Especially about how to figure out
what to do after making a mistake.
You said you consider
Sasuke a brother.
That's why, Naruto,
I believe you are the only one
who can stop Sasuke.
I'm leaving Sasuke to you.
That's why...
I won't let you kill me.
Naruto... Sasuke...
Show me your answer...
Show me the answer for all shinobi!
Inferno Style: Honoikazuchi!
His left eye is...
How the hell do you think
you understand?
You've been alone from the start!
It's because I have these ties,
that I feel this agony.
How could you possibly understand
what it feels like
to lose all that?!
What's the matter?
Are you just going to play defense?
If you keep stalling, you'll die.
I don't want to kill you!
To me, you've become
my closest friend.
You're trying to be alone again
and I can't let that happen!
Especially since we both know
what that's like...
That's why I can't let you...
... go there...
... intentionally!
Stop your rambling.
We're both different from
the two boys who
fought here long ago...
I know your heart...
... and you, mine...
But you still want to fight me?
All the more, because it's you.
I have to cut you out of my life.
There's no guarantee that the world
you'll rebuild
after severing the past...
... won't end up just like this one,
you know.
That's exactly why I'll continue
to watch over that world...
So it doesn't.
You're missing the point!
The Five Villages
are finally united!
Yeah... But that's only because
they found a common enemy.
To defeat the Akatsuki, Madara,
and Kaguya...
the Five Villages had no choice
but to discard their grudges
and form an alliance
in order to survive.
But their mutual foes are now gone.
Eventually, conflicts between
each village will begin again.
So this time,
you're going to become the enemy?
And? What'll happen
after you're gone?
Finally,
all the dots have connected
and formed a straight line.
I started with the Sharingan
and now, I possess
the power of the Rinnegan.
Reincarnation, immortality...
I have many options.
I'll also be able to control things
from the shadows,
instead of through battle.
You're planning to
return to that hell,
for the rest of your life,
or rather for all eternity?
While being hated by all?
To me,
that's what a Hokage ought to be.
That's not even
close enough to kill me.
I told you!
I'm not trying to kill you!
I'm—!
Enough.
I'm the strongest in
this world right now.
So right now, right here...
will be my first step
into the shadows.
This is bad...
He's merging all the chakra
that's been scattered into one...
And doing it unbelievably well too,
almost unrivaled.
He's just as good as
Old Man Six Paths...
Well, except he's doing
the reverse thing...
There's no Gedo Statue here, so he's
making the Susano'o the receiving vessel.
Something incredible
is going to emerge...
Don't let down your guard, Naruto!
That jutsu again?
Naruto...
That jutsu of yours
symbolizes your weakness.
That's right...
It's a jutsu that covers up
your loneliness!
Why that—!
You only hold a little piece of
each Tailed Beast's chakra...
You can't win against me now.
Nor this...
Not yet?!
Kurama!
I might have amassed too much, in fact.
It's everything that's available.
Here it comes!
I can feel it!
How did he gain so much
Nature Energy so suddenly?
Let's do this!
Yeah!
You finally decided to kill me, huh?
We've taken on a lot of responsibilities
upon our shoulders...
But you see,
I...
I want to fight you too.
I want to fight,
and win against you fair and square!
But...
... not against the current you!
You already know that too...
right, Sasuke?!
This fight with you right now,
will be my last.
Indra's Arrow...
Currently, the most powerful jutsu
in my arsenal...
So just... die.
Just be gone already!
Damn it...
You're not—!
Naruto!
If my Nature Energy
didn't make it to you in time,
you'd have been
blown away just now!
And your chakra's already
long been drained from—
Amaterasu!
Only a diversion, huh?
I can't actually take
him down with this...
I need the Tailed Beasts...
I've used too much chakra...
can't maintain control!
At this rate, I can't use
my left eye's abilities either!
He's still not—!
Give it up already...
– Sasuke!
– Naruto!
Damn it!
Sasuke wins!
All right, both of you,
make the Unison Sign.
Not even a nod of acknowledgment?!
You jerk!
I've got to get this off my chest!
You jerk! No, you colossal loser!
Ouch!
I told you that shinobi Kumite is
a time-honored and sacred tradition!
Now, make the Unison Sign now!
You're finally awake.
It's dusk already.
Where are Sasuke and Naruto?
They're currently fighting
their final battle...
... in order to settle things for good.
Hang in there!
It's not much, but I've finished
infusing some more chakra—!
This is one of the abilities
of the Rinnegan.
As someone who possesses
the eyes of the Uchiha...
My victory is inevitable.
Now...
Now, I can finally be alone!
Farewell...
My one and only...
friend!
That was a great counter!
You didn't miss the fact that
his visual prowess is weakened!
Over and...
... over and...
... over and over
and over again!
Just give up and
let me cut you down!
Can't do that.
'Cuz I'm your one and only friend!
I figured as much...
He's assimilated the chakra I created
and infused for you, and made it his own...
And now Flame Control...
He intends to finish this
with one last blast.
Listen, I'm giving what remains
of my own chakra...
Once I do that,
it's going to put me to sleep.
Don't unleash your jutsu
until the last minute,
so he doesn't absorb
more chakra from you.
Well, not that he can use
his newly awakened Rinnegan
to absorb chakra while
putting out his own jutsu...
Who are you to be so confident when
you couldn't even save Sasuke?
I've never given up...
Once you give up, it's over.
I will save Sasuke, and...
I'm coming after all that hate
inside you too, someday!
Now go...
You're the one and only
for us too...
That's why Sasuke is...
Sasuke wins!
All right, you two...
make the Unison Sign.
You want a piece of me, you loser?
What is this?
Am I dead?
This sensation...
It must be...
Probably.
Pitiful, isn't it?
You had the Nine-Tails...
and I was an Uchiha.
We were ostracized from the village
and treated like outcasts.
And we resented the village
and its people.
Right?
I won't let you say I'm wrong.
You called me your brother...
In that sense, perhaps we were.
You're totally wrong!
Damn it,
you don't understand, do you?
Sorry, Grandma Tsunade...
I promised... I wouldn't die...
until I became the Hokage...
Oh yeah! The Infinite Tsukuyomi!
This is bad!
The Release Jutsu can't be activated
without us being there, right?!
You're dead... and you're worried
about what happens to the world?
Of course!
We can't leave it like that!
Sakura and Kakashi still remain.
They'll figure something out.
I hope so.
Naruto!
The Hokage, huh...
Pretty soon, Big Brother, they might
carve your face into the rock over there!
Big Brother?
Forgive me, Sasuke. This is it.
And no matter what you do
from here on out, know this...
I will love you always.
Big Brother...
I'll be seeing you... soon.
You've finally come to, eh?
As you can see...
if either of us moves too much,
we'll bleed out and die.
Why would you go that far?
Why do all that...
just to get in my way?
I gained the power to enter the darkness,
and sever all bonds...
And naturally, everyone's tried to cut
their ties to me as well, at some point.
But you...
You've never attempted
to cut me off.
The only one who can handle
all that hatred is me!
Why do you keep
involving yourself with me?
You already know, don't you?
Now that your body can't move,
your mouth sure is moving a lot.
Just answer me!
'Cuz you're my friend.
What is it with you anyway?
I'm your friend!
Just what the hell do you want?
Why are you so fixated on me?
It's because I'm your friend!
I've heard that before.
But what exactly does that mean
to you anyway?
You ask me to explain it,
but I really can't put it into words.
It's just that...
when I see you take on stuff...
and get all messed up...
It kinda...
hurts me.
It hurts so much inside,
that I can't just leave it alone, y'know?
Though right now, it hurts so much,
I can't really do anything.
Naruto... I knew you were
always alone back then.
The village shunned you,
just like they did with me...
the lone Uchiha survivor.
You intentionally did stupid things
to get scolded,
most likely to get people's attention.
In the beginning, I thought
you were good for nothing.
A weakling who just constantly
wanted to goof around.
But the more I watched you doing stupid things
and getting scolded over and over...
For some reason,
it started weighing on my mind.
I thought back then, that your weakness
was gradually rubbing off on me.
Then, every time I'd see you,
I'd think about you more and more.
Seeing you desperately
trying to bond with others...
made me remember my own family.
And I don't know why,
but I felt relief.
But at the same time,
I considered it a weakness.
I trained hard
as if to escape that weakness.
In order to get my revenge
on my brother
to become stronger than him.
And yet... I ended up
on the same team as you.
And I began thinking about
my family again.
I went on missions with you
as you jabbered on and on
about becoming Hokage...
I saw how both of us
were getting stronger...
And one day, I started to feel
the desire to fight you too.
And I began to see a shadow
of my own family in Team 7...
That's why every time
I saw you suffering...
That's right...
I felt it...
I felt pain too.
When I understood your hurt,
I finally saw you as a comrade.
But on the other hand...
I couldn't leave you alone.
You were getting stronger and stronger.
Watching you steadily get stronger...
I...
I knew that you were always alone.
I wanted to walk over and start talking.
I'd get sort of giddy.
But I stopped myself.
I was jealous because
you were good at everything.
So I made you my rival.
You've been...
my goal.
I had nothing, and I found a bond.
I wanted to be strong
and cool like you.
That's why I kept chasing after you.
It was the opposite.
In reality, I was the one
who was jealous of you.
Because you had a strength
that I didn't.
You were always walking
in front of me.
Just like my late Big Brother.
And... even today...
I'll let you deal with Sasuke.
That was my plan from the start!
Entrusting it to you was
the right thing to do, after all.
These are—!
Naruto's memories.
My dream...
is to surpass the Hokage one day!
And that's why I'm going to
make everyone in the village
acknowledge me!
I have to be ready...
I'm going to be called the Hokage,
someone that everyone acknowledges.
There's no such thing as a shortcut!
Quit messin' around,
I'll never run away!
I will make it!
Even if I stay a Genin
for the rest of my life,
I'll become the Hokage.
So I don't care!
I never go back on my word.
That's my ninja way!
I'm different from you.
I'm absolutely going to
become the Hokage.
Becoming the Hokage is my dream.
I won't die...
until I become the Hokage!
I'm going to become the Hokage
to surpass all the previous ones!
That's my dream, you idiot!
The Hokage is someone
who endures the pain
and takes the lead
in front of everyone.
So a Hokage never walks over
his comrades' corpses.
There is no shortcut
to becoming the Hokage!
And there is no running away
for the one who becomes Hokage!
No way can a guy who can't even
save one friend become the Hokage.
Isn't that right, Sasuke?
Naruto...
How far... have you—?
No matter how powerful you become,
don't try to shoulder everything alone.
You share your father's dream,
don't you?
Then don't ever forget...
Becoming Hokage doesn't mean
people will acknowledge you.
But when the people acknowledge you,
you can become Hokage.
Never forget your friends!
Big Brother...
I see.
Then...
show me...
Where are we?
Don't tell me this is really
Heaven this time?
Looks like we fell asleep
and slept until morning.
We've failed to die again.
Damn it! I still can't move!
I was hoping to punch you hard and
make you finally open your eyes!
Wh-What is it?
We're messed up like this,
and you still want to fight?
Damn right! No matter
how many times it takes—
I admit it.
I've...
lost.
You idiot!
This fight isn't about winning or losing!
It's about punching a sulking friend,
to make him snap out of it!
That's what it's about!
The real match that I want,
comes after that!
Hey, Naruto...
I just acknowledged you.
If I die here, the long cycle of destiny
the Sage of Six Paths mentioned
will probably end as well.
This is... a kind of revolution too.
You can release the Infinite Tsukuyomi
after I'm dead,
by transplanting my left eye
into Kakashi or someone else.
I'll put an end to myself.
By dying?
Don't think dying will settle this!
If you're willing to die,
then live and help me instead.
What I want to do is to make
all shinobi cooperate with each other.
And that definitely includes you!
Just because you want that
doesn't mean others will agree to it.
Damn it! If you keep whining and sulking,
I'll slug you again!
There's no guarantee
I won't stand against you again...
Then I'll stop you again!
Besides, I know you're not going to
do that kinda thing anymore.
How can you be so sure?
Don't make me repeat myself!
Haven't you figured it out yet?!
Now that I think about it...
You were always pretty stupid too...
There they are!
It figures they'd be here.
Thanks, Sakura.
Sakura...
Never mind me...
Stay quiet now.
I need to concentrate.
I'm sorry...
Sorry? For what?
For everything...
You should be.
Really... you...
damn...
idiot!
He's finally back.
Naruto...
I've been thinking about
what you once said to me.
When we were together,
you wondered if it was
how having a brother would feel...
Now, finally...
I think I know what you meant.
I felt how my mother, father,
and brother Itachi suffered.
In that same way...
Naruto...
I'm sure I will start to feel your pain
and your emotions...
You never cut me off.
You always kept me in your thoughts.
Naruto...
You'd have been justified if
you'd come at me with hatred...
Instead, you always called me
your friend.
And I tried to betray
even those feelings...
As I explained,
it's the village policy.
Only those authorized are allowed
at the interview.
All others, please leave!
What? Do you know
how far I traveled?
Let us see him, just once!
– Yeah!
It's the village policy...
– Let us see Naruto!
Please don't push! It's dangerous.
This should settle
the succession.
It's a lot of paper.
Yeah...
Anyway, congratulations on becoming
the Sixth Hokage, Kakashi.
Thank you.
I just wonder...
Can I do this?
You'll manage. After all, I did.
I'll do my best.
Excuse me.
Status report:
The Raikage's entourage and
the Kazekage's entourage
have arrived.
May I escort them to Naruto, too?
You may.
Further...
I have a request.
I see, Shikamaru.
I understand your intentions.
I want to get some experience
and improve my prospects too.
All that's left is him.
A ton of visitors are asking about him.
Suddenly he's Mr. Popular.
That's all right.
He's not the type to get carried away.
Hey! Gaara!
Naruto...
You... saved me yet again.
And us.
How's your wound?
It's about what you'd guess.
Can't say I'm in the best shape.
Then, what'll you do about that arm?
Oh, Grandma Tsunade said
something about
harvesting cells from Hashirama,
the First Hokage, or whatever.
She's going to fuse them with mine,
I suppose?
I don't really understand.
Will it be as good as new?
Yeah! I think.
I'm here today so they can check.
I see...
Naruto is the ninja world's sun!
His right arm is second to none!
Losing it is devastation! Yay!
So to get it back intact!
Use Hashirama's cells, in fact.
It'll be as good as new
and back on track! Yay!
What's he up to?
I really don't want to say much.
I promised I wouldn't.
I see.
S-Sensei!
Don't cry, Lee!
Even if the springtime of my youth ends
here, there is still a future for me!
The sun that shines bright!
The sweltering heat!
The red-hot days of
summer are here!
O-Oww...
Guy-sensei!
I'm inspired!
What a brilliant way of thinking!
Oh yuck...
Shikamaru...
I hear you're
the Hokage's personal assistant.
Well, yeah.
I have to keep moving forward too.
So why'd you ask me to
come to the Academy?
Iruka-sensei? And Kakashi-sensei?
More like Lord Hokage now.
Huh?! When did that—?!
You must have seen all the messages
that came in this morning.
I had no idea...
Don't worry about it.
So what do I call you?
Kakashi Hokage?
Hokage Kakashi Teacher?
Well, let's decide that later.
Naruto!
You never got to take
the Chunin Exam, right?
No...
Naruto Uzumaki!
I, the Sixth Hokage, hereby grant you
the rank of Jonin of
the Hidden Leaf Village.
... is what I'd like to tell you.
But there's something
you must complete before that.
The educational materials
you'll be needing.
You mean...?
Yes, you have to study.
Study?!
No way!
No way, no way!
If I'm going to have to study,
I'll just stay a Genin!
Hold on, Naruto.
There's no shortcut to
becoming the Hokage!
Got it?!
Naruto...
I don't have to tell you
that your skill as a shinobi
is second to none.
However, if your goal is
to become the Hokage...
You must learn how to stand
above others and lead them.
You catch on fast,
and for most things,
Shikamaru will support you
with his resourcefulness.
Still, a minimum of learning
and knowledge is essential.
We're rivals who both aim to
become Hokage, right?!
You really dug in, Naruto.
Two more years,
and you can become a Jonin.
So long...
Okay, let's call it a day
and go grab some ramen.
All right!
Now what toppings should I choose?
Hey, don't get carried away.
It's all thanks to you, Iruka-sensei.
Huh?
Do you remember that day?
Hmm?
That night, Sensei...
You accepted me.
It was the first time ever.
That's why I'm here today.
If no one acknowledged me
and I stayed the way I was...
Maybe I would've resented the village
and everyone in it, and gone wild.
But your words
that night changed me.
But Naruto is different.
He's...
He's an exceptional student
and I acknowledge him!
He is...
Naruto Uzumaki of the Hidden Leaf!
Thank you, Iruka-sensei.
That... that does it!
Today, you can have
all the toppings you want!
Awright!
Sasuke...
I'll be blunt.
By rights, you should be
in prison right now.
But we have heard your plea and
all your actions up to now
have been pardoned.
Breaking the jutsu
for the Infinite Tsukuyomi
played a big part in the decision.
As well as the fact that I happened
to become the Sixth Hokage,
and that Naruto,
the key figure in ending the war,
testified on your behalf.
Don't forget that.
And please don't get too reckless.
Otherwise, I'll be held responsible.
Understood. Thank you.
Must you go?
The artificial arm that
Lady Tsunade is creating
from Lord Hashirama's cells will soon...
I need time to understand
my feelings.
How I should view the shinobi world,
this world.
Perhaps I'll be able to see things
I couldn't see before.
Things that can't be seen
unless I do this.
Also, there's something
I'm worried about.
What if I said... I'd go with you?
This is a trip to atone for my sins.
My sins have
nothing to do with you.
Nothing to do with me...?
Maybe next time.
Thank you.
I didn't think
you'd come to see me off.
Here.
You kept that thing?
You sacrificed your arm to stop me.
Thanks to you, I was saved.
Once, all we did was clash
with each other.
But now, we share each other's pain.
After all my travels through the
world, I came to the conclusion
that this sharing of pain
can perhaps be applied to something
much bigger than just us.
But I can't do things like you.
Things don't go that smoothly,
as you and I know more than anyone...
The larger the world, the harder it is.
I'm returning this.
I'll hang on to it...
... until our real match.
This idea is almost a prayer.
To keep enduring, no matter what,
until things come to pass.
And for us who must endure,
perhaps that's what it means...
... to be a ninja.