I can't believe it.
I know. I never knew that
Lord Tsuchikage could be so crazy.
Damn it... I'm going to strain
my back again!
Are you sure about this?
Wouldn't it be better to
go by sea?
Also, we don't have to fly
so high, do we?
Don't be ridiculous, Akatsuchi!
That giant snake might
sense us again!
We're almost there.
The world flipped over again.
What's happening on
this island anyway?
Captain Yamato went to check
what's going on outside,
but he hasn't come back.
Don't you think
something happened?
We're already looking into that.
You don't have to worry about it.
My mission here is done!
I'm going back to the Hidden
Leaf Village to wait for Sasuke!
He and I... made an oath.
Not yet?
Not yet. Just sit still.
The next time you use your eyes,
you'll see a completely
different world.
This is going to be fun!
I couldn't care less about your war.
The one who will destroy
the Hidden Leaf... is me.
Anko, please rest a little.
You've been working nonstop.
War is at our doorstep.
So we have to gather as
much intel as possible.
Especially if our intel
can save our comrades.
They're here!
You're kidding, right?!
The white snake that
crawled in earlier...
That chakra... is Kabuto's.
This is the hideout, after all.
I sent my insects to investigate.
They've sensed significant
signs of life underground.
Tokuma, down below!
Towards four o'clock!
Your Byakugan will be able
to perceive what's down there!
Please, Tokuma!
Byakugan!
Th-This is...
What do you see, Tokuma?!
Ranka! Prepare to contact
Headquarters!
So many of them...
How come the animals get
to go outside, but I can't?!
Impatient Naruto...
Haste makes waste...
You still haven't mastered
Tailed Beast chakra control.
While you're training,
I shall personally patrol...
When we are done,
Tailed Beast chakra will feel
like an extension of you...
They'll feel like your arms and legs,
it's true...
Yeaaahh!
Whoa...
With your Tailed Beast chakra...
Catch them!
Stack 'em up like building blocks...
Using your chakra and
the Tailed Beast's...
Balance those rocks!
He took the bait!
Nice work, Bee!
Try it out.
All right. I have to use
the Nine-Tails' chakra, right?
I have to stack up these rocks
so that they don't tumble, right?
All right! I'll do it!
Don't be reckless there.
Your control is fair.
But you don't have
fine-tuned control.
He pulverized the rock.
Is it too hard to grasp?
Damn it!
One more time!
Gently... this time...
More gently...
Put spirit in... leave power out.
All right!
Don't get all satisfied with just one...
Or you'll never get done!
The first one is always easy... The
next one is key and it won't be so breezy.
Great, Bee! This will buy us
plenty of time.
The time has come.
It seems that old Fence Sitter
brought them here safely.
We'll hide Turtle Island along
with Bee and the Nine-Tails
at the rear of our headquarters.
Any objections, Princess Tsunade?
Fine.
I will go and
welcome Lord Tsuchikage.
Don't fall. Stay put... stay put.
– That was so close!
– Damn it!
– Turtle Island just shook.
– One more time!
Does that mean we've reached
our destination?
Ouch! My back!
That's because you overdid it!
Welcome back, Lord Tsuchikage.
So what is the situation?
Both the Eight and
Nine-Tails are fine.
But the Wood Style User that was
guarding the Nine-Tails was taken.
Taken? Not taken down?
Then the enemy will learn
everything about us!
At any rate,
I'll go over the details inside!
Will you hurry up and start
making Zetsu stronger?
Before that, extracting intel
from Yamato takes priority.
But please don't kill him.
So it's better to keep him alive
to make Zetsu stronger?
Yes.
Poison, huh?
So that's how he's suppressing
the power of the Wood Style.
Damn that Kabuto.
He has researched the cells of
Hashirama quite thoroughly.
It's a drug I made to
curtail Hashirama's power.
Don't worry,
I won't use it on the Zetsu.
I can't move. Damn it!
I can't even execute
my own decisions like this!
At this rate... Damn it!
Forgive me, everyone!
We don't need the power
of the Rinnegan.
With my truth serum...
and your Sharingan, we can
glean all the intel we want.
If we learn who the enemy is,
we can strike them by sending out
their worst enemy.
There's no need to waste chakra.
Huh?!
That's the Hidden Leaf's!
It must be new intel!
Retrieve it!
The X marks the enemy's hideout.
It's known as
the Mountain Graveyard.
If we go by land,
we'll pass through
the Hidden Steam Village and
the Hidden Frost Village.
Advise the nations of Hidden Steam
and Hidden Frost to evacuate!
According to reports by
the Infiltration and Recon Unit,
the enemy is roughly
100,000 strong.
When one considers mobilizing
a regiment of that size,
I think only a fraction of them
will come by sea.
We'll be in a bind
if they surround us.
Then it'll all comes down to
who makes the first move!
Convene the Ambush Unit immediately!
Have the main regiment run
through its formations!
Yes sir!
Make sure the Medical Unit
is well supplied
with medical ninja tools!
Shikaku, help the Intel Unit check
their chain of communication.
Roger.
Contact Ao and the Sensory Unit.
Have them hurry!
Y-Yes.
Tsuchikage, these were finished
while you were away.
Oh! So they're done!
Take it.
Headbands for
the Allied Shinobi Forces, eh?
Nice work!
I came up with the design.
Former enemies who once
battled each other
are now one shinobi force!
Furthermore, shinobi and samurai
have joined forces.
The time is near!
– Next!
– Yes!
I am Kankuro of the Sand,
appointed captain of
the Ambush Unit.
Kankuro, you say?
What should be your nickname?
Huh?!
Is that wise?
Naming someone so young
the captain...
What if... what if...
Because of his inexperience,
he messes up and panics
and forces me to become
the acting captain...
Oh man, what'll I do?!
The headbands have been distributed!
Medical supplies have been checked!
My name is Shizune and
I have been appointed to lead this unit.
Good to meet you all.
First, there is something I want
all of you to remember.
This one is not food!
You're Inoichi, right?
And you are?
I'm Tenga! I've heard
so much about you!
Please let me put you
on videotape and...
I'm sorry I'm late.
I heard...
What a rough time you had, Aoba.
Yes, Yamato was...
But put that out of your mind now.
We, the Intel Unit, will oversee
all communication between units.
Intel must be transmitted
accurately and quickly!
In order to do that,
we must maintain calm at all times,
no matter what we hear!
Understand?!
– Yes!
A war, huh?
Your name was Cee, right?
Is this your first war?!
Yes...
We are the "eyes" of
the Allied Shinobi Force.
Our unit's performance can greatly
change the tide of battle.
Stay focused and alert.
I understand, Captain Ao!
Everyone, don't let down
your guard!
– Yes sir!
So... Who's our captain?
That spacey looking
guy over there.
I-I'm starting to feel nervous.
In war, stay calm...
and composed!
Hold on... my dad's Captain?!
It's finally time!
With Kurotsuchi beside me,
I'll turn the tide of battle!
Are you all right, Guy-sensei?
The fighting hasn't started!
What did you do?
I'd better eat while I still can!
Gaara is the captain of
our Fourth Company,
but he's also
the commander-in-chief.
As his deputy, you're essentially
the captain of the Fourth Company.
Stay sharp!
What a bothersome assignment!
Maybe I'll make a name for myself
in this war and become Hokage!
You fool...
Don't take war lightly!
We have to avoid showing off.
You don't have to worry
about that, Shino...
Now then, Gaara.
You are the commander-in-chief.
Please address everyone
when you're ready.
Summoning: Reanimation!
First, the former members
of the Akatsuki...
Itachi, Sasori, Deidara,
Kakuzu and Nagato.
Then the former Jinchuriki...
Yugito the Two-Tails,
Yagura the Three-Tails,
Roshi the Four-Tails,
Han the Five-Tails,
Utakata the Six-Tails and
Fuu the Seven-Tails.
And the former Five Kage...
The Second Tsuchikage, the Third Raikage,
the Fourth Kazekage...
And Explosion Style Gari,
the Demon of the Mist, Zabuza...
Ice Style Haku,
Hanzo of the Salamander...
Granny Chiyo of the Sand,
Kimimaro of the Kaguya Clan...
And from the Hidden Leaf...
Asuma Sarutobi, Dan, Hizashi Hyuga...
and a host of others
who had some skill.
And that's not all.
I used Yamato who has cells
from Hashirama.
He adapted quite nicely.
100,000 White Zetsu empowered
by the best ninja of all time.
Magnificent!
Let's go.
The Fourth Great Ninja War...
Begins!
They're on the move!
And there's a large
amount of them.
Join up with the main forces
and inform them of this!
I will remain here and
investigate the hideout!
It's too dangerous by yourself!
Quiet! Just go!
I'm aware of the risks!
But if we don't get word to them,
our comrades will be
in greater danger!
Zabuza...
I know...
This isn't the afterlife.
I'm totally conscious,
yet my body is moving on its own.
This is the Forbidden Jutsu...
the Reanimation Jutsu.
Someone summoned us
back to this world.
It means we're going to be
fighting from now on.
Someone's taking advantage
of dead people, eh...
I don't like being used
by any such person!
You will be our Commando Unit.
Go by air!
Sasori and Deidara will lay traps
and conduct enemy raids.
Chukichi of the Hidden Mist and
the Leaf Foundation ninja,
your job will be sensory intel
and support.
What is... this?
You guys are with the Akatsuki.
Let me make this clear.
If you try to control us...
If Akatsuki has to rely on a wimp
like that to order us around,
they sure have fallen
on hard times.
Not only that, the only survivor is Zetsu
and Tobi, the one who replaced me...
For someone who preached that
"eternal beauty is art"...
Don't talk so high and mighty
now that you're dead, Master. Hmmm!
And it's all because
of that humongous
weak spot stuck
on your chest, hmm!
Deidara, do you want me
to kill you?
I'm already dead.
And so are you, hmm.
Is this really going to work?
There are too many
reanimated shinobi
and it's difficult to
control them all.
Right now, I'm just focusing
on the mobilization.
Ultimately,
I will direct everything.
When the fighting begins,
I will erase their personalities
and turn them into
killing machines.
There's no need to worry.
Of course, it will depend
on their characteristics.
Sometimes, it's better
not to change them.
Leaving their sentiments intact
will cause the enemy turmoil...
We'll aim for that weakness.
Aren't you Master Dan?
Yes...
What we share in common
is that we're dead.
We have been resurrected
by a Forbidden Jutsu...
summoned to inhabit
the bodies of living sacrifices.
What is going on anyway?
I have a bad feeling...
Aren't you taking
Two-toned Zetsu?
I'm leaving Zetsu to keep
an eye on Sasuke.
I wouldn't put it past you
to look for the chance
to take him away
during the battle.
I'm having the 100,000 White Zetsu
travel underground...
Such a large army would
only attract attention.
Then we shall set out too.
Now then, first...
– Multiple Striking Shadow Snakes!
Just because you
have a Curse Mark,
you think you're like
Lord Orochimaru, Anko Mitarashi!
I could say the same about you!
Have you taken over as
the leader, Kabuto Yakushi?!
Taijutsu from a bookworm
will not work on me!
Wha—?!
I have no intention of
fighting you with taijutsu.
I'm a bookworm.
Poison? Me?
With all the antibodies that I have?
So who is the lord now?
The antibody that
Lord Orochimaru developed
will not work against
this poison.
It's... over... there...
Kabuto was right.
At two o'clock... I see three.
What's wrong?
Muta! Ranka!
You two, hurry on!
I will stall them!
The intel!
Get the intel to Headquarters!
And how should we evacuate?
Continue heading south from
the Land of Steam
into Hidden Leaf territory.
The north will likely
become a battlefield.
Hey, someone...
Yes, my lord.
It's taking quite long.
Please be patient for
just a while longer.
Can a young man manage as
the Commander-in-Chief?
Lord Gaara is not your
average young man!
How dare you make such
ignorant assumptions!
How am I supposed to know?
Until recently,
we were on opposite sides!
Right back at you!
It's not like we trust you either!
So watch what you say!
To be honest,
I feel the same way.
Right!
Huh?
What did you just say, Hoheto?
Even if Orochimaru
deceived them,
the Sand were behind the plot
to crush the Hidden Leaf.
If it weren't for them,
Lord Hiruzen would still...
Look... We were lucky enough to
be named to the Commando Unit...
Things are just about to start...
I know that! I'm a shinobi too!
I'm not about to oppose what our
nation and village have decided...
That was just
my personal opinion!
You Hidden Leaf
don't have the right...
A rogue ninja from the Hidden Leaf
attacked Lord Killer Bee,
as well as the Five Kage at their summit!
Are you willing to take responsibility
for the loss of
Lord Raikage's left hand?
What?!
No one completely trusts
each other yet.
It can't be helped.
After years on opposing sides,
you can't expect them
to bond in a day or two.
You Leaf bastard!
Want to do something about it,
Hidden Cloud?!
You're going to betray us
again anyway, right, Hidden Stone?
Are the Mist just all talk?
If you have a complaint,
say it with your fists!
You're the one who needs to
watch what he says!
What?!
Want to fight?
Sure! You Sand killed my father!
I'd be glad to kill you right here!
Hey, stop!
Huh?!
In the name of gain and profit
for one's nation and village...
Shinobi have hated and hurt
each other for many years,
from the First to the Third
Great Ninja Wars.
That hatred cried out for power,
and thus, I was born.
In the past, I too was
hatred and power...
I was a Jinchuriki.
And I hated this world
and the humans in it
and thought about
destroying them.
This is exactly what the Akatsuki
is trying to do now.
However... a single shinobi from
the Hidden Leaf stopped me.
He cried for me, his enemy!
We wounded each other in battle,
but he called me his friend!
He saved me!
We were enemies,
but we were both Jinchuriki...
When we share and
experience the same pain,
there can be no bad blood!
No one is an enemy here!
Because we all bear the pain of
having been hurt by the Akatsuki.
Now, there is only...
... shinobi!
If you still cannot
forgive the Sand,
after this war is over,
you can have my head!
The look in everyone's faces
has changed.
The enemy is now after
my friend who saved me!
If he falls into enemy hands,
this world is finished!
I want to protect my friend!
And I want to protect this world!
But I am much too young,
too inexperienced to
protect this world!
So I beg you all to
lend me your strength!
You got it, Lord Gaara!
Sorry about that...
No... I was wrong too.
Sorry... I said too much.
I apologize too.
The more passionate they are,
the stronger the bond
that is forged...
Right, Gaara?
You have to hand it
to Lord Gaara!
Lord Gaara!
You've become
a fine man... Gaara!
So now, we're all comrades.
It's a nuisance, but I guess we
have to learn all their scents!
The reputation of
the Inuzuka nose is on the line.
All who feel as I do!
Follow me!
I did it!
Not bad.
Next up is the final lesson.
Sad, but true,
it's hard to proceed...
But we must move forward
with the deed.
The Fourth Great Ninja War...
We will win!
That goes without saying!
We will!
I really didn't want to
experience war in my lifetime.
What if...
What if we suddenly come
under a surprise attack
and I'm the sole survivor...
Omoi!
Hey, Omoi!
Are you listening?
We're going to enter
the airspace above enemy territory.
Stay alert!
Sir...
Can I ask you something?
What is it?
You and I aren't too far apart
in age, Captain.
This is your first war, right?
Yeah...
Are you nervous?
Listen up!
The outcome of this war will depend
on the success or failure of
our Commando Unit.
The number of casualties
depends on us, too.
Think only about success!
If you want to protect
your family and friends!
They've been bombing indiscriminately
with the detonating clay.
We have to put more distance
between us!
They're still coming after us.
I'll increase the power
of the jutsu.
You irritating bugs, hmm!
Stop hiding all over the place.
Such a pain.
The insects are disrupting
my sensory chakra.
It's a jamming jutsu using insects.
They're good enough to be
an infiltration and reconnaissance unit.
However, don't underestimate
this artful duo!
If they're attacking with insects,
we'll answer with this.
They are swarming!
I got separated from Ranka...
I'm counting on you.
I must join up
with the main regiment.
Gather round.
We're in enemy territory.
We're going to set up
a base camp here.
And we'll conduct surprise attacks
and set traps!
Keep a ten-meter radius!
The exit points will be at
two and six o'clock!
Omoi!
Lay traps of paper bombs
in every other direction.
Right...
Sai! Continue aerial surveillance!
Roger.
Ittan, create trenches with
your Earth Style!
Will do.
Tango, put up the antenna for
the Chakra Communications.
Right.
Zaji and Hoheto, you two will be
on sensory and watch duty.
Got it.
Kiri and I will review
our plan of action.
Understood.
Kabuto uses one
of Orochimaru's ninjutsu
known as the Reanimation Jutsu.
According to the reports,
corpses are brought back to life,
their souls held in bondage.
And they cannot be killed,
no matter how many times you attack.
Jutsu to seal the souls or
stop their movements
seems to be the only solution.
Furthermore, even if we manage
to kill the jutsu user...
the jutsu itself can't be broken.
The goal of every unit will be
to find Kabuto and restrain him.
After that, we will break
his troublesome jutsu with genjutsu.
That's what I understand.
First Company, with me!
This is a jamming jutsu.
What's wrong?
I can't sense for sure because
of a jamming jutsu, but...
Something's coming.
That's Muta!
I can tell by his chakra.
The one from the Aburame Clan
who was with
the reconnaissance unit.
Hey, wait!
It's booby trapped out there.
I'll bring him back.
Muta, are you all right?
Byakugan!
The insect bag on his back...
They're not insects of
the Aburame Clan!
What?!
Zaji, get back here!
Be careful!
They saw through it instantly.
Muta!
I'm so sorry!
Everyone get out of here.
– Do it, Deidara.
– I know.
There's a white clump
that's packed with chakra
in the insect bag on Muta's back!
Ittan, do it!
Earth Style: Mobile Core!
Now that's art...
The Hidden Leaf in bits and pieces, hmm.
Make sure.
They're still there.
We couldn't save
the guy from the Aburame.
Damn it.
Kiri, tend to Zaji's wounds.
Right.
Can't we even take a moment
to mourn our dead in war?
Hey, don't move!
Here they come again!
Stay alert!
We don't even get
some time to think?!
What the hell.
Cloud Style:
Crescent Moon Slice!
They are...
Tokuma! Ranka!
Our comrades again?!
Are they being manipulated?!
Again! Above us!
Nice, Sai!
We're keeping these guys alive.
You damn...
Now... what will you do, hmm?
You're playing dirty.
I won't forgive you!
Sasori, I know you're there.
Come on out.
Hmm... You're a puppet master,
after all.
You're also a Commando Unit,
I take it.
It's unusual for
two Commando Units
to engage each other like this.
The one who wins here will
succeed in a surprise attack.
We started this war.
And a victory here will determine
the course of the entire war, hmm!
Then we'll win.
Is that so?
Well, we cannot lose.
It's because...
we're invincible, hmm!
What's wrong?
Impossible...
Run away, little brother.
Our bodies are indestructible.
There's no way you can win!
Brother Shin.
Brother?
What an emotional reunion, hmm!
They're intentionally pitting people
we know against us?
How dirty!
Can't waste time feeling anxious.
Trying to hurt our comrades...?
Well, I won't stand for it!
This is war! There's no room
for niceties here, hmm.
Hoheto, Tango, go!
You're next, Ittan!
Brother, snap out of it!
Nice moves.
But even if you make contact,
nothing will happen.
I must hand it to Master Sasori.
There's no need to
counter this, hmm!
Cloud Style: Back Slice!
Well done, Omoi!
No effect.
He pretended to
swing directly at me,
but actually slashed back!
So stupid!
Cutting my chakra threads...
What fine swordsmanship.
Over here!
Ittan, raise us up!
Earth Style: Mobile Core!
What?!
Why you—!
Attaching your threads to mine
and reeling me in...
Your thread-handling skills
have improved since last time, Kankuro.
Frankly, it's nice to get praise
from a Red Secret Technique Master.
But my Black Secret Technique
is now superior to yours.
I never imagined
you'd still be alive.
Fate deemed that I would
fight you again.
I owe you one for last time.
My own puppet, huh...
That body is worthless to me now.
Because now, I'm finally a real doll
that will never rot away!
This is the body that
I had always wished for!
Run...
Captain!
The guy from the Foundation...
He's got that clay inside his stomach!
I once heard that Deidara's detonating
clay is weak against the Lightning Style.
I still have a little...
Take Kiri and the injured
behind that rock!
Kiri, focus only on healing them!
Too slow!
Now!
Black Secret Technique: Salamander!
Brother!
An explosion?!
In any case, our reinforcements
will crush the enemy.
Zaji! What's happening out there?!
It's okay.
I can still read their chakra.
Everyone is alive!
Owww...
We're lucky to be alive.
The Salamander, eh...
So he surrounded the bomb with
a defensive puppet he had hidden.
Because of that, the blast didn't
have much force, hmm.
You called him... a bomb...?
You're going to complain about that?
As long as his soul
clings to this world,
I can revive him as much as I want.
I'll turn him into another bomb!
I...
Don't want to hurt you.
I died...
and was liberated from
the Foundation.
I've heard about the Foundation
of the Hidden Leaf.
You're raised together from
the time you are young,
like siblings...
Then in the end, they pit you
against each other in a death match.
It is a training system designed
to destroy your emotions.
Where there is no feeling,
there is no doubt.
That makes
a truly powerful shinobi.
Deep down, you are just like me.
Don't act like an artist just
because you can draw a little!
Art is an explosion!
I think it's time for
another big blast!
Just try it!
I have a drawing
I want to show you, Brother.
Really? Let's see it.
What is it?
I'm not finished yet...
so can you wait a little longer?
Secret Black Technique...
Damn! I should have just
detonated myself earlier!
It's so tacky to exhibit one's
ultimate art over and over!
But I guess I have no choice!
Hmm!
Lightning Style?!
Triple Iron Maiden!
Nice job, Omoi!
I'll use my Puppet Jutsu
and keep these two tied up!
Do something about Sai's brother!
Right!
I knew that if I remained
in the Foundation,
I would have to face you in battle.
So let's settle now what
we couldn't back then.
Settle that last match... huh?
However, it won't happen.
Brother...
So you finished it.
I finally got to see the picture
I longed to see...
It's as though...
your drawing has freed
my soul from its bindings.
Sai, these comrades who
call you by your name...
Cherish them.
Thank you...
What's going on?
The strings are slack...
Sasori...
The source of your power
lay in your soul.
You once turned yourself into a puppet,
and tried to erase your soul,
but you couldn't do it.
I can feel it inside this puppet
that you made,
where your undying soul dwells inside.
But now, you are living flesh,
but that's merely a human shell that
has degenerated into a puppet.
You were a first-rate
shinobi puppet master.
Not some lowlife that allows
someone else to manipulate you.
If I'm not mistaken,
you used Kabuto as a spy back then.
Now, he's the one using you.
It's over when a puppet master
is the one being manipulated!
And whether it's you, or Kabuto,
the one who is controlling you...
There's no way I'm going to lose...
Because I am the ninja puppet master
of the real Sasori puppet!
Your techniques and the puppets
you created will never decay.
As long as there are
future puppet masters
to inherit the soul that
resides within them!
So that is precisely
the true form of art I sought...
Quit joking around!
Master Sasori!
Don't pay any attention to this jerk, hmm!
Art is a single flash of light!
Art is an explosion!
Are you listening, Sasori?!
The soul of the creator
resides within, eh...
You're right...
Kankuro...
What is it?
I entrust you with the "Father"
and "Mother" puppets.
And when you die,
bestow them upon another...
Those two are...
Yeah... of course, I understand.
Hey! Master Sasori!
This is a sacrificial victim...
What's going on?
I heard that one couldn't die
under the Reanimation Jutsu.
Maybe Kabuto released the jutsu?
Let me out, you bastard!
It doesn't seem that way.
– Hey, can't you hear me?
– Sasori is gone,
but the loud one is still here.
We thought the Reanimation Jutsu
had been perfected,
but it seems to have a flaw.
It's not that easy to control emotion.
Looks like it's over.
Nope... this is just the beginning!
Sai, Omoi, Zaji!
Head out for immediate ambush.
– Yes!
– Right!
What is it?
Oh, nothing.
The Reanimation Jutsu...
There are still so many
mysteries behind it.
But I have a good idea of
how it works now.
Madara, head out to the battlefront.
I'll hide and focus on the jutsu.
This woman...
She had gotten
this close to our hideout.
And Kabuto was aware of it.
So he purposely lured her here?
That damned Kabuto...
Since the beginning,
he's planned for the Allied Shinobi Force
and us to destroy each other.
But that won't happen.
I'm the one who will use you.
Looks like that woman is still alive.
Lord Orochimaru's Curse Mark
has adapted to this woman...
His chakra flows through her body now.
She can't be killed yet.
No, get rid of her now.
This woman knows where
the real entrance to our hideout is.
I need to extract Lord Orochimaru's
chakra while she is alive and collect it.
You might as well call
my body Lord Orochimaru's.
It's crucial in order to increase
my own strength.
Then my power to bind
the Reanimation Jutsu will increase.
And another crucial thing is...
This jutsu requires a live human body.
That is why this woman is
being kept alive.
Increasing our battle strength...
Doesn't that further your cause?
Or am I wrong?
Today's friend is tomorrow's foe.
That may be so.
Your benefit could turn into
my disadvantage.
You still don't trust me, do you?
What do you want from me?
Prove to me right now
that the Reanimation Jutsu
really requires living bodies.
And... tell me all of its secrets.
Including how to stop it!
And if I refuse?
You will never acquire what
you desire and
what you desire will become
something else...
It will be your life!
It's not wise to take on someone
who uses Rinnegan right now.
Well, I still have a hand to play.
No need to rush it.
Fine...
But I don't have any sacrifices here.
As I said,
this woman cannot be used.
Those people are...?
Danzo's dogs.
They've been under a Sharingan-based
genjutsu from the time of their capture.
You don't go easy, do you?
All right, I got things ready for you.
I killed this one.
Now use this other one and
do the Reanimation Jutsu.
Let me say this first.
This is categorized as
a type of Summoning Jutsu.
I summon the soul of the dead person
from the afterlife to this plane.
To achieve that, I need a portion
of the one I want to revive.
A fixed portion of flesh.
A portion that contains
their genetic information.
Without it, the Reanimation Jutsu
will not work.
Furthermore, if the soul is
not in the afterlife...
Meaning, if the soul has been sealed
somewhere else, they cannot be revived.
In the past,
Lord Orochimaru tried to bring back
the Fourth Hokage and failed.
That was because the god of death
had already taken the Hokage's soul
with the sealing jutsu,
the Reaper Death Seal.
And the Third Hokage also
used the same jutsu
during the destruction of
Hidden Leaf Village.
The First and Second Hokage
were taken along too...
So that means...
Reanimation Jutsu can't be used
on the First through Fourth Hokage?
That's right...
I've brought many back to life...
But it wasn't easy to harvest
their genetic material.
It's basically just grave robbing.
It's hard to identify decaying bodies...
I had a lot of failures.
So this is the jutsu formula?
This is how you turn a living person
into a vessel for the dead one's soul.
Then the Reanimation Jutsu
is complete.
Th-This is...?!
You can call this jutsu
the most powerful jutsu
in the shinobi world.
The Second Hokage devised it and
Lord Orochimaru perfected it.
It's their greatest legacy
to the world!
I control his personality with this tag.
And once I assign his orders...
All the abilities he had in life will
be restored to this decaying man.
And he will become my puppet who
obeys my orders and cannot die.
Naturally, even rare abilities like
the Rinnegan of the Six Paths
and Itachi's Sharingan.
But I could not find
Shisui Uchiha's body anywhere.
Jiraiya's body is deep in the ocean
where the pressure is too strong
for anyone to venture in.
As for Danzo's right eye
and Pain of the Six Paths,
I don't have all the materials
with their generic material.
Don't get carried away.
Well, no matter.
We have more than enough pawns.
A jutsu this ideal has to have risks.
The most amazing thing
about this jutsu is that...
there is no risk for the jutsu user.
What?
It's true.
The Reanimation Jutsu has no risk.
Well, it does have one.
Because it is such
an amazing, powerful jutsu,
the name of its wielder will spread
to every corner of the world.
In name, I will be more famous
than Madara Uchiha.
But an academic like me
has no desire for fame.
I'll just become a target.
Don't get ahead of yourself!
There is a reaction to every action.
Stay focused.
I appreciate your advice.
If this jutsu has a risk,
it's that I've given you information
about it.
Well, I must be going.
Academics are better suited
to be in gloomy places.
Hold it!
You didn't tell me how to stop
the Reanimation Jutsu yet.
Oh! That's right.
I almost forgot.
Killing the jutsu user
won't stop this jutsu.
So what do you do?
It's quite easy really.
You manipulate me, the one
who controls the Reanimation Jutsu...
into breaking the jutsu by weaving
the signs... dog, horse and tiger.
With your Sharingan, for instance.
Otherwise, you can seal away the souls
of those under the Reanimation Jutsu.
That's fine and good, if it's true.
I'm not brave enough to lie to you.
Anyway, this conversation is over.
I've told you how to stop it.
I'm going.
As long as I have that other jutsu
along with the Reanimation Jutsu,
I am invincible.
In time, I will unravel the truth
of the Sage of Six Paths.
Is White Zetsu's spore tailing him?
Of course.
Then Black Zetsu, you can start
preparations for that other thing.
Understood.
I would have missed this
without Muta Aburame's intel.
A large army is
approaching underground!
We're going to widen our scope!
They're going to try to pass
right under us!
Are they planning to take
the rear of the Allied Force?
Use Earth Style and dig them up!
Notify Kitsuchi immediately.
Intel Unit!
Get word about it to
Kitsuchi immediately!
It's coming!
All right!
New intel.
Finally.
Enemy, roughly 20,000.
Coordinates: 25 by 30, underground!
So that's how they're coming.
Reinforcements...
The Reanimation Jutsu...
It's more refined than the one
the Second Hokage Tobirama used.
To control this many souls
at one time...
It's quite a feat.
Kiba! Shino!
That was fast, Kiba.
I was told to join you here!
Is the enemy near?
– Earth Style: Erupt!
Captain Mifune!
We received a message
from Headquarters!
The enemy force is passing through
directly under us, deep underground!
Our shinobi in the Sensory Unit
couldn't detect them?
They must not be human.
All right!
Considering our Fifth Company's
elongated deployment,
I'll send in several squads
closest in proximity to Kitsuchi and
his Second Company as reinforcements!
Make haste!
It seems like there are
a lot fewer guards around.
We could make a run for it now.
Let's look for Sasuke.
You go on ahead.
I'm going to look for my blade.
I found the key right away,
but my blade is
nowhere to be found.
They confiscated it, right?
Then look in the armory.
Let's go.
What? You're going to help me?
You're all right, Jugo.
Unlike that Karin.
Speaking of which,
where'd she go?
Want to look for her?
Without her around,
it's a little too quiet...
What should we do?
I'm going to keep releasing them!
Zaji, take care of the signal fire!
Right!
Red smoke,
that's the Commando Unit.
Hurry!
Right.
Are you all right,
Master Zabuza?
Looks like we wasted a jutsu, Haku.
This Reanimation Jutsu revives the dead,
but they can't be killed.
I don't like this jutsu...
You did well to detect them, Haku.
That species of giant bird
generally fly in pairs.
They work together to
catch their prey.
However, that's only
during the winter
when they are raising their young...
And that looks like a beacon
made to look like a cloud.
No doubt, the enemy
that attacked is over there.
Snow?
A cold air?
Secret Jutsu: Crystal Ice Mirrors!
Owww...
H-Hey... That thing...
What? They're just kids.
We can't die. So we can just strike.
They are Kekkei Genkai shinobi!
I'm different.
We bear no grudge against you.
We're just not in control
of our actions.
They're coming!
Kakashi?
Kakashi!
You're a lifesaver!
Don't start celebrating yet.
These guys are all pesky shinobi.
I knew we would have to fight,
but I never imaged it would
be against you, Kakashi.
That day on the bridge,
you were supposed to finish me off
and send me to hell.
When I came to,
I was in the same place as Haku.
It seems this is neither heaven nor hell.
This is the world of the living.
You are under the Reanimation Jutsu.
What? He knows them?
Wait for Captain Kakashi's signal.
Zabuza... Haku...
Oh... You've matured, Kakashi's kunoichi.
How is that kid?
Huh?
Uh-huh...
When a person has something precious
they want to protect...
that's when they can
truly become strong.
I know that well enough too!
You'll get strong.
I hope we meet again somewhere.
Yeah!
We lost because of him...
He must be all grown up.
He's probably famous too.
Yeah, that bridge is now called
the Great Naruto Bridge.
Everyone in the village calls him
the miraculous hero now.
Thanks to you both, Naruto was
able to find his Ninja Way.
And he made a pledge at your graves,
and he's grown into
a fine shinobi since then.
Then he will become even stronger.
Were you able to reminisce a little?
Because it's time to get serious.
Power is welling up!
The main act starts now!
Kakashi... Stop us...
Retreat!
Kakashi, these people...
I know! There's no doubt!
The Demon Zabuza Momochi!
And Haku of the Ice Style!
I'm losing... consciousness...
Damn...
The inside of my head...
feels so hot...
That demonic aura...
So this is the Demon Zabuza!
On top of that, the Ice Style child!
On guard! Stay alert, Guy!
No one comes close to him
in Silent Killing!
Kakashi... Please...
Stop us once again...
My dream was always to
be Master Zabuza's tool
and die protecting him...
The fact that Master Zabuza is under
the power of this jutsu means...
that I was not able to protect him
from you back then.
Furthermore, not only am I incapable
of protecting Master Zabuza,
I can't even serve as his tool now.
No, you protected Zabuza.
He died for a different reason.
And... Zabuza never thought
of you as a tool.
K-Kakashi, quit babbling nonsense.
Zabuza and Haku, huh.
They're quite tenacious.
I still haven't been able
to bind them completely
I'll soon turn you into
mere killing puppets!
You are my tools!
K-Kakashi, don't hesitate.
Use whatever means it takes...
to stop me.
I died already.
I died human...
Yes, I know.
Master Zabuza...
Thank you.
Here they come!
Captain Kakashi!
That Hidden Rock shinobi...
A user of the Explosion Style
Kekkei Genkai.
He's a former Explosion Corps captain
like Deidara... That's Gari!
And that woman is...
the Scorch Style Kekkei Genkai user
from the Hidden Sand...
Pakura!
Please be careful!
Kekkei Genkai shinobi... all of them.
Ninja Art: Hidden Mist Jutsu.
The fighting unit will comprise mainly
of sensory-type shinobi!
The rest will take a Manji Formation
at 12, 3, 6, and 9 o'clock
and provide cover!
We will pinpoint Zabuza
using only sound!
The mist is becoming thicker.
Our field of vision isn't good enough.
Sakura, you don't need to be afraid!
I will guard you with my life!
The last time, they attacked the dead spot
in this formation, the center.
Watch your backs!
After the mist... cold air.
It's begun!
It's different from the last time,
after all.
To be able to bind so strongly...
As one would expect from
Lord Orochimaru's chakra.
To be able to overwrite
my own control tags...
However, I purposely kept
their emotions intact
to psychologically torment the enemy.
That results in a weaker binding
and the soul dies when the heart
undergoes a change.
This time, I will kill all feeling.
Right now, I don't know who among
the enemy pawns I can do this to.
I'll just gather data from this war.
As for the rest of the pawns,
I'll bind them to the point of
obeying my orders,
and leave them to their own accord.
Some will probably be more beneficial
with their emotions left intact.
He was mummified.
This jutsu...
Here they come!
Scorch Style: Super Steam Kill!
My insides...!
Explosion Style: Land Mine Fist!
No way... Tajiki blew up!
You bastard!
– Leaf Hurricane!
Guy!
Comrades die on the battlefield!
That is one thing
you must learn to accept!
Losing your cool can cause
even more comrades to die!
Place your comrade's death
into the recesses of your mind!
Understand, newbie?
Y-Yes!
Hang in there.
You're going to be all right.
I'm beginning to understand how
the enemy is coordinating this.
Now it's my turn!
I'm not so naïve as to allow
the enemy time to act.
– Summoning Jutsu!
No way. Don't tell me...
That's...
The past members of the Seven
Ninja Swordsmen of the Mist!
Among the legendary
Seven Ninja Swordsmen...
they've chosen the strongest ones!
The Seven Ninja Swordsmen...
Nothing from the Ensui Platoon?
They'll be here shortly.
Maki of the Hidden Sand,
what about you?
We're ready to roll!
All right, buy some time
for Ensui's squad.
Everyone, attack together!
It's not here either.
You said you're gathering all
the lost Hidden Mist Blades.
Why are you so obsessed?
What?
You said you'd help me.
Don't tell me you're giving up?
You're the one who gives up.
Except when it comes
to the ninja blades.
I need one thing to keep me going.
Resurrecting
the Seven Ninja Swordsmen
and becoming their leader
is my dream.
Resurrect?
Yeah.
Right now, the Seven Ninja
Swordsmen consists
of a single brat named Chojuro.
Traditionally, the ninja blade is passed
down from generation to generation.
Right now, there is only one blade,
known as the Hiramekarei.
Nothing else.
The great blade, Samehada, is in Kisame's
possession, but he's a rogue ninja.
I finally got a hold of the
Executioner's Blade, only to lose it.
So officially,
that unit doesn't exist today.
For now, anyway...
What do we do against
guys like that?
They're the Seven Ninja Swordsmen!
The longer we keep this up,
the greater our disadvantage.
Don't worry so much!
The Reanimation Jutsu
can be stopped
by sealing away the soul
or immobilizing their body.
And other than Zabuza,
no one is wielding a sword.
That cuts their strength in half.
No.
It seems they brought their swords.
Not all of them have one.
The mist is getting even thicker...
We can't see through this.
And there's no sound
with Silent Killing.
We can't even hear them.
We must do something
about this mist,
or the Allied Forces are
at a disadvantage.
You have a plan?
I'm preparing it now.
Then I'll leave you to handle it!
Lee! Go after the Scorch Style!
I'll take the Explosion Style!
Understood!
Captain Kakashi!
I'm ready with my Shadow Possession
and Shadow Paralysis!
All right, fasten it to me.
Ensui, reduce the strength
of the Shadow Possession,
and stay focused on my movements.
Right!
Santa Yamanaka, use the Mind
Transfer Jutsu to enter my body.
With your sensory skills, you will be
able to track and find Zabuza in this mist!
Right!
Once you perceive Zabuza,
since I'll be under Shadow Possession,
guide me to a location
where I can see him.
Get me behind him
as close as you can.
When I have
a clear sight of him,
immediately release
the Mind Transfer Jutsu
and return me to my body.
I will grapple with Zabuza
and step on his shadow
and get him into position.
At that point, Ensui,
immediately increase the power
of your Shadow Possession
and Shadow Stitching Jutsu
and bind him!
Then Maki, completely immobilize Zabuza
with your Cloth Paralysis Jutsu!
Yes!
Let's do this!
Right!
Mind Transfer Jutsu!
Anyway, there are lots
of other blades.
Among the Ninja Swordsmen
throughout history,
there were super masters besides
Kisame, Zabuza and Chojuro.
First...
Imbued with lightning,
the sharpest blades of all...
The wielder of the Lightning Blades, Kiba...
Ameyuri Ringo.
Crushing through any defense...
The wielder of the Blunt Blade, Kabutowari...
Jinin Akebino.
The blade that pierces through everything...
and stitches it together...
the Long Blade, Nuibari.
Its wielder is Kushimaru Kuriarare.
The blade that adds explosive power
to every swing...
The Blast Blade, Shibuki.
And its wielder, Jinpachi Munashi.
The one who, just like Kisame Hoshigaki,
wielded the Great Blade, Samehada...
Fuguki Suikazan.
And the one who mastered
all seven swords.
Known as the second Coming
of the Demon, my older brother...
Mangetsu Hozuki.
And I am going to be the captain
of the new generation
of the Seven Ninja Swordsmen, and...
Enough. You're talking too loud.
Hey, I was coming to the climax.
The sword you broke
in two, right?
Shouldn't you just make
a new sword?
You don't know a thing.
That blade has a certain power.
The Severing Sword,
the Executioner's Blade,
cannot be chipped or nicked.
No, a better way to put it is,
the blade repairs itself.
It cuts into humans,
then absorbs their blood.
It regenerates itself with
the iron present in blood.
All right! Found him!
Mind Transfer Jutsu, release!
Good luck, Captain Kakashi!
All right!
He hasn't noticed me.
I can do this!
He intends to slash me along
with the boy?!
I'm glad you were
Naruto's first opponents.
Maki, stay behind me and
stand by with
your Cloth Paralysis Jutsu!
Right!
Why?
Why can't I keep up?
Damn it!
You can't possibly defeat me
the way you are now.
What was that?!
You still don't realize...
Zabuza...
That time,
you hesitated to kill Haku
and you couldn't hide the turmoil
in your heart over Haku's death.
But it's different this time.
You're just a tool
with no feelings.
Let's put an end
to a fight like this!
Hey, hey... Kakashi-sensei.
What do you think about this?
About what?
Well, those two were enemies...
I... liked those guys.
Is that weird?
No.
I feel the same way.
Ensui! Bind him!
That's my signal! Okay!
Shadow Paralysis Jutsu!
The way you died and your tears...
demonstrated your bond
to each other.
I have many things I want
to protect as a shinobi.
Zabuza and Haku...
Protecting the dignity of their deaths
is one of those things.
Especially since I am
their final enemy.
Naruto... What do you think?
Now, Maki!
Right!
Damn it!
This is...
The mist is clearing...
All right!
Now we can see the enemy!
As long as these tags remain,
they cannot be recalled.
I will keep an eye on
these two bodies.
All right...
The Reanimation Jutsu...
This is an unforgivable jutsu!
Sai, next we'll use your
Foundation Sealing Jutsu!
You're up!
But... But I still haven't mastered
that jutsu...
Isn't it a fact that you were
highly regarded by Danzo?
There's no need to suppress
your emotions anymore!
Well... It takes me a while
to get upset too...
But this time,
my boiling point was low.
Copy ninja Kakashi has copied
a thousand jutsu...
And I'm going to use them
to their fullest extent!
Attack!
Fang Over Fang!
Secret Jutsu: Insect Sphere!
Eight Trigrams Air Palm!
Eight Trigrams Palm Rotation!
Neji!
There are too many of them...
So they absorb chakra...
Gentle Fist Art: Body Blow!
One after another...
There's no end to them!
Stop whining and move!
Each one is strong and persistent!
This is attrition warfare.
Captain Kitsuchi!
We have word from Headquarters!
Several thousand have
gotten past us!
Dad!
Quiet! I know!
Here they come.
Mu is not moving.
There's no sign of him
or his chakra.
Seems the Second Tsuchikage
has been detected.
Even though he was known
as the "Null Man."
It will soon be ripe for war.
The real fight is just beginning.
With that class of shinobi,
I anticipate bigger results
by not killing off their
thoughts and emotions.
I'll let him do as he pleases
after the Summoning Jutsu.
The Second Tsuchikage...
The Third Raikage...
The Second Mizukage...
The Fourth Kazekage...
Too bad we don't have a Hokage.
Still, four Kage from history
are here.
I'll just let the Kage and
their progeny kill each other off.
Where am I?
My, my... What a gathering
of former enemies!
Well, well. I don't know this guy.
This is a foul jutsu of
the Second Hokage.
The dead are summoned back from
the afterlife and then bound.
You were summoned here by force.
The dead?! What do you mean?
Have you forgotten?
I killed you myself.
You died ages ago,
Second Mizukage.
Oh... back then... Hey wait!
You also died that day!
In fact, I killed you.
Was that so?
Well, no matter.
Let me continue...
Where was I?
Where is the Second Hokage?
He's the jutsu user who resurrected us?
I sense someone several kilometers ahead.
One with the same chakra
as this new face...
along with a huge army.
No doubt you are...
I am the Fourth Kazekage.
My predecessors have told me
about your exploits.
So this means the Sand has continued
through to the Fourth, no,
the Fifth generation.
It feels strange being in the future.
Listen, this is not the future.
We are merely relics of the past.
Listen to me,
or I'll kill you.
I'm already dead!
Besides, I'm the one who killed you!
Enough of that. You're missing the point.
I'm talking about the Second Hokage,
who resurrected us...
The Second Hokage was long dead by my time.
However, I knew a shinobi capable
of using the Reanimation Jutsu.
His name is Orochimaru.
Four... and among them...
is Father.
A jutsu that controls
the Second Hokage...
The user doesn't seem to be
the Second Hokage,
but this Reanimation Jutsu...
There are times when your body
won't do what you want it to.
Movement is restricted.
Seems that way.
I thought about killing you
earlier, but my body wouldn't let me.
I would have enjoyed
battling you all.
Such a shame, such a shame...
Gaara, eh...