Incoming message!
Killer Bee and Naruto have
both broken through the barrier,
and escaped.
What?!
That barrier is supposed to
be impenetrable, even to Jinchuriki!
No one foresaw two Jinchuriki
coordinating an escape!
Two of them?!
It seems Master Bee
is helping out.
Damn!
Now what are they up to?
I will personally stop the Jinchuriki.
Tsunade, you come too!
Who will manage Headquarters?
Shikaku of the Leaf!
Understood.
You can leave this to me.
All right!
Follow me, Tsunade!
Lord Raikage!
Please try not to smash any walls.
Let's go.
Oh... right.
Don't be afraid!
Surround him!
The tide of the war has suddenly
changed in their favor.
Darui, we must contact
HQ secretly and regroup.
I know.
It's almost dark.
We have to be prepared for
a night invasion and keep our eyes open.
Losing this war is not an option.
Make no doubt about it.
My long-standing desire...
Project Tsuki no Me...
shall be realized tomorrow,
at long last...
He's already sealed
Kinkaku and Ginkaku?
He only has part of
the Eight-Tails' chakra...
a single piece of his tentacles.
I think you're rushing into this,
but I'll go along with
your plans tonight...
I can't see the enemy.
What'll we do?
Retreat? Or advance?
Right now, this company is
without captains.
We'll just have to stand
our ground and wait for orders.
Luckily, we have a bunch
of Sensory-Type ninja...
who are ideal for this.
They're not coming...
I don't sense anything
in the sand either.
I should think the wiser move
with the Reanimation
is to keep raising the dead
and fight hard.
Lord Gaara, please use this!
You must conserve your strength.
Give that to him first.
Huh? To this little old man?
I am the Tsuchikage.
– Huh?!
We have no idea what they may
be planning in the dark of night.
Stay on guard at all times.
– Yes, sir!
Where is my ninja tool?!
I want it back!
You were told not
to use it anymore!
I don't want to!
I'm really good with it!
It's such a waste!
I notified HQ that Madara
has taken a Treasured Tool.
And that he got
the Tailed Beast's chakra.
I'm very sorry.
This was my fault.
If only we had
realized it sooner...
No, you responded well.
It can't be helped that
he was unstoppable.
In any case, we were able
to repel the enemy for one more day.
Nearly 40,000 out of 80,000.
That's how many
the Allied Shinobi Forces lost today.
50,000 out of 100,000.
That's how many Akatsuki
we got today.
Each side lost nearly
half its force.
But our side consists
of living flesh.
While the enemy...
The Nine-Tails' chakra Mode.
Great for lighting the night road,
could cost me my life
like a double-edged sword.
It's okay to use Nine-Tails' chakra
like a flashlight.
But stick close to him, Bee!
You got it.
You're always so careless
with my chakra...
It's not like you
to start up a conversation,
Nine-Tails.
I know you're starting to
get lonely and want to talk...
but I'm busy now!
Let's do this later!
Do you seriously think you can
end this war by yourself?
We'll talk after the war's over.
Later.
If your comrades are killed,
hatred will arise.
Are you planning to defeat
the enemy before that happens?
And if you defeat the enemy,
they'll bear hatred towards you...
Do you honestly think
you can take all of that
on by yourself?
Don't keep underestimating me.
You don't understand a thing!
You're naïve!
Can you honestly take on and
erase everyone's hatred?!
The war has already begun.
There must be a considerable
amount of casualties already.
And the resulting hatred to match...
First,
Sasuke who used to
stand alongside you,
has been gripped by hatred
for a long time.
Have you ever been able
to do anything for him?
In other words...
Regardless of who
you're dealing with,
you can neither erase their hatred
nor take it on yourself!
So...
Are you done?
What?
Hey...
You're the one who's naïve!
How can you be so confident
when you couldn't even
save Sasuke?
Once you question
your own beliefs, it's over.
I will help Sasuke somehow,
and I will do something
about this war!
The little brat thinks
he's all grown up, does he?
Ya know, Nine-Tails, I...
I'm going to come after all that
hate inside you as well some day!
You've put me through
a lot of pain,
but I know that it doesn't feel
good to be at the mercy of hatred...
Are you stupid?!
I'm the Nine-Tails!
Some little brat
can't change me!
I am hatred!
Then it's okay!
I'm no longer a little brat and it
will be more challenging this way!
Later!
So cocky.
Hey!
Neji, are you all right?!
Yeah...
I'm okay.
Don't overdo it.
Your eyes aren't the only thing
that can track the enemy.
I have my nose.
Leave this to me and
get yourself checked out
by the Medical Corps.
There's a medic tent in the rear center
of every company.
The coordinates are...
I need two Jonin Medics
over here, please!
We have to resuscitate now!
Quickly!
– Right!
Are you sure you can
handle this much?
Halt, please!
Under orders from HQ,
we Sensory-type shinobi will
have to verify your chakra!
We will not allow you to pass
until this is done!
Sure, I understand.
Hurry and get it over with.
I'll bandage it...
Okay...
That should do it.
Thank you...
Take care.
Okay, next please.
Neji!
I've taken care of all
your external wounds.
Thanks.
Please get some rest,
while you can.
Especially your eyes!
You shouldn't overuse them.
That's easier said than done.
My job is to discern things
faster than anyone,
and notify HQ, in order to improve
our chances in battle.
To do that, I have to put
my eyes to work.
I know that.
But while you're here...
Thanks.
All right, the next tents on
our rounds are F5 through G3.
B-Bad news! Toyosa, Takemaru,
and Hino are dead.
Someone has assassinated them!
What?!
What's going on?
A spy has infiltrated us.
They're targeting Jonin medics.
But how?
In order to get here,
everyone's chakra undergoes
strict verification.
It's impossible with a simple
Transformation Jutsu.
And you cannot get through here unless
you're a shinobi of the Allied Forces.
Which means...
that a shinobi of the Allied Forces is being
manipulated by a jutsu. It's highly probable.
It's a formidable jutsu.
I see...
If there are only
Allied Force shinobi here,
they'll be hard to distinguish.
We can't tell who the suspect is.
We're all standing
around right now,
and it could be any one of us.
And this is sure to breed
suspicion among us.
That's what the enemy
is hoping for.
We medical ninja are critical for
our battle strategy to succeed.
There's no way you can confront
the undead from the Reanimation Jutsu
without our back-up.
If we're paralyzed now...
It will ruin our chances in the battle,
that starts at dawn.
I'll find the killer with
my own eyes!
In any case, no matter what happens,
we cannot ignore the wounded.
We'll continue our treatment.
But we must be extra careful.
Especially the Jonin medics.
Now then...
I-It's time to go on rounds.
Y-Yeah...
Wh-Where did I... first meet you?
Huh?!
No... Listen, it's not like
I'm suspicious of you.
Of course not.
It's just... just...
You are suspicious of me!
Oh, it's you.
Don't scare us like that.
Say, have you seen
Sakura Haruno?
Is something wrong?
I got suspicious about someone.
I was tailing him, but lost him...
Thinking back, I get the feeling that
he was hanging around Sakura.
Sakura is in Tent 3.
What does this suspicious guy
look like?
Oh! It's you.
Is your wound still bothering you?
Oh, no... It's fine.
A-Actually, ever since you treated me...
I haven't been able to
stop thinking about you.
What is this?
I-It's... a love letter.
When I go into battle again,
there's no guarantee that
I'll come back alive.
So...
Thank you.
But... I'm already in love
with someone.
Oh, I see...
I guess he's probably... from the Leaf.
Well, a rejected man has no right
to pry into who you love.
I understand. I'll go now.
I'm sorry...
I hope it all works out.
If you love him...
he must be a great man.
You all right?
Neji...
It's easy to get discouraged.
We don't even know
who we're fighting.
Are you sure you don't need
to go to the medical corps?
Cut it out, Kiba! I said I'm fine!
You overused your Byakugan
and can barely stand!
So don't bother showing off
in front of your subordinates!
Shut up, Kiba!
What the hell? You're so weak,
you can't tell the difference
between a dog and a man!
And your Visual Prowess is
supposed to be your specialty!
By the way, Sakura...
Where is Captain Shizune now?
Huh? Did you figure something out?
Yeah... a little.
We need to be in contact to report
anything, no matter how trivial it is...
Until we find the suspect.
Well, I think she's in Tent B-2.
Shizune is treating Tonton.
Seems like a bad leg sprain.
Well, that's better
than injuring a hand.
Will they be able to
rejoin the battle?
I think so...
Tonton can still weave signs,
since the hand is uninjured.
I see... That's good.
By the way...
Sakura, would you mind taking
a look at my arm one more time?
It hurts a little.
Sure...
You can sit over there.
How did you know?!
Pigs don't have hands!
Cha!
Tonton... is a pig?!
She tricked us! Smart alec!
So, you're the murderer!
My Transformation Jutsu
is the best.
I may not be the only who
has infiltrated this place.
If this is just like
Captain Yamato's report...
Note... Regarding Parasitic Clones.
Kisame Hoshigaki was originally
thought to have been taken down
by the Raikage and Killer Bee...
But it appears he survived,
having switched places
with a parasitic clone
or something that is a type
of Transformation Jutsu.
Because this transformation also
replicates the target's chakra,
it is difficult to detect.
At the Five Kage Summit,
Zetsu of the Akatsuki suddenly
emerged from other people's bodies.
He had absorbed chakra...
What happened?!
Did you hear that loud
sound just now?!
Who's that?!
I have to contact HQ immediately!
Please take care of this guy!
Empty it all out!
We're on guard duty next.
My bladder must be bigger than yours.
Check out the ripples I made!
The ripples are...
Don't forget to piss either, Tetsu!
It's going to be a long night.
How about if I make you
bleed instead?
It happened again!
There are reports from
every sector that
our comrades are being ambushed
one after another!
There's confusion everywhere!
We don't know who the enemy is!
What's going on?!
A night raid is supposed
to have been ruled out!
On top of that, we added security and
positioned Sensory-type ninja...
Why can't we detect the enemy?!
Is it some kind of poison?
What's the condition of the corpses?
All of them have external wounds.
They're physical attacks.
No doubt they're controlling
Allied shinobi with genjutsu.
Could it be Itachi?
Hold on! We just got word from
the medical corps.
The enemy looks to be...
White Zetsu transformed into
Allied Force shinobi!
They're able to mirror chakra imprints!
That explains it...
So during the day battle,
if one of our shinobi got
his chakra absorbed,
White Zetsu can transform
into him completely!
What should we do,
Shikaku of the Leaf?
There is no way we can weed out
who is friend and who is foe!
How will we prepare for
the battle at dawn?
If we don't find
the enemy immediately,
we'll not only lose precious time,
but our own men will
become casualties!
In the end, they could
end up killing each other!
So this is the power of White Zetsu.
The battle during the day was
merely a setup for the night...
This was the enemy's true motive.
There's no sign of enemy movement.
Okay, but stay alert.
Yes. I have look-outs
posted everywhere.
I'm here to relieve you.
Okay. Thanks.
Get some rest. We'll keep watch.
Okay.
Deidara... Deidara.
Stop casually calling out
my name like that!
It's me, Zetsu.
Zetsu? Is that you?!
You were a fun guy.
I'm going to help you
for old time's sake.
Thanks. Quickly!
Hurry.
Hold on a second...
Oh that? In there?
What is it?
So, Big Brother Deidara... you still alive?
I'm dead.
That voice... Is that you, Kurotsuchi?
Did you come to rescue me
for old time's sake?
I was sent here because
we used to be friends,
but the situation's just
the opposite now.
I came because I need your help.
Huh? What do you mean by that?
She's interrogating
the Hidden Stone ninja.
Where is Kabuto Yakushi?
How should I know!
I wouldn't tell you even if I knew, hmm.
Look, bro...
Kabuto brought you back to life
and is now using you at
his convenience.
You're dead, so the least
you can do is forget the past,
and cooperate with us a little.
Kabuto gave me an opportunity
to acquire the Super Ultimate Art.
All right.
Then where is Sasuke Uchiha?
Sasuke, you say?
Are you saying
he was reanimated, as well?
Sasuke's not dead!
Don't be ridiculous!
I killed him with my Ultimate Art!
But I saw him.
After you died, bro,
Sasuke was alive and well.
He was fighting with the Raikage
and the others.
A-Amazing.
He joined the Akatsuki and
is an enemy of the Allied Forces.
He's with the Akatsuki?!
Right?
Huh?! Yeah, I guess.
What's with that?
Sasuke's alive?
And he's a member of Akatsuki?
You've have to be kidding.
There's no way
he could still be alive!
I'm telling you he's alive.
That was my Ultimate Art!
Nobody cares about art.
Sasuke, that bastard!
What was up with that guy?!
Wasn't he in awe?
Didn't he tremble with fear?
Didn't he despair?
Didn't he scream,
"What the hell is this?!"?
Screw you, Sasuke!
Your Lightning Style won't
hold me down forever!
Brother?
Hey, are you listening, bro?
Answer me!
This isn't getting anywhere!
Open it. I want to speak
with him directly.
You want me to open it?
Hey.
Sir!
Mountain.
Huh?
Mountain...
Distant skies?
It's "River."
Damn samurai!
You're so predictable.
You bastards!
They're Zetsu!
What?!
Careful! They'll absorb your chakra!
Art is... an explosion.
Deidara!
How?! Why didn't the Lightning Style
seal his Explosion Style?!
Is that how you channeled
the Lightning Style away?
What was that doing
inside the puppet?!
It was thanks to me...
Zetsu.
What?
Let's get out of here!
Huh? Wait!
Don't let him get away!
Man, he's troublesome
even when he's dead!
The prisoner, Deidara,
has escaped.
He's with his comrade, Zetsu.
Apprehend them!
Okisuke.
I will take full responsibility
for my blunder, I swear!
This is not the time for regrets.
After them!
Yes, sir!
Why are we running?
Let's kill them!
I'm out of Detonating Clay.
I need to get more somewhere.
Uh-oh... They're coming!
You're in my way!
In front, too!
Damn it!
Still weak as ever, aren't you?
That was a tactic to
give us more time.
Looks like you escaped the seal.
Kabuto!
I would've expected nothing less.
I'll take that back.
Wait!
My Ultimate Art was
completely rejected!
I can't die like this...
even if I'm already dead. Hmm.
You intend to stand and fight there?
I'm going to perfect
my Super Ultimate Art!
I just don't understand
how you artists think.
But intellectuals have
to protect artists.
That's...
Get away. I'll hold them off.
I'll leave them to you, Chukichi!
Hidden Frost Jutsu.
What the hell?!
Where is he hiding?
That's... a lot of 'em.
He's gone!
Curses!
I sense them!
Commander Mifune!
They went that way!
Let's go.
How much farther
are we going to run?
I need clay, hmm!
I need to find a place
with clay in the soil.
Leave that to me.
Unless we catch Big Brother Deidara
before he finds some clay,
this could get troublesome.
Previously, Omoi of the Cloud
contained the explosion
with his Lightning Style,
but he is in a different unit now.
Do we have anyone in this unit
who can handle lightning?
Fifth Company split into two.
Our company's main weapon
is samurai.
Our only ninja are sensory, sealing,
and intel support personnel.
Commander Mifune,
I am able to do Lightning Style.
Good...
They're coming, Deidara!
Our pursuers!
What?!
I've only managed to get
this much Detonating Clay!
Scatter!
Lightning Style!
What's happening?!
Did Big Bro—?!
Under us!
Land mines!
Jump!
You're not going to stop us!
Take that!
Not enough, hmm.
This is art!
Big Brother's going to explode.
You have to keep the current flowing!
We need a more powerful
Lightning Style!
Th-This is the best I can do!
Lord Mifune!
Hey, Deidara...
How tacky! The despair, hmm!
Why?
Art is a moment of brilliance,
blossoms that scatter all at once.
But this body can't scatter!
I'm going to find
a Super Ultimate Art
that transcends
the Ultimate Art, hmm.
Damn you, bro!
Lord Mifune? Where are you?
Lord Mifune!
The holes left by his landmines
became trenches.
Bro Deidara wasn't very thorough
with his Detonating Clay, was he?
We'll need a plan.
With insulation, we could keep him
from grounding the lightning.
The problem is
our Lightning Style wielder.
But... I'm not...
You just concentrate on
sensing their whereabouts.
Shall I request Headquarters
for reinforcements?
We don't have time to wait
for reinforcements.
We'll do this with
the personnel we have.
What am I going to do?
This immortal body and
my aesthetic are incompatible.
Sasori might be able
to do something.
But he went off quickly.
I'm all alone.
But artists are loners
to begin with, hmm.
I buried the landmines.
Well? Got any ideas?
Art doesn't come to one that easily.
Especially not a Super Ultimate Art!
Sasuke?!
Why are you here?
It's you guys...
Bastard! Why are you alive?!
Where's Naruto?
I don't know!
Right now, pay attention to me, hmm!
My business is with Naruto.
Damn it, not that again!
First Itachi, now Naruto?!
You really don't give
a damn about me, do you?!
Nope.
Bastard!
They're coming!
See ya.
Stop!
Deidara!
Don't let them get away!
You're not getting away!
Deidara! Wait!
This time,
I'll make you tremble with fear!
You'll be awed!
You'll feel despair.
I'll wipe that smug expression
off your face!
I see!
There! Over there!
I knew it. Your weakness
isn't lightning, bro.
It's your stupid obsession with art!
Kurotsuchi?!
Bastards! What's the meaning of this?
A dud?
Damn it!
That sword won't stop my art!
A samurai using Lightning Style?!
It's not Lightning Style.
It's a battery... Seems it works.
Does it...?
What the—?!
This is all bedrock, bro.
The sword can't penetrate.
Even if it could, it won't let
the lightning be grounded.
Damn it! Hey! Let me go!
All right.
And one other thing, bro.
Where is the real Sasuke right now?
Damn it, Kurotsuchi.
Don't take me for a fool!
Pretending to be Sasuke!
You even looked like him!
Screw you!
Yeah, I suppose it's no use trying
to get info out of you, bro.
You're totally screwed.
We're heading back.
We'll maintain our original frontline.
Inform Headquarters.
Commander, could I have that back?
Don't bother us again,
brother Deidara!
See ya!
That might work, hmm!
I've decided the theme of
my Super Ultimate Art!
That thing could use a face!
Art will never die!
Even if I'm dead... Hmm!
What's wrong?
The enemy is disguising
themselves as allies!
Maybe you're an enemy!
We can't trust anyone!
What's going on?!
There's murkiness spreading
everywhere!
G-Granny?!
No! B-Breasts...
Bee!
How dare you stare at
the Hokage's chest
when I'm standing
right in front of you!
Oh no, bro! I meant no offense.
I'm just shocked, is all.
The Hokage's jugs are
definitely immense.
We're here to stop you!
You will not pass!
So this is what Naruto looks like when
he's in control of the Nine-Tails' power...
You did it, Naruto.
S-Such immense chakra!
Bro!
Let Naruto pass... Hear my plea.
I can vouch for him, that I guarantee.
Silence! We are fighting
this war to protect you two!
If you guys are captured...
The enemy has perfected their jutsu
and the world is about to end.
Iruka-sensei told us.
If you know that, why are you going?
Are you crazy?!
It's because of that!
It's because they're protecting us!
I can't stand it that
people are dying for me!
If they die fighting
and we win this war...
and I'm the only one left standing...
It's not worth it!
I don't want that!
It's better than the world ending!
We all believe that.
That's why we're fighting,
prepared to sacrifice
ourselves to protect you!
You think that I can just sit here,
unharmed and do nothing
when I know that?
I'm not that kind of guy!
Besides...
Don't try to talk your way out!
You will not pass!
Can you keep up with me
in this Mode?
What is that punch?
Damn, it's powerful!
I'd better avoid a direct hit.
Granny Tsunade,
you understand me, don't you?!
I'll stop this war!
Let me go!
Granny...
We are now part of
the Allied Shinobi Force.
These orders are from
the Allied Forces.
Even though I am the Hokage,
I cannot act on my own!
Okay. I understand the position
you're in, Granny.
Then, I'll just force my way through!
This time, I'll do it faster.
You're fast, old man Raikage...
No...
It's amazing that when
you're in Nine-Tail Chakra Mode,
you can match
the Raikage's speed.
There's no shinobi faster than me.
Not since the Fourth Hokage!
You knew my dad?!
We fought many times.
I came to believe that
no one could ever defeat him.
I understand that Jiraiya
of the Legendary Sannin
called him the Child of Prophecy...
the savior of the world.
So why is this savior
not around to stop this crisis?
Because he failed during
the incident of the Nine-Tails!
You are his son, yet you haven't
learned anything from that.
Only a fool speaks without knowing
the odds...
If that's all...
If that's all you have to say,
don't talk about my Dad.
And you were born.
Minato cried and said,
"From today, I'm a father!"
He believed in you
with all his heart.
The Fourth Hokage did not fail!
If you... insist on going...
I will kill you right here!
Wha—?! Hey, Raikage!
This way, we'll be able to buy some
time until the Nine-Tails is revived.
And the enemy will be forced
to postpone their plans!
Looks like you want to die.
Wait!
Bee, you...!
Oh... He was saved!
In that case, why don't I,
the Eight-Tails, die?
Then the enemy's plan
can kiss itself goodbye!
If Naruto can go to the battlefield...
my life is one I'd gladly yield.
Octopops...
Raikage!
You cannot make
any arbitrary decisions
without consulting the other
Allied Shinobi Force leaders.
You may be the Supreme Commander,
but I won't let you!
My responsibility is to make sure
we win this war!
No matter what it takes!
Then as Eight-Tails said,
why are you targeting Naruto?
When the time comes, as Raikage,
I will be prepared to kill
my own younger brother!
But right now...
I choose to kill Naruto over Bee!
Because Bee is the Jinchuriki
who is able to control
the Tailed Beast's power...
That makes him
a stronger military weapon!
Unhand me, Bee!
No way! Fool, ya fool!
You Jinchuriki don't exist
solely for yourselves!
You maintain the balance
of power between nations.
You are the strength of your village!
To the nations and your village,
you are a special existence!
You can't just do as you please!
You must understand
the circumstances, you fools!
Sure, that may be so...
But I've got my personal feelings,
a spirit I can't abandon...
Without that,
I'm just another weapon.
Why are you defending him, Bee?
We bumped fists...
But you still can't read
my heart, brother?
Doesn't seem like there's any
good prospects this time...
Listen up!
Only one of you is worthy enough
to inherit the title of "Bee."
Ay here is a candidate
to become the next Raikage!
You all know that...
Here in the Hidden Cloud,
each Raikage is assigned
a tag team partner.
Someone who will bring out
the Raikage's full power.
And to be "Bee" is to be
the bodyguard of the Raikage.
We'll now test your
compatibility with Ay.
You will team up with Ay
and attempt to behead
this rubber dummy
using the Double Lariat!
Remember! To do this right, equal
strength must be applied from both sides!
If one side is weaker or stronger,
it will only bend!
First, bump fists with Ay and
determine how much power
you should use.
Then execute the Double Lariat
on the dummy!
All right!
We'll start from that end!
I'm honored, sir!
Next!
Yes sir!
Next.
Yes sir...
Next!
Right!
Next...
– Yes, sir!
– Looks like we won't find
– anyone this time, either.
If he'd had a real sibling,
we wouldn't have had to go
through all this...
Next...
L-Lord Raikage...
It seems we found him.
You're kind of an odd one.
Bump fists with me again!
We're brothers from now on!
I'm counting on you, Bee!
Let's go, Bee!
Your plan suits me just fine.
We'll bump our fists every time.
Okay, bro!
Eat up!
You have to get strong quickly
or our powers won't be in sync!
Okay, bro!
Our mission this time
is to recover a scroll.
Don't tell me you're already...
Okay, brother!
Is he asleep?
Yeah...
Bee is a good shinobi.
He's got talent too.
Although his rapping leaves
much to be desired...
I agree.
Probably after me,
this boy will become
the Jinchuriki of the Eight-Tails.
Is that what you've heard
from the elders?
No... No one's told me anything yet.
My old man, my uncle...
They all failed.
I'm not compatible either.
Listen, as your cousin...
But look, you have
the Eight-Tails under control...
– Right now...
– Just listen!
Only those who are
Jinchuriki can understand.
Friends and acquaintances start
to look at you differently after.
Well, they probably think
they're treating you the same,
but you begin to see
that they're not.
There's no turning back.
You can only look
toward the future...
One that is filled with
darkness and loneliness.
Have you really
achieved compatibility...?
If you walk through life with the
shadow of your own death beside you?
It fills your mind
day in and day out...
and you begin to lose sight
of who you are.
You feel a hole in your heart.
And the Tailed Beast waits to
pounce on that weak heart and run wild.
When you live with
the constant fear of death,
you start wanting to die.
But you have a knack for ninjutsu,
you have the skill
and the ancestry...
You have everything
going for you!
Yeah... That's exactly
the reasoning they used
when they chose me as
the Eight-Tails' Jinchuriki. But...
that's not what's essential
to become a Jinchuriki.
So what is it?
Having something that can
fill the void in your heart!
What is this "something"?
Just "something"!
If I can find it,
I feel I can stay strong.
Let Bee find that something.
Another failure.
This time, eight people
were victims of his rampage.
Because of the number of tails,
the Eight-Tails is that much harder
to control than the Two-Tails.
How long is this going to continue?
The next Jinchuriki is
supposed to be...
you know, that boy.
Such prestige, so immense...
The Eight-Tails' name
gave you presence...
Now I offer you incense...
Whee!
I don't think he'll make it...
Th-This kid...
How could he do this
to our comrades?!
Treating us with such contempt!
Let's go, Bee!
Okay, bro!
Bee?! This brat?!
So this means
you're the A/B Combo?
So you're familiar
with our technique?
D-Double Lariat?!
Bee, we still have a long way to go
before the Double Lariat is perfect.
I'm still holding back
to match your power.
You have to become stronger!
I-I know! Fool, ya fool!
How dare you call your
older brother a "fool"?!
It's the Iron Claw for you!
I'll surpass you someday,
you'll see.
On that day, I'll be carefree.
The trick to this technique is
keeping both our powers equal.
So you have to come up to par!
That sounds ideal to me.
Talking down to you is my fantasy.
You can fantasize after
you master the Lariat!
Tonight... we will seal
the Eight-Tails in Bee.
Right...
Having something that can fill
the void in your heart!
If I can find it,
I feel I can stay strong.
Let Bee find that something.
What is it, bro?
You will now become a Jinchuriki.
Things won't be the same anymore.
It will be extremely tough.
No kidding?
It's always been like that.
I'll just give the octopus
a nickname as I rap.
Listen up, Bee...
Always tell me everything, got it?
You are special to me!
We are the ultimate tag team.
Even if he does have
the Iron Armor Seal,
I wouldn't be surprised if
the Eight-Tails starts acting up.
We'd better stay on it
and watch him.
Wheee!
The Eight-Tails is me,
the cool Killer Bee!
Yay!
The blonde hair and
the Teleportation Jutsu!
That's definitely
the Yellow Flash, right?!
Then we've have to
get out of here!
So he's the one who single-handedly
prevented the recovery of the Nine-Tails!
And you are Unruly Ay, son of
the Hidden Cloud's Third Raikage.
Rumors say that
you are extremely fast yourself.
Brother and me are gonna
get you, fool, ya fool!
Everyone, stay out of this.
I will take care of this!
He countered me at my top speed?
What's this?
Forgive me, Bee.
Are you all right?!
No way...
Is he...
the Eight-Tails' Jinchuriki?!
It's the signal to evacuate!
Minato!
We'll retreat for now!
This is child's play!
Eight-Tails is the cool Killer Bee...
That's me!
You have amazing prowess.
Not as the Jinchuriki
of the Eight-Tails...
But as a shinobi, it seems you
possess something very powerful.
He's got more natural talent
than me!
No, I don't mean that.
He possesses something
more precious.
Huh?!
Ay... You have a fine family.
As do I.
In any case,
the next time we meet...
I suspect we'll be fighting
as one Kage against another.
If you don't figure out
what your little brother considers
most precious to him...
he will be neither a Jinchuriki
nor a human.
Don't try to fool me
with that nonsense!
You are not getting away!
The Teleportation Jutsu goes
where the kunai are...
I've marked the locations of all
his formula kunai.
If I can figure out
which one he'll pop up at,
I can get him using
my top speed.
I've got my own responsibilities...
Go fly!
Now! Which kunai will it be?
So I won't fail.
On the Eight-Tails' tentacles...
There's a Teleportation Jutsu Formula!
Was that when...?
Fine, let's do it, one on one.
We'll stab each other and be done!
You are my foe... but I like you.
You definitely got the moves
of a shinobi killer...
This is my chance!
Damn it!
No doubt! He's fast!
But... I'll try one more time!
He's so fast, I can't track them!
Do you think you can beat me
with your Lariat?!
Octopops!
Instead of worrying about him,
you should worry about-
Why, Bee?!
Don't you get it yet, brother?
Fool, ya fool!
Thanks, Octopops!
No!
Hokage! You help too!
Lady Tsunade...
Until I become Hokage,
there's no way...
I'm going to die.
Granny!
Hokage!
You'd better have
a good excuse for this!
Even if you kill Naruto to
buy us some time
until the Nine-Tails comes back to life,
I can't see the next Jinchuriki
managing to control
the Nine-Tails' power,
to this degree!
Since we have no idea
which way this war will go,
I say we use every weapon we've got,
and not hide the Jinchuriki!
I'm letting Naruto pass!
Nice excuse!
I mean, now you're talking!
That's the Granny Hokage I know!
Hokage... Who's the one making
arbitrary decisions now?!
Each one of you...
What evidence do you have
that Naruto will succeed?!
I told you, your Lariat is too weak!
Bro, ever since you became
the Raikage,
you've underestimated my power,
fool, ya fool!
No one ever expected
the Third Raikage to die...
Where's bro?
Over there? Over here?
All of a sudden,
he started punching
his way out through the wall.
There should be a bunch of holes
in the walls now.
Follow them to find him.
All right, will do...
I'll look for bro beyond
the walls I go through.
Hang in there, bro.
From today,
you're the Raikage, y'know.
I know that!
We're in the middle of a war!
As the Raikage,
I will protect this village and
this nation to the very end!
That is what my old man wanted!
Bee! Starting today, you will go
to Unraikyo, the Cloud Thunder Ravine
to work on your Tailed Beast Bomb.
You will not be engaging the enemy.
But my Lariat...
I don't need your Lariat anymore!
If the enemy attacks the village,
you will stay and
take them out with
your long-range Tailed Beast Bomb!
Remember! You are never to go
outside the village ever again!
Bee, you and Naruto
are precious Jinchuriki!
You are special to
your villages and nations.
That's why I'm saying you cannot go!
No matter how powerful
a Jinchuriki is,
the others have been captured
by the Akatsuki and sealed.
We ain't going to lose, Naruto and me.
That I can personally guarantee.
Fine, let's put it to the test!
My Lariat against yours!
We'll see who's stronger!
Bee, we still have
a long way to go
before the Double Lariat is ideal.
Right now, I'm toning down
my power to match yours.
You have to become stronger!
I'll surpass you some day, you'll see.
On that day, I'll be carefree.
That sounds ideal to me.
Talking down to you is my fantasy.
W-Wow...!
See, with Naruto and me...
it ain't just the power
of the Jinchuriki.
We have something
stronger fundamentally.
Your words to me, and me alone,
before I became the Eight-Tails...
They'll keep me strong, no matter
what, even when all else fails.
Just "something"!
If I'm able to find it, I feel as though
I can stay strong.
Let Bee find that something.
I see...
You are special to me!
We are the ultimate tag team!
What I said that day...
at the Waterfall of Truth...?
So you finally understand,
fool, ya fool!
Preaching at you from above
is my fantasy.
The fantasy is now a reality, oh yeah!
You are very special to me...
I do not deny that I said,
"We are the ultimate tag team."
That's it?
Just those words are enough
to keep you strong?
I don't just live and fight
for the village and nation.
I live and fight for you too, bro!
Still you're way
too overprotective, bro.
And you're losing faith
in my strength, y'know.
You lose a lot as a Jinchuriki...
I tell ya, the heart grows empty.
But it made me see what's dear to hold
and now my heart is made of gold
Tailed Beast power isn't
my foundation! Okay?!
Before the Tailed Beast
became my mate,
something inside me
had started to illuminate.
I saw that it was
as big as the sun.
And that's my true power,
it's the one.
That's why I can keep
the Eight-Tails reined in.
Naruto has the same sun deep within.
And he has two of 'em, it's amazing.
Talk about a sensation.
You're right...
It really is like the sun.
Naruto Uzumaki,
what are your two suns?
My mom and dad!
Your mother and father?
The Fourth Hokage and
Kushina Uzumaki?
But both of them died right
after you were born.
When I was trying to
control Nine-Tails' power...
Dad made sure to let me
meet my mom.
He sealed her chakra inside me,
so that if the Nine-Tails' seal
was undone,
Mom would come and see me.
He did it all for me!
The Fourth Hokage studied
the unique Sealing jutsu
of the Uzumaki Clan...
And Kushina's chakra and
life force were powerful...
It's possible.
Just as I thought.
When she gave me this power,
Mom told me everything.
That long ago, dad fought with
the same guy with the mask...
And he learned two things...
One was that this masked guy
would try to destroy the future.
And the other was that...
The only one who could stop him
was the Jinchuriki who controlled
the Nine-Tails... Me!
A masked man... Was it Madara?
So Madara caused that Nine-Tails'
incident in the Hidden Leaf?
So the reason Minato sealed
the Nine-Tails in Naruto,
and leaving the key...
it was for this purpose?!
He never did anything that
was unnecessary.
So he concluded that
this masked man, Madara,
posed an enormous threat to us.
And that only the one who controlled
the Nine-Tails' power
had a chance of defeating him...
So he chose Naruto...
Minato left everything to you?
He knew he wasn't the savior?
I don't know if dad ever considered
himself to be a savior or not.
But my master told me that
dad was the Child of Prophecy...
the savior.
Do you recall what
I told you earlier?
That savior, Minato, is dead.
Don't you think that was a failure?
You're right. My dad died.
He died along with my mom,
trying to protect Konoha
from the enemy and the Nine-Tails!
Trying to protect me!
It only lasted a moment...
But at that moment,
they gave me something.
They gave me the belief that
I am capable of lots and
lots and lots of things!
And they entrusted me to
be the savior of the world!
Raikage!
If you kill Naruto to buy time,
then the Nine-Tails will just
end up being taken anyway!
And it will definitely spell
the end of the world!
Only Naruto can control
the Nine-Tails' power.
Just as Minato believed!
Letting Naruto go is the way to
protect shinobi, and everyone!
My bet is on Naruto!
So what is your decision?!
Let me go too, fool, ya fool!
Like you always said,
I'm a big fool too.
And Naruto here is just like me...
Don't you agree?
But to succeed, you need
fools like us
who don't care at all
how big or strong the wall!
Yahoo!
Bro's at top speed,
you can't go much faster!
He really means to kill Naruto...
This is gonna be a disaster!
As always, you're so stubborn.
I have no choice, but to join in!
I can't involve Granny in this!
Here I come, Naruto!
A lot of people have
put their trust in me.
I won't fail!
He dodged it?!
Fool, ya fool! He really is...
... just like the Yellow Flash!
You're right, Raikage...
If I fail, I won't be a savior.
So I will not fail!
Just like my Dad didn't.
Just like my dad, the savior, did it!
I just wanted to see for myself...
So I came at you, with intent to kill.
You're only the second one
to ever outrun my fastest punch.
It seems the savior is alive...
within you.
Now go.
Right!
The long night is finally
coming to an end.
They should be able to
use their eyes now.
New Pains of the Six Paths
using Jinchuriki.
I've just added a little something...
If Kisame's intel is correct,
Naruto now has the same ability,
just like Mito Uzumaki,
the wife of the First Hokage,
to sense the enemy.
Naruto will have no choice.
He'll have to battle
with White Zetsu.
It's all going according to plan...
Today, the Senju's Will of Fire
shall be extinguished.