I'm beginning to lose my patience
with these shinobi.
How long do they intend to keep
us feudal lords cooped up like this?
Now, now...
What is the harm?
We should decorate them
after the war.
What shall we call it?
Is this it?
How hard the wind blows
As we course through
the deep and winding road
The smell of the wind reminds me
of the capital...
Officials and we feudal lords are used
as hostages in times of war.
It is the duty of the shinobi to
guarantee our safety.
Which is why I accompany you,
Lord of the Land of Mist.
We will reach
your hiding place shortly.
Now then, what is a suitable title
for the decoration?
Certificate of... Certificate of...
Is that the enemy?!
I didn't detect anything!
Do not let them get close
to the Feudal Lords!
He fell for it!
So, this wasn't it.
Damn! He got away.
Get word to the other hiding place! Stat!
Oh!
I have the perfect name
for the honor!
Land of Fire's Hidden Leaf,
Land of Wind's Hidden Sand,
Land of Earth's Hidden Stone,
Land of Water's Hidden Mist,
Land of Lightning's Hidden Cloud
Allied Shinobi Decoration!
It's too long!
The Allied Award will suffice!
No, that is much too short.
It doesn't sound distinctive enough.
Feudal lords are so carefree.
What's the fuss over
getting a decoration?
That's their job.
Don't knock it.
If there weren't any medals
and decorations,
we wouldn't know what honor is.
Someone has to set the standard.
Well... I guess so.
You don't get decorated
by just thinking about it!
Stay alert. It's almost time to move.
Feudal Lord of the Land of Frost...
We are now headed for
the fifth hiding place.
Fifth?
Yes...
We will be moving you
at fixed intervals to five locations
to prevent the enemy
from finding you.
Your bodyguards are
all skilled shinobi too.
That is reassuring.
Yes...
They've underestimated me,
Black Zetsu!
I am the land itself!
Playing with those building blocks,
it's only natural I completed it,
at my level now.
You're expected to do
that simple act...
The next one won't be so easy,
that's a fact.
Oh... So this connects to that room
where I struggle with Nine-Tails' chakra.
Take a good look.
This time,
it's a statue of the Eight-Tails.
This is a drag every time!
Here's the entrance to another room.
For the final Tailed Beast training!
Now stop complaining!
I'm going to teach you
the most powerful jutsu for a Jinchuriki.
What do you say?
Preparations okay?
Right! I have to know how
to control stuff.
So? What do I do first?
Transform into a Tailed Beast
in Tailed Beast mode!
That's step one.
Now it's your turn!
Hurry and get it done.
Isn't that dangerous?
Transforming into a Tailed Beast
is sorta scary.
You can do it now, fool, ya fool.
'Cuz you can draw out
pure Tailed Beast chakra.
It's not going to run wild, ya fool!
Well then...
Visualize your Tailed Beast, ya fool!
Can't, huh? Too bad.
Well, it's not like you're pals
with the Nine-Tails...
Anyway, Tailed Beast Transformation
was a failure.
So how are you going to teach him
the Tailed Beast Bomb?
That's the first technique
a Jinchuriki can use
after going into Tailed Beast State, Bee.
Man, I'm dead tired.
So I used the Nine-Tails' chakra
all for nothing?
By the way... shouldn't you tell him that
this Tailed Beast mode is risky?
Bee, the risk for you and Naruto
is fundamentally different.
Look, I'll explain. Let me out.
I hand over the baton
for the mumble jumble
Saves me from the verbal fumble...
Hey! Naruto!
I'm the Eight-Tails, not Bee.
Now listen carefully
to what I tell you!
Man, this is so complicated.
But you don't talk in rhymes,
so it's easier to understand.
First, I'll go over the risk when you
switch to Tailed Beast chakra mode.
Risk?
There's a risk to this mode?!
Big time!
It's very important,
so be quiet and listen.
Y-Yeah...
The risk when you switch to
Tailed Beast chakra mode...
That's...!
Yes?
Basically, when you're in
Tailed Beast chakra mode,
your own personal Naruto chakra is
being taken by the Nine-Tails!
Because you momentarily
shelve your own chakra
in order to use the Nine-Tails' chakra.
So of course, if your own chakra is
emptied out completely... you're a goner.
Huh?! But how come
Mr. Eight-Tails is okay?!
Even if you take over
the Nine-Tails' chakra,
you haven't really tamed him.
Bee and I were like that in the past.
We fought over each other's chakra.
Oh and, you shouldn't
use Shadow Clones
when you're in
Tailed Beast chakra mode.
Shadow Clones made from
your own chakra will be taken.
They'll be gone in an instant,
and you'll die.
But my chakra takes the Nine-Tails' chakra
that's been leaking
and reconstitutes it or whatever...
so I have lots.
Fool! Don't underestimate
the Nine-Tails!
He'll wipe out your chakra!
Restoring your stolen
chakra takes time!
So be careful!
If you get carried away and
use only the Nine-Tails' chakra in battle,
you'll end up dead.
Wh-What...?
By rights, you and the Tailed Beast should
negotiate how you both use chakra.
But Nine-Tails isn't the type to do that.
Also, there's a limit to the chakra
you managed to tug out of the Nine-Tails.
So much risk...
And yet, I can't use
a Jinchuriki's ultimate jutsu?
Well, forget about
the Tailed Beast Bomb.
You should just concentrate on
polishing up your special moves.
Tailed Beast Bomb?
What kind of jutsu is that?
Oh, it's simple.
You take your chakra and
change its form...
gather it up and compress it...
Then just spew it out.
Like that time...
It's almost like vomiting.
I want to try it in this mode!
Like this?!
It's impossible without
Tailed Beast Transformation.
Anyway, I've explained it all to you.
I'm going to switch with Bee.
Oh well, too bad.
It can't be helped.
You just have to do your special move
in Tailed Beast chakra mode, is all...
Rasengan requires Shadow Clone Jutsu,
so it's not suited to this mode.
chakra release and rotation...
plus change in chakra form
and compression...
That's a two-person move.
Tailed Beast chakra...
Your own hands and feet,
that's the sensation.
And the real ones, are just an illusion.
I see...
Maybe like this?
Not bad at all.
Try that special move of yours.
That move you already have.
All right!
Rasengan!
Huh?!
This is...!
Change in chakra form with
rotation and compression...
That jutsu!
It's exactly like the Tailed Beast Bomb,
fool, ya fool!
Hey! Naruto!
Who taught you that jutsu,
ya dimwit?!
Huh?! Well, it was Pervy Sage...
I mean, Jiraiya-sensei.
But the Fourth Hokage invented it.
Fourth Hokage...?
What a coincidence.
Or maybe fate?
Truly not a shame!
Rasengan!
The method is exactly the same
as Tailed Beast Bomb.
It's exactly the same!
Created with
the Tailed Beast Bomb in mind!
That's the Rasengan!
It's like he entrusted you with
the Tailed Beast Bomb.
You couldn't have been luckier.
It's easy when you're in
Tailed Beast mode.
change in chakra form as
a human is impossible.
If you add rotation,
it makes it possible.
Yeah, but...
I can't do it as well as
my usual Rasengan.
Tailed Beast chakra is
a combination of
positive blue chakra and
negative red chakra.
Their ratio is key.
During compression, if you change
the red-to-blue ratio to 2:8,
it will become a ball!
Try it!
Okay!
You haven't got it yet.
Your red is at 9.5 and blue is 0.5!
It looks easy, but it's hard.
All of a sudden,
there's talk of positive and negative,
red and blue chakra, and numbers...
I don't understand this stuff!
Besides, this Rasengan is heavy.
I have to use both hands
or it'll break apart.
I can't be bothered with
all those details.
I'm the type that learns
by doing things.
So as for this Tailed Beast Rasengan,
I'm going to keep doing it
and doing it...
Until I get it right!
It's impossible in human form...
it's too much toil.
Rest a bit.
The wounds on your hands
come from the jutsu's recoil.
I told you, I can't worry
about the details.
Octopops, you said the ratio
should be 8:2.
Keep watching me and
tell me when I get it...
I want to remember
what that feels like!
You sure are a persistent guy.
Very well.
I take back what I said.
That's all.
It's a message from Headquarters.
Our Commando Unit has skirmished
with the enemy's Commando Unit.
Our predictions about
the enemy were correct.
But they are raising the dead
with a jutsu
known as the Reanimation Jutsu and
sending them onto the battlefield.
Who knows what kind of shinobi
we'll see on the battlefield.
So everyone, be prepared.
That's the signal.
The enemy is near.
But there's no word from Headquarters
that they detected the enemy.
What's going on?
It probably means there are enemies
that even Headquarters cannot sense.
After all, the enemy will only
revive the strong ones.
We have to fight dead people?
What do I do?
I'm getting scared.
Hey Choji, now that you're here
it's too late to whine.
We just received word from
Captain Gaara's Fourth Company.
Four of the enemies have
been spotted.
They are the Second Mizukage,
the Second Tsuchikage,
the Fourth Kazekage and...
And who's the other?!
The Third Raikage.
What?!
My old man too?!
Damn the Akatsuki!
The numbers don't match up with
our own sensory readings.
Are you sure this data is accurate?
Princess Tsunade...
It's the Second Tsuchikage
that has appeared.
Huh?!
It's no wonder we
could sense three,
but couldn't detect one.
The reason sensory detection
was futile is the doing of Lord Mu.
There's someone who
can evade detection
from even the Headquarter's
Sensory Division?!
What is he?
Captain Ao!
There are far too many
of those white monsters.
It's impossible for me to detect
the ones with special characteristics.
Darui's First Company will soon
encounter several thousand enemy troops!
Please distinguish the white ones
from those under the Reanimation Jutsu!
All right!
You take charge of
the broad-range scan!
Huh?!
This is not good!
Darui's First Company will
be facing too many
who are under the Reanimation Jutsu!
What's more,
they're all powerful shinobi!
They're coming.
Give the signal to get
into position for battle.
Right.
There are so many...
It's not just their numbers.
Headquarters was right.
I can distinguish the adept ones
with my Byakugan.
Lord Hiashi!
Look at your 10 o'clock.
Th-That's...
N-No way. That can't be...
What's wrong?
What about them?
That's...
They're... Lords Kinkaku and Ginkaku...
What?! These two are bathed
in the Nine-Tails' chakra!
Incredible chakra!
There's no doubt!
They are the Gold and Silver
Brothers of the Hidden Cloud.
What?
Even Dan is among them?
The Fourth Company is
facing my old man.
And the First Company is looking
at Kinkaku and Ginkaku.
Now that it's come to this, I have
no choice but to go out there myself.
Please wait...
Lord Raikage...
You are the Supreme Commander
of the Allied Shinobi Forces!
The Supreme Commander must
remain safe in order to give orders
to the troops until
the final stages of the war.
That is your duty towards
your forces.
But an enemy force
of enormous strength
is converging
on Darui's First Company!
The tide of battle is
like a living thing.
It changes second by second.
To discern those changes
is why I am here!
Bring me the map!
First, let us verify
every company's status.
At the forefront...
There's Kankuro Commando Unit.
It seems they have skirmished with
a Commando Unit of reanimated shinobi.
However, they defeated the enemy!
Presently, they are moving forward
towards the Akatsuki hideout.
Among the combat battalions,
Kakashi's Third Company
is leading the charge.
They are in the midst of battle now,
but they have taken
the advantage.
Right now, the main battle
is being waged here
by Kitsuchi's Second Company.
And Mifune's Fifth Company is the
reserve unit standing by to assist.
Now then, it begins right here.
The enemy unit that came by sea.
Darui's First Company
will take them on.
Let's call this Battlefield A.
And facing the previous Kage
who suddenly appeared...
is Gaara's Fourth Company.
We'll call this Battlefield B.
When you look at it like this, we
seem to be evenly matched in strength.
It's unwise to think that.
The ironclad rule of warfare is
to take the advantage
by mobilizing troops!
The enemy advances
from two directions.
You counter that by attacking from
one direction with full force.
We have two battlefields:
A and B...
First, we must deal with A.
We will concentrate our troops
with Darui's First Company.
So, we will deploy
Mifune's Fifth Company
in belt formation as support to
reinforce the ranks from the rear.
Then we will move Kitsuchi's
Second Company to the side
and pin the enemy against the sea.
Kitsuchi's Second Company
may be stretched thin.
But, the Fifth Company's deployment
in belt formation
will serve as a barrier.
Meanwhile, Gaara's Fourth Company
will break up and
make a slow retreat to
the opposite side of the village
as if to lure the enemy.
From there, half of the company
will join up
with Darui's First Company
as reinforcements.
And after the enemy is crushed
in Battlefield A,
Darui's First Company and
Gaara's squads will turn back
towards Battlefield B...
and the enemy that Gaara's
Fourth Company had kept occupied
will be crushed from the rear
all at once.
Why start with Battlefield A?
If you split
Gaara's Fourth Company into two,
won't the enemy seize that
opportunity to attack?
Don't underestimate those four.
They are former Kage!
With Battlefield A, Companies Two
and Five are in proximity
to Battlefield A and
can move quickly.
Also, Kitsuchi's Second Company
has engaged the white ones before
and is familiar with them.
Attacking the white clones
from the rear
will ensure a high rate of success.
As for the enemy in Battlefield B...
The former Kage cannot
launch an attack.
If the troops suddenly
break off into two,
the enemy will assume we're up
to something and will not charge.
The battle-hardened former Kage will
not be so foolish as to attack...
I see.
And even if they were to attack,
Gaara's Fourth Company is
a long-range battle unit.
They specialize in fighting from
a distance, which means
it would take longer to engage them
in a short-distance battle.
In other words, it is a company
that could buy us time.
What will you do,
Supreme Commander?
No wonder we could not
take down the Leaf.
You are blessed with
fine shinobi, Tsunade.
Save the compliments
for after the war.
So? What will you do?
All right! Let's do it!
Inoichi,
you've been listening, right?
I'm already on it. Also...
We've already sent word to Mifune
about the Commando Unit.
They are on their way.
And Shizune is allocating her people
evenly to provide medical attention.
All companies have been notified!
All right, it's been a while since
Ino-Shika-Cho went into action!
I have one question,
Nara from the Hidden Leaf.
What is it?
In order for your strategy
to be foolproof,
you must add in one thing.
Which is?
The Second Tsuchikage is
no ordinary shinobi.
The only one who can stop him
is the old Fence-Sitter.
His name has come up often
in our discussions.
What kind of shinobi is he?
From the time I heard that
his chakra could not be detected,
I knew he would be a problem.
He has an advance form of
Kekkei Genkai...
He is known as a Kekkei Tota shinobi...
Kekkei Tota?!
I thought you, Third Tsuchikage,
were the only one...
The Second Tsuchikage too?
The ability to activate
the three chakra natures
of wind, earth and fire,
all at once.
He was my teacher
who taught me the Particle Style.
To have to battle my master
at this age...
It does not pay
to live a long life.
Will you go?
Yes.
What choice do I have?
Nara...
Yes?
I'm not going just because Lord Mu
of the Particle Style is there.
Your tactical plan is brilliant.
And while all the resurrected Kage
who stand before
the Fourth Company know war,
they will not make
unnecessary moves.
You are probably right in
your battle assessment.
But the opposite is also possible.
The one who united
the Allied Forces is Gaara.
His youthful passion was
the primary catalyst.
Are you saying this could have
the opposite effect on the battlefield?
I appreciate your insight.
Well then, I guess it's time
to leap into the war
and show these young brats
what fighting is all about.
Especially that brazen young kid.
How dull...
But I'll show them why
I'm the one guarding the coastline.
I'll launch the opening shot!
Then continue!
– Yes sir!
Lightning Style: Black Panther!
Black Lightning!
Captain Darui is
the only one authorized
by the previous Raikage
to inherit the Black Lightning!
Sorry about that.
Up above!
We're not going to allow you
to pass so easily!
Keep on going!
Don't let them break
through the barricade!
Now go!
Choza...
What?
I see...
You're all grown up, Choza.
I still have a lot to grow.
Release!
Eight Trigrams Palm Rotation!
Brother...
Forgive me...
I am a member of the branch family,
sworn to protect the main family,
I'm standing here now as your enemy.
This must be my punishment for
resenting the main family long ago.
My body will not do
what I tell it to.
As it is, my decision
to choose death
for the sake of the village
has been undone...
This is the fate in store for me,
a member of the branch family.
There is no such fate!
Your son has fought
to demonstrate that!
So has my daughter!
Neji...
And Lady Hinata too...
Damn, there's no end to this!
Are you all right, Neji?!
Yeah... Thanks, Hinata.
It's not about the branch family protecting
the bloodline of the main family anymore.
We protect each other as comrades!
That time has actually come to pass?
Then Brother...
This is all the more reason,
by your hand I wish to...
Hey!
All this moving around
is making me sick!
Talk about being artless, hmm!
Shut up.
I'll be happy to seal
that mouth shut too.
I'm not into tight spaces!
I'll show you what real art is,
so let me outta here, hmm!
Damn it...
Ouch!
We stopped... hmm.
Granny Chiyo...
And...
Well done, Kankuro.
You seem to have stopped Sasori.
Hmm? That voice...
Hey! If you're here to help,
get me out of here!
It's stifling me and
I'm about to explode, hmm!
No, you're wrong.
You can't explode,
that's the reason you're in there...
Explosive Style kid.
Oh... well, that's true.
Hey, don't put it like that, hmm!
Both the Akatsuki and the shinobi of
the Five Great Nations are enemies to me.
I have no intention of helping you.
I loathe this jutsu.
I have no control over my body.
Listen up.
Retreat on my signal.
Right.
We just got tactical orders
from Headquarters.
We're to transmit this
to the front immediately!
Get the tactical data
to the captains!
Captain Kitsuchi!
This just came in from Headquarters!
Tactical orders!
All right! Tell me!
Got it.
Sorry, I just got orders to
take half this company
and join up with
the First Company.
Half?!
Are they out of their minds
at Headquarters?!
No, I agree with their strategy.
If everything goes according to plan,
things will be okay.
And I'll be back.
You didn't have to bother
stepping up to help.
And who was it that didn't stop me?
Then let me ask you this.
When did you all
forsake yourselves?
This is where I take back
my forsaken self!!
Super-Expansion Jutsu!
It's no use!
We can't lose them.
Tango! Get HQ!
The Commando Unit,
attempting to retreat, is reporting
that the enemy pursuit team
is closing in.
A relief team from Fifth Company
has been dispatched.
Give them the coordinates of
the closest rendezvous point.
I said let me outta here, hmm!
Lord Orochimaru's chakra
is penetrating my skull
and coursing throughout my body.
I must succeed in my mission.
Over that way...
Whether it was Akatsuki
or Orochimaru...
Whoever revived me will regret it!
Everyone is going to think
I was playing possum again!
How embarrassing is that?!
I'm trying to focus.
Can you shut up, puppet granny?
You shut up, Scuba-face!
Just a little more.
This is close enough.
Summoning Jutsu!
Wha—?!
Ibuse, do it!
Poison Fog!
What?!
He resorted to the poison because
he was fed up with chasing us?!
Damn it!
I should be resistant to poison,
but my body's going numb.
Are those reinforcements?!
Hey, I'm over here!
I've caught up to you.
Damn it!
Hanzo, I presume?
I am Mifune, leader of the samurai.
I wish to challenge you!
We're saved.
Sorry we're late.
Are you all right?!
Be careful. The enemy uses poison.
The masks we wear are
specially made for fighting ninja
and are impervious to poison.
Put it on!
Thanks.
They need antidotes!
Take the Commando Unit members
to the Medical Corps immediately!
Lord Mifune!
I don't need any help!
If you don't want to get hurt,
stay out of my way.
So you're Mifune.
Why do you side with the shinobi?
How can you call yourself samurai?
We do not serve the shinobi.
The one master that we follow has
never changed since the olden days.
It is peace!
Peace?!
We pledge ourselves to peace,
and act upon that conviction!
Lady Chiyo!
I haven't been playing dead.
You understand, don't you, Kankuro?
Uh... yes?
Never mind that.
Hanzo controls a poison salamander!
I fought him many times
in the past.
That's why I know the ingredients
to the antidote.
I am also aware that the salamander
takes five minutes
to produce and store up its poison.
That old hag...
Rambling on about everything!
Ibuse! Retreat for now!
Even though I'm being manipulated,
it seems I don't have to
fight them right now.
I am going.
Here he comes!
It's hard?!
You countered that nicely.
You're not bad for a weakling
who preaches peace and neutrality.
Don't look at me that way.
I once sought peace myself.
I wanted to unite the Five Great
Nations into one shinobi world.
But I realized right away that
such a thing was impossible.
Realized?
Battle after battle after battle...
And all that's left at the end is death!
"Dedicate yourselves to peace?!"
You know better than anyone,
what happened to that samurai!
Many samurai have
become shinobi instead,
and your techniques have been
passed over to the shinobi.
Capture them!
Sorry, but my body is acting
on its own and running away.
Samurai no longer have
a role in this world!
They don't believe in peace,
are influenced only by money,
and their roles have been taken over
by ninja who wield powerful ninjutsu.
Those shinobi fight and die,
leaving nothing behind.
I am the same.
You are wrong.
It's not about life or death.
I don't care if I lose my life
in the pursuit of peace!
Having conviction is to stir
oneself into action!
Your conviction has been warped!
According to the Samurai Way,
people are the sword and
they can live on in memories...
like my Famed Blade Kurosawa.
Do not compare people to swords!
What can you possibly glean
from a lump of iron?
Take your ritual of seppuku.
Why do you samurai try
to throw away your life?
I repeat... conviction does not fade.
Enough of this nonsense!
I will get rid of you, samurai,
once and for all.
I will not allow you to use ninjutsu
beyond this point!
The rumors were right.
You are indeed a master swordsman.
This is what they meant by
ninjutsu being useless on you.
You didn't even give me time
to weave a sign.
And that second attack with
my sickle and chain...
Even if one was familiar
with that move,
no one has ever countered it.
Long ago,
when I was still unknown,
you and I fought,
although you probably
do not remember.
Is that so?
Then why aren't you dead?
You snapped my sword with
that sickle and chain,
and slashed my head.
But somehow I survived.
So you're that samurai...
You didn't die?
Well then, this time I will make
certain of it.
Unfortunately, that will not happen.
From that first blow,
I understood why someone
as strong as you was killed.
What?! What do you mean?
I'm amazed that a shinobi of
your caliber did not notice.
Don't you remember how you died?
Who could bring me to this point?
Have you forgotten my face?
You are...
Yahiko of Akatsuki!
You are supposed to be dead.
What's going on?!
You conspired with Danzo
and betrayed us.
You now only think
of self-preservation.
You're trash.
I once respected you.
But, you have changed.
Just who are you?!
How can you be so strong?!
And you don't even understand
why you will lose.
Vanish, Hanzo!
S-Stop...
What do they mean?
What am I missing?!
Be bathed in venom and die!
I've had enough of your nonsense.
What?!
A sword that is continuously
honed will gain renown
and will be passed on. And...
Men who cling to their convictions
and defend them
become heroes whose stories
live on throughout the ages!
How?!
How were you able to cut me this time?!
The blade is not stained at all.
Is he that fast?!
You lost your conviction and
stopped honing your skills.
Your swordsmanship has
lost its edge!
Your blade is dull,
dirtied by blood and rusted.
A dull blade is worthless!
People are like swords!
You did not remember me.
And you probably don't recall what
you said as you left me to die.
It's salamander poison.
I smeared it on my sickle too.
But do not fear.
The poison will numb the pain
and you will die within two days.
Do you know why I am feared
as Hanzo the Salamander?
I shall tell you my secret.
Consider it a parting gift.
In my village, there was
a venomous black salamander.
I was just a boy then,
but when it died,
its venom sac was implanted in me.
Right around here...
in order to turn me into a man
capable of producing poison.
I can poison people just
by breathing on them.
From the time I was a child,
I was feared.
So I was forced to breathe
through this mask.
Then why didn't you take off
your mask during our fight?
I've done that in the past.
But doing that has risks.
The mask serves another purpose.
It protects me as well.
If during battle, the venom sac
is cut and ruptured,
the poison would vaporize.
Even with my resistance,
my body could not counter the
powerful gas, and I would be paralyzed.
It wouldn't kill me, but it would give
my foe an opportunity to attack.
Against someone of your caliber,
I must keep the mask on
to prevent that.
Although, my blade was indeed dull.
People are like swords...
Which means that I wasn't sharp.
I will tell you one thing.
Death is not the end.
Loss of conviction is the end.
That's why it's such a nuisance.
It's hard to discern one's conviction
just by looking at them.
If you die here, it wasn't
because you weren't sharp.
Blame your comrades, who cowered
at the first mention of my name,
and gave up, leaving you to fight me.
H-Hanzo the Salamander?!
R-Run!
You used your body as
a shield to protect them.
I shall spread word of your heroism.
Name yourself in exchange
for your life!
"As compensation for my death..."
Promise me one thing.
Say it.
Leave my fellow samurai alone!
Here's the antidote.
I told you that it's hard to discern one's
conviction just by looking at them.
But it's possible by fighting them.
It's been a while since
I fought someone like you.
I will spare you this time.
Well, it's possible that you'll die,
even if you take the antidote.
It is difficult to see
one's convictions through.
I, too, have my own conviction.
To bring peace to this world.
I'm going to use you as a test.
To see if you will die,
still embracing your convictions...
Or you end up surviving,
and abandoning those convictions
over time.
You're the one who insisted
on testing me.
Have you really abandoned
your conviction?
Well, that's hard to tell just
by looking.
There is a way to stop me,
even though I am immortal.
I believed I explained it
to you before, Mifune.
So step back and wait for
the opportunity to seal me.
I believe you are...
Lord Mifune!
His poison!
I'm fine.
I am resistant to this poison.
But that may not be
the case from here on.
Everyone, retreat with me
and get ready to seal him!
Just as I thought.
He didn't survive the poisoning
for nothing.
We'll observe from here.
Lord Hanzo...
Mifune... I...
entrust you with my conviction!
Seppuku?!
By a shinobi?!
He's defied the orders in my tag!
Suicide?!
I have no choice but to erase
his consciousness completely.
Why isn't he moving?
Hanzo would never take orders from
one who hides behind the shadows,
manipulating others like puppets.
You put your life on the line and
regained your conviction.
My friend, you were no dull blade.
Seal him!
Yes!
They sealed him.
I shall spread word of your heroism.
I hereby witness
your unwavering conviction.
Lord Hanzo,
you were admirable indeed!
Lord Mifune?
I understand Hanzo
did not have a grave.
I must find someplace suitable
for him.
This is pitiful...
That we're caught in the jutsu
of the Second Hokage
whom we've beaten before...
eh, Kinkaku?
My apologies for embarrassing you,
Kinkaku and Ginkaku,
long revered as
the shining light of the Cloud.
Ginkaku, look at his left shoulder.
It's the kid who inherited
the Third Raikage's lightning.
He seems to have some skill.
I don't mean to disrespect you,
but I'll have to shame you
some more.
I may end up stripping the plating
off your silver and gold...
With one strike of my Gale Style!
Even though it's dull.
Calm down, Raikage.
You are the Supreme Commander.
You just don't know how frightening
the Gold and Silver Brothers are.
I can't believe I just heard
you say the word "frightening."
It's not that I'm scared...
They are the most reviled criminals
in the history of the Hidden Cloud.
The brothers staged
a coup d'état during
the alliance ceremony
with the Hidden Leaf
and attacked the Second Raikage
and Second Hokage.
It is said they use four of the
Treasured Tools of the Sage of Six Paths.
They left the Second Hokage
near death. I know that much.
Long ago, it seems the Hidden Cloud
made an attempt to capture the Nine-Tails...
and the Nine-Tails apparently
devoured the Gold and Silver Brothers.
But the brothers kept
thrashing around in its stomach,
forcing the Nine-Tails
to vomit them out.
Ever since then,
they have been infused
with the Nine-Tails' chakra.
Not surprising, considering they
were inside the Nine-Tails' stomach
for two weeks.
It's hard to believe, but what
about the rumors that they are
able to wield the Treasured Tools
of the Sage of Six Paths?
Normal humans cannot handle
the Treasured Tools.
They absorb massive amounts
of chakra from its user
that would kill the average man.
They are shinobi
with monstrous chakra
who wreak havoc and fear nothing,
not even the Nine-Tails.
What scares me is
the thought of our subordinates
who must face them...
I don't like that tone
you're using toward your seniors.
I'll shut you up!
It can't be helped.
Seems like a lot of time has passed.
No one knows about us anymore.
Samui, Atsui.
If you're really
the Gold and Silver Brothers
we read about in our scrolls,
don't talk to me
like we're comrades.
It's not cool.
Well, well... For someone
who's always cool,
you're quite hot right now.
I sense that you guys
are pretty formidable.
Let's do this, Ginkaku!
All right, Kinkaku!
What is that?!
No doubt about it,
those are the ninja tools
of the Gold and Silver Brothers
that were described in the scroll!
Four of the five ultimate ninja tools,
which the Hidden Cloud collected long ago.
The Kokinjo binds its victim and
squeezes out the victim's spirit word!
The Shichiseiken severs and
curses that spirit word...
The Benihisago records the spirit
word and seals the speaker within!
And the Bashosen conjures up
all five chakra natures:
fire, water, lightning,
wind and earth!
Sorry to interrupt
your lecture, Sis, but...
Let me handle this!
Cloud Style: Flame Slice!
Those ninja tools look nasty,
but ultimately,
they're just mere tools!
They're no match for our ninjutsu
that's imbued with our hot souls!
Atsui, wait!
Stay cool until I finish!
Damn it! He's too hot-headed!
They talk too much...
This is perfect.
I'll take the one in the back!
Got it, Ginkaku!
Leave the others to me!
The nerve of the guy...
Avoiding someone like me,
with a hot fighting spirit,
to go for Darui!
Did you think you could avoid
my hot-spirited attack
with a crowd of bodies!?
Pay attention, Atsui!
Stay cool and look around you!
That punch was pretty hot!
Damn it!
Atsui, Samui! Are you all right?
Don't look away, kid!
Change places, Kinkaku!
Right, Ginkaku.
Can't I even stop one foe?
Forgive me, Samui, Atsui...
Whoa...
I'm your opponent this time!
That Kinkaku fellow packed
a pretty hot punch!
And this time it's Ginkaku, eh?
Squeeze them! Kokinjo!
Curse them! Shichiseiken!
Record them!
Benihisago!
All right.
My side is done, Kinkaku.
He's been struck...
That's what you think, you jerks!
It's our turn now!
Didn't I tell you to let me finish?
Now listen. Don't say another word.
What do you mean?
A Curse Mark Jutsu and
Sealing Jutsu have been used on us.
Our Spirit Words have
been taken hostage.
The word we've uttered
the most since our birth.
If we say that word...
We'll be sucked into that gourd
and sealed away.
You know a lot, don't you?
It seems the passage of time
revealed a lot of things.
The word we've said
the most is now forbidden?
We're not playing
some silly word game...
How dull...
I see.
Bashosen!
What?
What is the hot word I love
to use the most?!
You probably don't have
to think too hard to figure it out.
Scroll of Fire!
Hot!
Damn it!
Stupid...
Atsui!
There's an old saying,
"Silence is golden."
The mouth is
the source of calamity.
Right, Ginkaku?
Yeah, Kinkaku!
This is what happens when
you can't keep your mouth shut.
Words are used to lie. They're
merely tools for deceiving people.
If you make fun of words,
Bee will let you have it.
Bee? Never heard of him.
If you move, the girl dies.
And I'm not lying.
I'm sorry, Samui.
Just as I expected.
I must say, you're both
true Hidden Cloud shinobi.
Gale Style:
Laser Circus!
He's fast.
And to top it off,
it was a Precision Ninjutsu?
Don't take us lightly, brat!
Owww...
Kinkaku did a good job
of applying the Kokinjo.
This one's first.
What's going on?!
She didn't say a word,
but Samui's been sucked in?!
Curse him!
Shichiseiken!
His arm has already regenerated!
Record him, Benihisago!
The word I've used most often in
my life is without a doubt,
"dull."
As long as I don't use it...
I won't be sucked into that gourd.
However... Samui didn't say a word,
but she was sucked in.
Which means...
If you stay quiet for a fixed amount
of time, you can get sucked in...
Am I right?
Sharp of you to notice.
It seemed no one had
figured that out yet.
You're pretty smart.
"Silence is golden"? As if...
They also say that,
"speech is silver"!
Especially when spoken
with a forked tongue!
In this case, silence is
the most forbidden taboo.
Didn't I tell you?
Words are tools with which
to fool others.
In the shinobi world,
trickery and betrayal are
fine military tactics.
The spoken word is also
a ninja tool.
Is it any wonder that you two
are symbols of disgrace
among the Hidden Cloud?
How dare you say that,
you third-rate underling?!
You're just another pawn
for the Raikage...
A mere ninja tool.
A mere ninja tool!
So you can cut the drivel!
What the hell is wrong
with the ninja of today?
Boss...
I'm sorry.
I was chosen to be your bodyguard
and yet you lost your left arm...
Don't worry about it.
But...
I don't miss my left arm.
After all, I have two right arms.
Two?
This and...
you.
How about including Cee
and making it three?
Well, all right.
You can never have too many.
I am the Boss's courageous
right-hand man...
Not some timid rabbit!
Why?
I didn't say "dull."
I am the Boss's courageous
right-hand man.
Not some timid rabbit!
I am the Boss's courageous
right-hand man...
Not some timid rabbit!
Timid rabbit is...
Dull!
Damn it!
My apologies, Samui... Atsui...
My apologies, everyone...
My apologies...
My sincerest apologies...
Ready to move on, Ginkaku?
Right, Kinkaku.
Why?!
Damn it!
I touched the Kokinjo!
Why didn't he...?
I...
I apologize about the desks
and the wall...
My apologies for embarrassing you,
Kinkaku and Ginkaku,
long revered as the shining light
of the Cloud.
Apologies, Samui...
I guess that means
I'm a pretty humble guy.
That's not so bad.
Don't tell me...
While he was being sucked in,
his most-used word switched places
with his second-most uttered word?
Curse him! Shichiseiken!
Record him! Benihisago!
I think that's the way it goes!
Why you...
This uses up so much... chakra...
I feel like I'm going to drop first.
It's true... words can be used
as tools to trick people.
But when it really counts,
the spoken word...
is a precious thing that conveys
the truth that's right here.
Help me... Kinkaku.
That's why I'm going
to seal you now.
Kinkaku!
Samui... Atsui...
It's all thanks to you.
I swear I'll save you later.
But now... there's one more.
How dare you!
What?!
Hey, he's exactly like the...
What is that?
There's more of them?!
It's been a while since I've seen
that happen to Kinkaku.
So I guess Ginkaku's a goner.
The red and blue balance of
your Tailed Beast chakra looks good!
Go, Naruto!
Here I go, Tailed Beast Rasengan...
Concentrate!
Didn't work, eh.
You were close.
That's a shame!
You lost your focus!
And you have yourself to blame!
What was that feeling I just felt?
This is really not good.
I apologize!
It's too late for that!
After all, huh?!
If I can just seal that one
in this gourd too...
In order to do that though, I need the
Kokinjo to squeeze out his spirit word.
But that rope is on his left arm
covered by the Nine-Tails' Cloak.
I can't get it.
Captain Darui! We got word from HQ!
They are sending
the Kohaku no Johei.
I see...
That would be better than
this gourd.
This is the Kohaku no Johei,
one of the five Treasured Tools,
that was used to
seal the Eight-Tails.
It's more of a pot than a bottle.
It differs from the gourd,
Benihisago, in that...
if the target responds to the voice of
whoever is holding the pot,
his voice is immediately recorded
and he becomes sealed.
We managed to take
this away from Kinkaku.
We will send this to Darui!
But the situation is urgent.
Won't it take long to deliver this?
Lord Raikage...
Preparations are complete!
We can send this to Darui anytime!
Mabui uses
the Object Teleportation Jutsu
that transports matter
at the speed of light.
That is precisely why
she is my personal assistant.
But if it once belonged to them,
surely they know how to
counter this tool?
Although it will depend on how you
make him answer and seal him.
Then, I have an idea.
Any strategy you come with
is sure to work.
I leave it to you!
Do it, Mabui!
Ethereal Transmission Jutsu!
We are blessed with fine aides,
aren't we, Tsunade?
You are right.
It's here!
That's the Kohaku no Johei that
was once in our possession.
I see...
You intend to seal me with that.
I'm glad it's here...
But Kinkaku knows
how this tool works.
How am I supposed to seal him?
Well, HQ came up with
this strategy.
Until I know what that is,
I'll guard it!
Sorry, I can't afford to
let you catch me.
Protect Captain Darui
with your lives!
Fire Style Squad! Go!
Water Style Squad!
Weaklings!
Earth Style Squad!
Sorry about this...
Double Black Panthers!
Did he do it?
Why you—!
I'll tear you all apart!
They've all been defeated...
by just one man?
A barrage of Fire, Water, Earth
and Lightning Style had no effect.
Forgive me, everyone...
Shikaku, this jutsu
won't last long.
I know, please do it.
Darui...
It's Shikaku from Headquarters!
Listen to me.
I've been waiting to
hear from you...
You have the Kohaku no Johei,
don't you?
For this plan to be successful,
the Ino-Shika-Cho Formation
is absolutely critical.
Please hold on
until they get there.
Ino-Shika-Cho...
That's...
But Shikaku and Inoichi
are still at HQ...
We've lost so many men already.
To hold on is a really tall order.
Where did he go?
Kitsuchi!
Sorry I'm late!
Look! Reinforcements!
Over here!
Now, we can keep on fighting!
Listen! Shikamaru, Choji, Ino...
I am using Inoichi's jutsu to
communicate directly with my thoughts.
Listen carefully to what I say.
I see...
So that's the plan.
I understand.
So we're going to take care
of this monster Kinkaku
who killed the Second Hokage!
What a drag.
I feel a little scared.
Hey, you guys...
Don't chicken out on me.
Legends become exaggerated
over time.
And when a legend is surpassed,
new legends are born.
He may have the power of
the Nine-Tails,
but we have the power of
the Ino-Shika-Cho bond.
The Ino-Shika-Cho bond ranks in
the top two of ninjutsu legends.
Be confident!
Do not back down!
We must hold the line!
More reinforcements...
Sorry we're late.
He...
How could he...?
Everyone, cover them!
Hurl your kunai!
You third-rate underlings!
How is it going?
You're just weaklings...
As if you can bring me down!
Human Boulder!
Why you...
Shadow Possession complete!
One petty trick after another...
What extraordinary power...
This is nothing. I can break it
in an instant.
He broke through
the Shadow Possession!
Die!
Nice timing, Ino...
Got him!
Mind Transfer Jutsu complete!
All right.
Kinkaku!
Yes!
Come back, Ino!
Ino!
Choji!
For being scared,
you did pretty well, Choji!
I feel like I lost a ton of weight
from all that cold sweat.
That was just a feeling.
You look fine, the same as always.
It went exactly as planned.
Well done, Choji.
You've gotten good at controlling
the speed and release of
your Mind Transfer, Ino.
Units 6 through 10,
search for wounded!
The rest, follow me!
The rope that squeezes out Spirit Words
has been sealed along with Kinkaku...
So he can't use the ninja tool.
Now then, one more ninja tool...
Where is the Bashosen?
Let's go, Choji... Ino!
Already?
C'mon, stand up.
Th-That's...!
Long time no see,
you Ino-Shika-Cho brats.
You're Kakuzu, right?
We took the "Gold."
As for the "Bishop," we know your tricks
and how good you are...
From now on, we're on the offensive.
The brat who uses shadows.
Your being here means that
Hidan has been stopped, huh?
Did he get his head chopped off again
while he was praying?
Or does it mean he's not here
because he's still alive?
As if we know what he's doing
while he's rotting away somewhere!
So I don't have a rook,
my gold and silver were taken and
I'm completely on the defensive.
That's the fifth one.
That's right...
That guy has five hearts, so we have
to bring him down five times.
Yeah, you're right.
Time to finish the game.
By the way,
we also have gold and
silver pieces too.
Would you be interested
in knowing who they might be?
Dan Kato... Lady Tsunade's lover.
And...
Asuma Sarutobi.
The son of the Third Hokage,
and your master.
Asuma... Sensei!
I guess you're not the only ones
who took game pieces.
We have a few others as well.
Ironic, isn't it?
Why you—!
Choza!
Why is the Four Flames Formation
taking so long?
Hurry up and shut me inside
the barrier...
before I use my Spirit
Transformation Jutsu!
It's not that simple.
Not when you're the target!
A weird black thing has appeared!
Watch out!
Let's begin our counterattack.
We owe you one. I hope you
haven't forgotten, you stitch-face!
Sorry, I don't remember anyone
who can't make me money.
They say that money talks,
even in hell.
Was that true for you?
Masters!
Izumo, Kotetsu!
Shikamaru! Choji! Ino!
Help us seal him!
Izumo, Kotetsu...
You two and Darui will be left
to deal with Kakuzu.
Kakuzu uses Earth Style.
Center your battle on
Darui's Lightning Style.
Shikamaru, Choji and Ino
will take on Asuma.
But... that's too harsh!
Master Asuma is their teacher!
You can't do that!
They were Asuma's students,
the former Team 10.
They know Asuma better
than anyone else.
They have the best chance
of winning.
But...
No complaining! This is war!
One that must be won!
But...
I...
I'm going.
Shikamaru!
What'll you do, Ino?
Choji!
Take a good look around you,
at your comrades!
Go!
Come at me!
Choza!
I know!
Choji...
Do you remember
Asuma-sensei's dying words?
Choji...
You're a kind man who
cares for his comrades...
That's why...
you'll become a shinobi who's stronger
than anyone else.
Be more confident in yourself.
You're strong-willed,
and dependable.
Both Choji and Shikamaru,
they're clumsy.
So please take care of them.
Let's go, you guys.
Right!
U-Uh-huh...
You haven't been getting it
for a while.
Half-hearted attention,
not enough preparation.
Something's been bothering me
for a while now.
What is it?
Earlier...
I thought I sensed
the Nine-Tails' chakra.
But there's no way someone else
has the Nine-Tails' chakra, right?
You probably just imagined it.
chakra here is cut off,
both inside and out.
Nine-Tails is only inside you.
It's a bad joke, no doubt.
Naruto's beginning to
sense things.
The only ones with
Nine-Tails' chakra besides Naruto,
are the Gold and Silver Brothers.
Which means, they've been resurrected
with Orochimaru's jutsu.
However, he has the power to perceive
the chakra more intensely in this room.
We won't be able to fool him
much longer.
What'll we do, Bee?
Do what?
What do you mean, "do what"?
Weren't you paying
attention to the plan?
We're not supposed to
let Naruto out of this space!
That's what you're here for, Eight!
What a...! Damn it.
Where's the bathroom?
Go outside.
It's the door to your left.
You idiot!
Naruto's going to escape!
Follow him!
Oh!
Don't panic. Contact HQ.
What?
Nine-Tails is attempting to go out?
What is Bee doing?!
Actually, Master Bee wasn't paying
much attention to the instructions...
However, we've taken measures.
Lady Tsunade, please issue the order.
Mmhmm.
Stop... Naruto.
Why are there so many guards?!
Something's not right.
Naruto, I'm sorry,
but I cannot let you pass.
Please go back to that room.
Okay, but why is Shino's pop here?
Why are you watching me?!
Enough! Just go back inside,
I'll tell you there.
Why can't you tell me outside?
Shibi, I'll talk to him.
I-Iruka-sensei!
What are you doing on this island?!
We now have a secondary mission
on this island.
And we're here to back you up.
We heard this place is dangerous.
So why can't I go outside?
There's an unidentified creature
that we're trying to confirm.
That's because...
I sensed the Nine-Tails' chakra.
Is that related somehow?
He was able to perceive Kinkaku and
Ginkaku's chakra even in here?
A place where all chakra
is blocked out?
Letting him out would
be dangerous.
We must stop him.
Do your best to convince him, Iruka.
O-Oh, yeah.
The creature seems to possess
the Nine-Tails' chakra.
I guess there were others
like the Nine-Tails here.
We can't afford to let you out
and rile up the Nine-Tails
inside you.
That's why we want you
to stay inside and lay low.
Is that why Captain Yamato
hasn't come back?
Yes. The Wood Style works best
to suppress the Nine-Tails' chakra.
You know that.
Come on, let's go back inside.
Master Bee stands at the top
of this island's hierarchy of beasts.
That feeling I had when I
exchanged punches with old man Bee...
That was for real.
If those animals are running amok,
I'll suppress them.
Let me check them out!
Do not let Naruto escape!
Right!
All right! I have him restrained
with Shadow Possession!
Wh-What's going on?
He sensed it all with Sage Mode.
Why is this happening?!
It's war...
Madara is waging war on us.
Hey, Iruka! You...
Shibi, let's stop lying.
Naruto isn't stupid.
We should tell him the truth
and try to make him see
where we're coming from.
My comrades are fighting,
and going through hell...
Why are you keeping
all this from me?
This is a war to protect you.
Madara launched
a full-scale assault.
In order to capture Nine-Tails
and Eight-Tails
inside you and Lord Killer Bee.
If he succeeds in getting
both Tailed Beasts,
his jutsu will be complete,
and this world will end!
Protecting you means
protecting the future,
and protecting everyone.
Everyone is putting
their lives on the line.
They are fighting to protect you.
Naruto, your battle is with yourself.
This is where you must endure it.
Now, let's go back in.
I'll stop this war by myself.
I'll take on all
the hatred and the pain.
This is my duty!
Haven't you been listening?!
You have the Nine-Tails inside you!
This isn't only about you, Naruto!
You were the very first teacher
who recognized me,
yet you're only concerned
about the Nine-Tails!
Why can't you have faith in me?!
Don't act like a spoiled brat!
To me, you are...
An important student.
And...
I think of you as my little brother.
The enemy leader is targeting you
with everything he's got.
How can we allow you to
face such danger?
And besides, there is no reason
for you to shoulder that burden alone.
I'm different from before.
I've become stronger!
And Sensei, you're the one
who gave me that headband.
Hey... Iruka...
No!
I still can't let you go!
Sensei, didn't I tell you
I'm stronger now?
A barrier like this is...
He broke through!
I won't let him!
The Nine-Tails' chakra is too strong.
The Parasitic Insects are useless!
Temui!
Notify the Barrier Corps up ahead
that Naruto is heading their way.
Right!
The rest of us will pursue Naruto!
Let's go!
Why, Iruka-sensei?
What's this?
Knowing you, you will rush
to the battlefield.
That's how determined you are.
If you are reading this letter...
it means I wasn't able to
stop you.
Ever since Lady Tsunade
ordered me
to detain you on
the Cloud's secret hidden island,
I've had this letter ready,
for this very moment.
I'm disappointed in myself
for failing my mission.
I don't know if I'll even
be able to get you this note,
but there's something
you need to hear from me.
You've gone off,
so this is the only thing left to say.
Come back alive, no matter what.
I'm sorry, Naruto. I'm weak.
I act like your older brother,
but I've never been able
to protect you...
So he's gone... fool, that fool.
Killer... Bee, right?
I need to ask you a favor.
I'm not sure,
but I've seen you someplace
Every time,
I can't remember the face.
Please protect Naruto!
That's not the way to appeal, you see.
You have to raise your fist at me.
L-Like this?
Gotcha! Fool, ya fool!
It's you...
Should you be making
a promise like that?!
You're Naruto's guard!
If he couldn't stop Naruto,
no one can.
That's because...
You're always in Naruto's heart.
You are his state of mind.
Me? In Naruto...?
I don't know what you did to Naruto...
But to him,
you are someone special
Even though my rap style is informal.
Naruto listens to all you say.
Naruto has kept it safe inside him,
to this day.
What has protected Naruto
all this time...? What were your words to him?
Are you seriously going to leave
this place to go after Naruto?
We're still in training, you fool, ya fool!
You're going to get
Raikage's Iron Claw afterward,
that's for sure!
You learn faster in
actual battle, you fool!
We're taking the shortcut, ya fool!
What is the meaning of this, Tsunade?!
The Nine-Tails couldn't be stopped!
That Iruka...
We'll just have to use force.
What's the status of
the Barrier Corps?
They've put up a 36-layer Self-Regenerating
Barrier around the perimeter.
Even a Jinchuriki will not be able
to pierce through it.
Please rest assured.
It's Naruto! He's approaching!
It's time for us to show what we,
the Barrier Corps, can do!
This is the reason why
we went through all that hardship,
to put up this multi-layered barrier!
Do not let him pass!
The only message HQ
will receive from us is...
"Mission accomplished!"
Do you understand?!
Wha—?!
What's this?!
Up ahead stands a barrier wall.
We're gonna smash it and make it fall!
Octopops!
I'll break the barrier, fool!
Naruto, you get the Tailed
Beast Bomb in, ya fool!
Right!
Bee the Eight-Tails too?!
What?!
Here we go, ya fool!
It's no use!
The barrier isn't regenerating
fast enough!
At this rate...
Chief...
What do I tell HQ...?!
We couldn't stop him!
Yeah, I figured.
– D-Damn it!
– It's no use...
But there were two
of them breaking it.
No one mentioned
there were two of them!
There it is!
Huh? Wasn't this an island?
How come it's connected to land?
Minor stuff you don't need to know...
Now, are ya ready?
'Cuz here we go.
I'm bored with playing cards.
How else can we amuse ourselves?
Found them!
This is it!
So before I can get
the Feudal Lords,
I have to get
through you first, huh.
Get through us.
It's noisy outside.
How am I supposed
to concentrate?
Lava Style!
Chojuro...
I won't let you...!
The Eight-Tails' and
Nine-Tails' chakra!
They've appeared at last!
I must send word.
Looks like the Eight-Tails and
Nine-Tails have appeared.
So the Eight-Tails and
Nine-Tails are out.
But what about the Feudal Lords?
We should capture them to use
as bargaining chips, right?
No, we don't need
the Feudal Lords anymore.
If we capture them,
the nations would pressure
the Allied Shinobi Forces.
But from the very beginning,
those lords were mere tools
to lure the Eight and
Nine-Tails out.
Now that the Eight and
Nine-Tails have emerged,
there's no need for
indirect measures.
We're dealing with the Raikage.
He's aware that in this war,
the Feudal Lords have no value.
If Project Tsuki no Me succeeds,
it's all over.
What, really?
So Black Zetsu is fighting
Mizukage for nothing?
No. shinobi still cannot disregard
the Feudal Lords who hired them.
Tell Black Zetsu to continue
his guerilla assault.
By stalling the Mizukage
and her men there,
we'll be able to split up
the enemy's battle strength.
It's finally time for me
to join the battle.
First, I'm going to steal
the substitute.
It took time to find that
important sword.
Now then,
where's that damn Kakuzu?
I picked this up earlier...
What? I'm pretty good at using it!
You're not getting away!
All right! I got the one
that produces lightning!
This thing is great!
But I wonder who lost it?
Did you think I'd stay put?
Captain Darui!
I got the orders from HQ...
But!
Captain, let's attack with
Lightning Style all at once!
I'm sorry. I went overboard earlier.
I don't have enough chakra.
Can you give me a moment?
We're going after him, Kotetsu!
Right!
I'm really sorry.
All right!
The kunai were to distract us.
This is what they were after.
So strong!
Damn it!
Fire Style: Burning Ash!
What is this...?!
A smoke screen?!
It's you guys...
We're prepared for the inevitable.
So Sensei, please be prepared too.
Choji... Shikamaru... Ino...
You've become fine shinobi.
That's all thanks to you!
Show me what you've got,
Ino-Shika-Cho!
We'll cut him down in one sweep!
A Substitution Jutsu!
Run!
Your movements are slow, Choji!
Pull yourself together!
He's coming!
Shikamaru!
Cast your Shadow Possession
to lead me towards Choji.
That's just what I plan to do!
Shadow Possession Jutsu!
One more move!
Even if it's a bluff,
if he knows Mind Transfer Jutsu,
he'll ward it off!
If he dodges the Shadow Possession
and makes a run for it,
he'll be in Ino's blind spot.
Exactly what I hoped for!
And there...
Partial Expansion Jutsu!
Checkmate, Asuma!
Now, Choji!
All right!
What are you doing, Choji!
Snap out of it!
We prepared ourselves for this!
Choji...!
This is...
This is too much for me!
I can't take our Sensei down!
Choji!
Move!
That's...!
Wind Style: Dust Storm Jutsu!
Damn it!
He countered it!
Are you all right?!
Barely.
Why? Why does it have
to be like this?!
It's too late to whine!
We agreed to stop Asuma ourselves!
What's with that look
on your face, Choji?
Right now, I am your enemy,
plain and simple!
I'm already dead!
Don't hesitate!
I know. I know that, but...
Even back then, Sensei, you...
Enough is enough, fatso!
Just try and take me down!
Did you call me "fatso"?
You just said "fatso," right?
I am not... I am not fat...
I'm just a little chubby!
It's no good.
Choji has totally lost his will to fight.
Why, Choji?!
It didn't work!
Choji! Move away!
Choji!
Ino Mind Transferred into Choji.
That was close!
Thanks for the Shadow Possession,
Shikamaru!
Ino...
We went on many missions
with Asuma-sensei as Team 10.
I know exactly how you feel.
Shikamaru and I don't want
to fight him either.
But because we know Asuma-sensei
better than anyone else,
we can stop him with the least amount
of risk to the Allied Force!
Choji...
Choji, you haven't forgotten what
these piercings represent, have you?!
Everyone in Team 10 is
now a Chunin.
That means I'm no longer
in charge of you.
Each of you will go on
to become captains
and eventually lead
your own teams.
These earrings are a gift to
celebrate your promotions.
Don't ever forget that the four of us
were members of Team 10!
And these earrings are proof
that you have come of age
in your respective clans.
Each of you knows the story behind
the Practice of the Piercings.
Now go, and present
your earrings to your clans.
And when you do,
you will be officially recognized
as full-fledged shinobi!
Now, get going!
Full-fledged shinobi...
I... I...
Fire Style:
Burning Ash!
Ino, Choji!
Choza!
Old Man!
Choji!! Snap out of it!
We're not brats who need
to be protected!
We're the ones doing the protecting!
Would you let Asuma kill
his own child?!
Your idea of kindness is wrong here!
Shikamaru is right!
Why do you think you
have that piercing?
Quit pouting, Choji!
You're the 16th head
of the Akimichi Clan!
Akimichi Clan...
Choza! Please come quickly!
Sorry, I'll be right there!
If you are truly kind...
there is no other time like now.
Or are you merely a coward?
Choji! It's all right!
From today on, you are an adult.
You will have a new piercing
upon which you make your vow...
and it will be your turn to nurture
your own child and pass on that earring.
What is it?
Do you think...
I can really get married?
What kind of look is that, Choji?!
You know what it is, right?
When Asuma always tells you
that you lack something.
Even I was able to get married.
Have more confidence in yourself!
But I might not be as lucky as you.
Times are different...
And it's hard to meet girls.
Choji, the time has come
to make your oath!
You know the words, don't you?
Uh-huh...
Human Boulder!
I won't hand over
this last bite to anyone!
With an appetite like that,
there's no need to
worry about your body.
After I finish eating,
can you help me train, Asuma-sensei?!
Lastly, Ino, Choji, Shikamaru...
There's something I want to say.
Choji...
You are kind and considerate
of your comrades.
That is why you will be stronger
than any other shinobi.
Have more confidence in yourself.
Okay.
And... you should diet a little.
I don't know if it'll work,
but I'll try my best.
I just thought that
I'd change naturally.
I thought both my heart and body
would get stronger when I got older.
I, the 16th head of the Akimichi Clan,
hereby swear,
I shall pass on this oath entrusted
to me by the 15th head,
unto the 17th, to my future child!
Sorry, Ino.
I'm okay now.
You can switch back.
In order to protect the Yamanaka
and Nara Clans,
and the Hidden Leaf Village...
I, Choji Akimichi, swear to
transform from a caterpillar...
Into a butterfly, and take flight!
Choji!
It's time to change!
So you grew wings, Choji...
without using the pills!
Choji!
That's my boy, Choji.
Yes! That's the look!
Choji's skinnier!
Did he take that pill
he took long ago?
This looks like the effects
of the Chili Pepper Pill.
Will he be all right?
He'll be fine!
He didn't use the Akimichi Clan's
Secret Calorie Control Technique.
He transformed on his own.
In other words, he'll have
no side effects from the pill.
Was the shell of the chrysalis harder
than you thought, Choji?
Well, you can fly now, right?
Oh yeah!
I'm going up!
Old man Choza!
I'm sorry Choji's been
such trouble!
But that's all over.
He is now worthy of being
the 16th head of the Akimichi Clan.
We'll deal with Asuma!
Please take care of the rest, old man!
Come get me!
When you've weakened him,
send him over to us!
You sure can bark out orders.
We should go and help.
Shut up!
That's the Sealing Corps!
Like it's that simple!
Shikamaru! Your back!
Right!
Go, Ino!
Mind Transfer Clone Jutsu!
I'm up next!
Shadow Stitching Jutsu!
There's no way to counter this.
Nice work, Choji!
Choji... That's the look.
As long as you have that look, you will
be stronger than any shinobi out there.
Right now, you have
the expression of
someone who has all
the confidence he needs!
Choji!
To beat me with the memento
I left you...
I can't move because
I'm filled with emotion.
I call it my Shadow Possession
Shuriken Jutsu.
That's why you can't move.
All right!
Leave the rest to us,
the Sealing Corps!
Can you wait a bit?
What?!
We already heard your last words.
Hearing them a second time
won't have the same impact.
Then let me add one thing
I couldn't tell you the last time.
I have nothing more to say
to you three...
because your Ino-Shika-Cho
formation is complete.
Sensei...
Asuma...
Asuma-sensei...
– Thank you.
What is that?!
I'm ending this battle now!
So help me out, Shikamaru! Ino!
All right!
Choji, I've been with you
for a long time...
but I've never seen you
take charge!
– Ninja Art:
– Four Flames Formation!
Well done!
Once inside this barrier,
even those controlled by
the Reanimation Jutsu are helpless.
Yes...
Right.
This is...
the last one!
I'm dying. Help me...
You used too much chakra.
Don't use this ninja tool anymore!
But, I'm so good with it.
Thanks, big guy from the Leaf!
It's far from over.
This is just... the beginning.
That's some assessment.
We're the victors here.
We've defended
the coastline to the end.
Your amphibious operation
is a failure.
Summoning Jutsu!
No way!
What is that?!
It's bigger than Choji.
I have a bad feeling about this.
I-It's not just big...
That's some assessment
on your part too.
Come! Choji!
Please deal with
Kakuzu and Hizashi!
I'll handle that one!
Sealing Corps!
Go, Gedo Statue!
It's there, eh...
Now, Choji!
He stopped me?!
What happened?
What's happening up there?!
I can't believe this.
Get back!
Everyone, retreat to
the coastline!
Earth Style: Mountain Jutsu!
What is that thing?
What power... It's overwhelming!
Taking into consideration
all the data gathered so far,
and the data Temari of the Sand
gave to the Allied Forces Council,
I wonder if that's...
Why you—!
Damn it!
You can't have that ninja tool!
I don't want the ninja tool!
I want what's inside.
I'll return the ninja tool later.
If you want it that badly.
You used the Gold and Silver Brothers,
who possess the Nine-Tails' chakra,
by deploying them to the front lines.
Now that you're through with them,
you want to seal their chakra
inside that statue...
Seems the Allied Forces have
a shrewd one in their midst.
Am I wrong?
What a shame
that you're my enemy.
Don't tell me that giant is...
No way...
Damn it!
Shikamaru?!
Are you all right, Shikamaru?
You're a lifesaver, Choji!
Sorry to bother you twice.
Don't stress over it.
I apologize.
So what happened to him?
He disappeared with
the ninja tool.
They retreated?
Choza, seal me!
Hurry...
Hurry and seal me!