All right! We've cornered him!
Just when I thought I regained
consciousness, this happens...
What's that?!
You're strong, after all...
Pakura-sensei.
Maki...?
Let me out!
I've had it! I'm completely fed up!
I'm going to explode, hmm!
You're okay with that, huh?
We got you sealed
with the Lightning Style,
especially so you can't explode.
So shut your trap! You dud!
There are no such things
as duds in art!
Huh?!
No way, an explosion?!
What is it?!
What is this?
Dan!
Yeah. Looks like someone succeeded.
Naruto, the Jinchuriki are fading away!
Looks like Itachi did it!
Thanks, Itachi!
But this battle ain't going anywhere!
No time to waste! Let's go!
Tell Ohnoki...
He must secure the future of
the Allied Shinobi Forces...
Only then can he come
and tell me all about it...
Just what the hell is going on?
I get it...
The four-eyes has been
taken down... hmm.
It was a dud.
Don't scare us like that.
It wasn't a dud!
Art is...
indestructible!
Scaring us like that...
Granny Chiyo!
Looks like I'm free
of the cursed spell.
Looks like I can finally die...
Granny Chiyo!
Kankuro...
I entrust you with the techniques
of the Puppet Master.
I accept and will take it over...
Granny Chiyo.
No need to play possum anymore!
Choza, forgive me.
Those signs are for the Ghost
Transformation Jutsu, aren't they?
I understand.
Please hurry to
Lady Tsunade's side!
This jutsu has killed so many shinobi...
I couldn't have imagined that
it would come in handy like this!
Ghost Transformation Jutsu!
Just as I thought!
Souls ascending after being released
from the Reanimation Jutsu
can be manipulated with this jutsu too.
But it doesn't seem like
you have much time.
Please hurry!
Yeah...
Farewell, Choza!
Thank you for everything!
Amazing...
He flew off like a ghost!
Just what is the Ghost
Transformation Jutsu?
It allows one to become
a living ghost
that can span long distances
to kill a foe...
Originally, that is...
Tsunade...
I...
Curse Kabuto, he's failed.
Hey, what are you looking at?!
You're fighting me!
As well as the Green Beast!
Looks like the Reanimation
has been released.
And...
what of it?
What is... that light?
The Susano'o is gone and now...
the dust from the Reanimation
is in a fierce whirlwind.
Without a doubt, this means...
The Reanimation has been released.
What?!
We haven't located Kabuto yet.
It's too soon!
Even if Kabuto was found,
to be able to stop this jutsu...?
Who could have done this?
It doesn't matter!
Whoever did it is a hero
who's saved the Shinobi World!
The heavens haven't forsaken us yet!
It appears you have able shinobi
on your side too.
It can't be helped...
He was prepared for this?
Not yet!
He's planning a final strike
before he disappears!
Fire Style: Dragon Flame Caterwaul!
Water Style:
No... It won't make it in time!
Lady Hokage!
I'm all right!
The 100 Healings Jutsu has worn off!
But...
we've won...
Damn!
What was that?!
I thought she completely
lost consciousness!
It's been a long time... Tsunade.
It's me, Dan.
Dan... How are you here?!
The Reanimation has been undone.
And I flew over here with
my Ghost Transformation Jutsu.
But that was a close one!
Dan...
You haven't changed at all... Tsunade.
I have always honored your...
There's no time to wallow
in sentimentalities.
I have to go.
Dan!
I ran from my memories of you
for a long time, after your death.
But I've changed!
And now...
I can finally fulfill the dreams
and goals you left behind!
I've become the Hokage!
But...
Thank you, Tsunade.
You are fulfilling my dreams
for me just fine.
I really caused you a lot of pain.
I'm sorry.
I'll be waiting for you on the other side.
But don't come too quickly, okay?
For you yourself are my dream.
I was able to protect you at the end...
It appears a little bit of good did come
from being reanimated.
Hokage, are you all right?!
Your vitality has returned.
And you received chakra?
I got to see an old friend
for just a little while...
Well, you'll meet again right away.
What? What's going on anyway?
I thought the Reanimation
was undone!
Reanimation is a jutsu that
summons the dead.
However, there is one risk...
Risk?
As long as one knows the signs,
the reanimated dead can break the
Reanimation Contract from their end.
Rescind the contract?!
When that happens,
you end up with
the biggest problem of all.
An immortal body with infinite chakra...
that can move without control.
Impossible!
Tell the jutsu caster...
Never use a Forbidden Jutsu carelessly.
Reanimation, release!
How... How can that be...?
Your trivial jutsu can't hold me.
You should know that
after fighting me, right?
Now then...
The Perfect Susano'o...
Everyone who sees it dies...
or so they say.
I'm almost embarrassed
to have to do this again.
I already used it once...
My interest has waned,
thanks to the interference.
Perhaps I ought to go
retrieve Nine-Tails instead.
What?
Lord Tsuchikage!
We cannot stop him.
We still have to fight!
We must stop him here!
So sad...
Lightning Cable!
Guy!
Right!
Take this! Little Toe Attack!
Heh! You don't look too happy!
What's that supposed to mean?
Since you're hiding your face,
I can only guess.
If you feel insulted,
take off that mask
and show us how composed you are!
Stupid!
Nice going, Naruto!
I told him not to rile up his opponent.
Well... It seems I have
no choice but to use it.
What is that?!
A giant gourd and a bottle...
Frankly, I wanted to revive this
when the conditions were perfect.
It's only a fragment,
but it's not lacking in power.
It's taking too long.
It's time!
The statue's been acting weird
since it swallowed something earlier.
Watch closely and feel it
through your skin...
The return of Ten-Tails!
And the beginning of the end!
So that's it!
That statue was
the Ten-Tails' actual body!
Huh?! What's Ten-Tails?!
But what's going on?
When he declared war at
the Five Kage Summit...
The purpose of this war
was to collect
all nine Tailed Beasts' chakra
in order to revive Ten-Tails.
He doesn't possess Eight-Tails
or Nine-Tails yet...
Is he bluffing?
It's too risky to get up close.
Oh...
Only a fragment,
but it is not lacking in power.
Have we given him one tentacle
arm's worth of chakra?
We're always dropping rhymes
But maybe we messed up big time...
Yay!
The chakra from a tentacle
was taken, just a little
I may not look it
I admit I'm flustered a bit
He took the chakra from one
of Eight-Tails' tentacle arms...
Does that mean only a portion
of a Tailed Beast is sufficient?
Naruto...
You felt it too, didn't you?
That was my chakra in
that bottle and gourd.
Yup...
Let me take over, Naruto.
I'll explain.
About Ten-Tails too.
You listen from in here.
You know about Ten-Tails, Kurama?
Yeah, of course.
Listen up, everyone!
Hmm?
That voice!
Naruto and the Nine-Tails
have switched places!
He'll explain everything to us...
Nine-Tails and Naruto
are tight now!
If even just a portion of
the Tailed Beast is sufficient...
Then that statue already has a piece
of Eight-Tails' and my chakra inside it.
The Nine-Tails too?!
The bottle and gourd that guy
summoned and fed to the statue just now
were two of Old Man
Six Paths' treasured tools.
They both possess powerful Sealing Jutsu
that can seal away anything and everything.
Once you get put inside either one of
them, you can't get out, no matter what.
So...
Sealed inside the bottle
was a guy named Kinkaku.
And Ginkaku was sealed
inside the gourd.
I suspect they were reanimated
using the Reanimation Jutsu,
used in the war and
then sealed away.
So Kinkaku and Ginkaku
had some of your chakra.
But given that they're just fragments
of Eight-Tails' and my chakra,
who knows what form or shape
the revived Ten-Tails will take.
We must act before Ten-Tails
fully comes back to life.
Old Man Six Paths used to say
that Ten-Tails' full revival
would signify the end of the world.
Is the Ten-Tails really that terrible?
I get that he's got Ten-Tails,
but just how powerful is he?
He's the aggregate of the chakra of all
the Tailed Beasts, One-Tail through me.
He was the beginning of chakra
and a creator-god of many nations.
Amenohitotsunokami...
Datara... Daidarabotchi...
He has many names.
He drank oceans, split open the
earth, and hoisted up mountains...
He is the progenitor who is said
to have created this very land.
Simply put, he has the total power
of all nine Tailed Beasts.
Honestly, I couldn't take him on
by myself and hope to win.
But if he only has a piece
of Eight-Tails and me,
who has the most chakra
out of the nine...
it might be worth a try.
You're all mistaken.
For me, the revival of Ten-Tails
doesn't need to be complete.
My end goal is a super genjutsu...
The Infinite Tsukuyomi!
I will put every human on
this planet under a single genjutsu...
A single world that belongs
to nobody.
One perfect world
without war or ill feelings.
Only within a single
collective consciousness...
where the individual has been
cast aside, can truth be found!
The world no longer needs hope,
a future or famous heroes.
Even if incomplete,
once Ten-Tails is revived,
the Infinite Tsukuyomi jutsu
can be achieved.
Then reality will come to an end...
And all that will exist will be
a single unending dream...
that will last for all eternity!
I had Dad, Mom, and Pervy Sage.
Kids love looking up to their hero.
That's why I can keep running
forward without hesitation.
I will become the greatest Hokage
of them all!
That's my dream!
I guess cracking that mask of yours
will have to come first.
You will not touch the statue!
Naruto! You know about
his abilities, right?
Your window of opportunity is the instant
he tries to suck you inside himself.
That's when he's solid.
If you attack him normally,
you'll just pass right through him.
So it's like you're aiming
for a counterattack.
Diversionary tactics are a must.
Create an opening through
continuous close combat!
Avoid using big moves!
I know!
That's why I made a clone!
Bee! Please raise me up high!
I'm good to go.
We should avoid attacks
that touch him directly.
Up you go!
Super Mini Tailed Beast Bomb!
Mangekyo Sharingan!
Twin Fangs!
This one!
I guess not.
Then it must be...
Nice timing!
I'll deal with you...
first!
That's so cool,
Bushier Brow-sensei!
Okay! I've infused more
than enough chakra!
Sorry, but...
I'm going for the statue!
Kamui!
If I gouge out its head...
it shouldn't be able to survive,
statue or not!
So naïve.
What happened?
He vanished?
Naruto!
These boulders are in the way!
Damn it!
Bee!
I've got it!
Fly!
He cut through that boulder
with his Lightning Blade.
Nice, Kakashi!
I'm not going to make it in time!
Naruto! Just keep going!
I'll take care of the kunai!
Kamui!
Damn it!
He's really strong.
I can't get my attacks to hit him.
Are you all right?
Yeah...
But if even that attack is no good...
What can we do?!
What's happening all of
a sudden?
Hey, Kakashi...
Did you see that?
– Yeah.
– Huh?
There's a crack in his mask.
Huh? Where, where?!
You're right... On the left side!
Looks like Naruto's earlier attack
grazed him
before it passed through!
Nice going, Naruto!
Let's keep it up just like that!
All right! Now I feel like
we have a chance!
To be honest, it didn't look to me
like Naruto's attack landed.
You're doing it again...
You always say things like that!
Are you saying
it was something else?
What's going on?
You're wide open!
Don't mock me!
Uchiha Flame Formation!
Hot! Hot! Hot!
Whoa!
Are you all right,
Octopops and Eight-Tails?!
Do I look all right?
Now that he's erected a barrier,
we have no choice but
to tackle the masked guy first.
That's been my plan since
the beginning, y'know!
Damn it!
It's no use just thinking about it.
It's an implausible theory,
but it's not impossible, either...
Guy, Naruto, Bee...
– Yeah?
– Hmm?
There's something I want to test.
Help me out.
Let's do it!
Okay!
Yo!
Impressive destructive power.
How's that?!
You don't have any time
to suck me in, do you?!
You underestimate
the Sharingan too much.
I can read your movements.
I'll keep these.
He materializes while
he absorbs things.
Now!
Rasengan!
Don't you understand
that it's futile?
It's just like you said, Kakashi-sensei!
I don't really understand why,
but I finally landed
an attack on him!
I knew it...
I thought he was using
two different jutsu:
One that lets him phase through things,
and one to absorb or expel targets.
But that's not the case.
– Huh?
It's all one single jutsu!
It's one jutsu?
Yeah.
Well, no one's better at jutsu analysis
and breakdown than you.
Can you explain his jutsu
to us in simpler terms?
Knowing what it is might change
how we approach the battle.
The way his jutsu works
is really simple...
You see, the jutsu he uses
to absorb things,
and the one he uses to slip through
objects is Time-Space Ninjutsu.
What do you mean?
How can you tell?
Well...
Let me explain it in order.
First, the crack in his mask.
My kunai made that mark.
I'm absolutely certain.
From the look of the wound
on his right shoulder,
I can tell it was caused from being hit
by Naruto's Rasengan just now.
What these two things have
in common is that
they both involve areas of his body
that were overlapping
and in contact with Naruto's body
while he was slipping through him.
Never mind that!
Why did your kunai hit
and not my punch?
Although it looks like your attack
slipped right through him,
in fact, only the part of his body
that would have been
in contact with yours
was transported into time-space.
In other words,
the left side of his mask
that your punch "passed through"
was simply transported
into time-space and
no longer existed on this dimension.
At least materially.
And then almost simultaneously,
remember I hurled that kunai
into time-space using Kamui?
Just as his momentum
carried him forward
when he extended his arm
toward you to grab you...
my kunai finished entering time-space
and scored his mask.
Did the same thing happen
with the Rasengan?
Yeah...
So that's what happened.
But how come both of
your visual abilities are linked?
Where did you get that eye?!
Where, huh?
If anything,
in the last Great War.
The Battle of Kannabi Bridge...
The same battle where you earned
the nickname "The Sharingan Hero."
Are you...?
I thought I told you not
to flap your mouth so readily!
You're just all talk now!
Your words are worthless!
It's too late for regrets.
Reality just keeps cruelly
moving ahead.
You've seen reality,
so you ought to know.
Not one wish ever gets granted
in this world.
That's why I'm guiding it to
the dream of Infinite Tsukuyomi.
I'm going to create a world
where it won't be necessary
for a hero to pathetically make excuses
in front of a grave.
Hey, are you all right, Kakashi?!
You bastard!
Are you still blabbing on
about that?!
I thought I told you too!
I'm not giving up my dream
of becoming Hokage!
I've been entrusted with way too much
from way too many!
Entrusted, eh?
What if you were to lose the things Jiraiya
and the Fourth Hokage entrusted you with?
I wonder what they would think?
Naruto, if you fail at the things
you were entrusted with...
I wonder what you will think
of yourself as well?
If you postpone dealing with problems
and cover it up with the word "hope,"
all that awaits you is
an empty reality.
Both one entrusted, and those
who entrusted him... all in vain.
Naruto, switch with me!
There's something I want
to say to him.
Sorry, but your words
don't apply to this guy.
Is that Nine-Tails?
The Fourth Hokage entrusted him
with me.
Not only has Naruto
befriended me...
but he's completely mastered
my power as well!
The Fourth Hokage sealed me
within Naruto
as a force to help take you down.
Go... Naruto.
You won't fail!
Yeah!
That power again, huh?
Kakashi, we ought to—!
That man, he couldn't be...
I've got a pretty good idea
of what you're thinking right now.
I feel the same way...
But leave it be.
There's no time to wallow
in sentimentality.
Your former subordinate, Naruto,
has already jumped into action!
How stupid, jumping in alone!
Yo! Yo!
Damn it!
I'm not alone!
Don't forget Kurama!
There's also Octopops and Eight-Tails...
Bushier Brow-sensei!
And Kakashi-sensei too!
Naruto...
I'm glad you were
my subordinate!
Let's go... Guy!
My dear rival!
That's what I'm talking about!
Considering my remaining chakra...
I only have a few shots left.
I do not fear a borrowed power that
you can't even use in rapid succession.
The true power of Kamui...
This Kamui...
I will not miss...
– Now watch and learn!
– my timing!
Their knowing the trick to
my jutsu changes nothing.
If he has to materialize
when he takes things in,
he has to do so when
he spits things out too!
This is our chance!
That's if you can counterstrike!
What is this?
Naruto!
These have Curse Marks on them
that restrain Tailed Beast power.
Whatever you do, don't touch it!
Octopops!
Could you shield me for a bit?
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
All right, come here!
I'll be your umbrella!
Kamui!
If it's that same trick again,
all I need to do is not have
Naruto slip through me.
What? A Shadow Clone?
Kakashi!
Seems my attack was
quicker than you, Kakashi.
You missed transporting away
the Rasengan...
... and wasted another Kamui.
Not yet!
Tailed Beast Bomb!
A bit late. How futile.
You're—!
Naruto Uzumaki!
I see, so that Kamui just now
wasn't transporting the Rasengan,
but the Shadow Clone itself!
He beat me to it...
Damn you, Kakashi!
Who...
Damn it!
... are you?!
Whatever the village
or anyone else may say...
I think that you're a great Jonin...
It's true, that's how I feel.
Please accept this...
There's no mistake.
That's Obito Uchiha...
You can call me by
that name if you want.
It means nothing to me.
Who is he?
He was our classmate and
an Uchiha who was a Leaf shinobi.
We all thought he was killed
in action during the last war.
If you survived, why didn't you
come forward sooner?
It's irrelevant whether
I had survived or not.
Although, I suppose...
If you really want an answer...
It's because...
you let Rin...
die.
Relax...
Besides, what's with
that look, Kakashi?
You're not going to condemn me?
What would I gain from criticizing
this absurd reality at this point?
I have no interest in the affairs of a
world that shall soon cease to exist.
Kakashi-sensei!
I don't know what went down
between you two,
but this is no time to be depressed!
We can discuss it later!
Right now, stopping what this guy
is trying to do comes first!
Naruto!
Kakashi! Naruto is absolutely right!
The fate of this world currently
rests in our hands!
I have nothing more
to talk to you about.
Stay tied down to reality and die...
Fire Style:
Bomb Blast Dance!
The Nine-Tails' tail, huh?
Huh? What the—?!
Looks like you're having fun
over here...
Obito.
That's...
It's just like you... to have defied
the Reanimation Jutsu.
More importantly,
what's taking so long?
Why? Why is that Madara over here?
He's a Shadow Clone too...
Where's the real one, Obito?
What's happened to
everyone over there?
Brother...
He's over there, eh?
I asked you what happened?!
I'm not sure, but I suspect...
... that none of them are doing too well.
Summoning... Jutsu!
Lady Tsunade!
Katsuyu... Do something for me...
Yes! I'll reattach your body right away...
No...
My lower body can wait.
First...
Bring the other Kage... to me...
I... can... still save them.
Faster than the Curse Mark Chains
can wrap around!
I'll return that to you.
It's yours to begin with.
Finally, I can move!
Thanks, Naruto!
Now, it's my turn!
Obito, did you launch
the plan haphazardly
before you even took in
the Eight and Nine-Tails?
He knows about the plan...
What's their relationship?
You were hasty, Obito.
Is that also why I was revived
in this form?
Well, knowing you...
I'm sure you have something in mind.
What have you been up to
all this time?
Where's Nagato?
You were supposed to determine
the appropriate moment
and bring me back to life
with Rinne Rebirth.
That was the agreement.
He betrayed us.
He used the jutsu to revive
the Leaf villagers.
I can't depend on any of you.
Well, no matter...
It's still not too late.
I'll capture the Eight and Nine-Tails!
Dead men shouldn't go around
messing things up!
Huh?!
It didn't explode?!
Uchiha Reflection.
I'll get the Eight and Nine-Tails.
Obito, you take down those two.
Obito...
What happened to you?
Why would you join up with him?
Am I... dead?
Where am I?
In between this life and the next...
young Uchiha.
Those eyes!
No way, Gramps...
You're an Uchiha too?
Well, perhaps.
He rescued me?
But wait...
You said we're between
this life and the next.
Where are we?
It's dark and I can't see so well.
Anyway, who are you, Gramps?
Heh! Don't tell me you're Death!
The guy who escorts people
to heaven or hell...
Nooo!
I don't want to die yet! Help!
I just saw a scythe or something!
You're Death for sure!
One especially for the Uchiha!
Wait! I lived my life by the motto
of helping the elderly in need!
Sure, I caused a lot of mischief
and broke a lot of rules...
But I'm sure my scale tips
on the positive side!
Please don't take me to hell!
Oww...
The fact that you feel pain
means you're still alive.
However, it's a miracle
that you survived.
I'm amazed you weren't completely
crushed under those boulders.
It's almost as if you passed
right through them.
Where did you find me?
In an underground passageway
I had created...
collapsed next to crumbled rock.
Still, half your body
had been crushed.
I patched you up as best I could.
So you saved me, Gramps.
Thank you.
It's too soon to thank me.
I expect you to repay
your debt to me.
After all, helping the elderly
is your motto, right?
Well, yeah.
So what do you want me to do?
Help you with bathroom stuff?
That would be good.
Sorry, but I can't stay here forever!
Now that I know I'm alive,
I'm going back home to
the Hidden Leaf Village.
There's a war going on.
My Sharingan's finally
awakened...
So now, I'll be able to protect
my comrades even better!
Protect your comrades better, eh...?
What is it?
With that body...
your life as a shinobi is over.
No, no, no!
Finally... I finally got this eye!
I'm confident my attack combinations
will be better now!
Wake up to reality.
Nothing ever goes as
planned in this world.
The longer you live,
the more you realize that
only pain, suffering,
and futility exist in this reality.
What's with this old man...?
Listen to me...
In this world, wherever there is light,
there are always shadows.
As long as there is
a concept of victors,
the vanquished will also exist.
The selfish desire for peace
gives rise to war.
And hatred is born in order
to protect love.
These are all nexuses,
causal relationships that
cannot be separated.
Normally, that is.
The old man's on a roll...
Old people ramble forever
once they start.
So... where are we anyway?
Because you were hurt,
someone else was saved.
Isn't that so?
Shut up already!
I don't want to stay here long!
I have to...
Leave if you really want to.
If you can move, that is.
Wait a minute...
There's something weird
about this.
What's an old man with the Sharingan
doing here all by himself?
If I think about it,
I know all the old folks
in the Hidden Leaf Village.
and if I've never seen him around...
It means this guy is currently
not a Leaf shinobi.
Which means...
Gramps... I bet...
you're a rogue ninja, aren't you?
Just who are you?!
I am... an Uchiha ghost.
I am Madara Uchiha.
M-Madara...?!
By Madara...
You mean Madara Uchiha,
as in my ancestor?!
That Madara's supposed to
have died ages ago!
What era are we talking about?!
So you're more likely to
believe that I'm Death?
I guess I am Death, in a sense...
For this reality, truly is hell.
I'm a cheater of death who
would be dead in no time...
if I weren't continuously
siphoning chakra
from that Gedo Statue behind me.
I'm going home!
I wouldn't bother.
There are no exits here.
In any case, neither you
nor I can leave this place.
At least, not with our bodies.
If you move, the synthetic tissue
of Hashirama
that I went to the trouble of
attaching to you will peel off.
Do you want to die?
There are a lot of things
I'd like you to do for me,
for the rest of our lives.
I went to great pains to save you.
Don't rush to your death.
What do you want?
What does a geezer like you want
from a brat like me?!
To sever the fate of this world.
A world of only victors...
a world of only peace...
a world of only love.
I will create such a world.
So what! Who cares!
I just want to go back to everyone!
I told you, things don't go
as planned.
You will realize that in time.
If you really want to die so badly,
then go ahead.
But I'll be taking that Sharingan
of yours.
Why do you want my eye?!
You already have
your own Sharingan!
Actually, I gave my original eyes
to someone else.
These are merely spares
I transplanted later.
I'd like to have a few more in stock...
Since I don't have a right eye yet.
And only with two together can
the Sharingan's true power be unleashed.
Then... that means...
If I team up with Kakashi,
we'll both be even stronger.
Then we'll be able to
protect Rin properly, together!
I definitely can't stay here.
Just you wait... Kakashi... Rin!
I'm...
alive!
Hey there.
How are you doing?
Bad... What do you think?
How long have I been here?
It feels like it's been a while.
Don't worry,
you don't need to pay rent.
Those of us created from
the Gedo Statue don't have to eat either.
No food bills,
no need for a bathroom.
We don't even poo!
Don't lump me in with you guys!
I just have half of that weird stuff
stuck onto me.
And thanks to that, you can survive
without eating or drinking.
In fact, you should be grateful
and thank us.
Good grief. We're the ones who don't want
to be lumped in with you!
What you have is
emotionless synth-tissue.
We are full artificial humans.
We have feelings and everything!
You may have a better sense of humor,
but what we have is much better!
Both our vocabulary skills and
mental acuity are far higher than yours!
But we don't poo...
Shut up!
All right, explain how you're at
a higher level than I am!
We are...
The ones...
– in charge of watching you!
Don't talk in synch!
That pisses me off!
We're only helping you
with your rehab
because Madara ordered us
to get you up and running
and usable by the time he wakes up.
So he makes these noisy puppets
keep an eye on me...
while he gets to sleep
the whole time?
I swear I'm going to get outta here
and return to Rin and Kakashi!
Where's the exit?
Can't be done... there's no exit.
Madara sealed it off
with a huge boulder...
after we lugged you here
on his orders.
What?! He sealed us in?!
By the way, you've been saying
"Rin-Rin-Rin" in your sleep a lot.
Do you want to go outside to
get a bell or something?
Once in a while,
you said "stupid-stupid-stupid.”
And "stupid Kakashi."
Yeah, yeah, that's right!
Every so often.
What's a "stupid Kakashi"?
Beats me. Why don't you ask him?
Was I really saying that?
Um, may we ask you a question!
What?
When nature calls...
In short, what does the urge
to poo feel like?
For example...
I thought you wanted to know
about stupid Kakashi!
Why are you guys so obsessed
with poop?
You don't have to get so angry.
All right, we'll ask you about
Rin and stupid Kakashi later.
Especially you, with the swirly face...
You don't poop,
but you look like poop.
I hate you!
Anyway, where'd the other white guys go?
They went outside to collect intel.
What?! You guys can get out?
It's because we can move
through the ground.
What the hell?!
I'm locked up in here,
and I have to hear about all
this weird stuff.
So sorry to have bothered you
about poo!
That's not what I meant!
I mean, what Madara talked about!
Something about severing fate
and all...
Oh, that...
Madara's not nice enough to talk
to a brat at his level.
Simply put, he's talking about discarding
all the bad things in the real world and
escaping inside a dream
that's full of good things!
Inside a dream?
Since it's a dream,
everything is how you want it!
Even those who are dead
can be alive again!
Yeah...
Just think of it as all of us going
to this huge dream world
that was created using genjutsu!
Well, it's more like forcibly
taking everyone there...
and for life too.
With genjutsu?
That's so beyond stupid,
I can't even understand it.
If you have as much power as Madara,
anything is possible.
It's just that he's weak right now
and can't do it yet.
Much still needs to be prepared.
Oh really? Well, I'm not interested.
More importantly...
I swear I'm going to make it outside!
And get back to Rin and Kakashi!
What?
I've got to get this body working again...
Yaaaay!
What?!
Don't act tough and hide your wounds!
I'm always watching, you know.
It's starting to feel natural.
Just a bit longer.
I'll see you soon, Rin... Kakashi!
I was just outside!
Your friends, Rin and
stupid Kakashi, are in trouble!
What happened?!
They're alone and completely
surrounded by Hidden Mist shinobi!
You can't break through boulders
with that body yet.
I have to save Rin and Kakashi...
Why don't you wear my body?
But you guys serve Madara.
Are you sure about this?
He's... a good boy.
Don't you want to help
Rin and Kakashi?
Thanks, you guys!
You stayed connected to the statue and
borrowed its power? Nice.
I'm pretty good, huh?
All right!
So you're going?
I'm grateful that you saved me.
But I'm leaving. I have to go.
You're being too hasty...
It may be premature to thank me.
I'll probably never come back here.
I've given my thanks.
I'm going!
You... will return.
And that's when I'll get
your true gratitude.
White one!
What's Rin and Kakashi's location?!
Take me there right away!
What you've got on your body
is like a clone of me.
And we can talk telepathically to
each other over limited distances.
Others of us are scattered
here and there underground.
We're able to exchange intel.
I'll use them to guide you.
Swirly!
First, we need to get outside.
I'm counting on you.
How are Rin and Kakashi
doing right now?
From what the others are saying,
it looks pretty bad.
They're talking about some Hidden Mist test
subjects, but I don't really understand.
Test subjects?
Anyway, it seems Rin and Kakashi
are totally surrounded.
And they're saying they all appear
to be Jonin or Black Ops.
What's Minato-sensei doing?
Who is that?
I'm asking you what the Yellow Flash
of the Leaf is doing!
Seems he's on a different mission.
At a time like this?!
Kakashi! You made me a promise!
Please...
Please protect Rin somehow!
I'll be right there!
Obito, this will probably turn
into a battle.
So I want to tell you
some things beforehand.
What is it?!
Your fighting ability is lower
than mine.
Plus right now, it's like my big body
is wrapped around
and protecting
your wounded little body.
So what?!
I think it would be better
if I do all the fighting.
Remember what Madara said?
That only with a pair together can the
Sharingan's true power be unleashed!
Kakashi, the other half of my pair,
will be on the battlefield.
Our combo attacks are superior!
Kakashi and I will protect Rin!
As I recall, you do have
Hashirama's tissue attached to you.
A whole different strength may emerge
when Senju and Uchiha powers
are combined together, but...
What was that?
I thought it was rain, but it's...
I just got word from one of my guys.
It seems...
That's the location.
Let's go!
What's happening?!
Stop showing these weird images!
A little bit...
Just a little bit farther!
Kakashi...
Damn it! He did it!
After all the trouble
we went through to get her!
Rin...
Where...
in the world...
is this place?!
Who is that guy?
Reinforcements maybe?
What a fool, jumping in alone!
I won't accept it!
I will not...
What just happened?!
Did he dodge them?
... accept any of this!
Do not mock the Blood Mist Village!
Die!
I can't hit him!
Who is that guy?!
He wields a strange jutsu!
At least grab the girl!
Don't hand her corpse over
to the enemy!
There's no mistake!
This guy passes right through you!
All of a sudden,
he's able to use
the Wood Style Cutting Sprigs Jutsu...
Obito, now I understand
why Madara chose you!
What is he?
I get it...
I'm...
in Hell.
The longer you live...
the more you realize
that only pain, suffering,
and futility exist in this reality.
Listen to me...
In this world,
wherever there is light,
there are always shadows.
These are all nexuses,
causal relationships
that cannot be separated.
Normally, that is.
He's talking about discarding all
the bad things in the real world
and escaping inside a dream
that's full of good things!
Since it's a dream,
everything is how you want it!
Even those who are dead
can be alive again!
A world of only victors...
a world of only peace...
a world of only love.
I will create such a world.
Again, Rin...
I'll create a world where
we can be together again.
I shall sever the nexuses...
of this world...
That's why I've come back.
I hope no one saw you.
I'm the only one who saw him.
Obito slaughtered everyone,
so we're safe.
He didn't seem to want
to kill Kakashi though.
But Kakashi didn't see anything.
When reinforcements from
the Hidden Leaf arrived,
he was screaming,
"Who killed the enemy?!"
So you still felt loyalty to
your one-time teammate?
No, it doesn't matter
to me anymore
whether he's alive or
dead in this world.
Kakashi will exist
in the world we'll create.
Rin too...
Madara, teach me how to create
this world of dreams.
I don't need
your thanks anymore.
Come here.
Starting today,
you will be the savior.
Look into my eye.
You are inside my genjutsu.
It's still a blank canvas,
but I can project my will upon it
to create whatever I want.
And even control them.
Anything is possible,
since I'm linked to, and borrowing,
the power of the Gedo Statue.
Like this, see?
We'll use this genjutsu
to create the ideal world.
And then, we'll cast the genjutsu
on everyone and bring them here.
The scale of this jutsu
is accomplished
by projecting it off the moon instead
of our eyes.
So that an entire world of dreams
is achieved.
You make it sound so simple,
but I still don't quite get it.
Let me explain,
starting with the Sage of Six Paths
and Ten-Tails.
Isn't the Ten-Tails just a legend?
Legends are always derived
from something real.
The Tailed Beasts
that roam the world...
resulted when
the Sage of the Six Paths
split up the power
of the Ten-Tails.
Do you have proof
that story is true?!
I do.
After I obtained the cells
of Hashirama Senju,
I implanted them into my wound.
At that time, nothing happened...
It was only when I was starting
to die of old age...
that my Rinnegan awakened.
And it simultaneously led
to the undoing of a certain seal.
I was then able to summon,
and extract,
the husk of the Ten-Tails
from a Sealing Stone.
The Ten-Tails' husk?
I call it the Gedo Statue.
And the Seal Stone is
what we know as the moon.
Immediately, I used the statue's body
as a catalyst
to culture Hashirama's cells
into what you see before you.
One could say that these artificial beings
are clones of Hashirama.
Although they are reduced in quality.
The Rinnegan cannot be awakened
without the possessing
both Uchiha and Senju powers.
And the statue cannot
be controlled easily.
You have Senju cells attached
to the right half of you.
Even if you never awaken
the Rinnegan,
you should be able to
eventually control the statue.
Did you see them?
That redhead's eyes?
So they're Madara's Rinnegan, huh...
They're Madara's actual eyes.
When that kid was younger...
he secretly transplanted them
without anyone noticing!
Nagato is of Senju bloodline.
And the only other person
in addition to Madara
who can summon the Gedo Statue.
As Madara said,
first, we win him over and...
Huh?! What are you going to do?
I'm going straight for him.
H-Hey, shouldn't you plan
a strategy first?
I don't need to do that.
Obito...
I shall teach you the Uchiha
Forbidden Jutsu, the Six Paths Jutsu.
And the Yin and Yang Style Jutsu.
I've implanted my will
inside this one...
Think of him as being half of me.
Though he'll be degraded too.
You can use these beings
that I created
using Shadow and Light
Style Jutsu as your soldiers.
That Black Rod was created
as a physical manifestation of my will.
Use it when you perform
the Six Paths Jutsu...
Now, go on...
Until the time when I will be revived...
You shall be...
Who are you?
I am Madara Uchiha.
You're either a criminal
or a total idiot
to claim Uchiha Madara's name.
Why'd you approach us?
The Rinnegan...
To guide those who awaken it,
is the mission
our organization has been
entrusted with since ages past.
You know about my eyes?
You are the reincarnation
of the Sage of Six Paths,
who dreamed of world peace
and stability.
Only the villages of large nations
are showered in light.
Leaving your small country's village
in the shadow, dying.
That is why your eye
has awakened here.
Wherever light strikes,
there are always shadows.
So long as there is
a concept of victors...
the vanquished will also similarly exist.
The selfish intent of wanting
to preserve peace initiates wars.
And hatred is born in order
to protect love.
These are all nexuses, causal
relationships that cannot be separated.
Normally, that is.
But a world of just victors,
peace and love...
such a world can be created too.
If you allow us to collaborate,
you can learn how.
As soon as you attain
the true power of the Rinnegan...
Your very own world can
be immediately actualized.
Now...
I can't do that.
You're just trying to use us.
Your offer sounds way
too convenient.
One can only reach
the true world
after knowing another's pain
and shedding tears alongside them.
Shedding tears alongside them, huh?
You mean in revenge?
No, that's not what I meant.
I meant in mutual understanding.
Stop talking so idealistically.
No such thing exists
in this world.
Let's go, Konan... Nagato.
We can't trust these guys!
Don't you dare approach us again!
I'll wait here at
the same time every day.
You'll eventually realize it too.
We finally made it up to this point.
Nagato.
You're—!
Reality is moving ahead quickly.
Cut your ties with Yahiko immediately
and join me.
Otherwise, you will all...
We will what?
What Yahiko speaks of
are just ideals.
He tries to understand others' pain... but
they do not even attempt to know our pain.
Furthermore, this world has
no desire for that either.
That is reality.
You possess the Rinnegan,
so you should understand.
No matter what you say,
I believe in Yahiko's ideals!
I guess without pain...
you cannot experience reality.
In that respect, even though
you possess the Rinnegan,
you still think like
an average person.
Very well...
Go see reality for yourself,
and experience pain.
There you are, Nagato.
Yahiko...
Was someone just here?
No...
Let's get going.
Or we'll be late for the meeting
with Lord Hanzo.
Right, let's go!
Oww!
What's the big idea?
I was having a nice nap!
What?
Hey! Where'd Brothers Yahiko
and Nagato go?!
I think they left already.
The meeting with Hanzo is today.
Wake the guys up!
We have to catch up with them!
What's wrong?
I'll tell you later!
What's going on anyway?
We just received word from a
member of the Hidden Leaf border team.
The Leaf's ANBU Black Ops are
on their way to Hanzo's as well.
The Leaf's ANBU?
Why are they going to Hanzo's?
I don't know the specifics.
But I just don't like the timing
of it all, you know?
And when you think about it...
this thing with Hanzo just sounds
too good to be true.
Then that means...
today's meeting with Hanzo is...
Whatever it is,
we need to let Brothers know!
As much as I regret it,
I can't let you go any further.
Who are you?!
My name is Madara Uchiha...
Damn you! Did Hanzo send you?
I don't work for Hanzo.
But I can't let you interfere right now.
I want Nagato to see
what reality is.
We don't have time for
your nonsense.
Kill them!
You take care of the weaklings.
You sure like to order me around!
I'm Kyusuke the Swift!
Don't underestimate my speed!
I slipped right through him?
What's going on?!
Kyusuke!
You bastards!
Why... are you... doing this?
I'm going to awaken Nagato's Rinnegan
in the truest sense possible.
What are you talking about?
There is no such thing as peace
in this accursed world.
Nagato must abandon this dream
and set out into a new world.
I'm not going to let you!
Daibutsu!
Now! Go right through me!
Hurry!
I'll see you in the next world!
The Water Prison Jutsu?
You can't beat me with a jutsu like this!
This is no ordinary Water Prison.
This is cement!
For the first time in
my dismal life as a war orphan...
I found hope in the Akatsuki!
You think... I'd let some bastard
like you take that away?!
He's sacrificing his life
in this attack...
But, as expected,
we're literally in different dimensions.
No way!
Kyusuke...
Your death will not be...
Owww...
The surface hardened...
and I shed the layer, but it stings!
Sorry, but this is the end for all of you.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Come, we have to hurry!
We have to witness Nagato's destiny!
Konan...
Yahi—
Summoning Jutsu!
Gedo Statue!
There it is!
So he summoned it.
It's the Ten-Tails' husk...
What... is that?!
Nagato... No! Don't use that!
We're dead if that touches us!
Nagato, Yahiko, Konan...
The world of dreams...
I shall let you see each other there...
without fail.
I'm sorry I haven't been by.
It's not that I've forgotten...
I've been... sworn to secrecy...
but Minato-sensei is going
to be a father.
This generation won't know war.
If only we were born a little later...
I should tell Obito too.
So I'll be going, Rin.
Summoning Jutsu!
Minato-sensei...
All of this...
This world...
- None of it matters anymore!
I'm not going to let
that happen, idiot!
I'm the son of
the Fourth Hokage, you know!
I'm not going to fall for your talk!
I see.
I was going easy on you because you
were the actual Jinchuriki, not a clone.
But if that's how you feel,
I won't hold back on you!
This is Hashirama's Wood Dragon, which he
used to bind the Nine-Tails long ago.
Madara really is crazy powerful.
That's what makes him
worth fighting.
You're pretty good at acting tough.
I'm not going to hold back
against a zombie either!
Since you're already dead!
Why?!
Why ally yourself with someone
like Madara?
I've got nothing to say to you.
All that's left...
is this final battle!
Earth Style: Mud Wall!
Why?
How about shutting up already?
You're only talk.
You're nothing but a piece of trash.
I believe that the White Fang
was a true hero.
Sure, in the world of ninja,
one who breaks
the rules and regulations
is regarded as trash.
But those who abandon
their comrades...
are worse than trash!
I am trash for sure...
But Obito, you've always...
Kamui...
... been my hero.
So why?
Damn it!
That damned wooden thing!
It's absorbing
the Nine-Tails' chakra!
We have the same eyes...
So you made it out, huh?
Obito, how did you end up like this?
I said, trash should keep
their mouths shut!
Die.
I... couldn't keep
my promise to you.
You're right. I'm trash.
But you...
You're a hero of the Leaf.
There's no reason for you
to become trash too.
This is reality.
Those who leave things behind,
and those left behind... both.
All shinobi who survive
in this world become trash.
You and I are prime examples,
Kakashi.
No one can escape the cycle
that gives birth to trash in this world.
That's why I intend
to remake the world!
You guys make me so mad,
I can't even think straight.
So instead, let me tell you
something about myself.
I'm not trash!
I'm not planning on
becoming trash either!
I will...
stop you!
- I'll never let my comrades die!
I'll never let my comrades die!
I'm sorry, Naruto.
I'm the one who taught you
Obito's words, and yet...
I was about to waver again.
Hirudora!
Lightning Blade!
Guess it wasn't just a bluff.
Obito...
Your once strong will
is still alive today...
Right next to me!
What the current me can do
is protect the current Naruto!
You'll protect the current Naruto?
Same here...
They're both at their limits!
These Hidden Leaf guys
sure love to act tough!
The wood's constriction
is weakening.
Octopops!
Ow oww!
Be careful, Naruto!
The enemy's Wood Style binding
is identical to the First Hokage's!
It has the power to
bind Tailed Beast Power!
Like Captain Yamato's technique...
A Lightning Blade that relies
on the Sharingan...
You've mastered your left eye...
Even awakening the Mangekyo.
But can you make it back
from the other dimension
in your current condition?
Go back to the trash heap, Kakashi!
Kakashi-sensei...
is just like... me!
Looks like we're going to have to
start worrying about Ten-Tails.
Let them handle Obito.
Then we'll make our move!
Now I see it clearly...
your pained face.
Save those lines for
the one right next to you.
I definitely have to help
Kakashi-sensei somehow.
He's completely drained from
overusing the Sharingan.
If he gets sucked in...
Naruto, switch with me...
Huh?
Let me handle this.
But...
Don't argue. Just switch!
Hey, Kakashi, give me your hands.
You're...
Never mind that!
Just stick out your hands!
Kurama! What the hell did you just do?
Now you don't have any distractions.
I'm leaving the rest to you, Naruto.
What?!
Damn!
Now that we know how
your ability works, I can counter it.
Here's another!
Oh yeah, that certainly
is a pained face Obito.
What's going on?
Kakashi did that from the other side.
The difference between
you and me is...
I can give or take chakra at will.
I'll show you how it's done later.
When did you pass it to him?
When I grabbed his hand
to throw him.
So then...!
Yeah, whenever he wants to,
he can use Kamui to come out.
Kakashi-sensei!
Thank Nine-Tails for me.
Sure!
Let's blast him to bits
before he revives!
Put in everything you've got!
Right!
It's ready to go,
Octopops and Eight-Tails!
Okay!
Fire!
It's over now!
The Statue's chakra... is gone.
We did it.
We did it, fool! Ya fool!
All right then!
It's over?
Yeah... for this world.
Now then...
Shall we get started?