You're finally going out.
Well, there have been
a lot of changes to our plans.
I wish you wouldn't say it
like I'm to blame.
Thanks to you,
we had to change our strategy.
Thanks to me,
your military strength and strategic
options have increased, haven't they?
Don't do anything strange
while I'm away.
We're comrades.
You should trust me more.
You only look after
your own interests.
You won't even tell me
where you're off to?
The Hidden Rain Village.
The Hidden Rain?
They're not even directly involved
in the Great Ninja War,
so why are you going now?
It doesn't concern you.
What?!
Naruto's going through
harsh training like that?!
I can't ignore a young man struggling
in the springtime of his youth!
Take me to Naruto!
He... is a bit eccentric.
So I apologize.
It's all right.
All right!
What happened?
Did it go well?
A lot of things happened.
Yo!
I see! I get it!
Understood!
Your expression now is looking good!
What about the Nine-Tails?
Did you get it under control?
That's real good news.
Especially when you used it,
in that situation, yo!
Whoa, Naruto!
Don't tell me that by that, you mean...
You know what?!
Yup!
That's right, ya know!
So tell me what happened!
That's too abstract...
It makes no sense!
This is all on purpose!
You're talking like that on purpose!
That much I know!
Relax, Captain Yamato.
I have the Nine-Tails' chakra safe
in a separate place inside me.
So that I'm not using it all the time.
This is what it's like when I use
the Nine-Tails' chakra.
Amazing...
It's overflowing with life energy.
I can't believe my Wood Style
is reacting to it.
What?
You really think...
you're hidden?
Do you sense some other chakra?
He actually sensed it... his presence.
I noticed nothing... I'm so dense!
Impossible!
My chakra is the same as Samehada.
There's no way
anyone could sense it!
It's not chakra!
It feels hazy... something sinister.
That's it! That thing!
The sword?
It seems that you can sense hatred
and feelings of evil.
The limitations of sensory-types
don't apply.
Is that the power of a Jinchuriki
who has mastery
over the Nine-Tails?
You're the shark guy of the Akatsuki!
How? I thought we cut
his head off a while back...
How did you manage to escape
our tag-team attack?
I simply switched places while we
battled inside the sphere of water.
Don't you think you're overdoing it?
Don't you think that was
just right for the Eight-Tails?
I guess it's my turn now.
I leave it in your hands.
Clones disappear
when they're struck!
The corpse remained
post-mortem... no question.
And if someone else had
transformed into you,
Cee would have sensed it.
So it's a confusing situation.
It was a special kind of clone.
A Parasitic Clone that I can
manipulate remotely.
Anyway, enough about this subject.
Now then, two Jinchuriki
and a Wood Style user...
I am in a serious predicament.
What?
How did you know the way to
open the door to this room?!
That's a silly question.
I came here to spy.
That was Body Flicker Jutsu?
The first smash...
Just like the Yellow Flash!
So fast... I didn't expect that.
My foot!
I had so much force,
I hit it too hard!
It seems you're not up to
the Fourth Hokage's level yet.
Bee! Please go after him!
I'll see to Naruto.
Right! Leave the chase to me.
I'll catch him in a jiffy.
What?
Your true self appears from
inside the waterfall?
Is that for real?
Yes. Naruto faced and defeated
his true self at this very spot.
Guy, why don't you try it out
for yourself?
Don't be stupid!
We have to go and
help Naruto first!
I came here as a teacher
to protect Naruto!
Don't get so upset.
Are you afraid to face
your true self?
Is that it?
What did you say?
You think I'm scared?
No problem!
No, I was just joking.
I have a feeling
your true self isn't human.
Don't take me so seriously.
Honestly, you really shouldn't be
going on about "youth," should you?
Overdoing things can hurt
a man past his prime like you.
I know you have to keep up
appearances for Lee's sake.
But no one expects you to
force yourself to stay youthful.
Show yourself!
You can say what you like
to my face!
Fine.
You can take a long,
hard look at your true self.
Is this my true self?!
An Odd Beast?
I'm sure this is...
the Odd Beast!
Hey me! The one who has
forgotten what youth is!
I'll beat some sense into you!
Guy!
That's not your true self!
Leaf Rock...
Crushing Square!
It's not my true self.
Take a good look!
It's not you,
no matter how you look at it!
The moment you open your eyes,
you leave the Waterfall of Truth!
This is... I'm certain it's...
the fish they call puffer fish!
I see that you are still dumber
than a beast.
He's an Akatsuki agent!
If he escapes,
they'll get intel on us.
And that would be
a huge disgrace!
Damn you, Samehada...
I see, I see... He forced you.
That must've been pretty tough.
Hey, hey! Don't play too rough!
But what can I say,
I got the right stuff!
He's taking your chakra!
Guy! Please assist me!
I'm going to get data
from him instead!
Secret Jutsu: Stone Needles!
All right!
A jutsu where chakra is poured
in to stop my movement.
Now that's perfect!
Is he absorbing my chakra instead?
So much pull!
Leaf Hurricane!
I've gotten all my chakra back.
Water Style:
Shark Bomb Jutsu!
Damn it, he got away!
He's fast!
If he gets past the barrier
around this island, it's all over.
We must stop him before that,
because my sensory powers
won't work then.
I'll stop him!
The Eight Inner Gates!
The Sixth Gate of Joy: Open!
Let yourself be captured by
the arms of my Eight-Tails...
Odd Beast!
Far, far away you'll go...
In the direction of
ten o'clock I'll throw.
Don't sacrifice the truth just
for a rhyme!
He went towards two o'clock!
All right!
I'm counting on you!
I was going to say it's been a while...
but really, midair?
I'm going to borrow your back!
Looks like I gave them the slip.
Summoning Jutsu...
You're persistent!
So... That scroll you gave to that
shark contains intel on us.
I won't let you get away!
I wouldn't be so sure.
I have the geographical advantage.
Water Style:
A Thousand Hungry Sharks!
I don't know which shark is which.
In that case...!
Asakujaku!
Where's the scroll?
Damn it.
There are too many of them.
It can't be helped.
I have to cover a wider area.
He won't let the sharks
in the water go either.
Fine.
I'll just let them tear you apart!
The Seventh Gate of Shock!
Open!
I see...
A taijutsu that crushes opponents
with a shock wave
of air and flames created from
the friction of punched air!
An Odd Beast indeed.
A shinobi with taijutsu
this powerful is truly rare.
This will be the third time for me.
The next taijutsu will be nothing
like the previous ones.
It's a special single-blow attack.
It's something you'll rarely see...
The blue chakra is pushing
the water away.
Water Style:
Super Shark Bomb Jutsu!
Hirudora!
This Super Shark Bomb is
no ordinary jutsu.
The jutsu itself absorbs chakra
and becomes even stronger.
And the stronger the opponent's
ninjutsu, The stronger it gets.
What's going on?
I exhausted his jutsu...
but my Super Shark Bomb
isn't getting stronger?!
I know I absorbed his chakra!
Was that not
a chakra Energy Bomb?!
Roar, my youth!
What is that?
That's...
Guy's Eight Inner Gates attack...
Hirudora!
Hirudora? That's a lame name
for a jutsu.
Considering Guy-sensei's obsession
with youth.
There's no time to nitpick!
The Hirudora has a wide blast radius,
and it hits instantly.
Brace yourselves!
Don't move.
That jutsu...
It wasn't an Energy Bomb, was it?
And your blue aura...
Hirudora is not
a chakra-based ninjutsu.
It is taijutsu.
It's just an ordinary punch,
but it's a super fast punch.
A focused thrust of air pressure
right at your opponent.
That compresses
and spreads in an instant.
And this aura that envelops me
is not chakra...
Those who open
the Seventh Gate of Shock,
perspire blue sweat!
That is what's evaporating
from the heat of my passion!
I thought that looked too small
to be an Energy Bomb.
This is my third time fighting you.
But you still had something
like this up your sleeve.
You probably don't remember me.
I thought I told you not to move.
I got to hand it to
Bushier Brow-sensei
for bringing this guy down!
If this goes well,
I'll be able to extract intel
about Akatsuki and its plans,
as well as the identity of its leader.
I'm not as good as Inoichi,
but I'll give it a try.
Here I go.
Now then...
Here comes the hard part...
Hoshigaki...
Won't you eat with us?
There's no need to be nice to me.
Hey, you heard him.
Just leave him alone!
He doesn't like to rub shoulders
with Intel Division geeks like us.
Run!
Surrender!
You're completely surrounded.
There's no way you can win.
I know you.
You're that brilliant guy from
the Leaf ANBU's Torture and
Interrogation Corps...
Want to fight?
Now's our chance. Run!
Hoshigaki, what do we do?
Hoshigaki?
Wh-What are you doing?!
However...
You must not allow any member of the
Cipher Corps to fall into enemy hands.
Your mission is to guard the code,
whatever it takes.
Do you understand
what that means?
Yes, I do.
I shall not hand over any of
the Cipher Corps shinobi alive.
Why?
Because killing my comrades
is my special mission.
What a terrible life...
Your comrades... why?
Why?
You, of all people, should understand.
We cannot let our code fall
into enemy hands.
Besides, they would have
talked right away.
If we both survive,
let's meet again.
Kisame... You...!
Good work, Kisame.
I had a feeling he would let his guard
down with his subordinate.
And I was right.
He was collaborating
with the enemy.
From this moment on,
you are the master of
the great blade, Samehada.
And my subordinate as well.
That is, until you eliminate me too,
Lord Fourth Mizukage.
I can trust you because
of who you are.
You have executed dirty missions
for the sake of the nation and village.
You've undertaken missions
of betrayal.
You are well aware that this world
is full of lies and deceit.
I knew that from the first moment
I killed a comrade.
Killing a Hidden Mist ninja
despite being one myself.
So what am I?
Am I an enemy or an ally?
What is my purpose?
Where do I stand in this world?
Where must I go?
And where can I go to find inner calm?
There is one thing that is clear to
me... I am trapped in a false existence.
Then I shall release you from
the pain of those falsehoods.
I will create a place
where you belong.
Who are you?
First, we'll start with this nation.
You have toiled to dispose
of your comrades up until now.
From now on, work with me
as my comrade.
You seem to have trust in me.
But I still don't know who you are.
Those eyes...
that gleam in the dark!
I see...
The one I thought was
the Fourth Mizukage...
was actually you.
To think the Fourth was being
manipulated by the Sharingan.
This world really is full of lies.
To manipulate the Fourth,
the Three-Tails Jinchuriki...
...that is some ocular power.
Just who are you?
I am... Madara Uchiha.
He is supposed to be dead.
I don't believe you.
Show yourself.
Fine.
You can decide whether
to trust me or not.
His tongue...
He bit off his own tongue!
He woke himself up to prevent me
from extracting intel.
Are you serious?
Yes... That is my plan...
Project Tsuki no Me.
That is a true world free of lies.
I would have liked to see that...
I was using my Wood Style
to suppress his chakra,
but he still has so much power left.
He just doesn't know
when to give up.
Capture him alive!
We'll never have
another chance like this!
I want to extract
more intel from him!
I know that!
Water Prison Jutsu!
I can't reach him because
of this wall of water!
Summoning Jutsu!
Itachi... It's just like you said.
I'll be teaming up with you
from now on.
I'm Kisame Hoshigaki,
formerly of the Hidden Mist,
and an ex-member of
the Seven Ninja Swordsmen.
Pleased to meet you.
And you are Itachi Uchiha,
formerly of the Hidden Leaf.
I've heard the rumors...
You slaughtered all of
your fellow Uchiha clansmen.
I understand you well.
That's the reason why I decided to
team up with the Akatsuki.
The sensation that comes from killing your
comrade is indescribable, isn't it, Itachi?
You talk a lot.
You may know a lot about me,
but what about yourself?
You got lost in the mist
and ended up here.
You're just a thug who
couldn't figure out where to go.
Isn't that so?
Do you want to know
something interesting?
Some sharks are ovoviviparous,
which means the eggs
hatch inside the
female's body, then are born.
However, with some kinds of sharks,
the number of eggs that hatch
don't match up with
the number of pups born.
Do you know why?
Cannibalism.
When the eggs hatch,
the pups resort to
cannibalizing their siblings
in the mother's stomach.
From the moment they're born,
the fratricide begins.
Other than itself,
every other pup is fodder.
From today, you and I
belong to Akatsuki.
Please be wary...
of me.
That goes for you too...
Anyway, let's have some fun together.
And hope that we're not
the last two facing each other.
Anyone who has raised
their hand against a comrade,
even once,
never dies a decent death.
Remember that.
Which means you and I
are both worthless.
No...
We aren't fish, we're human.
No matter who you are...
You do not know what kind of human
you are until the very end.
One realizes their true nature
at the moment of death.
That's the way to view death.
Itachi...
Did you realize
the kind of person you were...
at the moment of your death?
Itachi...
It seems I wasn't such...
a worthless human, after all.
Feeding yourself to the shark
you just summoned...
He was already quite weak.
He figured out that
he couldn't escape us.
The Akatsuki member who was
paired up with Itachi himself...
The one who was feared as
the scourge of the Hidden Mist.
It's hard to believe this is
the way Kisame Hoshigaki met his end.
Is he really dead?
This fella's downhearted
Looks like it's for real this time.
The guy's already departed.
But...
He did this so that we, his enemy,
wouldn't get any intel.
Even in the Akatsuki,
there was someone
who put his comrades first.
He may have been a foe,
but he died admirably.
The measure of a shinobi's life
is determined
by the manner of his death.
Kisame Hoshigaki!
I shall remember you
for the rest of my life!
In any case, no intel was leaked
to the Akatsuki.
He intended to put down intel about
us onto this scroll and get out of here.
Let's check the contents
of the scroll.
If we know what kind of data
he was after,
it will make
counter-intelligence easier.
You're right.
The water is so heavy...
This is the Water Prison Jutsu!
It was a booby trap!
Watch out!
Sharks!
Damn, it's making its way
towards the ocean!
The water pressure is making it
hard to move!
Fools, ya fool!
I used up all my strength
on the Eight Inner Gates...
Guy, hang in there!
Watch where you're biting!
Damn it! It's getting away!
What do we do?!
Looking for something?
Yeah.
Where have you hidden Nagato's body?
You won't find him here.
Rinnegan...
It seems you aren't going
to cooperate
and tell me where you hid Nagato.
I knew that you would
appear before me.
I've been waiting for you.
So I could stop you.
Just because you used to be a comrade
does not mean I'll show you any mercy.
The Akatsuki does not
put up with traitors.
Understand?
I have one question.
Why would such loyal members
as you both betray me?
You and Nagato both approved
of my Project Tsuki no Me.
Naruto Uzumaki...
You think he's that worthy?
He is the light.
That's why we...
will make the flowers of hope bloom!
You bare your fangs at me, yet
you still continue to wear that cloak.
I see that you are still attached
to the Akatsuki.
Yahiko founded the Akatsuki.
The red cloud on this cloak
symbolizes the blood
that rained over
the Hidden Rain from war!
You merely latched onto the Akatsuki.
These cloaks represent our justice,
not yours.
Furthermore, Nagato,
a shinobi of the Hidden Rain,
awakened the Rinnegan.
And that too, does not belong to you.
His eyes are this nation's...
this village's treasure!
You are mistaken on two points.
It's all over for you anyway,
so I will tell you.
I am the one who encouraged Yahiko
to establish the Akatsuki.
And I was also the one
who gave Nagato the Rinnegan.
So it's only right for me
to ask for it back.
Well, no matter.
As far as I'm concerned, you're
just a girl who knows nothing.
Except that, right now,
you know where Nagato's Rinnegan is.
Once I capture you,
I can do anything I want.
Do not underestimate
the visual prowess of the Uchiha, girl!
Using a manifold attack,
she intends to find a chance
to attack when I materialize.
Fine. I know she has
some strategy to tempt me.
I accept her challenge!
Over here!
She mixed in paper bombs!
I will take you with me
to the afterlife.
I didn't take you seriously enough.
I should have remembered that you
are a former member of the Akatsuki...
The moment I sucked you in,
you intended to blow yourself up,
and take me with you.
However, you failed.
I sucked in the explosion itself.
I was faster, although I felt
a little of the impact.
And luckily, you were spared too.
You should be grateful.
Does this mean
your secret strategy is over?
Madara, let me ask you one thing.
What is it?
Do you know why we betrayed you?
Do you know why
we have faith in Naruto?
Well now... That's your problem.
Besides, Naruto is just a naïve
child chasing after an immature dream.
I can see if Nagato was swayed
by the thought of true peace
and hope.
But you too, Konan?
I realized something
after meeting Naruto.
You are darkness.
Flowers can only wilt in
a world without light!
I won't let you get away!
Your teleportation failed.
I've been paying attention
to you all this time.
When you suck in yourself,
you always materialize yourself.
And it takes longer to suck yourself in
than another person or object.
If I didn't stop teleporting and shift
to the side to evade the explosion,
things would've turned nasty.
Furthermore, you are only able
to pass through objects
for five minutes!
What are these?
They're all paper bombs...
I amassed 600 billion paper bombs
in order to kill you...
And they will continue
exploding for ten minutes!
I am the one who encouraged Yahiko
to establish the Akatsuki.
And I was also the one who
gave Nagato the Rinnegan.
Both Yahiko and Nagato were
acting on their own free will.
They were not your pawns!
You and Konan must do
everything you can to survive!
Whichever way they chose...
They both fought and died
following their beliefs!
That is why their will is connected!
I will not let you interfere!
My Sacred Paper Emissary Jutsu
has come undone.
I didn't expect it to take
this much chakra.
At least...
Madara is...
... Is dead?
How? You should be dead.
I ran the simulations over and over.
I was sure this sequence
would work.
The Izanagi...
In exchange for losing sight
in that eye,
a user can connect illusion
and reality.
It's a Forbidden Jutsu
of the Uchiha.
Only those who
possess both the powers
of the Uchiha and Senju
can use this Forbidden Jutsu!
Uchiha and Senju?
Both powers?
But that's the power
of the Six Paths.
You do not have that power...
Since you are a former comrade of mine,
I will tell you a little about
my jutsu and myself.
The Izanagi is simply
the practical application
of what you already know as the
Sage of Six Paths' Creation of all Things.
Originally, the Uchiha and Senju
were one and the same.
The Sage of the Six Paths
was their founder
and he passed on his blood
and power to these two.
He also created many things.
With the power of Yin Style, based upon
spiritual energy that governs imagination
... he created form out of nothingness.
And with the power of Yang Style,
based upon physical energy
that governs life...
... he breathed life into those forms.
The Tailed Beasts are
one such example.
He used the powers of Yin and Yang
to create the Tailed Beasts from
the chakra of the Ten-Tails.
The incarnation of imagination
into life...
that is the jutsu known as Izanagi.
Just who are you?
The world knows Madara Uchiha was
the one who lost to Hashirama Senju.
However, what is the real truth?
The victor is the one
who can gaze into the future.
The real challenge begins from now.
The previous battle was merely
to obtain his power.
I am Madara Uchiha, and I possess
the power of Hashirama Senju.
I am the second Sage of
the Six Paths. I am unique.
Unable to master Hashirama's power,
some have tried to use
an imperfect Izanagi, and failed.
In the afterlife,
the two of you can commiserate...
about being fooled
by Naruto's nonsense.
There is no such thing
as true peace!
There is no such thing as hope!
Nagato only believed in Naruto
because he wanted
to find solace within
his pathetic existence.
This can't be...
Nagato is going to be
the bridge to peace.
My job is to be a pillar
that supports that bridge.
He is the bridge to peace.
His will itself is the bridge.
I guess this is
as far as it goes for me.
Naruto... I know you can truly—
The rain in the Hidden Rain
is never ending...
What's going on?
Yahiko! Nagato!
Your will shall not be extinguished!
I also believe in Naruto!
It's his turn now!
He is the bridge to peace!
And I shall be his pillar!
Thank you, Nagato.
Your death has made my dream
even clearer to me.
I am expendable, a mere flower.
I shall take you with me.
You called me darkness.
Well then, I shall make you wilt.
And I shall also make your rainbow,
this seven-colored bridge of peace,
fade into the darkness as well.
When this genjutsu is over,
it will be the end of you too.
After I make you tell me
where the Rinnegan is.
So this is the place...
You are the third
Sage of the Six Paths.
The red hair that was once proof
of your Uzumaki lineage...
turned white from exerting
a power so strong.
You betrayed me,
and still you laugh at me?
That took some time.
We are leaving this place
in order to make
our dreams come true!
And once that happens...
Even if we are split apart,
let's meet back here one day...
And the three of us will
celebrate together!
Yes. Then we should invite
Jiraiya-sensei too!
Yes!
I guess you're right!
That took a lot of trouble,
but you got yourself a nice eye.
It was always mine.
By the way, this arrived too.
What is it?
Intel from Kisame.
We've learned the whereabouts
of the Nine-Tails.
Everything is going our way.
So this is from Kisame.
Let's go collect the Nine-Tails!
Wait...
I will go to the Eight and
Nine-Tails' location.
What are you up to?
It's a good chance to build trust
and strengthen our alliance.
Furthermore, Naruto, the Nine-Tails,
always has someone close by in the form
of Yamato, the copy of the First Hokage.
I want him for my experiments.
If I can't go,
I'd settle for Zetsu's body.
If you'd let me have one of him.
Also, the revival of the Ten-Tails
isn't far off, is it?
You seem to be very well-informed.
I knew Orochimaru was secretly
checking around, but...
According to intel that Kisame sent,
the Allied Shinobi Force
is 80,000 strong.
We also know what
their military formation is like.
But the key military power for
this side is Zetsu here, right?
Just how much do you know?!
With the data I have gathered
and my knowledge,
I can maximize Zetsu's strength.
On the condition that
you take me there.
Will you trust a guy like him?
If you bring me the Nine-Tails,
I will give you one of Zetsu.
Follow me.
This is...
the Gedo Statue.
It's down here.
This is...
Yes, he's alive.
That's the First Hokage,
Hashirama Senju.
Well, what I stole from him
during that battle...
is nothing more than what
I cultivated from living cells.
He's not conscious.
But what you're interested in
is down below.
This is amazing. Since when?
However, there's a risk.
I used a considerable amount
of chakra
from the Tailed Beasts inside
the Gedo Statue to create this.
I want to preserve it
as much as possible.
If the revival of
the Ten-Tails is delayed,
it means my plans are
delayed as well.
How many are here?
Roughly 100,000.
Lost sight of my target.
That spy pulled one over me.
Should have figured out their intent...
Are you all right, Guy-sensei?
I'll help you out!
Hey! Do not touch Guy right now!
He'll be experiencing the after-effects
of the Eight Inner Gates soon.
Even the slightest touch will cause him
intense pain all over his body!
What? Really?
I'm sorry, ya know!
Quietly, quietly!
Because of the Water Prison Jutsu,
I wasn't able to send a message
about the intel leak.
I think we can conclude that
the enemy knows about this location.
Which means we must act quickly
to relocate Bee and Naruto!
The enemy will figure that out too
and take immediate action!
I understand, but...
We will relocate them, but not by ship.
They will remain on this island.
What?
Leave him alone!
Bee! How did it go?
Not good!
Fool, ya fool.
What do you mean when
you say you'll relocate them,
but they'll remain on this island?
You can't even find this island
on a map.
Even if they try to find it,
it won't be that easy.
That's because this island...
Y-You're huge!
But I am still a very,
very small turtle.
Impossible!
I've never seen nor heard of
any turtle larger than you!
What did you say?!
Yes, a mobile stronghold,
an island that can move.
This is a colossal turtle reared
by the Hidden Cloud since ancient times.
Ouch!
We can say for sure that
the enemy knows about this.
However, this island is much safer
than returning to the Hidden Cloud
Village by ship.
Besides, hasn't Naruto been told
that he's here on this island
for a top-secret ecological
survey mission?
He'll get suspicious if
we tell him we're already leaving.
It seriously hurts!
The Five Great Nations face
an extremely critical situation.
And as they prepare for
the Fourth Great Ninja War,
there is concern that the shinobi and
samurai units will not be sufficient.
Hence, a third military unit,
made up of animals will be formed.
To this end, it has been decided
that a Jinchuriki
who is able to communicate with
and understand animals...
One who loves animals such as
Naruto Uzumaki, will be assigned
the task of selecting and
organizing this animal unit.
He will start by analyzing
the biology of the animals,
– Can we pass off...
– then ascertain their strengths...
– such a childish trick?
– and categorize them...
– We have to.
– by gender and physical attributes.
This is a top-secret S-rank mission!
Work diligently.
Fifth Hokage Tsunade of
the Hidden Leaf Village.
To arrive here to find that
intel has been leaked...
We'll have to rethink our strategy.
But as long as they know that
the Allied Shinobi Forces
are aware of the leak,
they will watch the situation.
Perhaps it will be easier
to lay some traps.
What about the island?
Even if it's mobile,
we can't let our guard down.
Those two are their targets.
They are sure to come
in search of them.
I established an escape route
just for situations like this.
In addition, the clouds hide it.
The enemy will not be able
to find it.
If they come searching,
the enemy will probably
send a small reconnaissance team first.
They won't infiltrate and try
to divide our troops, will they?
There's no doubt Kisame put
the coordinates of the island on the map.
Even if we move,
they will search the area thoroughly.
We can't lose focus.
In any case, send reinforcements.
But it will be meaningless
if the enemy spots us
mobilizing large groups.
Send a few of the elite.
I will go!
Lord Tsuchikage!
Old Ohnoki?
Then I have no complaints.
Same here.
Someone who can fly through
the air will move swiftly.
Is it really all right?
Don't worry, Kazekage!
I am the Tsuchikage, feared as
the Fence Sitter of the Hidden Stone!
My back!
I will go, after all.
I can ride my sand and
be there in no time...
Fool! I said I would go.
Well, you guys relax.
We're off.
It's the ocean from here on out.
We'll have to fly.
Yay! It's been so long since I flew!
This is going to be fun!
Don't get so excited, Akatsuchi!
We could be entering into a battle!
Yay!
I said to quit playing around,
you brat!
You're so embarrassing!
Damn it! It does look like fun!
But I can't get excited right now.
Damn that Akatsuchi!
You're up next Kurotsuchi.
Guess I have no choice...
Looks like you're awake at last.
It's a different seal from
Lord Orochimaru's.
I won't bind you completely... Deidara.
I don't know anything about art.
And I know little about you.
Well, my ninjutsu art isn't easy
to understand... Hmm!
But I'm grateful to you.
I once perfected the ultimate art.
So now, I can go even further...
Speaking of which,
that last explosion of yours...
It really didn't create a lot of buzz.
I just told you!
My art is not easy to understand!
These things take time... Hmm...
I said to line up straight!
Hurry and get into the tunnel!
Listen up! The ecological survey
will start once you're inside.
Cut it out!
You want to fight again?
Damn it! It's tough moving
all these animals.
I win again! Rock, Scissors, Paper!
And I'm going to win again
forever and ever!
Hey, you there! Octopus! Crab!
Hey! Line up!
As long as there is a risk of
the Akatsuki coming,
taking refuge inside
the giant turtle shell is a wise move.
Plus, Naruto is really taking
this mission seriously.
It will be disastrous if
Naruto finds out about the war.
He won't take the news quietly,
he'd rush to the battlefield instead.
We must prevent that at all cost.
After all, this is a war to protect Naruto.
Based on Kisame's intel,
these are the coordinates.
But they've already moved out.
That was a light punch.
I'm certain this person is...
Of all the people to ambush me, it's
none other than the Tsuchikage himself.
I was just testing you out.
Judging from your response,
you're a clone!
It wasn't Madara, after all.
And...
What's going on with bird and Deidara?
Let's just say, they're better
than the original.
However, you are...
a clay clone.
Hey, Old Man Ohnoki.
Long time no see!
You too, huh?
What?! Something is approaching
at high speed!
And it's... not human!
What's the matter?
You took me by surprise.
I had heard that
you were dead, Deidara.
I never expected your clay clones.
So that was...
... a stone clone of the Tsuchikage.
We were thinking
the same thing. Hmm!
Brother Deidara!
I thought you blew
yourself up in a big way.
Why are you still alive?
So you didn't die, after all?
Don't get excited, Akatsuchi!
It's Orochimaru's jutsu,
called the Reanimation Jutsu.
It may seem as though
he was brought back to life,
but he's not real.
Damn it. Still causing trouble,
even in death!
A youngster from
the Hidden Leaf beats you...
And then you have the gall
to sneak back in amongst the living!
Shut up!
I killed Sasuke Uchiha... hmm!
And now it's your turn, geezer,
for mocking my art! Hmm!
Seems Deidara doesn't
know anything.
Enough! I'll capture you both!
Do you intend to get in our way?
I knew we would be ambushed.
You didn't think we'd come
unprepared, did you?
What do you mean?
Seems we found them.
Sorry, but we have to go there.
Why?
What? My body won't
respond to me!
No way!
Don't tell me he found them!
We're going after him, you two!
– Right!
– Gotcha!
What's going on?
I used various drugs to activate
the original Manda's cells
to create a second Manda...
He surpasses the first Manda
in size, power, and intellect!
The fact that this island is a moving
animal turns out to be its fatal flaw.
What is that?
An island?
What's that island supposed to be?
It's not an island.
It's a giant turtle and it's moving.
And that is where we'll find
the Eight and Nine-Tails.
I get it! So that damn Naruto
is there! Hmm!
What's the plan?
In any case,
we have to stop that turtle island.
Deidara, give me a big one.
Damn!
They're fast!
Katsu!
Wood Style:
Deep Forest Emergence!
It flipped over.
It can't move now.
Oww...
What happened?
Heaven and Earth really
did trade places, yo.
Fools, ya fool!
I knew it!
Even if Heaven and Earth flip over...
A male is still a male and...
This is no time to be doing
an ecological survey!
Calm down, Yamato.
Remember, this is an S-rank mission.
Something must have
happened outside.
But we have to keep fooling him.
We cannot allow those two
to leave this place.
We have to deal with it ourselves.
Kabuto, you search for
the Eight and Nine-Tails. Hmm...
I'll handle those guys.
I owe them nothing less.
Fine, let's do that.
Deidara!
You shall feel my wrath.
Damn it, the geezer's snapped.
You haven't forgotten, have you?
This is getting bad!
Don't tell me he's going right
to his Particle Style?! Hmm!
Things are starting to get out of hand.
I won't let you get away!
What are you doing, Akatsuchi?!
If you do that, you'll end up
killing turtle island!
Damn!
This is complicated!
It's so large that it just looks
like a landscape!
There's my chance! Hmm!
Katsu!
Old man!
Akatsuchi's Golem!
Still attached to the Tsuchikage I see...
What a nuisance! Hmm!
I should get him away
from this island.
That damn snake!
So that guy over there is
the one controlling the snake!
The nerve of that wimp.
He was just pretending to
be Orochimaru's henchman!
I see...
So Naruto is inside this turtle.
Now then, how do I get in?
Damn it! What's going on outside?!
Th-There've been
a lot of tremors today...
Y-You're right.
Still, this is too weird.
Can the world turn upside down?
Well, it seems to be possible
on this island.
Although it's an extremely rare event.
Oh really?
I think I'm going to take
a look outside!
No! You're on
an important S-rank mission,
so stay focused!
Yeah, well...
I'm just going to take
a quick look outside.
It is a ninja's duty to see through
his mission until completion!
And this is a mission
only you can accomplish!
That's why you were selected.
Do you understand, Naruto?
We will see what's going on outside.
That's about the only way
we can contribute here.
However, let me repeat.
You are on a crucial S-rank mission!
Even Naruto is beginning
to sense something.
We bluffed him into thinking
this is an S-rank mission.
But basically, he's just checking
to see if the animals are male or female.
Naruto's not an idiot.
He might have already
figured it out.
Okay, I understand!
I'm going to focus on my mission!
All right!
This is going to work out!
Thank goodness he's so dense!
You're too slow!
Corrosion Style: Quicklime Jutsu!
There they are.
Is that him?!
There should be five humans!
So Aoba is here too.
Don't come crawling out!
Didn't we say that
we'd take care of this?
Having said that...
Perfect timing.
You can take me to Naruto.
A snake...
And that voice.
Don't tell me you're...
We meet again, Yamato.
I'll sweep him your way!
So get him!
Water Style: Water Trumpet!
Nice!
No good! He had it figured out!
I told you guys to get him, but...
I got him!
This is...
I see...
Idiot! Now you can't move!
My Quicklime Jutsu is like
fast-acting cement.
I spread it around
an area with water...
making it cause a reaction
that makes it harden like cement.
Motoi, Aoba!
Don't step into that water.
That's for extra insurance!
All right! You're ours!
I'll extract intel out of you!
The geezer is faster than
he was in his prime!
You've always snuck around
and fought from a distance.
I never liked that about you!
Shut up!
I'll finish him off with my C4...
Hmm!
They're too fast! I can't keep up!
Kabuto, how you've fallen.
You've become just like Orochimaru.
Aoba, concentrate!
Yeah, I know. I'm okay.
He's molted?!
He's gone that far?
Motoi, get away!
Yamato!
Damn it!
Lucky for me, Kurotsuchi, I knew
the hand signs for your jutsu.
I was able to
put you all off guard.
This should be high enough.
Don't underestimate me,
old geezer!
Prepare to die, Deidara!
Let's see which one is real art,
your Particle Style or
my Explosion Style!
This is—?!
What?!
Right when we were getting
to the good part! Hmm!
Damn!
I can't move!
Hold on!
When the kid from Hidden Rock returns,
she'll free you!
You're... Lord Tsuchikage!
Deidara got away.
What about you guys?
Someone from
the Hidden Rock went after him.
Damn it. Yamato's been...
What happened?
The Wood Style user and the Nine-Tails'
guardian, Yamato, has been taken.
He didn't bother going after
the Eight or Nine-Tails.
We don't know if he wanted
a hostage to interrogate...
or if the Wood Style user himself
was the target.
But the problem is the intel that
can be gleaned from Yamato!
Yamato would never break down
to reveal intel that easily!
That's not what I meant.
If our foe is Madara, he will
have formidable visual power.
Once someone is caught
under his ocular jutsu,
there is no escape.
This present you brought is very
different from what I expected.
You're right.
But he is
the Nine-Tails' guardian
and he also possesses
highly classified intel.
Furthermore, I can use him to make
Zetsu and the others much stronger.
Instead of pushing my luck, I
decided to settle by just capturing him.
This works out better for you guys.
Then hurry up and do it.
This left eye of mine
is itching to battle.