Iruka.
Yes, Lord Hokage?
The Fourth Hokage wanted the
villagers to regard Naruto as a hero.
He placed the seal
and died hoping for that.
Third Hokage... Fourth Hokage...
There is a hero
right before our eyes.
I never imagined
that Pain would be defeated.
We must notify Tobi. Let's go.
All right. No one's around.
For something I came up with
in the spur of the moment,
that was a good plan!
What do you mean "good plan"?
You sacrificed one of my tentacles.
Now, now, don't get mad, Eight-o.
Ya know they'll regrow,
and ya know I was right-o.
Will you stop that annoying rapping
when you're in my presence?
You suck!
I know, I know.
Since I'm the one who owns ya,
I know best of all, ha!
That's why this time...
What? Don't start saying
weird stuff again.
It will be enka!
Anyway, now I can finally
escape Brother's bossy ways
and get away from the village.
I'm free!
As far as he knows,
the Akatsuki's captured me.
Raikage is probably on a rampage now.
Are you sure about this?
I've been imprisoned in
the village as a weapon
all because I'm a Jinchuriki.
I need to get out for
some fresh air once in a while, right?
So? What are you going to do?
When it comes to enka,
Kin-sensei is the man!
Who is that?
Huh?
Don't be lame and remember the name, fool!
He's the King of the enka ninja.
How can you be so carefree?
The Akatsuki won't sit still for long.
Not only that, since you summoned me,
you don't have much stamina left.
Did you really have to call on me
when you had the advantage?
Among all the guys
I've faced in battle,
that Sharingan has to rank
in the top two in strength.
I got carried away.
Times may be changing soon.
Huh? Through my enka?
I heard, Konohamaru.
You took down one of the Pains!
I wasn't determined to catch up
to you just for fun, you know!
But that was nothing compared to
how you saved the entire village.
That's not true.
Besides, there were
many things I couldn't protect.
Big Bro Naruto...
There's something
I want to show you!
Hey!
Where are you going?
Just follow me!
Here!
Why'd you bring me to
the evacuation shelter?
We're going just up further!
The valuables warehouse?
And...
this is my family's storage space.
Ta-dah!
This...
... it's my jacket...
It's a precious treasure.
So I brought it here just in case.
I kept my promise!
Konohamaru... You're a great kid!
I know!
One day, I'm going to challenge you
for the Hokage's seat!
So, from now on,
consider me your rival!
All right!
And that's the whole story.
I never expected Pain to be defeated.
This is unexpected.
Konan isn't coming back here anymore.
What should we do?
We have so many vacant positions.
We need another pawn who can
synchronize with the Gedo Statue.
Kisame...
You go look for the Eight-Tails.
What about you?
I have slightly different
business to attend to.
This is... I wasn't expecting this.
You're late.
Did Naruto do it?
No, it was Pain's doing.
Pain?!
But Naruto handled it.
He defeated Pain.
Naruto did that?!
What about the Nine-Tails?
He was able to control it on his own.
I see...
What? Naruto controlled
the Nine-Tails on his own?!
There's no time to be surprised.
Rebuilding the village
is going to be hard work.
Yamato, we're going to need your help.
Okay!
What is it?
An emergency council has been called.
As Jonin squad leader,
your presence is also required
at the Feudal Lord's palace, Lord Shikaku.
Already? All right.
What'll I do?
Huh?!
Well, the Hidden Leaf Village
has tons of pretty women.
And what if all those women
declared their love for me?
I was wondering what I'd do.
Oh yes, I see.
Well, why don't you
go out with them?
With as many as you can
get your hands on!
But... when the time comes
to leave the Hidden Leaf
and they say they can't bear
to part with me, what'll I do?
I'd be so scared if they suggest
something like a lover's suicide.
So are you happy or scared?
What are you trying to say?!
We haven't even reached
the Hidden Leaf Village yet.
Don't get so carried away!
It's creepy!
But maybe some handsome guy
with a super-good looking face
might come on to you too.
Why can't you just
say handsome guy?
Although a rich, tall, famous ninja
in addition to being super-handsome
wouldn't be farfetched.
No, you're letting
your imagination run wild.
No way that would happen!
Absolutely no way!
I didn't ask...
for your opinion!
What would we do if that stone
hits a boulder and it crumbles
and the falling rocks hit
another bigger boulder
that causes an even bigger rock slide
that falls over
the Hidden Leaf Village
and destroys it?
Who's over-imagining things now?!
Idiot!
She used Lady Katsuyu's jutsu
to protect everyone.
She's been unconscious ever since.
We honestly don't know when
she'll regain consciousness.
Granny...
Regarding the Akatsuki,
we intend to continue pursuing them
with assistance from our allied nations.
With everything that's happened
to your village,
we of the Land of Fire shall also provide
full support in rebuilding the village.
First, we need to put together a budget.
Then, we need to ease tensions
between other nations.
More importantly...
There's something
we must attend to first.
The selection of a new Hokage.
I knew it would come to this.
Don't you think we should just
wait until Tsunade recovers?
Lord... Tsunade remains in
a comatose state.
The village is in ruins, and we don't know
when Tsunade will awaken.
We're having a difficult time deciding
what line of action to take.
Besides, she is responsible for bringing about
the destruction of the Leaf Village!
I always thought that Jiraiya
would be next.
I liked him,
but he's no longer here.
So, who else is there?
In that case, I...
I recommend Kakashi Hatake!
The son of the White Fang, huh?
Yes! Why not?
What do the rest of you think?
Indeed... He's renowned, powerful,
and virtuous.
But perhaps a bit too young?
I believe Minato, the Fourth Hokage,
was younger.
Who was Kakashi Hatake's master?
The Fourth Hokage.
Is that so? If I'm not mistaken...
Jiraiya was
the Fourth Hokage's master and
the Third Hokage was Jiraiya's master!
There seems to be no problem at all,
is there?
All right! Well then...
The Third Hokage's teachings are
practically what annihilated the village!
Akatsuki's leader,
the one who destroyed the village,
was once Jiraiya's student.
This is what happens when
one sympathizes with foreigners
and teaches them ninjutsu!
They're naïve! All of them!
That naïveté throughout the ages allowed
our ally, the Sand Village, to betray us
and allowed Orochimaru to lead
a campaign to destroy the Hidden Leaf.
It allowed the rise of the Akatsuki and
allowed Sasuke, a survivor of the Uchiha,
to go rogue and work underground!
What sort of Hokage
do we need now?!
Someone who can handle the aftermath
of this terrible situation,
and change the ninja world
by enforcing ninja laws.
I will become a Hokage
like no other!
Lord... Why don't we allow Danzo to
handle this for the time being?
A rigid and one-sided way
of doing things is not-
Yes, I've made up my mind.
Danzo...
I appoint you as Sixth Hokage!
Hey, over here.
Don't you think we can still
use this timber?
I think you're right.
But...
There's nothing left of what was built
by generations of Hokage.
Who could have imagined
this would happen?
This village isn't the only thing
the Hokage left us.
You're absolutely right.
Yamato...
We're all still here!
Wood Style: Row Houses jutsu!
At this rate, the Leaf Village
will be rebuilt in no time!
Easy for you to say.
Is Granny Tsunade still in a coma?
Yes.
I have so many things
I want to tell her.
Don't worry.
Lady Tsunade will wake up soon!
She's a strong woman.
Our Hokage!
She'll be all right!
What am I encouraging Naruto for?
I'm the one
who needs convincing... Naruto.
It's been a super-long time,
Naruto! Sakura!
It's great to see our hero again, Naruto!
Is that...?
Inari and Old Man Tazuna?!
Inari, you've grown up!
Old man, you've gotten even older.
Shut it...
I'm a carpenter now.
That's why I've come here,
at the request of the Hidden Leaf.
And I thought I'd say hello
to you guys.
Sakura, you're so pretty.
You think so?
Man, how long has it been?
Two years? Three? Longer?
Imagine, that little kid is now...
Akane and the others too.
They're carpenters like me.
See? They're working over there.
What a surprise.
Back then, and that time with Gato.
Thank you for everything.
Because of you, the Land of Waves
has become very prosperous.
So this time,
we're going to return the favor!
First, for you... it'll be Ichiraku!
Just you watch...
I'll build an amazing one!
Inari...
Thanks.
Huh? You're already here?
Kakashi!
Oh, Kakashi!
We rushed over after hearing
the Hidden Leaf Village was in a crisis!
I see.
Huh?
What is it?
Where is Sasuke?
I want to talk to him too.
Oh...
Well, actually...
Sasuke is... you see...
Sasuke and I had a small fight and
he's out of the village right now.
Don't worry,
I'll go bring him back right away!
When I do, please say hello to him.
I know Sasuke would be happy.
Right, Sakura?
U-Uh-huh.
Don't tell me...
It's over some love triangle, eh?
No, that's not it!
Thank you, Naruto.
Sasuke... Where are you right now?
You have no siblings, or parents!
How can you understand
anything about me?!
You've been alone from the start!
What can you understand
about me?!
Having a bond is what
makes it painful!
And how could you know what it feels
like to lose that bond?!
I thought I knew Sasuke.
But I didn't understand him at all.
No matter what I said to him back
in the Valley of the End,
it wouldn't have reached Sasuke.
Naruto...
I didn't know Sasuke's pain,
so how could I laugh with him?
Why should he give me the time
of day, let alone fight with me?
It'll probably hurt like hell,
but next time, I want to have
a serious fight with him.
Because some day,
I want Team 7 to laugh together again,
with Sasuke back where he belongs!
N-No way...
It can't be! I didn't mean to do this!
I mean, how could a rock that size...
K-Karui, what have you done?
There's no way.
Anyway, let's look for someone.
Who are you three?!
I'm Samui from the Hidden Cloud.
I am a messenger for the Raikage,
the leader of the Hidden Cloud.
Lord Raikage?
Please pardon our run-in earlier.
We're all on edge lately.
There weren't any guards
from the Leaf around
and finding the village
in such a state...
We were shocked and
wondered what had happened.
- It was the work of the Akatsuki
- Here's your stone.
- that destroyed the village.
- Precautionary measures...
Are being taken immediately
and security will be tightened.
- We would like an audience
- That's got nothing to do with it!
With your Hokage.
I am here to deliver a letter
from the Raikage to Lady Hokage.
Actually...
Is something the matter?
Oww!
Don't tell me
this lump on my head...
Enough!
Talk about bad timing.
A sealed tube never
contains any good news.
It's a letter calling for an emergency
Five Kage Summit Conference.
You see?
A Five Kage Summit Conference?!
Lady Hokage is in a coma?
I am her aide, so I will accept
the letter on her behalf.
If it's uncertain when
she will regain consciousness,
the interim Hokage will do.
Someone must read the letter
and give me a reply!
The Raikage cannot wait.
But...
That woman is
no longer the Hokage.
I am the new Sixth Hokage.
I will look at the letter.
Don't tell me that Danzo has...
What is it?
Doesn't Lord Raikage
want a reply?
Sasuke...
So it has come to this.
And your reply?
Ow! Hey!
What's wrong, Kiba?
Now stay calm and listen!
Lady Tsunade has been
removed as Hokage!
- What?!
- Huh?
It seems someone named Danzo
is the Sixth Hokage!
I don't know too much,
but apparently he's been
active behind the scenes!
Danzo?!
I have a bad feeling about this.
And that's not
the only shocking thing!
The Sixth Hokage declared
Sasuke as a rogue ninja,
and has given the order
to dispose of him!
What the hell's going on?!
Even I don't understand.
They couldn't wait until
Lady Tsunade recovered.
It makes sense in a way.
Kakashi-sensei...
Sasuke is indeed a rogue ninja.
Normally, he would have
been eliminated long ago.
It's only because of Lady Tsunade
that he's been allowed to live.
I'm going to see this Danzo!
Wait, Sakura!
Storming into his office
will solve nothing.
Lady Tsunade isn't even conscious yet!
How could they do this to her?!
And what about Sasuke?
You can't expect me
to keep quiet!
I'm coming with you.
Calm down, you two.
At a time like this, staying calm
is crucial or things won't work out.
How can I stay calm?!
I won't let them lay
a hand on Sasuke!
I said wait!
Danzo has already figured out
that this is how you'll react.
So you'll go see him, then what?
I won't do anything violent!
I just want to talk to him and ask him
to change his mind about Sasuke!
I hardly think that he'll go along with
whatever you have to say...
Danzo has been appointed
by the Feudal Lord.
While he has yet to win
a vote of confidence from the Jonin,
he is the Hokage.
If you make a wrong move,
you'll be thrown into jail.
That's fine with me!
I'm going!
Me too!
H-Hey guys...
Naruto, you possess
the Nine-Tails.
What about it?
Danzo would like nothing better
than to confine you in this village.
Do you want to
be locked up in jail?
That's exactly what he wants.
Then you won't be
able to look for Sasuke.
Don't make a scene right now.
You wanted to see me?
Keep an eye on Naruto.
If you notice anything amiss,
inform me immediately.
Yes sir.
Umm... May I ask you a question?
What is it?
What do you plan
to do with Naruto?
Do not worry.
Naruto is the village hero
right now.
Everyone trusts him.
Even more than they trust me,
the Sixth Hokage.
If I do anything to Naruto now,
it will affect my reputation
as the Hokage.
This is a crucial time,
right before the vote of confidence.
Still, Naruto is a Jinchuriki.
As the Hokage, I must keep
the Jinchuriki under surveillance.
I cannot be lax like Tsunade was.
I understand.
You're excused.
Should I be relieved?
Sai!
We were just looking for you!
We need to talk to you.
What is it?
Tell us what you
know about Danzo.
Sai!
That's impossible.
Why?!
Don't tell me you're
working for him again!
No... It's nothing like that.
It's not possible for me to
say a word about Lord Danzo.
Due to this.
What the hell is that?
Is it a Curse Mark?
Yes, it's a Curse Mark
placed by Lord Danzo.
If I start to talk about Lord Danzo,
my entire body will become numb
and I won't be able to move or talk.
This is true of all who
belong to the Foundation.
He's a cautious man.
Lord Danzo and the Foundation
engage in espionage.
They've done a lot of dirty work behind
the scenes in order to protect the village.
This cannot be revealed.
So even if one is captured,
not a word will be uttered.
But what a thing to do...
Putting a Curse Mark on
one's own subordinate?
I can't accept that.
It's what has protected Hidden
Leaf Village from the bottom up.
Their methods may have
been unscrupulous,
but their love for the village
is no different from yours.
Then why did he overturn
Lady Tsunade's decision about Sasuke?
Isn't he planning to dispatch
tracking ninja to go after Sasuke?
I-Is that so?
I haven't heard anything
regarding Sasuke-
You can tell us all about
this Sasuke fellow!
You seem to be his friends!
Shadow Clone Jutsu
Don't kill him!
I know that!
Sakura!
Are you all right, Sakura?
Judging from their headbands,
they're ninja from the Hidden Cloud.
Why would they come here?
What the hell do you guys want?
You were just
talking about Sasuke!
Tell us what you were saying!
It's got nothing to do
with you Cloud ninja!
It's got everything to do with us!
Sasuke Uchiha of the Hidden Leaf
attacked our village!
Your rogue ninja kidnapped our master!
We don't even know if our master
is dead or alive, you idiots!
Th-That's a lie!
Why would Sasuke
do such a thing?!
Like we'd know what
the Akatsuki's motives are!
The Akatsuki?!
What do you mean?
Huh?! Don't kid around!
Sasuke is a member
of the Akatsuki!
You guys let your
rogue ninja roam free,
so Lord Raikage ordered us
to come here.
And we've gotten your Hokage's
permission to get rid of the Uchiha!
Sasuke...
abducted their master?
We'll get our revenge!
The Uchiha is ours!
Sasuke...
What... happened to you?
Hey, Sasuke.
I suddenly sensed his chakra.
What's going on?
Aw man... Bad timing.
How did you know where to find me?
Don't underestimate me.
I have considerable powers.
So what do you want with me now?
Taka left the Akatsuki.
We're done with you.
As it stands, you reneged
on your promise to me.
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about hunting
the Tailed Beast.
We already captured the Eight-Tails
and delivered him to you.
That was just a substitution.
In other words, you guys failed.
The Eight-Tails pulled
a fast one on you.
I saw it all with my Sharingan.
There's no way he had
an opportunity to make a clone.
The only part of his body
that I cut off!
Frankly,
I'm disappointed in you all.
So what are you going to do?
It's none of our business now.
Wrong.
You will finish whatever work you started
as members of the Akatsuki.
Having said that,
you can forget about the Eight-Tails.
I've decided to give you
a different task.
And if I refuse?
We'll fight it out right here.
And you won't be able to
go to Hidden Leaf Village.
We'll force our way through!
It's a little too late to
go to the Hidden Leaf.
I went right through him.
Just like before.
Is this his power?
Your purpose is fruitless.
Too bad.
What do you mean?
The Village Hidden in
the Leaves is no more.
What are you saying?!
I'll explain it to you.
Who is he?!
Relax. He's my partner.
So, who is the new Hokage?
Someone named Danzo.
It's pretty much
what we expected.
Danzo... is the Hokage?
Yes, one of the high-ranking elders
of the Hidden Leaf
who drove your elder brother
into a corner.
He is the new Hokage.
What the hell happened in
the Hidden Leaf Village.!
My subordinate, Pain,
destroyed the Hidden Leaf.
And because both you and Pain
were a bit too reckless,
it seems the Five Kage
are going to take action.
The Five Kage?
There will be
a Five Kage Summit Conference.
I'll explain from here.
You will tell us everything
you know about Sasuke.
Of course,
his ninjutsu style and powers,
but also any data
you have gathered about
the Akatsuki and Sasuke's partners,
as well as their past actions.
No way! It's a lie!
Sasuke wouldn't join
the Akatsuki!
Are you sure about this?
Yes! The Uchiha family crest
was verified!
And his facial composite
matched the list.
That's... That's not poss...
Why are you crying?!
We're the ones who want to cry!
Your tears won't bring back
Lord Killer Bee or Lady Yugito!
If you have time to cry,
then start talking about Sasuke!
Wait, guys.
Huh?!
When the authorization to
terminate Sasuke was given,
all Hidden Leaf data relating to him
should have been passed on to you.
It's not necessary to
press these two any further.
Oh, you're right!
Our captain is now waiting for it.
We were just trying to get whatever
other information was available!
You can't expect us to stay still!
We don't even know
how our master's doing!
I will avenge Pervy Sage!
I can't just sit around
doing nothing!
You're not involved in this,
so you wouldn't understand how we feel!
Is your master a Jinchuriki?
How did you know?
I'm a Jinchuriki too.
The Akatsuki is after the Jinchuriki.
So actually, I am involved.
The Akatsuki will always
capture a Jinchuriki alive.
That means your master
may not be dead.
Are you serious?!
Never mind Sasuke.
You need to save your master first.
Are you really sure about this?!
Really, really sure?
Didn't I tell you?!
Our master wouldn't die so easily!
I'll help you rescue your master,
and I'll give you whatever information
we have on the Akatsuki.
Hey blondie,
you're quick to understand!
Come with us and
tell us about Sasuke!
Naruto...
Leave it to me, Sakura.
What's your name?
Naruto?
This Naruto guy defeated Pain
all by himself?
That's right.
He's become extremely strong.
I think he's stronger
than Sasuke right now.
I don't care about that.
My main concern is
this Five Kage Summit.
What are we going to do?
The Leaf Village is no more.
And if this Danzo, our target, is going
to the Five Kage Summit,
shouldn't we be heading there too?
Wh-What? Am I wrong?
We, Taka, will take the Hokage's head
at the Five Kage Summit.
We're changing our destination.
Sounds like a plan.
So, where is this Five Kage Summit
taking place?
This is becoming a really
bothersome situation.
Zetsu!
My clone will guide you.
Okay, follow me!
Can we trust them?
We'll wait and see for now.
If I sense anything suspicious,
I'll get rid of them with
my Amaterasu.
There's something I've been
meaning to test out anyway.
All is going as planned.
Not everything.
Nagato's Gedo Art of Rinne Rebirth
was supposed to be used for my benefit.
I never expected he would use it
for something other than that.
To betray me...
Even if Sasuke should become
stronger than Nagato,
it is meaningless if
he cannot be controlled.
It will be awhile before I consider letting
him synchronize with the Gedo Statue.
We need to keep an eye on him.
So you had contingent plans
in case Nagato died?
Somewhat.
However, it's certainly not
what I had in mind.
Naruto Uzumaki...
He managed to put
a small dent in my plan.
What next then?
Make our move?
We're done moving ahead cautiously.
Let us push forward
on "Project Tsuki no Me."
You're late, Kankuro!
Assembling my new puppets
took longer than I expected!
Lord Kazekage, have a safe journey.
Lord Kankuro, Lady Temari...
We're counting on you.
We know.
But Gaara doesn't really
need bodyguards.
We're off.
Kurotsuchi, Akatsuchi,
we're counting on you two!
Lord Tsuchikage!
Show the other Kage
what you're made of!
Traveling to a summits
at my age is quite a chore.
Look at those young ones
romping around.
They don't even know what it's
like to have chronic back pain.
Then maybe it's time to retire, Gramps.
Why drag out the glory?
Let me carry that pack for you,
Lord Tsuchikage!
Hands off, Akatsuchi!
I don't need your help!
My back!
Well? Want to send
someone else for you?
Y-You idiot!
Who do you think I am?!
I am the Tsuchikage,
once feared as Ohnoki of Both Scales
of the Hidden Stone!
Enough!
I shall carry my own packs!
Seriously... What a stubborn old geezer!
Here, you can carry
your own pack if you wish.
Now let's go!
Of all the...
Do as you please!
Just admit that's better, Gramps.
Have a safe journey, Lord Tsuchikage!
Guard Lady Mizukage well.
Make sure Lady Mizukage
doesn't overdo things.
I know.
Thank you.
Great Elder...
I swear upon my title of Mizukage
to carry out my duties flawlessly.
Chojuro, you are one of
the Seven Ninja Swordsmen of the Mist.
Protect our Mizukage well.
Y-Yes sir.
We should be fine...
I think.
Have more confidence in yourself.
You are strong.
That is why I chose you to
accompany me to the summit.
Okay, Chojuro?
Yes, ma'am.
I can handle it... I think.
She's so kind.
"Yes, ma'am" would be enough!
Such an uncertain attitude
will get you nowhere!
I swear, young people these days lack
the dedication to manage themselves.
Marriage?
Ao! Enough with the lecturing!
Get going or you'll be late!
Late... for marriage?!
It's my way of offering advice!
Why, in my day...
Shut up, or I'll kill you.
Huh?!
All right, Chojuro, Ao...
Let us go!
I will do everything to protect that
smile on our gentle Lady Mizukage!
I hope I can.
What are you doing, Ao?
Lady Mizukage has left.
Oh, no!
Lady Mizukage, please wait for me!
Still no word from Team Samui?!
No, sir. But I do expect to
hear something soon.
And Samui has already been given the route
you will take to the summit, Lord Raikage.
She will either rendezvous with
you directly, or send a messenger bird.
Good! Then I shall be off as well!
Let us go! Shee! Darui!
Yes, sir!
Right.
Follow me!
Not again!
Let's go, Darui.
No... I'll just use the door.
Go on, I'll catch up.
This should do.
All right, let's hear about Sasuke.
Well? Start talking!
I can't do it.
I can't sell Sasuke out.
Quit playing around!
You can't take it back now,
after all that's been done.
Still, Sasuke is also a ninja
from the Hidden Leaf Village.
He is a comrade!
We would risk our lives to save him.
That's the Hidden Leaf way.
Naruto... This is a once in
a lifetime request.
Please...
Please bring Sasuke back.
Well?! Say something!
I know I'm being selfish.
But I can't sell out Sasuke.
Why you...
I understand your desire
for revenge.
But if you let your hatred rule
and you kill Sasuke,
this time, my comrades
may not put up with it!
Eye for an eye!
The vicious cycle will start
all over again!
The people we want to protect
will kill each other off one after another!
Your Sasuke is the one
who started it all!
I don't give a damn what you say!
We're going to kill Sasuke!
Then where do you suggest
we take our hatred?
How would you take responsibility
for that?
Beat me up until you're satisfied.
That's about all I can offer...
You sure know how to spit
convenient words, don't you?!
Let's test your theory.
See if it would really make me
feel better, huh?!
How's that?! And that! And that!
Take that!
I have Anko being followed by
Dajimu and Tera, both skilled men.
Perhaps now is the time
to dispose of her.
This is a crucial time.
I want to avoid any mishaps
that could worsen the situation.
Increase our troops.
Get Kabuto before Anko does.
That man might know about
my connection to Orochimaru.
Kabuto has the research data
from Orochimaru's human experiments.
We must get that data without fail.
I'm certain it will be useful for
my right eye and left arm.
Fu and Torune,
you two stay here.
Terai, I'll rely on you to
deal with Kabuto.
Now go!
Yes sir!
Now, I must leave for
the Five Kage Summit Conference.
Except in special cases,
we are only permitted to bring
a maximum of two retainers to the summit.
You are the top two in the Foundation.
I have decided that
you shall accompany me.
Masks are forbidden.
Remove them.
What level of arms are
we allowed for your protection?
Do not concern yourself
with any limitations.
I'll leave it to your judgment, Fu.
Yes sir.
Torune...
Make sure your subordinates
watch Naruto.
I doubt that Sai would do
anything to betray the Foundation.
But it's a precaution.
Yes sir.
They are to make certain that the
Nine-Tails does not leave the village.
Let me make this clear!
No amount of pummeling is going
to make me feel better!
I won't stop until you start
talking about Sasuke!
Don't interfere.
He asked for this.
Sai... Stay out of this.
Naruto...
You don't have to get beaten up
for Sasuke's sake.
Shut up. It's my choice.
Sasuke... keeps hurting you
over and over again.
If I were you...
If you get in the way,
we'll beat you up too.
Enough already, Karui.
Beating them up won't
get us anywhere.
You should know that.
He promised to help us
rescue Lord Killer Bee.
What?! Where's your usual skepticism
about promises being honored?
This isn't like you at all!
Naruto...
No matter what we do,
he refuses to sell out his friend.
He may be a foe,
but I like guys like him.
A man shouldn't be loose with words.
However much you thrash him,
he won't betray Sasuke.
He's the type who means
what he says.
Captain Samui.
Omoi, Karui.
How goes the intel-gathering?
I hope you haven't gotten into trouble.
Never mind that.
We've learned that
Lord Killer Bee may be alive!
Let's go and save him!
First, we have to find
the Akatsuki hideout!
And then what?
Just the three of us against a foe
who managed to capture
Lord Killer Bee himself?
Besides, we don't even know
how many hideouts the Akatsuki have.
Where do we start?
We need to gather intel,
and then analyze it.
That comes first!
We cannot repeat what happened
back then with Yugito.
We'll take the intel we've gathered
directly to Lord Raikage!
There is too much information
to sort out.
T-Take me with you.
I want to help you guys save
your Jinchuriki.
Naruto!
And I... have something I want to discuss
with the Raikage.
Lord Raikage?
You've got to be kidding!
Karui...
So this child is Naruto.
Naruto Uzumaki... the one everyone
in this village is talking about.
We don't know enough about you.
And with Lord Raikage on the road
under minimal guard,
there's no way I can have you meet him.
Karui, Omoi. Let's get going!
We have permission to inspect the intel
on Sasuke and the Akatsuki.
It'll take time to transfer the notes
and I need your help.
Sai...
What is it?
Take me to Kakashi-sensei
and Captain Yamato.
Okay. Here...
You should let Sakura take
a look at that.
No, it's okay.
If she sees me like this,
it'll just cause more trouble.
Besides, I heal fast.
Sai...
What you did earlier... Thanks.
No problem.
Boy, they really worked you over.
Oww!
Oh, I'm sorry.
You'd better take some time
to recuperate.
I'm going to see the Raikage!
What are you saying?!
The Five Kage Summit is
about to convene!
It is agreed that every Hidden Village
will exercise restraint
in leaving their lands and
conducting radical missions!
What will you do by seeing him?
I'm going to convince him
to forgive Sasuke!
Right now, you don't even have
the necklace that seals the Tailed Beast!
A Jinchuriki like you must not
leave the village!
It was bad enough that as many as eight
tails transformed during that last battle!
We were lucky that the Seal activated
in time to suppress the Nine-Tails,
but who knows
about the next time?
Besides, I'm in charge of
the village reconstruction.
I cannot stay by you all the time!
I met the Fourth Hokage.
That last time,
it was the Fourth Hokage
who stopped
my Nine-Tails transformation.
Wh-What does he mean?
The Fourth Hokage
passed away a long...
There are still many mysteries to
the Sealing Jutsu, the Reaper Death Seal.
He probably sealed his own
mental energy into the sealing spell.
That's when the Fourth Hokage
told me...
A guy wearing the Akatsuki mask
orchestrated the Nine-Tails incident
16 years ago.
And he was so strong, even the Fourth
Hokage was almost no match for him!
On top of that, he said this guy
was the mastermind
that was probably using Pain.
If Sasuke has joined the Akatsuki,
then he's also being used.
This is just what Lord Jiraiya feared.
That incident 16 years ago...
To think he was behind it.
He possessed the Sharingan.
He belonged to the Uchiha clan and
left the village harboring great hatred.
And only he, Madara, is capable
of summoning the Nine-Tails.
Anything is possible if it
involves Madara.
So he's still alive.
Madara...
That vision and chakra more
ominous than mine...
It's just like Madara Uchiha
from long ago.
Who's Madara?
A man who was defeated
by the First Hokage.
The former leader of the Uchiha Clan
of Hidden Leaf Village.
The higher-ups must be informed of this.
Sai!
Yes?
Report this to the Hokage.
R-Right.
Naruto. What did the Fourth Hokage
say to you?
Fathers like to tell their sons
all sorts of things, right?
He said... he believed in me!
Good!
Naruto, you will go to the Raikage!
Huh?
With Yamato and I as your escorts.
What?!
This is a bad idea!
What? Can't listen to what
I have to say, Tenzo?
Hey! You're not supposed to call me
by that name, remember?!
Now, now...
Lord Danzo...
I know.
I haven't seen combat in a long time.
This is the perfect opportunity
to loosen my muscles.
Do not interfere.
I will handle them!
It hurts.
Seven, eight, nine, ten...
Seventeen total, eh?
Okay! I'm ready!
Please don't mention Naruto's actions
when you report to the Hokage.
Tell him there's been no movement.
It seems you still do not trust me.
You work under Danzo and
your job is to keep an eye on Naruto.
However, you are also
a member of my Team 7.
So I do believe in you.
He said... he believed in me!
What is this feeling?
Catch you later!
These are remnants of the Hannya
Black Ops from the Land of Woods
that we annihilated in the past.
It's always been like this.
Enemies looking for
the slightest opportunity to strike.
Now that you've
come out of the shadows,
things may become more
troublesome for you, sir.
A ninja lives in an ascetic world.
To remain anonymous was
a source of pride.
But by exclusively controlling both
the surface and the underground,
one can truly strengthen village
and nation.
I will make certain that
this summit is a success
and that I am recognized
as the Hokage.
Then the Jonin Council will have no choice
but to accept me as their Hokage.
My era has finally come.
Finished at last!
Seriously...
Try to maintain your cool more if you
want to call yourselves ninja, got it?!
We must hurry to Lord Raikage!
- Gotcha!
- Right!
Sorry, but I'm planting
Signal Seeds on you.
I may not look it,
but tailing is my specialty.
Now then...
I should contact Kakashi
and Naruto.
I wonder if that Naruto kid is okay.
If you say another word,
I'll beat you up!
It's been bugging you too, eh?
I told you not to talk!
Man... Your hands move
as quick as ever.
Begin tailing.
Right!
Chojuro...
Your Great Twin Sword Hiramekarei
must have been heavy during the journey.
Are you all right?
Oh... yes.
Although I feel a bit warm.
Let me see.
Lady Fifth,
you spoil Chojuro too much!
This is why youth these days
get so full of themselves!
Feeling feverish after
a short walk like that!
In my day...
Ao...
We're no longer in the dark ages when
we were known as the Blood Mist Village.
The nightmare under
the Fourth Mizukage is over.
Please stop harping on
about the past.
P-Pardon me, I just...
Now, let us stop such depressing talk
and have some supper instead.
I am looking forward to
the meal here.
Oops!
What's for dinner?
Something engaging, I hope.
Engaging?
Engagement!
You did make arrangements
for dinner, didn't you, Chojuro?
Th-There were so many choices,
in the end, I couldn't decide.
In the end, it was...
Such indecisiveness!
Youth these days have no ambition
in their hearts! Only voids!
Void?!
I'm so sorry. I'll get on it right away!
My engagement...
in the end, it was... void?!
Why, back in my day...
Shut up, or I'll kill you.
Why?!
Man, it's getting cold.
The Land of Iron is just
a stone's throw away.
Wait, there's something up ahead.
I've never been to the Land of Iron.
I'm so excited.
There's nothing special about it.
What's it like, Gramps?
It lies among three mountains known
as the Three Wolves.
It has its own culture,
its own jurisdiction,
a powerful military
and maintains neutrality.
So it has its own culture and power.
What makes it different from
the Land of Earth?
There is a long-standing rule
that ninja will not meddle with it.
The Land of Iron does not
rely on ninja.
Instead, it is protected by those
who are known as samurai.
How did it go?
The security is real tight due
to the Five Kage Summit.
Jugo, use animals to scout out
the route to the summit
where the security is the thinnest.
Okay.
We have been awaiting your arrival,
Lord Kazekage.
My name is Mifune,
a General of this Land of Iron.
It is a pleasure to meet you.
I am the Kazekage, Gaara.
It's cold.
The climate is totally different
from the Land of Wind.
Some hot tea will warm you up.
Please come inside.
It's gotten cold all of a sudden.
We're in the middle of tailing!
So, shh!
How is it?
We can go up a route
on the west side.
There aren't many guards.
Karin, keep checking
the chakra positions of the guards.
We're going to infiltrate now.
I have to come too?!
This is the time to demonstrate
your powers.
Zetsu, was it?
Yeah?
I need you to confirm which
one is Danzo. You're coming too.
A message from Sai, it seems.
What is it?
Just a routine report.
Let's go.
Why can't we just ambush him
before he arrives?
I'm getting tired.
Are you stupid?!
If the Hokage is late, they're bound to
think something went wrong.
Then samurai reinforcements
will swarm all over the place.
And what if the other Kage come too?
We don't know the enemy's strength.
So we should wait for our chance
for a surprise attack on his way home.
Right, Sasuke?
Karin, just focus on
the enemy's chakra positions.
Busted.
Shut up!
Sasuke, it seems you have
your hands full.
Never mind that.
I need you to verify which one
is Danzo before the meeting.
You better not lie.
I am attuned to chakra.
There's always a disturbance
in chakra when one lies.
So just remember,
I'll be checking on you all the time.
I won't lie.
Danzo is a hindrance to us too.
Lord Raikage, it's Team Samui.
Let's descend!
I have returned from
the Hidden Leaf Village.
And how did it go?
Samui, you've been tailed.
Come out, you Hidden Leaf dogs!
You actually tailed Samui.
You guys are pretty good.
Y-You...
You're Naruto!
You tailed us! What's the big idea?!
Boss, the one on the right...
is Kakashi Hatake.
I know that!
Did the Hokage send you,
Kakashi Hatake?
No, I came to ask you personally
about a request by Naruto Uzumaki
of the Hidden Leaf.
Naruto Uzumaki?
If you could hear him out
for just a while.
Isn't this a bit rude?
Stopping us en route to the summit
without any prior notice.
I am fully aware of that.
No matter.
You there, boy! Speak!
Sasuke...
I want you to revoke the order
to eliminate of Sasuke Uchiha!
H-Hey, this isn't really the place...
Are you still talking about that?!
You sure got guts.
What are you saying?
I know it sounds ridiculous!
But this is the only way
I know how to say it!
Sasuke is my friend!
My friend's going to get killed. I
can't just stand by and let it happen!
On top of that,
I don't want Sasuke to be
the cause of the Leaf and
Cloud Villages killing each other.
I don't want my friends,
or the Cloud to fight for revenge!
I'm begging you!
I don't want us killing each other
out of vengeance anymore!
All Sasuke ever thought
about was revenge!
He became obsessed with it
and that changed him.
Vengeance makes you go mad.
It turns you into someone
you don't recognize anymore.
I don't want anyone else
to become like Sasuke!
I don't want the Leaf and Cloud Villages
to destroy each other!
That's why...
We will eliminate Sasuke!
After that, you can stop the cycle.
What a fool.
We are in a hurry.
We've let you have your say.
Lord Raikage...
The incident in which you tried
to obtain the Hyuga Byakugan
is still unresolved on our side.
The Hidden Leaf swallowed
tears of blood and
avoided fighting the Cloud,
who fueled the fires of war.
It's thanks to those noble sacrifices
that your people still exist.
Please try not to forget that.
Right here and now,
this young ninja,
no matter how awkwardly,
is bowing his head in his concern
for the Cloud and Leaf,
village and nation.
Lord Raikage...
As one of the Five Kage,
what do you think of this?
A ninja does not bow
his head so easily!
A ninja values action and strength!
Concessions are forbidden
in agreements made between ninja.
The history of man is a history of war.
Since the three Great Ninja Wars
every nation, and every land
has tried to obtain powerful ninjutsu.
Those without power are crushed.
That is the truth of the ninja world.
The Akatsuki will be branded
as wanted fugitives.
Then, not only I, but the whole
world will hunt Sasuke down.
Yet you bow your head for this criminal
and plead for mercy for your friend.
In the ninja world,
that is not friendship!
Boy from the Hidden Leaf,
think hard on what you must do!
The ninja world does not indulge fools!
Let's go!
Naruto...
Enough already.
Raise your head.
We have been waiting for you.
He's the one.
The old one in the middle.
So that's... Danzo!
Please remove your Kage hats.
In response to Lord Raikage's request,
the five Kage have assembled here.
I am Mifune, your moderator.
The Five Kage Summit Conference
is called into order.
I shall speak first. Hear me.
There's such a difference
in Kage these days.
To be a Kage at your age is quite
an accomplishment, Lord Kazekage.
It seems your father trained you
extremely well,
except in the area of proper etiquette.
You're probably right.
It is the reason why
I can be here as Kazekage.
You certainly are cocky.
Lord Tsuchikage,
there's no need to make fun of him.
Continue, Lord Kazekage.
I am a former Jinchuriki.
I was captured by the Akatsuki,
- they took my Tailed Beast
-The nerve of that Tsuchikage!
- And nearly killed me.
- Quiet!
So I consider the Akatsuki
extremely dangerous.
I sought the cooperation of the five
Kage many times, but was ignored.
Except by the previous Hokage.
At a time when various lands
have had their Jinchuriki stolen
the response by this group
has been far too slow!
How can the Hidden Villages of
the Five Great Nations serve
as an example when they allow
their Jinchuriki to be taken?
It is an embarrassment!
It is common sense to resolve this
in utmost secrecy.
Seeking the help of other lands
just because of that is nonsense!
Saving face... Prestige...
Such old-fashioned beliefs.
Such a brat.
Old-fashioned beliefs aside...
I will acknowledge that as the
Mizukage, I have delayed action.
However, having our Tailed Beast
stolen is no cause for immediate fear.
Controlling a Tailed Beast requires
skill, knowledge and time.
The Jinchuriki and the Tailed Beast must
mature together and adapt to each other.
And still, controlling
the Tailed Beast is difficult.
It is not a simple task.
Isn't that so, Lord Kazekage?
The only ones who were capable
of controlling a Tailed Beast were
Madara Uchiha and
the First Hokage, Hashirama Senju.
Also, Fourth Mizukage Yagura,
and Lord Raikage's younger brother,
Killer Bee.
However...
- Chojuro!
- Right!
This is a place of discussion.
Please refrain from disruptive actions.
Stand down, Fu, Torune.
You too, Kankuro, Temari.
Ao, Chojuro. I'm fine.
Yes, ma'am.
Let us continue our discussion.
The Hidden Leaf, Stone, Sand and Mist...
rogue ninja from your villages
make up the Akatsuki!
And that is not all!
From our investigations,
we know that among you,
including your previous Kage,
there are those who used the Akatsuki!
Used them?!
I do not trust you!
I had no intention of even
discussing this with you.
But the reason I convened this summit
is to question your loyalty!
What do you mean, "used" the Akatsuki?
You are the Kazekage,
yet you have not been informed?
Ask the elders back home!
You used the Akatsuki in the past war!
The Great Nations are heading
towards uniform stability.
They are moving from military expansion
to military disarmament.
As fear and the threat of war
diminishes between nations,
Hidden Villages, which are
the source of its military strength,
become costly hindrances.
And yet, carelessly downsizing
the villages poses a risk.
What if war suddenly breaks out?
It would be a problem to depend on
ninja who have no experience in war.
It would mean certain defeat!
And one way to reduce that risk is
mercenary soldiers.
Namely, the Akatsuki?
It takes effort and money to train
skilled ninja from your own village.
But the Akatsuki,
which makes war its livelihood,
is made up of experienced professionals.
Furthermore, they can be hired
for cheap.
Best of all,
they return exceptional results.
Get serious, Tsuchikage!
The Sand used the Akatsuki
to destroy the Hidden Leaf.
I'm speaking of Orochimaru!
It is not clear if he had broken away
from the Akatsuki or not.
But as a result, your father,
the Fourth Kazekage,
and the Third Hokage Hiruzen, died.
And frankly, it's hard not to
rule out the idea
that this was someone's scheme.
The old fox.
The most suspicious is the Hidden Mist!
You Mist do not conduct diplomacy.
There are even rumors that
the Akatsuki originated there!
Since we have come this far
I will speak honestly.
Is Lady Fifth going to reveal...
There were suspicions that
someone was manipulating Yagura,
our Fourth Mizukage.
And there was a possibility that
it was the Akatsuki.
No one wanted this to
get blown out of proportion.
Each and every one of you...
Hold your tongue, Raikage!
Ultimately, it is because your village
disregarded the disarmament efforts
and sought powerful ninjutsu.
We had no choice but to counter
by hiring the Akatsuki!
What?!
Before we start arguing
about the situation,
there is a statement
I have been waiting to make.
What is it?
The leader of the Akatsuki is...
probably Madara Uchiha.
Are you sure of that?
Hasn't he been dead for several decades?
He is right.
He died long ago.
I do not know the details.
But the information is quite reliable.
Are you saying he is immortal?!
Perhaps.
To think... that he was really a monster.
I want to speak on behalf
of the neutral nations.
The leader of the Akatsuki was
able to read the times well.
Despite stabilization,
nations had private suspicions
and the Akatsuki took advantage
of that weakness to amass its power.
What are you trying to say?!
Calm down.
Turn calamity into good fortune.
It is extremely rare for all
five Kage to assemble.
What do you say?
Until the Akatsuki is eliminated,
why not establish
the world's first Allied Shinobi Forces
of the Five Hidden Villages?
An allied force?
That is a fine plan.
We are in an emergency state.
Cooperation is crucial.
It's going perfectly.
Going forward, we must determine
a chain of command.
We must avoid any further confusion.
So? Who will we choose to
lead the allied forces?
Leaving that to you five
will only result in arguments.
So I ask that you respect
the position of the neutral nations
and allow me to come up
with a proposal
to decide who among you
five Kage is most suitable.
This spells the end of Tsunade's era.
Presently, only Hidden Leaf Village
has a Jinchuriki, the Nine-Tails.
The key is how to utilize it.
How about granting
the supreme authority
of the Allied Shinobi Forces
to the Hokage?
If you all approve,
I will accept this appointment.
Why the Hokage?!
He is known as
"The Shinobi of Darkness"!
We cannot let him take charge!
Then whom would you suggest?
Not one of the Akatsuki came
from my village!
This important post requires trust!
I should be the one to...
I cannot agree to that.
What?!
I am well aware that passion
and strength are essential
in bringing the strong together.
But someone like you,
who lets his emotions rule
his use of power,
would send the Allied Forces into
disarray, just like that desk.
I am simply making
an objective, rational observation
as a representative of
a neutral nation.
Lord Kazekage is much
too young to wield such power.
He does not yet have
much pull with nations.
His title of Kazekage alone
is inadequate.
Lord Tsuchikage, on the other hand,
is too advanced in years
and gives the impression of
one whose power has waned.
And, he used the Akatsuki too much.
He is the least trustworthy.
Lady Mizukage's Hidden Mist is said
to be the birthplace of the Akatsuki.
There is the fear that inside information
will be leaked to them.
That there are spies.
We do not know why the Akatsuki
is gathering the Tailed Beasts
or what they intend to do with them.
But we cannot let them
have the Nine-Tails.
The Nine-Tails belongs
to the Hidden Leaf.
Hence, I believe that the Hokage
is the logical choice.
First, I refuse to recognize
an Allied Shinobi Force
that would compromise
the security of my village!
Something about this
just doesn't feel right.
I'd better check.
Chojuro...
Be prepared for battle.
Huh?
Huh? Where'd that guy go?
Ready?
Yeah.
Then begin.
Byakugan!
Th-This is...
What's the meaning of this?
That right shoulder and right arm...
and the color of the right eye...
There's no mistake.
It's the color of Shisui Uchiha's eye!
He was a formidable foe
that I fought against once.
I'll never forget his color!
Lord Hokage!
I ask that you show us your right eye
underneath that bandage.
What's going on?
I believe you stole
Shisui Uchiha's eye
and then transplanted it into
your right eye, did you not?
Shisui... Uchiha?
The man praised alongside
Itachi Uchiha
as the Uchiha's most gifted in
the use of ocular jutsu?
Yes.
Shisui's particular ocular jutsu
allowed him to enter others' minds,
make them go through phantom
experiences and manipulate them.
The victim would be totally unaware
that he was being manipulated.
It was an ocular jutsu of
the highest degree!
Hokage! Don't tell me Mifune
is being...
But... that's...
My right eye is also a precious spoil
of war, from a battle against the Hyuga.
So like you, I am not really one
to talk.
But you cannot fool my eye,
which saw through the genjutsu cast
upon the Fourth Mizukage!
And...
Why you!
Hello!
Sasuke Uchiha has snuck in!
Now, where could he be hiding?!
What?!
Sasuke?
- Him?
- What's he doing here?!
The one with the Sharingan?
The one who took down
Haku and Zabuza?
Who's he?
A member of the Akatsuki.
I believe his name was...
Let's all go and look for Sasuke!
Yeah!
Where is Sasuke Uchiha?!
Answer me!
Th-This guy is super fast!
If you refuse to answer,
I will show you no mercy!
You leave me no choice.
I'll give you a hint, so...
Shee! Begin!
Yes sir!
You didn't have to kill him.
We could have taken him in and tortured him
into revealing intel about the Akatsuki.
No one in the Akatsuki talks.
They are extremely loyal.
Okisuke, Urakaku.
Issue an order to search for Sasuke.
And issue a Number 2
battle-ready state alert.
- Yes, sir!
Lord Raikage!
You! The eye-patch from the Mist!
Watch the Hokage!
Shee! Darui!
Come!
I'm so sorry about the desk
and the wall.
Darui, never mind that. Let's go!
What a violent fellow.
The Cloud's rascal hasn't changed
even as a Kage.
Number 2 battle-ready state alert.
Search for the intruder, Sasuke Uchiha.
Dispatch three squads
to the tower entrance.
Create a line of defense.
Roger.
Move out!
What's this?!
What is it, Karin?
The Samurai's movements
have suddenly become flurried.
I think they're looking for us!
What?!
But we didn't do anything to be spotted.
I bet it was Zetsu.
They're already gone.
Sasuke...
Where are you now?
And what are you thinking?
Do you think about me, Sakura,
or Kakashi-sensei... even a little?
Hey...
How about we talk, Naruto Uzumaki?
You!
A Rasengan right off the bat, huh?
You know it doesn't work on me, right?
Naruto, you just stay put.
As expected, Sharingan Kakashi.
You are fast.
We won't let you get your hands on
Naruto that easily, Madara Uchiha.
You did just hear my last line,
didn't you?
No attacks work against
Madara Uchiha.
I don't know if you are
merely erasing your presence
or if this is an astral projection,
but I know it's necessary for you
to manifest physically
in order to capture Naruto.
Otherwise, you couldn't actually
grab him.
We'll aim for that.
This here is now my territory.
I never thought it would be easy.
You see, I have my own plan.
But right now, I'd rather talk.
Talk?
Yes. What was it that made Pain, Nagato,
turn into a traitor?
Naruto... You have aroused my curiosity.
Who cares about something like that?!
What do you intend to do
with Sasuke?!
Tell me about Sasuke!
Sasuke, huh?
Very well. I'll tell you.
About the man whose hatred
of the ninja world
runs through his bones
to his very core.
About Sasuke Uchiha.
Sasuke's story cannot be told
without mentioning Itachi.
So first, hear the truth about Itachi.
It doesn't look like he'll be moving
around again.
Lord Ao,
please confirm if the Hokage's
Ocular jutsu is still engaged or not.
No. The flow of chakra in
his chakra network is very calm.
The jutsu is undone.
Relax. It's not a jutsu I can use
that many times in a day.
I'll decide that. For you are a man
who cannot be trusted.
I never imagined the Byakugan had fallen
into outside hands.
Had the traitor been a Hyuga
from the Hidden Leaf,
he would have been killed immediately.
You are probably planning to dispose of me
for learning your secret,
but that will not happen.
I will be your opponent then.
Because there may just be a connection
between the jutsu that had control over
the Fourth Mizukage and your ocular powers.
Lord Hokage, ninjutsu is prohibited
in this room.
You have lost your credibility.
Even if you hadn't resorted to this,
I may have chosen you, you know.
"May have chosen" was unacceptable.
I was prepared to use
any means necessary
in order to protect
the world of the ninja.
This world must become one.
In the same way that
the First Hokage, Hashirama,
united our people and
founded our village.
This time, I shall unite the villages
and create one ninja world.
There is no way this ninja world can
be united through discussions alone.
It takes time to realize one's ideals.
Impatience makes one lose sight of
his surroundings and invites failure.
That's you right now.
Nothing will change by
working slowly and ethically.
Sooner or later, the Akatsuki will
destroy the ninja world.
Well, that is just an impossible dream.
It may sound noble, but ultimately,
it will only breed distrust,
ill will and resentment.
Why Danzo, we don't even trust
your words at this point.
Whether I am trusted or not,
it's the outcome that is essential.
Unable to trust each other.
If that is the world... If that is
being human, there is no future.
What is it you want to say?
Understanding and trusting
in one another...
If we lose that, only fear will remain
in the world.
Acting with no regard for what is right...
resigning oneself...
I find such things hard to
accept these days.
For a kid who knows nothing
about governing a village yet,
you speak so simply of complex matters.
Now's your chance to
ask anything you'd like.
As your seniors, we're willing
to answer any questions you have.
Right, Danzo?
How dare you, you old geezer!
Don't, Kankuro.
He's still Tsuchikage.
The leader of another village.
Did she just say "still"?
Ignore them.
Then let me ask you this.
Sure. I will answer anything, kid.
When did you all discard your convictions?
What a pure-hearted child.
So Gaara, what will we do now?
We cooperated with the Hidden Leaf
on their mission to rescue Sasuke Uchiha.
But he's now descended
to joining the Akatsuki.
Sasuke Uchiha...
Hey! Don't go off without your guards!
Gramps, he's scored a point on you.
Shut it!
Lord Tsuchikage... What do we do?
Shall we go forth to battle?
Fool! What if I throw my back out?!
But I want to see this Sasuke who
supposedly took down Bro Deidara.
Do as you please.
Just remember, if you get caught
in the Raikage's crossfire, you'll die.
So stay out his way.
Gotcha!
What about you, Akatsuchi?
I'll stay with Lord Tsuchikage,
in case he has trouble with his back.
Later, then.
Lord Danzo, please allow
one of us to go forth
in order to retrieve the Sharingan.
You Hidden Leaf will stay as you are!
Lord Raikage has so ordered!
Fu, Torune... stand down.
We will play nice for now.
It's no good.
There are too many of them.
We'll be found in no time and captured.
Zetsu, was it? I'll get him for this!
So that's how they use chakra?
I'm very irritated right now.
If you attack, I'll show no mercy.
I would say the same to you!
He repelled it?
It's similar to our sword technique!
Karin, you don't have to monitor
the Samurai anymore.
Focus on Danzo's location.
But what about the Samurai?
I'll deal with them.
Just find Danzo.
Huh?!
Sasuke's chakra is different!
Hey... After all his warnings telling me
not to kill anyone...
This is...
He's not the same Sasuke
as before.
He's more intense than when he is
in the Curse Mark Second State.
And much...
colder.
He's not alone!
There's one chakra that is erasing
many other chakras!
No doubt it's coming from Sasuke!
Which way?!
Right below us!
Lord Raikage, you're not going to...
Something's coming. And it's huge!
What is that?!
Hey brat!
I'm going to teach you
the fear of true fury!
Sasuke! Don't go in alone!
He's lost his cool!
Water Style: Water Wall!
His attack, huh?
Lightning Style: Wave of Inspiration!
Looks like the intel was right, Boss.
This guy seems to possess
a lightning chakra nature.
Plus he has a fire chakra nature.
He's bound to use Fire Style
at some point.
Darui, keep Water Style
ready at all times.
Yeah.
Doesn't it look like
they have intel on Sasuke?
Hey, the one in the middle.
Isn't that...?
They're Hidden Cloud Jonin.
The huge one in the middle
is their Raikage.
They won't let us pass easily.
Seeking reinforcements!
Sasuke got us!
I'll stop him!
Something's coming!
Lightning Illusion: Flash Pillar!
Is he trying to blind us?!
No!
Jugo, don't waver.
This is a genjutsu.
Not bad, Sharingan. However...
You may have seen through
the genjutsu, but it's too late!
Damn it! My Executioner's Blade!
It'd already gotten cracked against
the Eight-Tails. It can't be helped.
Who told you to interfere?
We came to help you,
and this is what we get?
Although that's just like you.
Ninja sure fight rough.
They're crazy!
Shee, check and see if they've got
any other allies around.
I don't want to worry about
more popping in.
I'm sure there was one more.
But if I focus on that one,
it'll be hard to stay in the fight.
We don't need you.
Boss and I can handle them.
Uh-oh!
If I keep searching for Danzo like this,
I'll be the one found by that Shee.
Karin will probably extinguish
her chakra and hide.
She's got that ability.
That guy in the back is probably
a Sensory-Type ninja.
We have to take him down.
I'll do it.
I'll kill 'em!
His change in personality is
more surprising than his appearance.
Focus! This guy's chakra is ridiculous!
Jugo voluntarily gave in to
his killer impulse this time.
You think he still remembers
that we're on his side?
Now then, who's first?!
Don't get cocky!
You're mine!
Nice blade you got there.
Can't have this just
because yours broke.
One down.
You can't take me down with
a mere Sharingan!
Lord Raikage's nerve transmission
and reaction speed
are on par with that of
the Leaf's Yellow Flash.
Impressive that these guys are
keeping up as well as they are!
But Lord Raikage has manipulated Lightning
Style chakra to augment his reflexes.
Not even the Sharingan will
be able to keep up with him.
Plus, there's still...
Die!
Did he get him?!
He took Lord Raikage's blow
and still survived?!
I-Is this is... a genjutsu?
These guys are cleverly using
each other's attacks to divert attention.
And I fell for it. Damn it!
Can't... move...
Shee?!
Jugo can be useful, after all.
They can't detect me now.
Now's my chance to find Danzo.
Huh?!
I killed him! I killed the guy!
Who's next?!
You're lying!
That's nonsense!
No, it can't be.
Stop joking around.
Who'd believe that story?
It's not a lie. That's
the truth about Itachi.
He died for Sasuke's sake and
for the Hidden Leaf Village.
What does that mean?
Even if it is true,
if Sasuke is aware of this,
why would he help the Akatsuki?
Knowing him, he would return to
the Hidden Leaf to carry on Itachi's will.
As Sasuke's teacher and his friends,
you might have assumed you understood
Sasuke's true feelings.
But you were badly mistaken.
He's the real thing. A true avenger.
That's what he is.
Did you turn Sasuke into that?!
No, I didn't.
Sasuke chose this himself.
It's a lie!
I took a gamble too.
Would Sasuke carry
on Itachi's wishes,
or would he seek revenge against
the Hidden Leaf?
He chose vengeance.
In essence, he was meant to
be on our side.
Sasuke's goal at this moment is to
take revenge against the Hidden Leaf
for what they did to Itachi
and the Uchiha Clan.
Why?
Why him?
Why did this happen?
How could he turn to revenge?!
It was inevitable.
It is the Uchiha Clan's blood-soaked
destiny of hate.
Like a curse that has been
passed down through the ages.
A curse?
Yes. A curse of hatred,
which started generations ago
with the Sage of the Six Paths,
founder of the ninja world.
The Sage of the Six Paths?
That's just a myth.
The Rinnegan was
no more than a mutation!
Myths are born from truth.
Long ago, the Sage of the Six Paths
preached the Ninshu
and tried to lead the way to peace.
But before he could realize his dream,
time ran out.
The Sage of the Six Paths decided to
entrust the power and will of the Ninshu
to his two children.
The older son was born with
the Sage's eyes.
He inherited the Sage's chakra
and mental energy,
and believed that strength
was crucial to peace.
The younger son was born with
the gift of the Sage's body.
He inherited the Sage's life force
and physical energy,
and believed that love was
crucial to peace.
Ultimately, the Sage was forced to choose
his successor from his deathbed.
However, his decision
created a curse of hatred that
has continued for generations.
What do you mean by that?
Instead of his older son,
who sought strength,
the Sage felt that the younger son,
who sought love,
was more suitable, and named him
his successor.
The firstborn, who had long expected
to follow in his father's footsteps,
could not accept the decision.
Filled with rage,
he challenged his younger brother.
Even as time passed and
new generations were born,
the descendants of the two brothers,
continued to battle.
The descendants of the older brother
came to be known as the Uchiha.
And the descendants of the younger brother
were called the Senju.
As Madara Uchiha, my battle with
the First Hokage, Hashirama Senju,
was destined to take place.
This is only the second time I've met you.
But I can tell that you hold
the Senju's Will of Fire within you.
I can see the First Hokage inside you.
Even after death, he lives on.
He, whom I admired,
yet he was my rival.
And the man I hated most.
The Senju and the Uchiha.
The Will of Fire and hatred.
Naruto and Sasuke.
You both will probably be
the next chosen by fate.
The Uchiha was destined to
be a clan of vengeance.
Sasuke has shouldered
the entire burden of the Uchiha's hatred
and intends to strike the world
with that curse.
It is the most powerful weapon.
It's his friend and source of power,
this thing called hatred.
And it is Sasuke's ninja way!
Elbow Bolt!
A thrust attack using the Lightning Style
to increase force and penetration.
The same jutsu used
by Kakashi Hatake!
I wear Lightning Style armor,
yet you actually touched me.
That is some jutsu.
Damn it! It didn't work?!
No, it didn't.
Sasuke's dead.
Liger Bomb!
It's over.
Huh?
So that's the Mangekyo Sharingan.
Shee, you okay?
Darui... did you settle your fight?
Maybe.
No one's ever lived through
that Liger Bomb, until now.
Those bones and stuff...
What is he anyway?
I fell for his genjutsu and lost.
I still don't have full control of my body.
Geniuses like him appear once in a while.
Reinforcements?!
Hey Shee... The Uchiha's eye...
Doesn't it seem a bit different
from before?
Mangekyo Sharingan?!
I get it. That's what made
Lord Raikage activate that much.
He intends to counter with
his Body Flicker Jutsu.
Maybe I'm too weak against
the Lightning Style.
My body's too numb and
can't liquefy properly.
Raikage's chakra has grown enormous.
He's at Tailed Beast levels!
Come on, brat!
Amaterasu!
Put out the fire!
It's not ordinary fire!
Don't get close to it!
Lateral Bolt of Pain!
He's manipulating the Black Flames?!
He can even change
their chakra form!
Don't tell me he's more proficient
with the Black Flames than Itachi?
Don't underestimate the Raikage!
Lord Raikage! Impossible...
He's sacrificing his left arm.
You're finished!
Guillotine Drop!
Inferno Style: Flame Control!
Sand!
This is...
Gaara of the Sand.
Wind Scythe Jutsu!
So these are the flames
that never burn out, Amaterasu, huh?
You Samurai, get back.
This is a problem for the ninja world.
There is no need for Samurai
to become casualties.
Th-Thank you, Lord Kazekage.
What's going on?
Why did you interfere, Kazekage?!
Whether I punish you or not
depends on your answer!
If you had continued and
performed another attack,
the Black Flames would
have further injured you.
Besides, I wish to speak
to Sasuke Uchiha.
Boss!
Shee, hurry and stop the bleeding!
I'm going to attack Sasuke
the minute you're done.
Yes sir!
Sasuke was able to lay
a hand on Lord Raikage,
who was clad in
his Lightning Style armor.
And he's still alive despite
two heavy attacks.
Perhaps Sasuke captured Bee after all.
Your eyes are still as they were
in the past.
I once told you that you
have eyes like mine.
Eyes that seek strength.
Eyes overflowing with hate
and a hunger for blood.
Eyes itching to kill the one who threw you
into the hell called solitude.
Making revenge your sustenance
resolves nothing.
I learned that lesson personally.
It's not too late for you.
Do not cast yourself into a world where
you are all alone, obsessed with hate.
You won't be able to return.
And if I returned?
What would I find there?
Forget it, Gaara.
Naruto already failed at convincing him.
He's just a criminal now, who has
fallen to the level of the Akatsuki.
He's not like you.
Besides, neither the Raikage
nor the others
who have been victimized by
the Akatsuki will remain silent.
After attacking the Five Kage Summit,
he's now wanted internationally.
This guy has no future.
Sasuke, you and I are alike.
We've both walked through
the darkness of this world.
That's why you should be able to see
even the faintest glimmer of light.
In the past and even now.
I closed my eyes long ago.
My goals exist only in the darkness.
Leave your personal feelings
out of this.
You are the Kazekage.
I know.
I understand.
I'm impressed that you can guard
against my Inferno Style so effectively.
Your ultimate defense is
in good shape.
A-Amazing.
Found them! Danzo's among them!
It seems the enemy has
a Sensory-Type ninja.
They may come here in time.
What do we do?
Nothing for now.
When they arrive,
we'll slip out during the chaos.
Stop whispering over there!
Sorry, but I'm a Sensory-Type too.
I'm fully aware that the enemy is on to us.
But you are not to make a move.
We'll deal with the enemy.
It seems this summit is about
to become very interesting.
Are you done yet, Shee?!
Just a little longer.
Comrades of the Hidden Sand!
I will fire the first shot!
Press ahead after me!
Right!
Gale Style: Laser Circus!
Red Secret Technique: Puppet Triad!
Cyclone Scythe Jutsu!
Sand Shower Barrage!
Wh-What is this?!
Gaara... This is even greater than
your ultimate defense.
Did he use that to guard
against my attacks?
This chakra...
It's the same as that genjutsu earlier.
This doesn't look good.
Was this what he wanted to test?
This chakra...
He's no longer the old Sasuke.
It's too cold.
What is that?
The power... of darkness?
A power that only those who have awakened
the Mangekyo in both eyes can achieve.
This is the third power...
Susano'o.
Susano'o?
So that's the Mangekyo Sharingan?
That Uchiha... Always has something
hidden up his sleeve.
Darui, everyone from the Sand!
Please step back!
He's aiming for the pillars!
The pillars!
The ceiling won't hold!
What the hell?!
Were you able to pinpoint
Danzo's location?
Y-Yeah.
Take me there.
What about Jugo and Suigetsu?
Their chakra is still...
Never mind! Danzo comes first.
Hurry and take me there.
O-Okay.
They're all right too.
Sorry... Kazekage.
Looks like Sasuke used
that instant to get away.
If things are this bad here,
who knows what may have
happened to the others.
We're going after Sasuke immediately!
Looks like he's headed up.
Naruto... What would you have done?
Good thing that blade missed, but still...
I wonder how Sasuke,
Karin and Jugo are doing.
I'll still make it.
All right.
Naruto...
You will probably end up
fighting Sasuke one day.
Rather... I will throw Sasuke at you.
A battle that was predestined ages ago.
I'll have Sasuke prove
the existence of the Uchiha.
Sasuke isn't your toy!
Quit making selfish plans!
You think you can make Sasuke
have a change of heart,
like you did with Nagato?
That's just as selfish, Naruto.
Controlling people requires the skill to
manipulate the darkness in their souls.
Although, Nagato just happened to
be easily influenced by others.
Don't compare Nagato to yourself!
His ways were different,
but he truly wished for peace!
But you're different!
You're right.
The existence of the Uchiha...
If that's all you want to validate,
why hunt the Tailed Beasts?
Just what is your goal?
What do you hope to accomplish?
Let's see...
If anything, it's to become complete.
Complete?!
What do you mean?!
Talking to you is meaningless.
I'll explain more
in an appropriate place.
Our conversation... was quite fun.
So long.
Sasuke...
There's absolutely no trace left.
Space-Time Ninjutsu...
It's such a troublesome jutsu.
Kakashi-sensei, what he was saying...
It's dangerous to believe his story.
But if it's true, Sasuke is-
Naruto...
I know how you feel,
but you must not be impatient.
For now, we'll keep what Madara
said to ourselves...
in absolute secrecy.
We're in the midst of reconstruction
and must avoid unnecessary mayhem.
Furthermore, until we cross-check
the facts, we can't trust him.
There's too much that
we don't know about his claim
that the higher ups in the Hidden Leaf used
Itachi to slaughter the Uchiha clan.
Especially you, Naruto.
Do you understand?
Yeah, I know.
He's coming.
Above?!
He's using the Sharingan.
Sasuke! Danzo is escaping!
Lord Mizukage and Chojuro, stay here!
I'm going after Danzo!
Since the summit isn't over yet!
All right. But don't pursue him too far.
Yes ma'am!
I'll leave the Akatsuki rebels to you.
My back can't take it.
You people can deal with them
as you please.
Sounds good to me.
Karin! Come!
There it is.
Lady Mizukage's Kekkei Genkai,
Lava Style Jutsu!
You Akatsuki manipulated
the Fourth Mizukage
and trampled all over the Hidden Mist.
And yet when I look at you closely,
you of the Uchiha Clan are quite handsome.
Don't interfere.
Such a fine man...
What a waste.
I'll at least give you a kiss
that will make you melt.
A-A kiss?!
Just who the hell are you?!
And quit trying to seduce him,
you old hag!
Lady Mizukage is intent on fighting!
I must protect her! But...
He's the one who killed Zabuza.
Do I even have a chance?
Yes, even someone like me
has a chance. I can do it.
I have to keep telling myself that.
Lord Tsuchikage,
if you're not going to participate,
please keep your head lowered.
Not that again!
Keep my head lowered? The nerve.
Chojuro!
Y-Yes ma'am!
Hiramekarei, unleash!
Every cell in my body hurts.
Is this the side effect of using
Susano'o...
for an extended period?
I haven't even achieved
complete possession form
and yet there's so much pain.
What did Itachi endure?
It's just the two of us now.
S-So he was killed?
I couldn't read his chakra,
so I thought something was strange.
The wall next to you...
I closed it up after that first attack.
It's now a completely sealed room.
There's no way to escape.
I use three chakra natures:
Fire, Water and Earth.
That's why I possess two Kekkei Genkai.
Vapor Style: Solid Fog Jutsu.
Sasuke!
He's on the other side of that wall.
It's melting.
This is bad.
Sasuke's chakra is weakening!
He's overdoing it!
It seems you got roughed up
pretty badly by Lord Raikage earlier.
Sorry, but I have no intention
of helping you.
It pains my heart every time
I see such a handsome man melt away.
But you have to die.
So this time, it's corrosive acid mist?
What?
Wha—?!
What is it?!
This chakra...
Th-This is that Akatsuki from earlier.
It's that man's...
I can't believe no one detected
my Spore jutsu.
The Five Kage are just a bunch of idiots.
He's...
using my chakra.
He's absorbing chakra and growing?!
When did he do this?
It's a time-delay jutsu that
he planted before Raikage beat him.
Why you-
Damn... What now?!
My chakra is returning!
This is...
Sasuke! Are you all right?!
The mist will leak to where
the others are.
I have to adjust the pH level.
It seems they're having difficulties.
Akatsuchi, shall we go and
lend them a hand soon?
Okay!
Earth Style: Weighted Boulder Jutsu.
So a brat like you defeated Deidara?
Well, I hold no grudge against you,
but many ninja wish you dead.
So long.
Particle Style: Atomic Dismantling Jutsu!
Sasuke!
Sasuke's chakra is... gone!
You're right,
because I've disassembled his body
at a near molecular level!
You're next.
Wh-Why you...
Sasuke?
Where is Sasuke?!
Kankuro.
Got it.
Th-Thank you.
I am indebted to you.
Tsuchikage! Where is Sasuke?!
I turned him into dust.
What?! I wanted to do that!
You had no right-
You still... have a chance.
So stop making a fuss, Raikage.
My name is Madara Uchiha.
Sasuke!
I have something I want
to explain to you all.
And once you comprehend it,
I want to pose a question.
What is it?!
It's about my plan...
Project Tsuki no Me.
It seems Shee was right.
The Hokage did make an escape.
Yes, because of Sasuke.
Nothing planned by the Akatsuki
is going to be good.
Who knows what you're up to?
Sasuke is...
Bring Sasuke back!
Then listen to my explanation.
It will all depend on your answer.
Calm down, Raikage.
Let's hear him out,
and take it from there.
Revive Sasuke.
So that's Madara's ability?
Space-Time Ninjutsu.
Where am I?
Now then, are you all ready to listen?
Why are you trying to win Sasuke over?
A Sharingan capable of awakening
the Susano'o is rare.
I like to stock up on good eyes.
By battling the Five Kage,
I wanted him to hone
his ocular powers even more.
I'm the one who sent Sasuke here.
I was intending on weakening the Five Kage
and taking you all hostage.
It seems that is still not possible.
Taking us hostage?
For what purpose?!
To smoothly implement
the aforementioned Project Tsuki no Me.
It's quite shocking to learn that
Madara Uchiha is still alive,
but why would a man of your skill
resort to such a roundabout method?
Surely, you have the strength
to bring any plan to fruition.
The injuries I sustained during
my battle with Hashirama were too severe.
I have no strength in me now.
You could say I am merely
a shell of my old self.
Is this a plan to restore yourself?
You could say that.
But that's not all.
What are you scheming?!
Just what is this Project Tsuki no Me?!
I want to take my time talking to you.
Let me sit down.
We're asking you
what kind of plan it is!
All shall become one with me,
and result in a complete
possession form that unites all.
Become one? Unite all?
What do you mean?!
The Uchiha have
an ancient stone tablet
that has been passed down
through the generations.
It still exists underground in
the Hidden Leaf Village.
Upon it are written secrets, engraved
by the Sage of the Six Paths himself.
It cannot be read unless
you possess ocular powers.
With the Sharingan, the Mangekyo
Sharingan and Rinnegan, in that order,
the contents become
increasingly decipherable.
Your story is unlikely.
The Sage of the Six Paths doesn't...
It is the truth!
He did exist.
And he left the stone tablet.
Don't change the subject!
What does your plan have to do
with the Sage of the Six Paths?!
Do you know why he became
a legendary figure
and a godlike figure
that is revered as the God of Shinobi?
There lies the link between my plan
and this man.
Madara Uchiha...
You possess the Mangekyo Sharingan
and among the Akatsuki,
there was one who possessed
the Rinnegan.
You know everything, don't you?
We're listening.
He once saved the world
from a certain monster.
Monster?
Gaara, you also had one part of
that monster sealed inside you.
That monster was the combination of
every Tailed Beast in existence.
Something that possessed
the most powerful chakra.
The Ten-Tails!
Shukaku, Gaara's Tailed Beast
known as...
The One-Tail!
The fiery Monster Cat of
the Hidden Cloud's Yugito Nii...
The Two-Tails!
The former Mizukage's...
Three-Tails!
Roshi of the Lava Style's...
Four-Tails!
Han of the Hidden Stone's...
Five-Tails!
The rogue ninja Utakata's...
Six-Tails!
Fuu of the Hidden Waterfall's...
Seven-Tails!
Raikage's younger brother,
Killer Bee's...
Eight-Tails!
And the fox spirit of the Hidden Leaf...
The Nine-Tails!
The Ten-Tails' chakra was simply
divided up into the nine Tailed Beasts,
by the Sage of the Six Paths.
I don't like where this story is headed.
Is that why the Akatsuki are
gathering the Tailed Beasts?
The Sage of the Six Paths
developed a certain ninjutsu
in order to protect the world
from the Ten-Tails.
Even today, that ninjutsu is still
being secretly passed down.
It is the Sealing jutsu process
for Jinchuriki.
Yes, the Sage of the Six Paths was
the Ten-Tails' Jinchuriki.
In order to suppress it,
he sealed the Ten-Tails within his body.
The Sage, who saved
a world terrorized by the Ten-Tails,
became a savior and won praise as a god.
But if the Sage died, the powerful
and demonic chakra of the Ten-Tails
would once again be released
unto the world.
Fearing this, at the time of his death,
the Sage of the Six Paths summoned
every last ounce of his power
to partition the Ten-Tails' chakra
into nine parts
and scattered them across the world.
Then he sealed the Ten-Tails' body,
now devoid of chakra,
and hurled it into the sky.
And it became the moon.
What a tall tale!
As if a human could do such a thing.
When he became
the Jinchuriki of the Ten-Tails,
the Sage of the Six Paths went
beyond the realm of humans.
I understand now that
you seek that inhuman power
by gathering the chakra of the nine,
namely all, of the Tailed Beasts.
But what will you do with all that power?
Revive the Ten-Tails.
And I will become
the Ten-Tails' Jinchuriki.
I will use its power to strengthen
my ocular powers,
and activate a certain jutsu.
A certain jutsu?! What is it?
What do you intend to do?
A massive genjutsu,
where I project my eyes upon the moon.
Infinite Tsukuyomi.
I will cast a genjutsu on every human
that walks the earth.
And in that genjutsu, I will control
all humans and unify the world.
A world without hatred or war.
Everything will become one with me,
everything will be united.
That is my Project Tsuki no Me.
Stop joking around!
I'm not handing the world over to you!
Peace that exists only as
an illusion is deception.
Peace is only meaningful when it is
genuinely achieved in the real world.
So what exists inside such a world?
There is no hope, no dreams!
It's just an escape!
Unite the world, huh?
Danzo mentioned something similar.
But instead of uniting the world,
it just sounds like you want to
make the world yours!
All this talk and yet,
what have you Five Kage accomplished?
You of all people should know by now...
There is no such thing as hope!
To hope is equivalent to giving up,
and it's the biggest deception of all.
Turn over the remaining beasts,
Eight-Tails and Nine-Tails,
and cooperate with my plan.
Or there will be war.
War you say?
The Eight-Tails?
What are you talking about?
Didn't you get Bee?
The attempt to capture
the Eight-Tails failed and he escaped.
He is a ninja who is a perfect Jinchuriki.
Only your younger brother
has got what it takes.
Huh?!
Yeah, I sort of had a feeling about that.
That idiot!
He used that chance to slip away and now,
he's having the time of his life!
Unforgivable!
He's going to get my Iron Claw!
We will not hand over Naruto Uzumaki.
I agree with him!
What about you, Raikage?
There's no way I'll let him have
my younger brother!
I don't have the strength,
but the Tailed Beasts
we've gathered so far, do.
You people have no chance of winning.
We haven't given up hope.
Very well.
I hereby declare the
Fourth Great Ninja War.
The Fourth Great Ninja War?
Are you mad?!
The next time we meet will be
on the battlefield.