By the way, Kakashi-sensei,
who's that on your back?
She's one of Sasuke's comrades.
Not anymore.
I have a lot of questions
I want to ask her,
so I'm taking her
back to the village.
I see. So we're going back
to Hidden Leaf Village.
Naruto, not that way.
What are you saying, Kakashi-sensei?
Hidden Leaf Village is this way.
We forgot something in the Land of Iron.
Right, Sakura?
Forgot something...
Oh!
We should go back
and retrieve it, right?
Yes.
Hmm? What is it?
We're home!
– Lord Bee!
Yo! Long time no see,
Omoi, Karui!
Have ya been getting by cheerfully,
care-free-ly? Merrily?
Of course not!
Not after you suddenly disappeared
from the village like that.
Do you know
how worried we were?!
Now, now! He was safe all this time,
so it's all okay now!
Lord Raikage, welcome home.
I know it's sudden, but we wish
to hold a council right away
regarding what transpired at
the Five Kage Summit.
What? No downtime?
We can't afford to take it easy.
Things are about to
get even hotter.
Why is that?
The Fourth Great Ninja War.
Huh?
An Allied Shinobi Force
has been formed.
Tell them the details
at the meeting.
Also, we'll need to meet
with the Feudal Lord.
I have requested
an audience with him.
Huh?
What's that?
Just a spoil of war from my battle against
one of the Seven Ninja Swordsmen.
It's taken a liking to me.
It won't leave my side.
Wow, so this is one of the Seven Ninja
Swordsmen's blades, huh?
Unbelievable!
As expected of you Lord Bee!
As expected...?
Even the great Me...
just has to let it be.
Well? Did you record the battle?
Yeah.
What about Samehada?
The Eight-Tails took it.
I see. Then...
Yeah.
It went perfectly.
You've got to hand it to Kisame.
I will declare the start of
the Fourth Great Ninja War
at the Five Kage Summit.
So the time is now ripe.
Once I've declared war,
I suspect the Eight-Tails' movements
will be restricted and he'll be confined.
Then you can hunt him
at your own leisure.
I'm ready anytime, but...
First, we infiltrate.
We sneak into their midst
and obtain intel.
So this is an infiltration mission?
Use White Zetsu.
Once he makes contact, he can copy
a person's chakra and create a clone.
Leave it to me.
However, he's weak.
You can't use him in battle,
but he's good for deception.
If fighting the Eight-Tails
gets too exciting,
I might end up almost killing him,
but I accept!
All right.
I'll leave the Eight-Tails
in your hands.
Leave it to me.
Now then, this is where things
start getting tough.
It was good to let Samehada take
a liking to the Eight-Tails.
I never imagined it would even
share chakra with him.
Though that ended up
working in my favor.
Their sensory-type ninja
hasn't caught on yet.
It's not surprising.
Since Samehada takes in
Kisame's chakra and uses it for energy,
they have the same
chakra signature.
The enemy doesn't
know any better.
I could take on
the infiltration mission.
You are weak.
Ultimately, we are going to
capture the Eight-Tails.
Kisame is the suitable one.
But you pulled off
that performance quite well.
It wasn't easy switching places
with Kisame underwater.
I'm not used to it.
Don't you think you're overdoing it?
It was just right for the Eight-Tails.
I guess it's my turn now.
I leave it in your hands.
Water Style:
Super Shark Bomb—
– Double Lariat!
I can undo my Body Substitution
Jutsu now, right?
Yeah.
It's almost feeding time.
Let's merge.
Where'd he go?
I'm adapting to the power.
It feels good. This isn't bad.
I think I'll stir things up a little.
The Akatsuki possess
the Tailed Beasts.
We cannot go on and do nothing.
Besides, they are led by
that Madara Uchiha.
We must do everything we can now.
I know that.
Then hurry up and
give your approval.
Are you willing to lose this war?
But the Allied Shinobi Force...
What if we give them
too much power
and this decision comes back
to haunt us later?
Do you really distrust
your own nation's shinobi that much?
First...
We will need you to come
to a decision soon.
The battery is running low.
It is such a long distance.
Let's conclude this.
Lightning approves this.
Earth agrees with Lightning.
Wind approves this as well.
Why not?
Fire approves it.
All right.
Water approves it as well.
So now, with this...
The formation of
the Allied Shinobi Force is ratified.
Let the record show.
I, Tenga, shall serve as the witness.
Thank you all very much.
This ends the transmission.
It is finally over.
Now it would be good to contact
the Hidden Leaf at once.
Is this is what you forgot?
How could these guys
just lay around sleeping
while you were in
such a bind, Sakura?
Sakura!
They were going to help you.
Apologize properly after
you wake them up.
I will.
You're going to wake them up?
Damn it.
Naruto...
It's my fault that they're asleep.
So be gentle when you wake them.
I feel sick.
You're going to sleep too?
Naruto's like that because of you...
umm, Sakura, right?
It's because of your poison.
What a carefree guy.
He's already asleep.
He's sleeping so soundly.
I think a burden's been
lifted off of him.
However, we don't
have time to waste.
Sakura, wake them up.
Lord Kazekage has returned.
Did you receive
Tobimaru's message?
Yes, ma'am!
Any word from the Feudal Lords?
Yes, just a while ago.
Welcome home, Lady Mizukage.
We received word from
the Feudal Lord.
Let's hear it, go ahead!
Well, that was quick.
Those lords worked quickly because the
Tailed Beasts and Madara were mentioned.
Damn it, this is ridiculous!
We listened to her wishes and
even located Sasuke for her.
Now don't be so upset, Kiba.
Don't act like you're
the only hero here, Sakura.
You told us to keep this
a secret from Naruto,
but Sai went and blabbed it all to him,
on top of which, Sasuke got away.
Kiba!
Be a man and quit complaining.
Speak for yourself, Naruto!
Huh? Me?
Oh, you're right about that!
You are too simple and dumb
to be able to think as complexly
as you've been trying to.
Hey Sai!
Since when did you develop
such a carefree laugh? Huh?
Thank you.
That wasn't a compliment!
What is it, Bushy Brow?
It's like you're back
to your old self, Naruto.
He means you
haven't grown at all.
Once an idiot, always an idiot.
Kiba, you're the idiot!
Idiot!
I don't want to hear that
coming from an idiot!
I've had enough of
your smiling face!
This guy is the complete
opposite of Sasuke.
His chakra is... so...
bright and warm.
What is this?
Deep inside him...
A chakra like this? So dark!
As though...
Sai, you need to explain
everything that's happened.
Who are these guys?
Members of the Foundation,
from the Anbu Black Ops.
It seems you are aware of it too.
The reason why the Curse Mark
placed on us by Lord Danzo is gone.
Is Lord Danzo... dead?
Yes.
That's...
What about his bodyguards,
Foo and Torune?
I'm in the dark about them too.
They were not at the site.
Therefore, I would like to
propose a discussion
about the future of
the Foundation with you.
And with the new Hokage here...
New Hokage?
Kakashi Hatake.
Huh?!
We'll head back ahead of you.
You're going to be the next Hokage,
Kakashi-sensei?
Looks like it's going to be that way.
It's certain, the Akatsuki
is definitely strong.
Their war potential is unknown.
But the true strength of
our Allied Shinobi Forces,
which is unparalleled in history,
is also unknown.
Earth, Water, Fire, Wind,
and Lightning...
If we unite all the shinobi's power,
I believe we can
counter them thoroughly.
Above all, we must win this battle
or the world will end.
Begin stockpiling ninja tools
and rations immediately.
All official missions will be temporarily
halted in preparation for battle.
Give me a list of all shinobi
belonging to the village.
At the same time,
I want each squad to begin
preparing their tactical plans.
No way! Sasuke attacked
the Five Kage Summit?!
I hear they're about to announce it.
Seems there is utter confusion
among the officials.
So it's true that Sasuke is
a member of the Akatsuki,
who crushed the Hidden Leaf.
Looks like this is going to
turn out to be a drag.
These are orders
from Lady Mizukage.
Confirm our supplies of
ninja tools immediately!
Make a list of anything
we're short on!
I don't know about
this Allied Shinobi Forces,
but I won't join up with
those guys from the Stone.
The Akatsuki is a hateful group
that brought
the nightmare of
the Fourth Mizukage upon this nation.
The Hidden Stone has used the
Akatsuki time and again in the past.
The higher-ups may order it,
but there's no way Ganryu
would accept it.
You're being very careful with them.
They are the great masterpieces
of a legendary puppeteer.
I cannot allow myself
to be bested
by the generations of
puppeteers before me.
What about you?
I just sent off messages to those
ninja currently on far away missions.
But to think it has come to
killing a Hokage.
You mean Sasuke Uchiha?
I knew it, but he's really fallen
as low as you can get.
But...
If you are prepared to bear
the burden of being a Kage,
then do what is right
as Sasuke's friend.
He didn't seem to
be convinced, did he?
It's because he never gives up.
He's the one who changed
the old Gaara,
the one we could never approach.
No matter how lost in
the darkness a person might be,
he will hold out his hand.
He will try to save him.
That's how he is.
Gaara...
But it's Sasuke himself
who's seeking the darkness.
This time, I don't think...
It has to be Naruto's decision
after that.
What he will do as a friend.
I will simply give my all to
protect my friends...
and the world!
Sakura...
I'm back.
I heard from my dad...
about Sasuke.
Yeah...
And I fought with him.
"Fought"? You mean with Sasuke?!
I'll give you the details later.
Sorry, but would you mind getting
everybody together?
There's something I want to say.
Okay.
She originally worked
for Orochimaru
before she joined up with Sasuke
as a shinobi for the Akatsuki.
That means she knows a lot.
You better treat me well.
And...
It looks like she was there when
Sasuke and Danzo battled it out.
You saw them fighting?
You're interrogating me here?
Okay, we'll hold her at
the Intel Division.
We'll get everything she knows.
Take her away.
Yes, sir.
Hey... no! I won't try to escape.
So let go of me, will you?!
Geez!
I'm so thirsty,
give me something to drink!
By the way,
how's Lady Tsunade doing?
She's still unconscious.
I see.
Well, I'll go make my report
to the superiors.
Excuse me.
Kakashi...
The chain of command in the
Hidden Leaf Village is in shambles.
Someone has to restore order
as soon as possible.
Yeah... I know that.
Sasuke did that?
It's an unbelievable situation.
That's why I want you to
let me handle Sasuke.
You'll take on Sasuke alone?!
How can you expect us
to agree to that?
Tenten is right, Naruto.
We can't just give in to
your stubbornness.
The reason is that this is a
major problem for the village.
I'm not being stubborn.
You said you'd give us
the details when we got home,
but I never thought
this is what you'd say!
We've all made up our minds
to kill Sasuke!
Hey Naruto, don't tell me
you're saying
you'll get Sasuke all by yourself,
when you're actually planning
to protect him.
No, I have no intention
of protecting Sasuke.
– Chidori!
– Rasengan!
After all that fighting at the Five
Kage Summit, and fighting Danzo...
If Sasuke was weakened
at that time,
why didn't you take
him out right then?
Madara was there too!
It didn't seem so easy.
Besides...
That's no reason to let him
get away so easily!
Hey Naruto...
You're strong.
You're the hero who
took down Pain, aren't you?!
Hero?
Yeah. You could take Sasuke down
like you did back then.
That's not true.
Huh?
I wouldn't be able to beat Sasuke
with something like that now.
That's what I found out.
Inside him...
What is it that you found out?
In any case, nobody should take
on Sasuke as he is now.
What do you mean?
I'm the only one who can fight him.
That's what I mean.
That doesn't tell us anything!
Explain it in detail.
What happened?
I said I'd tell you when
the time comes.
Hey! There you go again!
Giving us the runaround!
Damn it.
Naruto...
Sasuke...
Were you able to read...
what was inside my heart?
And you saw it, didn't you?
That if you and I fight...
we will both die.
What are you hiding?
Well...
Please leave it to me.
Hey! Naruto!
Naruto...
Hey, Naruto!
Danzo too?
Such a shame.
The best ones go first.
We must quickly hold a meeting
to determine who will
be the next Hokage.
The Allied Shinobi Force
will be stalled
if the Hokage is missing.
That cannot be helped.
We will recommend you for Hokage.
The Sand,
a member of the alliance,
has also recommended you.
I am prepared for it.
Somebody! Somebody,
come quickly! Please!
What's happened?
Shizune... Don't tell me...
Thanks for accepting.
I would feel a lot better if you
would become the Hokage, Shikaku.
Don't be ridiculous.
I'm old enough to retire and
have my son take over.
Of course,
I'm in no position to do that.
Yes.
To think that Danzo fell
to the Akatsuki.
Yes.
We must decide on another Hokage.
We are all recommending
Kakashi Hatake.
Oh, that man?
Kakashi Hatake, enter.
All right. Kakashi Hatake!
You will be...
Please excuse me!
Guy?
What is this?!
We are in an important conference.
I have come to report a sudden change
in the state of affairs!
What? A sudden change?!
Lady Tsunade!
Shizune... you're hurting me.
Send messages to
the other villages!
Tsunade, the Hokage of Hidden
Leaf Village, is alive and well!
Report this to the Feudal Lords
of the other lands as well.
We should let the people of
our village know at once.
I will leave that to you.
Umm... Well...
May I go home?
Since we're here now,
why don't we go and eat at
that sushi boat restaurant?
Let's see who can eat the most!
You must rest for a while.
It takes some time to become
accustomed to the Mangekyo.
Are you in pain?
No.
It feels right. I can feel
Itachi's visual powers.
I can feel myself getting stronger!
Please eat more slowly!
This is not enough!
My chakra hasn't returned
to normal!
Bring me more food!
If I'm not careful,
I'll become an old hag!
Uh-oh, no, no!
The Hokage Quarters' supply stores
have run out.
I'll go and requisition
more provisions,
so please take a short break.
No! Don't do it!
What are you thinking?!
This one is completely off limits!
What are you talking about?
Huh?
K-Kakashi...
I'm glad to see you so well.
This is nothing,
I'm just getting started.
After all you've eaten,
it doesn't make any sense.
I am relieved.
I was dangerously close
to becoming the Hokage.
But well, I'm not really
the Hokage type.
Considering the present situation,
we need someone like you,
Lady Tsunade, with wide influence,
to be the Hokage.
I must say I am amazed to hear
about the Allied Shinobi Force.
And I'm surprised that the Tsuchikage
and the Raikage agreed to cooperate.
That just goes to prove what an
awful situation we are faced with.
Madara Uchiha...
He's really still alive?
We don't have absolute proof,
but considering what
they are trying to do,
I'd say there's no doubt about it.
Another war, huh?
Who would have thought
the karma of the Uchiha
would engulf all the shinobi
in the world.
I will call a meeting immediately
after this meal!
We must prepare for war!
Before he died,
Jiraiya said to me,
"go store yourself inside Naruto."
Great Lord Elder!
Are you sure this is the right thing?
Jiraiya claimed that Naruto
could completely control
the power of the Nine-Tails,
but when we tested him,
it didn't go well.
But Jiraiya refused to give in,
saying that it was for that purpose
that Minato had sealed
half of the Nine-Tails' chakra
inside of Naruto.
Great Lord Elder, Gerotora himself
is the key to Naruto's Tetragram Seal.
Is it safe to hand him over to Naruto?
What do you think?
Have Naruto Uzumaki come here.
I shall do a reading on him.
We will then see what
we must do.
Is everyone here?
We shall now start our war council
to discuss strategy!
First, assemble reserves of
ninja tools and foodstuffs.
We must divide our shinobi into
main battle units and support forces,
and consider how we should
build the squads
within the fighting forces!
Bring me the complete list
of all our shinobi!
War...
So it's finally come to that.
You were invited to this war council,
but you're still young.
Keep your ears open
and don't miss a thing.
Yeah. I know that.
I will make full use of my head
and hammer everything in!
It doesn't rhyme.
Isn't there a nice phrase?
Unless we are sure about the enemy's
headquarters, and where their hideout is,
it will be difficult to launch
an effective surprise attack.
And so, we will first dispatch
a reconnaissance team.
All right.
– To maximize their efforts, we will have
– "All right," eh?
– three surprise attack formations.
– Lacks originality.
To ensure success,
– each formation must be comprised of
– What if I switch it around like...
– expert shinobi from every nation.
– Aight, yo?
Right-o... And then I add
a little rap flavor and...
Aight, yo.
Aight, yo. Aight, yo. Aight, yo...
This gives us
a pretty clear picture of
the Hidden Cloud's military strength.
Lucky for us,
the Eight-Tails is a fool.
It's not working.
This phrase is making me mad!
Can't figure it out.
We don't have current intel
about the enemy,
so we must rely on intel from
the others to assess the situation.
So we're to go empty-handed
and depend on intel
from other villages?
Will they even share their data?
If they refuse to divulge
what they know,
then the Allied Shinobi Force
is meaningless.
We'll just have to trust them.
We don't have time to waste.
At this very moment,
Madara Uchiha is preparing for war.
All right!
We will hold a meeting of
the Allied Shinobi Force in three days!
Send word to each village!
Naruto!
Huh?!
So Grandma Tsunade is fine now?
Yes!
All right!
Is that right?
I'm happy about Lady Tsunade.
Okay! Since this is good news,
the ramen is on me!
Huh?! Are you sure?!
Why don't you have some too, Sakura?
No, thanks.
I still have more people to notify.
Well, I'll see you later, Naruto!
Now that that's off my mind,
I feel hungrier than ever!
Okay! I'm eating my fill today.
One bowl, two bowls, three bowls!
Here you go!
It's a special tonkotsu miso
with BBQ pork slices
to celebrate the Hokage's recovery!
Whoa!
Thank you for the...
Oh? He disappeared.
... food!
I'm surprised he dug right
into the food.
Looks like he really loves
my bug cooking!
What am I doing here again?
I did a Reverse Summoning on you.
The Great Lord Elder will
divine your future, Naruto-boy.
Divine?
Follow me.
Don't throw it up!
I have brought him.
Hey! Long time no see,
Giant Gramps Sage!
It was indeed I who
summoned you... er... umm...
Who are you again?
Naruto Uzumaki!
I wish you'd hurry up and
learn my name, Giant Gramps Sage!
Oh, that's right, that's right.
It's Naruto.
Listen, Naruto.
I have seen
a prophecy involving you.
A prophecy?
Okay, I'm ready for it.
In that case, listen carefully.
You will soon be meeting
an octopus.
An octopus?
Why an octopus?
Well, I couldn't see too clearly,
but I'm sure they were tentacles.
And then, it will come to pass that
you will fight a young man
whose power lies in his eyes.
And...
Yeah... I know.
What do you mean, "you know"?
So you saw it?
Yeah.
That young man whose power
lies in his eyes...
Do you know who that is?!
Yeah, and I've already
made up my mind.
Gerotora...
I also saw a dream where
you stored yourself inside Naruto.
Wh-What?!
Give him the Fourth Hokage's seal.
I have no choice but to do
as you say, Great Lord Elder.
What is this?
It is the key left by
the Fourth Hokage
that locks and unlocks
the sealing jutsu on your stomach!
With this you can let
the Nine-Tails run free,
if that's what you want.
Place your hand on that square area.
With this, you will have
the means to perfect that jutsu
that Jiraiya was talking about.
The key to release...
the Nine-Tails' seal.
Are you unsure, Naruto?
What are you waiting for?
Press the Storing Square!
You're unsure, right, Naruto?
I can't say that I blame you.
What do you mean?
Lord Fukasaku...
The Nine-Tails gets its power
by merging its chakra with its will.
To control this power,
you must isolate
only the Nine-Tails' chakra,
assimilate it into your own chakra
and make it your own power.
But it's easier said than done.
If you pull out the Nine-Tails' chakra,
you also draw out its will.
The Nine-Tails' will is a mass of hatred
that binds itself tightly to chakra.
No matter how hard you try
to shield yourself,
it will find some hatred that
you have buried deep inside
and it will try to overtake you.
In other words,
controlling the Nine-Tails' power
means taking its will and its chakra
and completely separating the two
with your own strong will
which should harbor no hatred.
The Fourth Hokage made
the Nine-Tails' seal in a way
that allows a small amount of its chakra
to leak out of the cage
in hopes that it would naturally
become one with Naruto's own chakra.
It is known as the Eight Trigrams Sealing.
It consists of two Tetragram Seals.
But if this key is used to
open the Tetragram Seal,
you could pull out all
the Nine-Tails' chakra!
And that means all
the Nine-Tails' will
would be drawn out along with
all of its chakra!
And as soon as Naruto's will
loses to the Nine-Tails' will...
The Nine-Tails will be
completely resurrected!
How terrible.
And has the key ever been used?
A while ago, the Tetragram Seal
was weakening.
So in order to control Naruto,
who was starting to transform into
the Nine-Tails during training,
Jiraiya used the key to
tighten the seal on him.
This should hold for a while.
Just a while, huh?
What's the matter, Pervy Sage?
Jiraiya was greatly concerned.
If the Fourth Hokage's Sealing Formula
was beginning to weaken,
there was no telling when Naruto would
transform into the Nine-Tails again.
I guess I'll try it.
Huh?!
A toad came out of your mouth!
Don't be so hard on me, Jiraiya!
You just summoned me
a while ago.
I need a favor.
Will you hear me out, Gerotora?
It's Naruto's Tetragram Seal.
Hey, hey... You just tightened the seal.
Do you want it tighter?
No, the reverse.
I want to loosen it just a little bit.
Wha—?!
Jiraiya wanted the seal to be opened
deliberately for just a short while
in order to train Naruto to develop
the power to resist the Nine-Tails' will.
But it didn't work.
I didn't mean to hurt Pervy Sage.
The harder I try to become strong,
the tighter the grip of
the Nine-Tails' will becomes.
He totally ignores my will and
tries to hurt everyone in my path.
That was the result of opening
Naruto's key just a tiny bit.
So that's the reason for the scar
on Jiraiya-boy's chest.
And then what happened?
Nothing good.
Right now, I feel safe, since
Fourth Hokage's seal has been tightened.
But it might act up again at any time.
Yet in order to fight Sasuke,
I have to use
the Nine-Tails' chakra.
I'm the Nine-Tails' Jinchuriki, after all.
I can't hide from that forever.
I sealed half of the Nine-Tails' chakra
inside of you,
because I believed
you could control its power.
Right, Dad?
Hurting my friends...
Giving in to hatred...
It's no use getting hesitant.
I understand now just how dangerous
it is to release the Nine-Tails' chakra.
But he has the Fourth Hokage's love
and that sheer determination
that Jiraiya instilled in him.
Contract complete.
I'm going into storage!
Huh? Going into storage?
You don't need to do a thing.
Just keep your mouth open.
Mouth?
Yes. Now say “ahh.”
Wider.
Here I go... into storage.
Hey! Open wider!
Are you going to let me go
into storage?!
Why through my mouth?!
It's slimy and feels awful.
Okay, storage complete!
I'm taking you back to
Hidden Leaf Village.
After that, we'll have to
look for the octopus.
Oh, right... You prophesied that
I would encounter an octopus.
Where is this octopus?
Can't you give more clues?
It's not clear,
but it's a solitary island.
People don't go near it.
It's like a paradise for creatures.
To me, it seems it would be
a fun resort.
And there, the octopus should be
of help to you.
In any case, you will find your way.
Right!
All right, I'm sending you back.
I'm back.
Where'd you go?
I thought you suddenly disappeared,
and now you're back!
I had something to do.
Oh, Naruto!
They said you suddenly disappeared
and everyone's in an uproar.
Huh? No kidding!
I never thought I'd run into you here.
Oh hey!
Give me your autograph!
Could you make it out to my kid.
He's a big fan of yours.
Autograph?
The hero of the Hidden Leaf.
The kid who created a miracle,
Naruto Uzumaki.
Give me your autograph too!
What's wrong? You won't do it?
It's not that. I'm just not used
to that sort of thing.
I don't have a clue what to sign.
Everyone's making a fuss
over him lately as the miracle kid.
But until just recently,
it was just the opposite.
I can't blame the boy.
Gentlemen, will you let him eat
a bowl of ramen before that?
Oh, sure...
Yes!
I finally get to eat!
Naruto!
Oh Sakura!
Where have you been?!
Where? I was suddenly
summoned and...
Just come with me right now!
Lady Tsunade and everyone else
are worried about you!
Oww... Sakura!
Let me eat my ramen!
That can wait.
There's no mistake,
it's Kabuto's doing.
This method of killing...
Kabuto is becoming more
like Orochimaru.
But why would he leave
a trail like this?
He would...
Is this deliberate?
What does he intend to do?
No doubt Kabuto is carrying
on Orochimaru's will.
Now, is he going after
the Hidden Leaf or the Akatsuki?
Let's start with the greetings,
shall we, Tobi?
No...
You call yourself Madara now.
You did well to find this place.
I roamed from country to country as a spy
and I once belonged to the Akatsuki.
Don't underestimate my intel network.
You were once one of Sasori's spies.
You are a traitor to the Akatsuki.
This is...
Reanimation Jutsu.
The Forbidden Jutsu known only to
the Second Hokage and Lord Orochimaru.
Now, I'm the third one.
And I have surpassed
the previous two.
This performance is dedicated to you.
So that you would believe
in my power and trust in me.
Rest assured.
I did not come here to fight.
What do you want?
I want us to join forces.
Join forces?
How will that benefit me?
I understand you intend
to start a war soon.
I'm offering to provide
more military might.
With these here...
Itachi.
Sasori.
Deidara.
Kakuzu.
And Nagato.
They each have formidable strength.
And I have even more up my sleeve.
And in exchange?
Sasuke Uchiha.
What are you plotting?
Nothing really.
I am only interested in
the pure truth behind ninjutsu.
And I need Sasuke
to pursue this.
I need a young, live,
sensitive Uchiha.
And if I refuse?
Summoning Jutsu: Reanimation.
Th-This is...
Surely, you didn't think that
I would come unprepared.
Yes. You can't refuse.
Why you...
Where did you get that?
I have my means.
Don't worry. I haven't told
anyone about this.
What's so funny?
Kabuto Yakushi.
Never did I imagine that
you would come this far.
Arguing with you now will
only weaken our side.
You came here,
waiting for the perfect opportunity.
You are very careful indeed.
What do you mean?
So be it.
We will join forces with you.
But only on the condition that
I hand Sasuke over to you
after victory in this war is assured.
You will not be allowed to
see Sasuke until then.
You understand things clearly.
I expected no less
from Madara Uchiha.
Your vessel is unique.
And you are insolent.
I'll reformulate my strategy after
I confirm your battle strength.
Follow me.
He brought corpses all the way
to this desolate place?
Judging from the way
the shinobi's bodies are strewn about,
I'll bet there's something up ahead.
I originally thought we'd pursue him
by way of Hidden Waterfall,
and back to Hidden Leaf Village.
But it's like he wants us
to follow him.
I don't get it.
Is it a trap then?
What do we do?
Tokuma! Use your Byakugan
at two o'clock!
Right!
Byakugan!
Captain Mitarashi! This is...
What's the matter?
It's not just Kabuto!
He's with a masked member
of the Akatsuki!
The two of them are going through
some kind of underground entrance!
What?!
A masked man?
Is it the one who calls
himself Madara?
Does this mean
we found his hideout?
What is he doing with Kabuto?
Have they joined forces?
Did Kabuto purposely lure us here?
In order to show us
Madara's hideout?
But why? If they've joined forces...
I don't know yet.
But we need to send word to
the village immediately!
You all came quickly.
The situation calls for quick action.
Princess Tsunade.
Are you really all right?
This is the perfect opportunity
to hand things over to a youngster.
You're old too.
Speak for yourself,
you Fence-Sitter geezer!
Setting aside the matter of Danzo,
I'm relieved that you are back
as the Hokage, Lady Tsunade.
Let us be done with the greetings
and get right to business.
First on the agenda are the Jinchuriki
of the Eight-Tails and Nine-Tails.
Then we will go on to any intel
relating to the enemy's headquarters
and military strength.
My shinobi have pinned
down a location
that may be the enemy's stronghold.
But it may be a trap.
We have no choice but to wait
for more intel on this.
I also have a reconnaissance team
gathering intel.
We need to sort through the intel
from each village quickly.
How about forming a separate unit
within the Allied Force
that only handles intel?
Good idea!
Share and share alike!
That goes without saying!
If each nation becomes driven
by self-interest,
the Akatsuki will pull the rug out
from under us.
So, where will we hide
the crucial Jinchuriki?
Hide them?
What is it?
Naruto and Bee can lend much
strength to this battle.
Why hide them away?
I thought so as well.
But those two are what the enemy
is after in this war.
Considering what could happen,
we cannot let them participate.
It was decided at the last meeting,
but you, of course,
were still ill.
Our enemy is Madara!
If we hold back battle strength and
lose the prospect of victory,
we are not going to get another chance.
We must hit them with
everything we've got—
The Five Great Nations
joined together and
our aim in this war is
to protect those two.
Your sole dissent as Hokage
is not sufficient.
We will decide this
with majority rule.
You child! Naruto is—
I know him quite well.
That is exactly why.
Before we even talk
about military strength,
the five Kage must reach a consensus.
Otherwise, there will be no victory.
I agree, Lady Tsunade.
It's fine!
The Slug Princess is back
to her impudent self.
It's proof that she is well.
We will now need to decide where
to hide the Eight-Tails and Nine-Tails.
Any objections, Hokage?
I understand.
Get on with it!
I have a place in mind.
And it is appropriately located
in the Hidden Cloud,
which has not produced
any Akatsuki members.
I set it aside, just in case.
S-rank mission?!
You're assigning me to
an important mission like that?
Yes. This is a mission that
only you can undertake.
You and Yamato will go to a certain
place in the Hidden Cloud region.
Is that the resort?
The Great Lord Elder's prophecy
was accurate.
It seems that is the place
he foresaw.
Then I'm going to see the octopus
at this resort island?
I feel sorta bad!
Everyone's so busy and
I get to go to a resort.
You fool! You are going on a mission!
I know. Just joking, just joking.
But about going to this place
that was prophesied...
Is it connected to the other one?
That I'll fight with Sasuke?
That, I don't know.
However, we are on the verge of war!
Hence, this S-rank mission.
When you get to the site,
you will follow Yamato's orders.
Okay! I understand!
You can count on me
for this S-rank mission!
We're going to freeze out here.
Let's go back.
I'll bear the burden of your hate,
and we'll die together.
What's wrong?
Nothing at all...
Octopus, octopus, octopus!
Octopus?
An octopus is supposed
to help guide me.
Remember?
Giant Gramps Sage foretold it.
That's right, it was an octopus.
He was right about this being
an isolated island paradise.
I'm sure there's no mistake about
meeting someone to guide me.
Naruto hasn't figured it out yet.
Please start preparing
to disembark soon.
Oh! I can see the island!
It's true!
An... island paradise?
It's like the Hidden Leaf's
Forest of Death.
But this is a bit more extreme.
This is a resort?
Don't worry it's safe.
As long as we don't provoke them,
the creatures are quite docile.
Except for one...
"Except for one" what?
What part of this place
is a paradise?!
You liar, Giant Gramps Sage!
For one that lives along the shore...
Huh? Octopus tentacles!
Okay, octopus! Come and guide me!
Naruto, this is actually a...
a squid!
It's here!
I was just about to warn you
that he's the one
you have to be careful about,
but he appeared before I could!
– What?!
One, two, three...
It's obvious without
counting its tentacles!
Naruto, come on!
But we should make sure.
A squid has ten legs.
An octopus has eight.
If this is the octopus who's going
to help guide me...
Naruto?!
This Squid's a deviation...
I'll save the explanation!
What the—?!
Here comes another one
saying weird puns!
This is so confusing!
6, 7, 8...
It's an octopus!
This one is an octopus!
Is that really an octopus?
Master Killer Bee!
Killer Bee?
Then this octopus is...
Y'all are late, fools, ya fools!
It changed into a human?
Hey, ya know Octopops, thanks!
Ya know...
What?
Will we clash
or make a splash?
Take it from me,
it's a no-go, WHEE!
Cause I'm a brat-hatin' outlaw...
What's up with
this beefy guy in shades,
singing lame puns at
the top of his lungs?
Is this geezer the octopus
who's going to guide me?
They're not puns.
It's his original style,
a combination of Enka singing
to a rap beat. Enka Rap!
Enka rap?
Welcome, everyone!
I've been waiting for you.
I am Supervisor Motoi
and I'll take care of your needs.
I'll take you to your lodgings,
so please follow me.
Oh, we're finally here?
We're standing on solid ground,
Guy. Get a hold of yourself!
Is Bushier Brow-sensei all right?
He never got over
his seasickness, did he?
We were at sea for a long time.
It sure was long.
It sure was painful.
Is this really a paradise?
I still feel woozy.
Hey, King, no need to panic!
These guys are okay.
It's a gorilla! A gorilla!
Is this a gorilla?
Master Bee stands at the top
of this island's hierarchy of beasts.
He's tamed them all.
So as long as he is around,
it's safe here.
Furthermore, Hidden Cloud shinobi
maintain a barrier around the island.
We'll know immediately if
anyone suspicious approaches.
Which is why this place
was chosen to detain them.
Who the hell is that
shades-wearing pops?
He is the Hidden Cloud's hero
among heroes.
Hero?
He's someone who not only
tamed these wild animals,
he is a Jinchuriki
who can control Tailed Beasts.
He is a Jinchuriki like you...
of Eight-Tails.
The Eight-Tails' Jinchuriki?
And he can control it?
That old guy?
He's Master Killer Bee.
Yo!
This island is also
where he trained
to gain control over the Eight-Tails.
The Hidden Leaf can use this floor.
There are ample rooms.
Eat all you want in the great
dining hall on the first floor.
Choose whatever rooms you want.
We'll adjourn until the meeting
tomorrow morning at seven.
I'm going to rest for awhile.
Ahh, it's the "ya know" brat.
What's up?
You want an autograph from me?
Train me!
Train you?
I'm the Jinchuriki of the Nine-Tails.
But I can't control it yet.
So please teach me
how to control a Tailed Beast.
No way.
I came here because
my brother, the Raikage,
ordered me to take a vacation...
Why should I give up
a rare vacation for that reason?
Fool, ya fool!
Because we're both Jinchuriki!
Why won't you help me out?
Your attitude is huge, I see.
Stop acting so shamelessly! Whee!
Old man!
Cool shades!
With a face that's tan,
you've really got it made! Whee!
Hey kid, you've got good style.
Yes! He's starting to like me!
Yo!
First comes the greeting!
We start with fist bumps,
while we keep rapping.
Hey old buddy...
Those shades sure look funny...
Shouldn't have said that!
Oh well, what the hell.
Harem Jutsu!
I've been begging for
so long on my knees.
Come on, my dear.
Teach me control.
Please...
How's that?
All men fall for this jutsu!
Hey old man! Old man!
You're stingy!
What's with that guy?!
All he does is talk in rhymes.
Whoever heard of
an octopus that raps?!
What do you want?
Show me how the old man
wearing shades
trained to control the Eight-Tails.
He trained here, right?
Oh, you're talking about Bee.
He won't give me the time of day,
so I came to ask you instead!
Me?
I don't care if he's the hero
of the Hidden Cloud or what...
He's selfish and stubborn,
and talks only in rhymes.
We're both Jinchuriki,
so why can't he be
more understanding?
– I mean...
– What do you know about Bee?!
If you keep complaining about him,
I won't forgive you, kid!
If you're a Jinchuriki,
you can imagine the kind of life
he's had to lead, can't you?
I sure can!
And that old man should be able
to imagine what it's like for me!
So why won't he give me
a break when I need his help?
Even I...
Bee has been watching
you all along.
There's a reason for his actions.
Did you introduce yourself to Bee?
We did... fist bumps.
Okay. Naruto, right? Follow me.
I'll take you to
Bee's training spot.
All right!
Then I'll join you.
Captain Yamato?!
I'm a Wood-Style user
and if something happens,
I'm supposed to look after him.
Oh? You're the Wood Style user.
Fine then.
Is this the place?
Yeah. This spot is known
as the Waterfall of Truth.
The Waterfall of Truth?
He learned to control
the Tailed Beast here?
No, it's the first step.
Sit here and close your eyes, Naruto.
You will see your true self.
My true self?
Yes.
Why?
Why didn't you give them
your autograph at Ichiraku?
What?
Those guys suddenly got nice
and tried to get friendly
with you, huh?
They were disgusting, weren't they?
This guy looks just like me!
Everyone in the village used
to treat us like lepers.
Who are you?
Can't you tell? I'm you.
I don't remember doing
Shadow Clones.
I'm the real you.
The real you that exists
deep inside your heart.
What are you saying?!
I don't know you.
Stop making stuff up!
This place is called
the Waterfall of Truth, right?
I never figured I'd be able
to come out like this.
What a great place.
Anyway, I'm your true self.
The real you.
The real me?
Yeah. I'm the precious hatred
inside you.
The dark part of you!
The only difference is...
the Nine-Tails has taken
a real liking to me.
You...
The Nine-Tails' will is
a mass of hatred
that binds itself tightly to chakra.
No matter how hard you
try to shield yourself,
it will find some hatred that
you have buried deep inside
and try to take you over.
Until now, the Nine-Tails
and this guy...
You got that right.
I'm the real one.
You can't kick me out, you fake!
Is that how it is?
You're the fake one!
On this island, I'm top dog.
Taking y'all down
Like a whirlwind clearing the fog.
You still have a ways
to go, Kintoki.
Hey Bee...
If you have time to play around,
why couldn't you have taken
a look at the Nine-Tails' kid?
You're both Jinchuriki,
why not give him a break?
I don't like Nine-Tails myself,
but that kid has promise.
I was a confused mess back then,
but I met you and
look at me now.
He sort of reminds me of you.
My style is rap
And I say shut yer trap!
I ain't acknowledgin' no rap-mockin'
"Ya know" fool!
Besides, he...
Damn it!
Our strength is identical.
There's no end to fighting him.
You can't beat me. Never.
Then I'll put my bet on numbers!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
What the hell?!
Is that how it is?!
Even the number of
Shadow Clones is the same!
You're pretty smart,
figuring that out.
Damn it!
Go!
What is going on?
When you sit before
the waterfall and focus,
you are able to enter
your subconscious.
And the waterfall becomes the
mirror that reflects your true self.
It is really a mystical place.
Right now, Naruto is battling
his other self.
– Rasen...
– ... gan!
Naruto, are you all right?!
What happened?
Someone exactly like me appeared.
And he...
What is it?
He was my dark self.
We're evenly matched and
he keeps attacking with
the same strength as me.
Our jutsu, our fighting style,
everything is identical.
It's an endless battle!
How can that be?
You must defeat him
or you will not be able to control
the Tailed Beast's power.
I told you.
The Waterfall of Truth
is just the first step.
How am I supposed to
beat that guy?
Well that, I do not know.
Octopops trained here too, right?
I can ask him...
No, he won't tell me.
Not with that attitude.
Probably not.
I wonder if Octopops had
a dark half too?
Hey, Mr. Motoi...
Can you tell me
more about Octopops?
Like how he grew up,
and his personality.
Maybe I can get some hints from that.
Maybe I can figure out
the difference between us.
I don't like talking about other people.
But Naruto, you're a Jinchuriki
just like Master Bee.
Being able to control the Nine-Tails
has a direct effect on world peace.
I'll do it.
Thank you!
I told you earlier...
Since you're also a Jinchuriki,
you can imagine
the kind of life he's had.
And it's just as you
would imagine...
Formidable power breeds
fear and antagonism.
Bee has always been shunned and
considered a nuisance by the villagers.
But he never got depressed
or complained even once.
He was always cheerful...
always trying to engage
with the people around him.
More than anything,
instead of being ashamed
that he was a Jinchuriki,
he didn't hide that fact.
To me, he seemed to
take pride in himself.
Yo.
The reason he was able to
take pride in being a Jinchuriki...
was probably because of
his older brother, the Raikage.
From days past,
in order to prevent betrayal,
Jinchuriki have commonly been
selected from close blood relations
of the Five Kage like siblings,
or even spouses.
A Jinchuriki is a weapon used
to protect the Kage,
the head of the village.
It is also a symbol of
the Kage's strength.
I think Master Bee tried to be
a fine Jinchuriki
for Lord Raikage's sake.
It's said that he mastered
his training
at the Waterfall of Truth in no time.
I deeply respect
the kind of person Master Bee is.
I consider him to be one of
the heroes of the Hidden Cloud.
Such a well-loved Jinchuriki.
Master Bee must be quite a person.
And you too.
I know!
Can you ask Octopops for
training hints on my behalf, Motoi?
I can't do that.
Why not?!
I have no right to request
such a thing.
I once tried to kill Master Bee!
Why?! You just said
you respected Octopops.
You seem to have a reason.
So what is it?
This is a confession.
You're a Jinchuriki like Bee,
so I think it's okay to tell you
about that incident.
This took place 30 years ago...
Back then, the Jinchuriki's power
was not strong enough
to completely control the Eight-Tails.
The Eight-Tails often went
on a rampage
and wreaked havoc
on the Hidden Cloud.
Every time that happened,
the Third Raikage...
and his elite shinobi would
stop the Eight-Tails.
Listen! I want you to stop
the Eight-Tails' movements.
While you're doing that, I will
seal him in the Sealing Urn.
Understood.
Okay, get to it.
Damn it! The chain forged
from the Sealing Jutsu...
Don't give up!
If we give up, Hidden Cloud Village
will be destroyed.
All right, this should...
Now! Pin him down!
Don't mess with me,
lowly humans!
They were somehow able to suppress
the Eight-Tails' rampages
and shove him back into
the Sealing Urn.
But there were fatalities each time.
However, despite the risk,
it was crucial to control
the Eight-Tails
in order to preserve
the power balance between nations.
Experiments continued
with the Jinchuriki.
Among the many who died or
were injured...
was my father.
Master Bee killed your father.
That's why...
No, that wasn't it.
Master Bee and I
used to be friends.
We were only five years old
when my father died.
Bee, you did it!
The Jinchuriki that killed
my father died
when the Eight-Tails was
extracted and sealed.
It was the previous Jinchuriki.
Right after that,
Master Bee was chosen to be
the Eight-Tails' Jinchuriki.
So why did you try to kill Bee?
There is no way to control
the Eight-Tails.
There would be many more victims.
That's what I thought.
My hatred towards
the Eight-Tails grew.
I was just a kid,
but I kept thinking
about getting revenge.
Master Bee was always laughing.
I started hating him more and more
because it seemed like he didn't care.
My hatred of the Eight-Tails
shifted to Master Bee, his Jinchuriki.
I thought if I killed Master Bee,
the Eight-Tails would also die.
I attacked Master Bee from behind.
But I failed and
ran away scared.
My face was masked,
but Master Bee might
have guessed it was me.
After that, I stopped talking
to Master Bee.
Even after all that,
how did you come to
respect Master Bee?
My hatred didn't
disappear overnight.
For a long time,
I continued to stalk Master Bee
and kept an eye on him.
But I wasn't the only one.
Master Bee was shunned
by the villagers and despised.
All the time.
Get lost! You're disgusting!
Even though he was forced to become
a Jinchuriki for political reasons,
in order to protect the village,
people still ostracized him.
Oh yeah?
Yo yo yo, check it out, yo!
Hey, yo yo, hey c'mon, yo yo!!
Check it out, yo!
Yo, hey, yo yo!
Anyone else would have gone insane.
And for the first time...
I realized that
Master Bee's suffering
was even greater than mine.
Why did you tell us?
Truth be told, I'd rather have
Master Bee hear this,
but I think I'm telling Naruto
because he is a fellow Jinchuriki.
I know that I owe it to Bee to
tell him the truth some day.
Otherwise, it wouldn't be
a confession.
How convenient for him.
Naruto, where are you going?
I need to be alone for a while!
It's that boy...
Remember, stay away from him!
Go away!
I believed in you!
You're a hero, Naruto!
Thank you, Naruto!
To them,
I am now a relic of the past
that is difficult to get rid of.
Gaara is the Kazekage, you know.
Don't be so disrespectful!
You're nothing but subordinates!
Gaara is reserved, cool, strong,
handsome, an elite, and...
Octopops has earned so much trust.
And Gaara has become
the Kazekage,
working for the sake of his village
and gaining acceptance.
And me, I have Iruka-sensei
and my comrades and...
The villagers treated us
like outcasts, but now...
I am the real you that exists
deep inside your heart.
I am the real you.
The real me.
I never even gave it a thought.
But somewhere deep inside,
I'm still...
It's true.
I'm still not confident that I have
everyone's trust in the village.
Where did Naruto go?
Don't tell me...
The location of this island
is top secret.
There's no way an enemy would...
That was old man Motoi.
Damn it!
Naruto! We're going to go
with Formation C!
Why... Why?
Naruto! What are you doing?!
Stop, Octopops!
Old man Motoi really trusts you!
It's a squid!
That's not an octopus!
Naruto! Save the talking for later!
Let's do this!
Gotcha!
Wood Style: Silent Strangle Jutsu!
Old man Motoi!
We're coming to get you!
I'll tell you how I feel...
I'm going to save you for real.
That's my deal...
That's my spiel.
Eight-Tails and me retake the stage!
Knocking the beat-up squid
right off the page!
The rest, I won't engage.
Octopops!
Bee, why did you save me?
Master Bee, you knew, didn't you?
That I tried to...
I tried to kill you.
And yet...
Did that happen?
What I remember is...
Me and Motoi...
Me and Motoi.
The times I spent
with Motoi, together...
We trained hard like
birds of a feather,
We made mistakes
but it was no disaster...
The two of us always exploding
into laughter.
The two of us laughing,
best friends forever...
The times I spent
with Motoi, together.
Yay!
Hey, Nine-Tails' brat,
thanks for trying to save Motoi.
Sure.
Naruto has the ability to
bring people together.
Just like Bee.
Yes! I totally agree!
I think I need to
reconsider ya mate.
You're quite a good guy,
real top rate.
Octopops,
ya got the best rap...
I'm so happy to know ya,
I'm one lucky chap!
It's great that Naruto and
Bee share similar traits.
But frankly, I wish he'd stop
copying his rapping.
Yo! Keep the beat.
Yo! I'm Naruto, ya know!
All right, it's decided!
Man, it's "ya know, ya know"
all the time.
Shuddup, ya know!
Go to the Waterfall of Truth.
You'll pass with flying colors now.
So have you come back because you
haven't learned your lesson yet?
It's going to be the same,
no matter how many times you try.
You cannot beat me.
I know.
Trying to defeat you
with force isn't going to work.
Because we use
the exact same moves.
You won't be able to
chase me out either.
I know you better than anyone else.
Then...
You already know...
What do you want to say?
What I decided earlier.
I don't remember.
Don't act like you don't know.
Well, never mind.
This place is supposed to show
the truth in your heart,
so I'll concentrate on the image
and show it directly to you.
This is my autograph.
Why you!
Oh hey! Give me
your autograph, Naruto!
Could you make it out to my kid?
He's a big fan of yours.
An autograph?
The hero of the Hidden Leaf.
The youth who created a miracle,
Naruto Uzumaki.
Give me your autograph too!
What is it? You refuse?
Oh no, but I'm not used to
that sort of thing.
I don't have a clue
what to sign.
Back at Ichiraku, I couldn't give
them their autographs.
Here it is now.
Who cares if you have it now?
What a joke!
Everyone in the village is
just sucking up to you.
They don't mean it.
They've been lying to us
the whole time.
Making up rules and
treating us like outcasts!
Don't you remember?
It was so hard and painful.
I'm the only one who will
ever understand you!
Don't trust anyone
from the village!
Yeah...
The villagers are important,
but there's someone else
I have to trust first.
I have to believe in myself.
I need to trust the version of me that
the villagers believe in.
Why?
After all that
they put us through?
Octopops made me
realize something.
He doesn't doubt himself at all.
He has pride in himself.
Do you...
Do you consider me a burden?
Just what am I to you?
Because you existed,
I became strong.
Thanks to you,
I've made it this far.
And?
And what am I...
And what am I
supposed to do now?
That's simple.
You just become me.
Since you are me.
Thanks for everything until today.
But it's going to be all right now.
It seems...
... it all went well?
It's too soon to celebrate,
fool, ya fool.
Shall we try to control
the Nine-Tails' power now?
From this moment,
I'll be your Master!
Better steel yourself,
or face disaster!
All right!
Come with me, Naruto!
Excuse me...
Do you mind if I join?
Okay!
What about Motoi?
I have to report in to the Hidden Cloud
at regular intervals,
so I'll take my leave here.
Thank you for your help.
Things won't be easy
from here on out.
So there was something on
the other side of the waterfall.
Wow!
You'll fight the Nine-Tails here!
Fight the Nine-Tails?
That's right, fool, ya fool.