Stone Golem!
It will pulverize him!
Wood Style:
Deep Forest Bloom!
Damn you!
As expected...
It's coming closer...
What should we do?!
That's... Grandfather's...!
Kazekage!
I know!
What is it?
Look at the scale of that!
To create a forest in an instant!
Everyone, beware of the pollen!
Do not inhale it!
Not just Deep Forest Emergence...
but Deep Forest Bloom as well?
How dare that Kabuto!
There is no shinobi alive today
who is as powerful as the First Hokage,
Hashirama Senju.
Everyone says that.
Just as they think that
the Sage of the Six Paths' power
was also a fairy tale.
It's time to show them that
all the fairy tales were real!
Wait, you bastard!
You were too distracted by the flowers...
N-No! Raikage!
Humph... Time to burn things up...
Fire Style: Majestic Demolisher!
Mizukage!
Water... Style...
I guess I am too old...
to do anything!
Look, the left side is dirty!
That's a precious rock of the Hidden Stone!
Polish it more evenly!
You need to put more spirit
into your polishing!
His puns kill me...
Hmm?
I don't know if it's a symbol of our village
or not, but it's just a plain old rock.
If we carved Stone Faces like the Hidden Leaf,
it would actually look impressive...
But our Lord Tsuchikage is such a cheapskate!
Ohnoki... I can tell the value of
a stone just by looking at it.
This rock...
symbolizes our village's Will of Stone!
It's our bedrock!
Don't be so cheap! And stop
using our symbol for your puns!
Well...
You're right.
This is just an ordinary rock.
Whaaaaaat?!
Wh-What's are you doing?
You stupid old man!
I can't tell which one it is now!
See... if you put a new one
here like this, no one would know.
What?!
What's important is
the Will of Stone inside you...
You see, I can also tell the worth
of someone's will just by looking at them.
Ohnoki...
Hidden within your will is
the power to change the world.
But if you're not careful,
that precious will of yours
may disappear...
Disappear?
Why?!
That's not the agreement!
Lord Hashirama said...
There is no alliance.
Just obey the Hidden Leaf!
And...
Never mention that shinobi's name
before me again!
Susano'o!
Barriers! As you keep
running into barriers,
you may abandon your will...
make excuses and even
replace it with hatred.
Listen closely, your will...
Never abandon it and
always stride with pride!
Seems you still want to keep dancing...
But there's no strength left in your step!
I'm making excuses...
Particle Style:
Atomic Dismantling Jutsu!
Look at me being pitiful about my age...
I should be excused...
for making an excuse!
What's this?
Ohnoki!
You're all awake!
All right!
Let's get on with our counterattack!
There he is!
You dance well.
But your step is still too weak.
That... looks like
the First Hokage's face!
I didn't want to believe it, but...
That's why he's able to
use the Wood Style!
And this is far different from what
Lord Orochimaru developed with Danzo.
The First Hokage was more
powerful than Madara.
This fusion of both will be
my ultimate weapon.
No one can stop
this Reanimation!
You there... woman,
user of the medical ninjutsu...
You have his blood running
through your veins, don't you?
And what of it?!
I'll bring you down first.
Taking out a unit's medic ninja
first is an established tactic.
Surely, you don't think we'd
let you do that so easily, do you?
You're wrong...
It's because she's a descendant
of Hashirama Senju.
Your medical ninjutsu
is only strong enough
to defer death only
for a short while.
Compared to Hashirama Senju,
your jutsu is trivial.
He was able to heal without
even weaving signs.
He was in another class
in every jutsu.
Everyone called him
the most powerful shinobi.
I fought a real death match
against him...
This is child's play.
Compared to him, what do you,
his descendant, have to offer?
You can't even use the Wood Style...
Your medical ninjutsu
doesn't even come close.
And most of all,
you're a weak woman!
Weakness disgusts me.
And a weak Senju disgusts me
even more!
You've gone on long enough!
I am a descendant of
the first Hokage Hashirama...
And true,
I don't use the Wood Style.
My medical ninjutsu is pathetic
compared to the First's,
who didn't even
have to weave signs!
And I am a woman...
But not a weak woman.
Simple strength isn't everything.
It's something passed on to me,
and continues to flow
from the First Hokage.
That is my true power!
You think you can beat me
with Hashirama's will?
Power is not will.
Power is only the ability
to make things happen.
You're wrong!
The will of the dead
shows its power
in those they left behind!
I used that will to develop
my medical ninjutsu.
From there, medic ninja and
Medical Laws were established!
Rule One! A medic ninja must
never give up on treatment
until their patient's dying breath.
Rule Two! A medic ninja must
never go to the frontlines!
Rule Three!
A medic ninja should always be
the last of their squad to die!
This is what I teach my students.
But there is actually
one more rule...
Rule Four!
A medic ninja who masters
the Ninja Art of Mitotic Regeneration,
the 100 Healings...
may break the first three rules!
The 100 Healings Jutsu?
I've never heard of it.
It's a Forbidden Jutsu that
applies only to me.
Which means,
I am the only medic ninja
allowed to battle!
The Particle Style Jutsu may
have dissipated the pollen...
But adding one medic ninja
won't make any difference...
Four wasn't working,
so we'll try five!
Don't you dare think
I'm an ordinary medic ninja!
She's not as fast as the Raikage...
Let's go!
But her power is greater than his!
Fire Style:
Majestic Demolisher Flame!
Water Style: Water Pillar!
Water Style:
Water Dragon Missile!
Weighted Boulder!
Lateral Bolt of Pain! Chop!
I admit...
You're not weak, woman.
However...
If you step in and die here,
all the other Kage will die.
Since you're the only one
who can heal them.
That's if I die.
Hashirama...
I don't know what
you left behind...
But this falls far short
of your abilities.
If you were going to let
your underlings take over,
you should have taught them
how to resurrect you too...
All that's left of you is the life
force of your cells that cling to me.
All that's left of
my little brother is
the visual prowess of his eyes,
which are now mine.
That's why...
I said you're wrong!
The only thing that is
passed down...
is hatred.
You're already dead!
So don't spread any more hate!
Kazekage! Now!
Grand Sand Mausoleum!
He's been sealed!
All right!
The one you sealed away
is a Wood Style Clone
that Hashirama used to use.
It is well-made...
My visual prowess made me the only shinobi
who was able to see the ruse...
in the past.
Now then...
It's over for the rest of you Kage...
How can you move?
Like I told you, I'm different!
Regeneration without weaving signs...
So that's the real power of your jutsu
mentioned in Rule Four.
It's just like Hashirama's power.
I wanted to catch you off guard
with this, but...
You can't kill me with
my own jutsu.
I can kill you, with my jutsu!
Have you gone senile, Ohnoki?
The Rinnegan can absorb
all jutsu.
Ninjutsu like that will
not work against me!
To kill me, you need to hit me
hard physically and seal me.
You know that.
My Particle Style grazed
your chest earlier...
There's no way that the Atomic
Dismantling Jutsu failed!
Oh that...
I just wanted to show you
all Hashirama's face.
I wanted to reduce your morale...
But it seems it had the opposite effect...
It boosted your morale instead.
Let me ask you a question.
While it doesn't change the fact
that you outwitted us with
the Wood Style Clone...
But from another angle,
you could say we managed
to corner you
into having to substitute
a clone for yourself.
Am I wrong?
It is five against one, after all...
Even if it is five-to-one,
we must win, no matter what.
Don't call it unfair!
In truth, it is a testament
to your might!
You are Madara Uchiha!
It's not unfair.
Five-to-one... It's just the right ratio
for playing games.
Now it's five-to-one.
Don't say this is unfair.
You are the Five Kage.
So now I've got
a question for you...
Would you like these clones
to use Susano'o or not?
Your choice.
Answer me.
Would you like these clones
to use Susano'o or not?
Your choice.
The likes of you have no answer.
Well, I'll answer for you.
Impossible...
T-There are so many...
They'll use it.
This guy...
Five against one for each of us?
Let's go!
The Five Kage are struggling
against Madara.
There's unbelievable chakra!
He's not just a legendary shinobi...
He's been reanimated.
He's immortal,
so he has infinite chakra.
It's no wonder the Five Kage
are having a hard time.
We must do something about
the user of this Reanimation Jutsu.
Any word from the Investigative Unit?
Nothing. They've been searching
every spot thought to be a hideout.
And not one sign of Kabuto.
And the Sensory Unit?
We're getting no response.
He's probably put up a barrier.
Shall I send out more shinobi?
We've sent every man available.
Anymore will weaken the front.
Who would have imagined that
Kabuto could do so much?
They're too strong!
How are we supposed to...?
You're right. At this rate...
Hokage, your fighting
is getting sloppy!
It might not kill you, but keep fighting
like that and you'll only exhaust yourself.
I'm putting my life on the line
for this battle!
There is no other way!
Hokage!
No...
Damn! How could I...
have fallen prey to
Sharingan genjutsu?
Release!
Thanks, Tsuchikage.
Damn that Ohnoki...
His wisdom in battle is
beginning to show...
He stopped Susano'o with
the Weighted Boulder Jutsu...
and saved the Raikage.
Stand, my fellow Kage!
No more weakness!
Let us look death in
the face together!
We are the Five Kage!
So choose final words that
will not shame your title!
Remember the battle that
we entrusted to Naruto!
He entrusted this battle to us and we
swore that we would win, no matter what!
And there is one more thing...
We cannot betray the trust of
each and every shinobi.
We must be worthy
of the title of Kage!
So the problem is...
Ohnoki, after all.
I have no choice
but to break his will.
More, Princess!
You don't have to tell me!
There's not much chakra left!
We must consider this
our last stand.
Particle Style:
Boundary Dismantling Jutsu!
Releasing Susano'o kept me
from absorbing the Particle Style...
I told you the only thing that will
work against me are physical attacks.
You think you've eliminated the clones,
and distracted me with the Particle Style?
It's not just sand!
If you don't like the sand,
just stop absorbing the jutsu!
But then, the Lightning Water Dragon
will paralyze you.
And I'll use that moment to
wedge him in with my Particle Style!
That will give us enough time
to seal him away!
Do you see this?
This is the full power
of the Five Kage!
I see...
This truly is worthy of the shinobi
who bear the name Kage.
Then I, Madara Uchiha,
shall also respond with full power!
The Five Kage are nothing
compared to me.
This is...
my Perfect Susano'o!
It's massive.
Is this...
the True Susano'o?
Not quite yet...
Settle down!
The big one's chakra
has settled down...
I can't believe the difference
in power...
I can't believe Grandfather
fought someone like him!
I already told you...
Hashirama was the only one
who could stop me.
But he's no longer here.
Though you could say that
actually works in your favor.
That's because...
It's just me...
so the maps will only need
to be redrawn a little.
Impossible! He split the mountain!
This is... Madara Uchiha...
Then why back then...?
Why did you hold back against us?
What adult goes full force
when fighting mere children?
Besides... Are you finished now?
We may be stumbling in the dark,
but we're close to the light
at the end of the tunnel!
Here, of all places...
This Susano'o is destruction incarnate.
A single stroke of the blade
contains enough power
to smash all things in this universe.
It rivals even the Tailed Beasts!
Take your philosophy, Five Kage,
and be crushed and be gone!
I see...
Lots and lots of shinobi?
According to these birds...
It's a war, right?
We should find Sasuke before
we get mixed up in this war.
You're so handsome!
But how dare you try to kill me!
Why that—!
Idiot! But I still want you!
No... He tried to kill me!
No forgiveness!
But he's so handsome!
What has she been doing?!
It's a hand-drawn picture.
She keeps talking to it.
Poor thing...
She must've gone through hell.
Oh... that picture of Sasuke?
Aren't we supposed
to confiscate that?
I tried to.
That's when she went nuts.
She'll stay calm if
we let her keep it.
It's just a picture. That's all.
Okay then, why don't we play
a nice, quiet game of cards?
Sure.
It'd be great if Sasuke
were here at this hideout.
This place is special, after all.
Orochimaru's favorite spot.
Hey, Sasuke... Are you here?
The size of this hideout
is ridiculous.
What's wrong?
Nothing. My head just started hurting.
Is he going to go on
a rampage again?
Sasuke, Karin and Jugo...
Hebi, Taka or whatever...
I'm the only normal one among us.
Suigetsu...
What is it?
Something's always bothered me
about you.
Oh yeah?!
Well, I'm always concerned
about you.
You keep me on pins and needles.
I'm here because I made
a promise to Kimimaro.
Why are you here?
Are you in Team Taka just to
cause trouble with Sasuke and Karin?
Why?
Yeah, why?
I would love to break those
two losers up for good!
I can't help it!
I just want to break everything in two!
You really are the worst,
you know that?
On that scale,
Sasuke is the worst of all.
I hate all of you!
I lead you idiots to water,
and you just splash it in
my face instead of drinking it.
That's why...
I hate you most of all!
Huh?!
This is...
I've been here lots of times...
I never knew this existed.
Is this one of...
Orochimaru's secret rooms?
Huh?
What?
This is... Orochimaru planned
all of this?
If so, this intel could change
the outcome of this entire war!
This might be a very nice present
for Sasuke.
We found something incredible
by chance!
Jugo... that punch is
water under the bridge...
Snap out of it, Jugo.
We've got to find Sasuke quick!
You didn't waste any time
coming after me.
What are you doing here?!
Or not... it seems...
I passed by two towns
on my way here,
but they were deserted.
I thought something
wasn't quite right outside.
Do you know anything about it?
We asked you a question first!
How come you're outside?!
What happened to the one of us
that was with you?
If you don't like the fact
that I'm out,
why don't you catch me?
Especially since you
outnumber me this time.
You didn't kill our original,
did you?!
With this many of you,
I hope it's more of
a challenge this time.
Susano'o!
Sharingan!
It's a war...
Take down the enemy.
Looks like Madara's started things.
Capture Killer Bee and
Naruto Uzumaki.
If you don't hurry...
More and more of his friends
will join up with him...
one after another.
You're someone who knows
the pain of solitude like I do.
And that pain makes people stronger.
And for that very reason,
by cutting that bond,
I will be able to obtain
even greater strength.
Have you forgotten, Naruto...
What real power is?
I'm going to where you are...
To cut you down.
You're not Hidden Leaf shinobi.
You're not part of the promise.
These are good eyes.
I'm quickly getting used
to them, brother.
When you have the same eyes
as me, come before me.
The scenes burned into these eyes...
that once belonged to my brother...
are disgustingly sad...
They weigh me down.
But that's only fitting.
Just you watch, brother!
Wait!
Is that you, Itachi?!
I said... wait!
This Susano'o...
So you are Itachi!
I'm surprised that you've been
able to master it too...
What are you doing here?!
You're supposed to be dead!
This is Kabuto's jutsu...
I am reanimated now.
I can't stop now.
There's something I have to do.
I don't care!
You're here before me and
I have a lot of questions!
Ask me later... But I guess
that's not going to happen.
You said so yourself!
To come find you once
I had the same eyes as you!
So why are you running?
To avoid admitting
that you lied to me?!
Or don't you have
the courage to tell the truth?!
I already know...
everything about you!
That's why I decided to destroy
the Hidden Leaf!
I told you when we fought...
That people live
under false assumptions...
I asked if you could think
about it that way.
And how one's reality
might be an illusion.
Is my truth really—
I no longer live
inside an illusion!
And I can see through
your genjutsu!
These are your eyes!
You're as confident as ever,
but I've heard about you
from others.
That you've changed a lot...
No! You changed everything
about me!
I was supposed to die!
You were supposed to kill me
along with our parents.
But...
Why me?!
How was I different from
mother and father?
Why just me?
Because you didn't know anything.
You had no part in
the Uchiha Clan's folly.
You were just a child.
Also, do you think
I did it just for you?
I wanted to be judged and
dealt with only by another Uchiha.
So I took advantage of
the hatred inside you.
That's why I failed.
Ultimately, I filled you with hatred
and made you go rogue.
And turned you into a criminal!
All I wanted was for you
to walk the right path.
Before I died, I tried to lead you
down that one path
without any forks or turns...
I changed the signposts
on that path with lies
and my visual prowess.
I was supposed to happily walk
that one path,
ignorant of everything?!
I... don't care for such a path!
Yeah...
You're absolutely right.
You must decide your own journey.
No matter how much you try
to rewrite the signposts,
my eyes can strip away
the top layer!
What's so funny?!
Nothing...
I'm just realizing that
the signposts were
not your only guides.
I'm a dead man.
There's no point in
talking any further.
When you were alive,
you never paid any attention to me.
Always flicking my forehead,
saying "forgive me" and running off.
Now you're dead, and
you're still running away from me?!
I'm not running away.
I told you.
There's something I must do.
Summoning Jutsu!
Damn it!
You stay here.
There, huh?
What a useless barrier.
I'm impressed you were able
to pass through my barrier,
and find this place.
When you were controlling me,
I was able to pinpoint where
your chakra was coming from.
That's another risk of this jutsu.
Though you won't need to
remember that for next time.
Thanks for the tip.
I didn't expect any shinobi
to counter this jutsu,
so I didn't even worry about it.
By the way, there's something
I'd like you to know as well.
This Reanimation Jutsu
will not come undone
even if you kill me.
But I am the only one
who can stop it.
In other words...
You can't kill me.
If I die, you'll never be able
to stop this jutsu.
I guess my luck
hasn't run out yet!
Things are not always as
we wish them to be, damn it!
I caught up to you!
What the hell are you doing here?
Is that... Orochimaru?
You're a little off...
That voice...
Kabuto!
It's perfect timing that my compensation
for participating in this war
would show up, on his own,
at this particular moment...
I am so lucky.
What are you talking about?
It's rather complicated...
Let me try to explain.
Go ahead.
And in the meantime,
I'll stop the Reanimation.
Sasuke...
You want to bring down Itachi, the
bane of the Uchiha, once again, don't you?
Since I brought him back
to this realm.
In short, Itachi is a nuisance
to both you and me.
Well? Shall we team up and
take Itachi down together?
We share the same power of
the snake and the same Master—
I have no intention of calling
that thing my Master!
Besides, it seems like
you don't know anything, do you?
I chased Itachi all the way here
to talk to him.
Well then... whose side
are you on right now?
Why?!
He's just like Orochimaru!
Which means he's my enemy!
And right now,
he's your enemy too, right?!
All right, we'll talk later.
First things first,
let's take him down.
But don't kill him.
If you kill the caster
of the Reanimation,
the jutsu can never be undone.
We'll put him under
my Tsukuyomi,
then we'll make him tell us
how to stop this jutsu.
And while he's still under
the Tsukuyomi,
I'll control him and...
I'll break this jutsu.
Thanks for the play-by-play.
I hope it goes as smoothly
as you say.
But I told you earlier,
this jutsu has neither weakness
nor risks—
Every jutsu has a weakness.
This jutsu's weakness and risk...
is my existence!
Itachi... you've kept lying to me,
telling me "next time"
or "later," then you died on me...
So this time for sure...
I'm holding you to your promise.
They say you take
your personality to the grave.
Well, I've already died once.
I intend to honor it.
The estranged brothers
come together to gang up on me?
How fun!
Bookish types like me
aren't used to being stared at.
Countermeasures for genjutsu, huh?
Judging from their movements,
those snakes can sense
exactly what we're doing.
Snakes perceive their surroundings
through body heat
and smell through their tongues.
You've done your research!
You're like a snake expert now.
Naturally. In order
to take down Orochimaru!
However...
You can't beat me by just
being a snake expert.
This is my field.
Nature is on my side.
The snakes have gotten bigger!
Does this terrain give him
an advantage?
Be wary of traps, Sasuke.
Traps?
Oh, that's not what I meant!
That's the Susano'o, right?
Don't get too violent, Sasuke!
Remember, I told you
not to kill him!
It seems he's acquired
Orochimaru's power.
He won't die so easily!
Sasuke!
The hood!
What?!
Why that—!
You're taking
the shyness thing too far.
First, you hide your face,
and now your entire body?
Did you just molt
to make a getaway?
All you have is what
you took from Orochimaru.
You're still nothing!
Sasuke... You underestimate me.
Well, then again,
I was listed lower than you
on the danger scale
in the Bingo Book...
And of course, I'm nothing
compared to Lord Orochimaru.
That's for sure.
Especially if you consider
this hiding.
Sasuke, watch out!
There's chakra everywhere...
It's hard to tell which
is the real one.
It's the ability to transform
one's flesh into liquid.
To detach and separate
using one's own life substance.
That's why it looks like a shedding.
I've researched and applied
the Hozuki Clan's Flesh Transforming
ability to this technique.
You know him, don't you? Suigetsu.
He can transform from human
to water, and back to human again.
Plus, I have the amazing ability
to recuperate quickly.
I admit it's a healing technique
that I studied
from the body of a woman
originally from the Uzumaki Clan...
Someone you're quite familiar
with... Karin.
Karin's from the Uzumaki Clan?
A special trait of those with
Uzumaki blood is their red hair.
And their life force is
as tenacious as a cockroach.
Now then, you must be thinking
about the last member
of your team.
Or perhaps he's no longer
your comrade?
You have a discerning eye
since you chose those three.
In the shinobi World,
those without talent are nothing.
But those who lack talent
can just steal it from those who do.
Seems like you have
Jugo's ability too...
Did you receive a Curse Mark
from Orochimaru?!
No!
That is just a temporary boost.
That memento is something
I actually cultivated myself...
at Ryuchi Cave!
Ryuchi Cave?!
Yes, I found it!
A place as legendary as Mt. Myoboku,
and the Shikkotsu Woods!
Lord Orochimaru is not
the only one to have reached it.
I went there...
and trained under the guidance
of the White Snake Sage.
And I was able to surpass
Lord Orochimaru at long last.
I did it!
Don't be impatient, Sasuke!
He dodged... that arrow?
My sensory ability is better
than it used to be.
Nature Energy is my ally now.
Nature Energy?
I knew it. So he does have...
Listen...
The members of Jugo's clan
have always had
special bodies that
absorbed Nature Energy.
That's the secret behind
those rampages.
The ability causes them to suddenly
become more wild and powerful.
Lord Orochimaru wasn't interested
in Jugo's rampages...
so much as the origin
of his clan's power.
And he finally found the source...
It was Ryuchi Cave.
Lord Orochimaru immediately
tried to acquire that power.
But, he didn't yet possess a body
that could tolerate it.
That's why...
He couldn't become the perfect Sage...
that I have become!
Just as I thought...
you're using Sage Mode.
You're just like Orochimaru!
A disgusting snake!
You ought to know better,
you snake expert...
I'm no longer a snake.
With my perfect Sage power,
I've shed my snakeskin...
I am now a dragon!
Sage Art: White Extreme Attack!
My ears...
And my bones... They feel like
they're being grated.
It's a jutsu that uses
light and sound
to impair vision and hearing...
A jutsu that causes the air to oscillate...
to paralyze the senses, freezing movement.
A snake's cornea can
block out the light
and by turning my flesh
into fluid,
I can easily absorb
the sound and vibration.
The only one who can move
freely under these conditions...
is me in Sage Mode!
It's no use!
We can't maintain Susano'o!
Yes, I should go for Itachi.
I'll rewrite the Paper Seal
in his head
and turn him into my pawn again.
Or even better...
Itachi...
It seems you always
end up finding me.
Can you sense my chakra?
I never said I was the one
who was able to sense
your chakra.
Only Nagato could do that,
and I was with him.
I have no such ability.
Besides, even now, I know
what your target is anyway.
I merely move to protect that which
I think you'll most want to attack.
If a man as cautious and
opportunistic as you wants Sasuke...
you will go for him first.
Your best chance to
capture Sasuke is now,
before either of us figures
out your jutsu.
And after that, you could use
Sasuke to manipulate me.
What sets you apart from
the rest of the Uchiha Clan
is that you have true visual prowess...
You have the ability to peer into
and read people's souls.
And use what you learn in battle.
That is why you are so good
at deceiving people...
You died lying in the first place,
that makes you a lying ninja
through and through!
He's on the ceiling!
You think a makeshift team of two
can outwit my perception skills?
And because your brother
lied so much,
you know nothing about each other...
Sasuke...
Do you remember that time
you tagged along with me
on my mission?
The wild boar?
That's it, right?
Don't kill it.
Huh?
Just hurt it, and it will return
to the mountain.
Let's go.
Yeah.
Don't hit a vital spot.
I know!
– Now!
He's going to steal my blade
and cut off his own tail
to escape!
That's why he told you
not to be so impatient.
Oh that's right, I'd forgotten.
I have horns here now.
Big brother...
You completely missed.
Sorry, big brother...
You need more training.
Let's go home, Sasuke.
I'll help you train
when we return.
Okay!
Looks like you might be able to
take down that giant wild boar now.
Instead of that giant wild boar,
we've got to take down that snake.
Yeah...
It's so funny...
What is?
Right now, you two look like
you're quite friendly
with each other.
What happened to those brothers
who fought and hated each other?
It's not hard to guess that something
happened between you two,
back when you took him down...
But what is it that you want to ask
of a once-dead man?
The truth.
Oh really?
Could it be?
With the way you're talking...
you don't really trust
Itachi, after all?
Sasuke...
Maybe you already know
the truth about Itachi?
No wonder you didn't return
to the Leaf
after defeating Itachi.
That's why you joined the Akatsuki
who plotted the Leaf's destruction!
I see now...
It all makes so much sense
to me now.
That's why you intend to
destroy the village
that caused your brother
so much pain.
As expected.
You're not denying it.
So you followed your brother,
who you happened across,
all the way here to find out
the truth once and for all.
Like "Is this what happened then?"
and "What about that time?"
in complete detail...
Like I said,
your brother is a liar!
I know.
So isn't it odd?
Itachi was willing to kill his
own family to protect the village.
Isn't that the opposite of
what you're trying to do?
Well...
I'm the one who wants
what you want, Sasuke!
After all, Lord Orochimaru could not
complete Leaf Destruction.
And it is I who inherited that task.
So think carefully...
Now's the time to stab Itachi
in the back and join me.
What? You don't have to feel guilty.
He's already dead.
He's just an imitation.
We received intel that
Itachi Uchiha of the Akatsuki is dead.
Put a mark on his image and
remove him from your Bingo Book.
So that traitor is dead at last.
But Captain,
who was able to kill him?
Looks like it was
his kid brother, Sasuke.
How ironic... His own brother killed
the one who slaughtered his family.
Serves him right!
After the atrocities he committed!
Not only that, he joined up with the
Akatsuki and came after the Leaf Village!
He's the most notorious villain
in Hidden Leaf history!
Damn it, I wish we got
our hands on him first!
Since he took down such
a special S-Class criminal,
his little brother will probably
receive many decorations
and a large bounty from
the nation and village, right?
I wonder how much?
It's not a question of money.
You're out of line.
Well... I know, but...
They don't know the truth...
Besides, there are
too many people around.
I'll teach them the truth!
Don't...
Even if they try to confirm the truth
about Itachi with their superiors,
the Leaf's elders will
deny it vehemently.
Even the current Hokage
doesn't know the facts.
Furthermore...
Itachi did slaughter the Uchiha,
and he joined the Akatsuki
on the pretense of attacking
the Hidden Leaf.
No one will believe the truth...
Look how long it took you.
For bastards like them...
For these bastards
who easily brand him a traitor...
my brother...
This is exactly what
Itachi wanted.
If you don't like it,
what is it that you want?
We're not the same.
My Leaf Destruction is mine alone!
I understand very well
why Itachi chose that life.
I was just like him...
It was nice being found
by a Leaf shinobi,
but because my background
was a mystery,
I was raised to be a spy.
In order to become someone
who could be trusted,
medical ninjutsu was
drilled into me.
I went from village to
village spying...
I pretended to be someone else,
living a life of lies.
With no place for the real me.
I had no friends
who knew the real me.
I continued to work
on suppressing myself.
And around the time I stopped knowing
who I even was anymore...
the Hidden Leaf Village
stopped trusting me
and I was relieved of my mission.
Both Itachi and I worked for
the good of the Leaf Village,
but in return, all we got
was dishonor and disgrace!
What in the world has
the Leaf Village ever done for us?
How Itachi lived is what led to
the creation of the current you.
And though I am still alive,
something similar to you
was born from me too.
No one understands you
better than I.
Thus, I will be your big brother
and stick by your side.
Now... join me...
Don't listen to him, Sasuke.
He was an even better spy
than I was.
Which means, he's even better
than me at lying.
And...
No matter what darkness or
contradictions lie within the village,
I am still Itachi Uchiha of the Leaf!
Sasuke... It's my fault
you're like this right now.
I know I have no right
to advise you in any way.
But I hope you'll hear me out
because I have to
tell you something.
But first, let's take care
of business...
and stop this guy.
You cannot kill me
as long as I am the user
of the Reanimation Jutsu.
And I can instantly recover
from any injury you inflict.
It's meaningless.
I shut down my eyesight.
So the much-touted genjutsu of
your visual prowess won't work on me...
You, brothers, can't beat me!
Because I cast it,
this Reanimation Jutsu
is invincible!
It's a pain listening to him.
But he explained
the situation perfectly.
I don't need you to tell me that.
So... what should we do?
He doesn't know the true power
of the Uchiha.
The Uchiha have a visual jutsu that can
be used on an opponent without eyesight...
In exchange for losing the light
in one's eyes.
Izanagi...?
You know about Izanagi?
Danzo used it when I fought him.
You're lucky to be alive.
Never mind about that...
How do we use Izanagi?
I'm not talking about Izanagi.
Another Forbidden Jutsu that
is considered its other half.
Another?!
I've already laid the plan.
An Ultimate visual jutsu that
holds his fate within its grasp.
Izanami!
Izanami?!
If Izanagi is a jutsu
that changes one's fate,
then Izanami is a jutsu
that decides it!
Sasuke... Do not leave my side.
A jutsu that decides one's fate?
So there's another jutsu
similar to Izanagi?!
I don't know what you're up to...
but nothing will work against me.
It seems you still don't
understand just who I am!
Sage Art: Inorganic Animation!
Itachi!
This jutsu brings
the lifeless to life
and allows me to control them.
It's different from a jutsu that
simply manipulates with chakra...
A bit extreme, don't you think?
Protecting Sasuke with
your Susano'o slowed you down.
Well, don't worry.
I would never harm Sasuke.
He's my precious test subject.
Now then...
Time to rewrite your mind with this.
You know what will happen, right?
Amaterasu!
So the ultimate offensive
visual jutsu
is also the ultimate defense...
It's so hot, the limestone cave
went back to being just a cave.
I'm sorry... Sasuke...
Sorry, but this is my win.
I am so near the point where I
can achieve and control everything...
I can't imagine myself failing.
All the laws and principles
of nature,
which Lord Orochimaru researched
and compiled for so long...
are now stored and
being used inside of me.
I have evolved from human
to snake to dragon.
I am the closest thing in this
world to the Sage of Six Paths.
Compared to me, the Uchiha are...
Shut up!
What would you know...
about the Uchiha?!
Listen...!
Kabuto...
When I look at you,
it's like looking at my former self.
And that is why you will lose...
Listen... I'm not on
the sidelines anymore.
You could say I'm a central figure
in this war!
I had the Akatsuki twisted
around my little finger,
and manipulated this war
to my advantage...
and I even pushed
the Uchiha brothers into a corner.
I hate you,
but I understand you.
We were both spies who
lived false lives in this world.
I didn't know who I really was
at one point either.
I finally understand that
to know oneself
is not to achieve everything
and become perfect.
It's knowing what you can
and cannot do.
Sounds like the words of a loser.
Acknowledging what
you cannot do...
Isn't that the same as giving up?
No.
It is to be able to forgive oneself for
the things one cannot do by themselves.
You can't do everything yourself.
That's why you have comrades
who can help you.
And it also makes sure that you don't miss
the things that you can still accomplish.
If you want to know
who you are...
You must reexamine and
acknowledge your true self.
I failed to do that.
I lied to everyone and I lied to myself...
and I deluded myself.
Those who cannot acknowledge
themselves will fail...
Just like I did.
And what would you two
really know about me?
I have been pursuing who
and what I am in my own way.
My whole life...
I bet he's from that city...
Where that recent battle was!
What'll we do, Sis?
He's bleeding from the head.
He's going to die soon.
Are you going to take him?
Urushi...
His injuries are less severe
than yours were.
Don't worry.
I may not look it,
but I know some medical ninjutsu.
Where are your parents?
What's your name?
Man... Don't you understand anything?!
Urushi, lend him your shoulder.
You're lucky, kid!
Come on, grab my shoulder!
That's my first memory...
I was a nobody
and had nothing from
the very beginning.
Your wound seems
to be healing nicely.
Hey, at least say, "thank you"!
Don't you have any manners?!
Hey, we don't want anything to
happen to you again, so put this on!
Ow...
You don't have manners,
you don't have parents...
you don't even know your name.
That's a first for me!
You'll be living here
with us now.
In other words, I am your mother,
starting now.
You can always ask me
for whatever you need.
It's inconvenient that
he doesn't have a name...
You're right...
What would be a good name?
How about...
"Kabuto" like the helmet?
– Sounds simple.
– That was quick.
Just based on looks.
It's best not to overthink things.
– I'll think of something.
– Not you!
What would be a good name?
Hey, he smiled!
I think he likes that name!
Oh good...
At least say, "thank you"!
Don't you have any manners?!
Hmm... What to do...?
We can't get by with just subsistence
aid from the village or nation anymore.
We have to talk to them once more!
Neither the village nor
the nation will give us a cent more.
But we're barely scraping by.
And we just took another one in...
I understand.
I'll do something about it, so...
Oww!
What are you doing at this hour?!
You should be in bed!
He just got here and
doesn't know about
our curfews and rules!
Please give him another chance!
You're too indulgent, Mother.
Come here and look at the clock!
It's already 20 minutes
past lights-out time!
Which makes lights-out
what time?
Let's learn it right now!
Well, what time is it?
You must learn it yourself!
He's still young.
He doesn't know arithmetic
or how to tell time.
Let's just call it a night.
Nine o'clock.
That's correct.
It seems it was just bad vision!
He's smart for his age!
We must get him glasses!
Huh? And where are we going
to get money for that?
Seriously! If you couldn't see,
you should have spoken up.
From now on,
you'll be able to be on time.
I just hope the lenses
are right for you.
Thank... you...
My name is symbolic.
My eyeglasses, a tool...
Thank you...
From the very beginning,
– I was a nobody...
– Thank you...
Thank you...
That's enough.
Kabuto, are you able
to keep going?
Yes, Mother!
I know it's for the sake
of the orphanage,
but why do we have
to help shinobi like them?
Doing nothing doesn't
bring in money...
Urushi, could you get more bandages?
Yeah, sure!
You're not a shinobi,
but you're quite skilled
at medical ninjutsu...
Mother taught me.
You said your name was Kabuto?
Why don't you become a shinobi?
You'd make a good one...
I'm sure of it.
I'm not interested in that.
I just want to help raise money
for the orphanage
and help Mother there.
She's done so much for me...
but I've only been able to repay her
with a pair of eyeglasses...
Really? What a shame.
You were known
as the Wandering Nun,
and now you're just a babysitter.
It's been a while
since I last saw you,
but you're looking a little tired, Nonou.
I cast aside that name long ago.
Talks with the Leaf for
monetary aid were concluded.
So why are you here now?
It seems the Espionage Unit's
former top spy
stopped knowing things after
she left the Foundation.
We did not come here only
in regard to the aid money.
In this time of war,
we have obtained intel that
the Hidden Stone are plotting
some sort of large-scale operation.
We want you to infiltrate
the Hidden Stone
and verify the validity of this intel.
And if it does turn out to be true,
you are to investigate what
this operation entails
and where it will occur
and report back to us.
This will likely be
a long-term mission.
Then you've come
to the wrong person.
I'm no longer...
You people don't understand
just how essential Mother is
to this orphanage and
to the children!
She has done her utmost
to protect this orphanage.
Such a dangerous task!
You Foundation people ought
to do it yourselves.
Why must you come
and bother her?
The Wandering Nun is the only one
we can entrust
this long-term mission to.
Currently, no one in the Foundation
has her espionage skills.
Most would likely break or
end up switching allegiances.
I know that she's a Kunoichi who
would never sell out the Hidden Leaf...
From that expression,
I can tell you've already
guessed it, Nonou.
Yes, if you refuse,
this clinic will stop receiving funding.
That's not fair!
This was already settled
with the Third Hokage!
You cannot do this!
This orphanage looks easy
to break into and rob...
You should hire bodyguards to
prevent robbers from stealing your money.
That is, if you can afford any.
While you're at it, take care that
your children don't get snatched either.
Children with no past or family
are worth something.
You're all rotten!
How dare you call
yourselves shinobi?!
You're the ones
who don't understand!
It's a small price to pay
to protect the Hidden Leaf!
I understand.
Wait, Mother...!
It's come to this because
you couldn't kill your emotions.
You weren't suited for
the Foundation, after all.
How dare you...!
Also, I've already lost a subordinate
obtaining this intel...
I'll be taking one of the children here
to replace him.
How far will you go?
I said I'd accept the mission!
This is a separate matter.
Your mission shall cover
subsequent payments.
But this current one is
in exchange for the child.
Some children actually wish to
become a Leaf shinobi, after all.
You should ask them
to choose for themselves.
There may just be one such child.
Why, Kabuto?
I think I'm suited to be a ninja.
Besides, I want to hone
my medical ninjutsu.
Kabuto! You're just going to throw away
the three years you spent with us?!
Come back here!
Have you forgotten
the house rules, everyone?
It's way past lights-out.
It's no use. I'm surrounded.
If I hadn't messed up,
I'd be in bed by now.
It's been five years since
I left the orphanage.
I wish I could've seen Mother and
everyone else one last time...
Mother!
No! Why are you here?
We want you to infiltrate
the Hidden Stone...
The Wandering Nun is the only one
we can entrust this
long-term mission to.
Don't tell me... you were still
on that last mission?!
Why are you healing my wounds?
Who are you...?
It's me, Mother!
It's Kabuto!
Don't worry, I'll save you.
Who... are you...?
This way!
Damn it! Nanigashi's been killed!
Mother didn't know me? Why?
Why didn't she remember me?
Why?
If she doesn't remember me,
then who was I all this time?
What were all those things
I received from Mother?
My name, that I was
one of Mother's children,
even these glasses...
Who...
are you?
It seems you no longer
see yourself clearly.
You've become a fine shinobi.
I remember you... Kabuto.
A-Aren't you...?!
I've been watching you
this whole time.
Along with Nonou.
Come with me.
Then I'll tell you everything
you want to know.
What I want to know?
What does that mean?
Why Mother targeted you...
and why she didn't
remember you at all.
Don't you want to know... all that?
This is my hideout.
No one knows about it.
Which means you are
my very first visitor.
Why did you bring me here?!
What are you going to do with me?
You are becoming
more and more curious.
That's a good thing.
People can never escape
their curiosity.
Which is why you followed me here.
Then tell me quickly!
You know what I want to know,
don't you?
To be frank, the Foundation had
decided to dispose of both you and Mother.
What do you mean?!
You both were too brilliant
as spies.
You ended up knowing too much.
What?!
We risked our lives for so long, gathering
intel for the sake of the village...
And this is what we get?
At times, intel becomes
even more powerful
than the mightiest jutsu or weapon.
You are seen as a very dangerous
person right now.
Well, your fate had been decided
from the very beginning...
It was written in the scenario for you
to take each other out.
Right after you left the orphanage,
Danzo revealed to Mother
the real reason why you had left.
That you sacrificed yourself and joined
the Foundation to secure funding for the orphanage.
Mother wished to liberate you
from the Foundation.
As a condition of accepting her wish,
Danzo ordered the assassination
of a certain person
several years ago.
Ironically...
The target of the assassination...
was you.
I thought it was the condition
for my release!
Why didn't Mother realize
it was me?!
I told you...
The Foundation intended for the
two of you to take each other out.
And there was other trickery afoot.
Trickery?
You and Mother were sent into
separate enemy territories
so that you two would never meet,
and Mother was kept informed of your
well-being and progress through photos.
The photos of you
were skillfully replaced
with those of another
without her noticing it.
Over time, Mother was made
to think someone else was you.
Gradual brainwashing.
A common practice used
by the Foundation.
That's the other Kabuto.
And so, Nonou tried to kill you,
never in her wildest dreams
imagining that you were Kabuto...
She thought you were a double agent
who betrayed the village.
And the Foundation dispatched you
to deal with whoever was left...
Is that it?
For someone who knows
nothing about himself...
You're very perceptive.
I always wanted...
an explanation about who I was!
And I thought
I had finally found it!
But thanks to you
Foundation bastards,
I've lost myself again!
These glasses were
what linked me to Mother!
The name she gave me
was mine and mine alone!
Mother was supposed
to be the parent
that didn't forget me,
no matter what!
But everything's wrong!
Then who in the world...
am I?!
You merely lack sufficient intel
with which to define yourself.
It's just that neither the glasses, your
name, nor the fact that you're her child
were things that denote
who you really are.
And that's fine.
If you're not satisfied with
what you've had so far...
Just find other things and add
them onto yourself, one by one.
If you plan on killing me...
why are you telling me all this?
I also want to know who or what I am.
And I've been collecting
all sorts of things.
I repeatedly experiment on
and inspect these many things
I've accumulated bit by bit...
and store the gained knowledge
and abilities within myself.
And then, I undergo rebirth,
ever evolving toward
a more perfect me.
Afterward, I again obtain
even newer items.
This time...
it's you.
There's no way you couldn't derive
who you are and what you are
by gathering all the intel and
things that exist in this world.
Why am I one of those things
to you?
Because I recognize your talent
more than anyone else in this world.
It would be a waste to kill you.
Besides, this medical research facility
was prepared just for you.
What are you plotting?
Instead of the Foundation
which erases individuality...
I will create an organization
that guides individuality.
I will create a village.
The Village of the Hidden Sound...
that does not belong to any nation.
From this moment, you and I will
desert the Hidden Leaf's Foundation.
From this moment, I shall be your
superior, your brother, and your parent.
I will protect you from Danzo.
From this moment,
this will be your
new personal history:
When you were very young,
you were found and raised
by a Medical Corps Captain
following the Battle at Kikyo Pass.
After returning to work under Danzo,
Nonou Yakushi kept her cover
as a captain of the Medical Unit...
and you shall be reborn today
as her son, Kabuto Yakushi.
I am Orochimaru.
If you want to know
who and what you are...
Come... be by my side.
There's another organization
I want to look into...
Please leave it to me.
What is this organization?
The Akatsuki.
Bring me Orochimaru's human
experimentation data
and any intel on
the Reanimation Jutsu.
Understood, Lord Sasori.
You are useful.
You can erase your sound,
your scent, even yourself.
You're just like one of my puppets.
If you're not satisfied with
what you've had so far...
Just find other things...
and add them onto yourself,
one by one.
It's still... not enough...
This is... still not me...!
That's why...
I've kept adding onto myself.
That's why I don't need
your lectures.
I need your abilities and intel.
Not only are you a Leaf shinobi,
you're of the famed Uchiha bloodline.
You possess the Sharingan that
has awakened the Mangekyo...
You bore many secrets
and stopped a war...
You had many jutsu
and much power.
Itachi, you possessed many things
that made you who you are.
There is no finer Reanimation
out there of mine than you.
And my pawns are
part of my power!
You exaggerate...
The reality is, I failed.
No, even though I mocked
the Uchiha name in front of you earlier,
I'm still quite envious
of that name.
The Uchiha name merely identifies
one's bloodline and clan membership.
So it's meaningless for you
to claim it.
No... It does hold meaning.
Are you sure we can't kill him?
We're stuck playing catch-up!
I told you no!
He controls the battlefield right now.
Be patient.
Is the Izanami still not ready?
He's about to come after us!
I'm already on him.
It's just going to take
a little more time.
Lord Orochimaru once said...
Sakon! Demon Twin Jutsu!
Jirobo! Earth Style:
Terra Shield!
"If you want to know who
and what you are,
"all you need to do is gather
every single thing
"and piece of information
that exists in this world!"
Kidomaru!
Spiral Web!
These threads can't be cut
with a blade!
– Amaterasu!
Kimimaro!
Macabre Bone Pulse!
Bracken Dance!
He's laid down the spider silk
all the way to the back.
I'll get the one behind us!
Take the front, brother!
Can you still use the Susano'o?
Yeah.
Inferno Style: Flame Control!
Running away to the back?
Well, it's no use!
Tayuya! Demon Flute:
Chains of Fantasia!
Are you okay, Sasu—?!
A genjutsu, huh?
Even your specialty, Susano'o,
cannot stifle sound...
I knew it...
Now you're immobilized.
All that's left is...
to take you into me
using Lord Orochimaru!
Well, Sasuke...
Do you recognize
this current form of mine?
That's...!
Kabuto...
You are not Orochimaru.
It's fine to imitate someone
you respect...
But don't remake yourself
into him, to that extent.
The majority of people start out
by mimicking someone.
Like how Sasuke mimicked you.
Such behavior is merely a process
to help one mature!
Don't use it as a cloak to
deceive yourself, like you've done!
You gain nothing when
you attach your self-value
to something external that's admirable
and praiseworthy to you.
I'll say this one last time.
Don't mislead yourself with lies.
Those who cannot acknowledge
themselves will invariably fail.
Fail? The way I am now?
How?!
Sasuke... Look into my eyes!
I understand!
Genjutsu... Sharingan!
Tsukuyomi!
I shall now engage the Izanami.
You have already... failed.
Is it over?
A genius that had everything
would never understand...
I just want to be who
and what I am!
I won't let anyone stop me.
Sa... suke...
Fire Style: Fireball jutsu!
Water Style: Giant Waterfall!
The same moves.
As expected...
It makes it easy for me to counter.
I already told you that as long as
I have my power of recovery,
wounding me is meaningless.
Since I shut off my vision,
genjutsu won't work on me.
You have no chance of winning.
Your fate is already in my hands.
Thanks to the Uchiha's other
Forbidden Jutsu.
That is...
Well then...
Shall we put that to the test?!
... the Izanami!
Sasuke, do not leave my side.
Why this is just like déjà vu.
I'm bored...
Let's end this fight already.
Your fate may be in my hands now...
but you're the only one
who can truly decide
how that fate shapes your destiny.
Remember what I've told you.
And think hard.
I have no idea what
you're talking about.
Enough of your word games.
I will have everything...
I am the strongest of all!
That is fact!
He who forgives oneself,
who can acknowledge one's true self...
is the most powerful of all!
Losers...
should be quiet!
This is...
What's... going on?
Why? That horn's already
been cut off!
How? I have no sight...
I should be invulnerable to genjutsu.
But this is clearly a...!
What did you do to me?!
You're in my visual jutsu.
Impossible!
It's the Izanami!
How...?
No matter.
No one can stop me!
There's nothing I can't do!
I told you...
I hold your fate in my hands.
Itachi Uchiha!
If this is a genjutsu...
Release!
Calm down...
This is an Uchiha genjutsu.
Moreover, Itachi cast it,
so it won't be easy to undo.
But there are many ways
to undo a genjutsu!
It's useless.
Recall my words to you.
Fine! I'll use the same trick
you two used!
Tayuya! Demon Flute:
Chains of Fantasia!
This will switch from Itachi's control
over genjutsu
to Tayuya's control.
Then, I'll do this!
Sage Art: Inorganic Animation!
This area is under my control!
I'll retreat for now...
Damn it!
Don't mess with me!
He cannot escape
this samsara, this loop.
This is the other Forbidden Jutsu...
the companion to Izanagi.
The jutsu that decides one's fate...
This is the Izanami.
It makes it easier to cast
my real visual genjutsu on him
by keeping him trapped in
a small loop like this.
So Kabuto's trapped in
your loop now?
And that's the Izanami?
When did you cast it?
The first time Kabuto stabbed me
with that blade.
Back then, huh?
But how?
You mentioned a visual jutsu
that is possible without sight.
How can visual jutsu work
without eyesight?
Izanami is a visual jutsu that
works with the physical senses
of both yourself and your opponents.
As you are battling your opponent,
you take a record, like a photograph,
of the physical senses that
both you and your opponent
experiencing during that instant,
with your visual jutsu.
We'll call that A.
As time progresses,
you find "B" is a more
important moment,
then you record "C" and
so on with Sharingan.
Then you recreate
those exact physical senses.
So you use your visual prowess to
create an exact copy of A.
We'll call this A.
By overlaying and connecting A to A,
the Izanami also links
a path for B and C
to create an infinite loop within
a fixed time.
In other words, it's the power
to create an infinite loop.
Naturally, all in exchange for
one's own sight of course,
exactly like Izanagi.
So Kabuto's consciousness
is trapped inside
fighting a phantom you and
a phantom me for all eternity.
No.
The Izanami was developed
to admonish
and save an Izanagi user.
What does that mean?
You know a little about
the Izanagi already.
It's called the perfect Uchiha visual
jutsu, designed to change destiny.
If something does not go
the way you want it to,
you can just erase that outcome
and start all over.
Ultimately, you can pick and
choose the most desirable end result.
What was created
in order to stop this inter-clan
rivalry over the Izanagi...
is the Izanami.
In the first place, reality is a
product of chance that we call fate.
We can't predict it.
But Izanagi can twist around
an inconvenient reality
and lead it to a new fate.
At a whim, the user can change
the original reality into a new one.
To the enemy, a fallen opponent
will revive, so it's a terrifying jutsu.
The Izanami is set up to take someone
who is using the Izanagi
to change the outcome
to benefit oneself,
and cause them to endlessly
circle around in a loop.
I believed that Izanagi was
the ultimate visual jutsu.
But that means the Izanami is
a far superior visual jutsu.
Izanami forms a loop
around the physical sensation
of Izanagi twisting reality.
The Izanami is a jutsu meant
for stopping the Izanagi.
There's an escape route built
into the loop.
Originally, it was a jutsu to save Uchiha
comrades from arrogance and negligence.
It's to stop you from taking
the easy way out with jutsu.
Once one accepts the original outcome
and stops trying to run from it,
the loop will stop.
This jutsu guides you toward
accepting your fate,
instead of relying on jutsu
to change it.
But a jutsu that has an escape
is too dangerous to use in actual combat.
That's why Izanami is
a Forbidden Jutsu.
If Kabuto stops trying
to transform himself,
he can stop the loop.
The strife-filled history
of the Uchiha...
The arrogance and recklessness
of those who used Izanagi...
and how they clashed and
were stopped by Izanami...
I understand now
why both Izanagi and Izanami
came to be Forbidden Jutsu.
And I see how one must learn
from the past
and accept one's fate
and move on.
But... why bother
casting this on Kabuto?
If there's a way to escape...
He reminds me of the old me.
He thinks by acquiring all there is,
he can accomplish whatever he wants.
He makes himself believe that
he can't fail, and lies to himself.
I stopped listening to anyone else.
I stopped trusting anyone.
In Kabuto's case,
he is so deluded
that he thinks all these powers
are his and his alone.
I empathize with him.
We were both used by
the shinobi world...
He can neither forgive himself
nor accept himself as he truly is.
What he is doing is certainly wrong.
But he's not completely to blame
for not being able to realize that.
My chance has passed,
but he can still forgive himself
before he dies.
Why would you ever feel
like you need to help him do that?
He is not like you.
You were perfect!
Sasuke...
I tried to control you
with the visual jutsu
called Koto Amatsukami.
I treated you like a child
because I thought you
needed my protection.
I didn't trust your strength.
It may be that a perfect being
does not exist at all in the world.
Sometimes two who seem to be opposites
are actually two sides of the same coin.
They can only succeed when
they actually work together.
Like the Izanagi and Izanami.
Look at me, and find in yourself
what I was unable to find in myself.
Do not say I was perfect.
First...
Impossible!
I will be a perfect being!
This is... not me!
How long will you imitate Orochimaru?
If you want to exit this loop,
acknowledge your mistakes!
Shut up!
I know he's going to come at me
with a Fire Style Jutsu.
Water Style: Water Dragon—
Water Style: Water Dragon Missile!
He anticipated that jutsu
with Sharingan!
How did I get this wrong?
Where did I...
make a mistake?
All I ever wanted
was someone... to appreciate...
who I was!
All I wanted was to
be acknowledged!
Where is the mistake in that?!
First...
you had to accept yourself
as you were.
Then you wouldn't have
had to lie to anyone.
To you... or to me.
If you lie to yourself,
how can you have friends?
How can you trust or
be trustworthy?
Lies will keep you from
ever seeing your true self.
If I wasn't trapped here...
I'd have won this war by now.
I'd be sleeping by now.
Damn you, Itachi!
It's 9 o'clock already?
Something wrong?
No...
I just wish we could wrap this up quickly
so I could get a good night's sleep.
They never tell us lackeys
what's going on.
That's true.
So, what are you going to do
when this war is over?
Well, I'll start by going home.
If the war ends and the Five
Great Nations continue to be allies...
then maybe my little brother who's been
on a mission for a long time,
can finally come home.
I envy those who have
a home to return to...
You want to come with me?
Huh?
My home is an orphanage.
And if my kid brother's back,
he can take a look at your wounds.
I appreciate that, Urushi!
I really hope
you come back this time...
Kabuto.
I'll stop the Reanimation Jutsu now.
And... all the reanimated dead
will fade away.
That should end the war.
But...
you'll be gone too, brother.
I have protected my village as
Itachi Uchiha of the Leaf once again.
I have no more regrets.
Why?!
Why help the very village that
put you where you are now?
You may be able to forgive,
but I cannot!
You have no more regrets?
What about what
you've made me become?!
I'm not the one who can
change you, Sasuke.
But I can stop this jutsu.
That will fulfill my promise
to Naruto, at least.
I will stop the Reanimation Jutsu!
Tell me the signs!
Tsukuyomi!
I kept my promise.
I leave the rest to you... Naruto.
That's it, huh...
All right... Rat
Ox...
Monkey...
I guess...
it won't matter what I say, will it?
When I saw you...
I followed you in order
to confirm
whether or not Tobi and Danzo
spoke the truth.
But that wasn't all I confirmed.
When I'm with you,
the past comes flooding back.
The feelings I had as a child,
of adoration for my big brother.
That's why...
the closer I get to you and
how we used to be back then,
the more I understand you.
And the more I hate the Leaf Village
for causing you so much pain!
I hate it more than ever!
I know what you want me to do.
And because you're my big brother,
you'll disapprove.
It's because I'm your brother that,
no matter what you say,
you're not going to stop me!
Even if you protect the village now...
I will still destroy it someday.
Tiger...
Dragon...
Goodbye.
Boar...
Reanimation Jutsu... Release!
Big brother...
Lord Tsuchikage...
It's unfortunate...
But I think this is the end.
Silence, Mizukage!
I'm not giving up yet!
What's going on?
Did something happen
to the jutsu user?
There's still time...
I feel like my consciousness
is slowly fading...
I need to tell you everything
before we part.
There's no need to lie anymore.
The night I left you,
I did do everything Danzo
and Tobi told you.
I'll show you... the whole truth.
These are...
Itachi's memories!
It no longer looks like the Uchiha
coup d'état can be prevented.
And if civil war erupts in the Leaf,
other nations are certain to invade.
Real war will break out.
When I tried to stop the coup d'état
with the Kotoamatsukami,
Danzo stole my right eye.
He doesn't trust me.
He intends to protect
the village his way,
no matter what it takes
or how it looks.
I suspect he'll come after
my left eye as well.
So I want to give it to you
before he has a chance.
Shisui...
You're the only person I can count on,
my best friend.
Please protect this village...
and the honor of the Uchiha name.
We cannot allow such a thing!
If they are going to start a revolution
and usurp our power,
we have no choice but to brand
the Uchiha as traitors of the Leaf!
Wait, Koharu.
Don't rush to such a decision.
But Hiruzen, the Uchiha Clan
will not be dissuaded.
We must take measures
to avoid mayhem.
And that includes innocent children.
Do not say such things
before Itachi.
Besides, taking on the Uchiha
will be no easy task.
There's got to be some sort
of strategy we can use!
We have no time to waste.
We must strike preemptively.
If we join forces with
our respective ANBU Black Ops
and launch a surprise attack
from behind,
it will be over in no time.
The Uchiha are old
comrades in arms.
I want to settle this
with words first before force.
I will come up with a strategy.
Itachi...
Buy me some time,
however little it may be.
Despite what Lord Third said,
he will move to protect the Leaf
if push comes to shove.
That's the kind of man he is.
In which case even Hiruzen,
as Hokage,
will have no choice
but to take decisive measures.
Whether it results in war or not,
the moment the coup d'état happens,
the Uchiha will seal their fate
of annihilation.
Including your innocent
little brother.
However, there is a way to spare just your
little brother prior to the coup d'état.
If things come to pass,
your brother will likely come
to know the truth.
And if he witnesses Leaf shinobi
slaughter his entire clan,
it will give him a vengeful heart
towards the Leaf.
And then unfortunately,
he will have to die as well.
Is that a threat?
No, I just want you
to make a choice.
Either align with the Uchiha,
launch the coup d'état,
and die along with your clan...
Or side with the Leaf,
save your little brother
before the coup d'état
and then help us eliminate
all other Uchiha.
No matter what,
things must be quelled before any mayhem
can arise in order to protect the village.
And the only shinobi who can be
entrusted with this mission...
is you, a double agent
for both the Uchiha and the Leaf.
There is no one else... Itachi.
This will be the most
painful mission for you.
But in exchange,
it will allow your little brother
to be spared.
I know you care about the village
as much as I...
Will you accept this mission?
How do you know about me?
You slipped through
extra tight Leaf Security
and went to examine
Nakano Shrine's secret stone tablet.
Only the Uchiha know its location.
Since then, I've kept an eye
on your movements,
and looked into what kind of character
you are and what your ideology is.
Well then, that saves me time.
For you already know
that I bear hatred
towards both the Leaf
and my own clan...
I have terms.
I will help you exact revenge
upon the Uchiha Clan.
But you are not to harm
the village itself.
Nor... Sasuke Uchiha.
I regret now, not telling you
everything before it had come to this.
I see...
So you've aligned with the other side?
Father, Mother...
I...
I know, Itachi.
Itachi, just promise me this.
Take care of Sasuke.
I will.
Do not fear.
This is the path you have chosen.
Compared to you,
our pain will be over in an instant.
Even if our philosophies differ,
I am proud of you.
You are truly a kind child.
There's nothing more to say.
I have told you the whole truth.
I won't have to ever again...
I always lied to you and
asked you to forgive me.
Deliberately keeping you at
a distance.
All because I didn't want you
to get caught up in any of this.
But now, I believe...
that perhaps you could
have changed
Father, Mother,
and the rest of the Uchiha.
If I had treated you as an equal
from the start...
and looked you in the eye
to share the truth,
then I wouldn't have
to stand before you now...
from above, as a failure,
trying to reach you.
So this time, I want to convey
this truth to you...
You don't ever have to forgive me.
And no matter what becomes of you
from here on out, know this...
I will always love you.