Here we go!
I'm gonna take care of
my duties with gusto again today!
Whoa! Mach 5!
Oh!
Good morning, Sakura!
Hmph!
Oh, not again!
These two...
They've been sort of strange since
we got back from the Land of Waves...
Well...
Good morning, everyone...
Today I got lost.
Hey!
Hey, hey...
Kakashi Sensei!
Our Squad Seven always has
the easy missions lately!
Aren't there more exciting
missions where I can be more active,
where I can use my way of the ninja
and my soul...you know?
Oh yes yes...
I basically understand what
you're trying to say.
Shoot!
He's always making me
indebted to him
and making himself look good
during our missions!
I won't lose, no way!
You little...!
Today for sure!
Hmm...
You are so much trouble!
That's what I'd like to say!
Hey! What're you doing, Naruto?
We're going on our mission!
Okay!
Well! It's because you're so reckless!
Geez, you are so much trouble.
Zazuge!
If you act up any more, I'll finish you!
Mmm...
Teamwork hasn't been good lately.
That's right, that's right!
Sasuke, you're to blame for
the poor teamwork!
You're always attracting attention!
That's you, you idiot.
If you don't want to owe me
big time...
you just need to become
stronger than me!
It seems like they're getting
along worse than before...
Shoot...
This is frustrating!
There're plenty of guys outside
who are stronger than I am...
Always making me go on
this kind of lame mission.
Well then...
Perhaps we should disperse.
I do need to submit a report
about this mission.
Okay, then I'm going home.
Oh! Hey!
Sakura! Just let Sasuke be,
and let's practice together!
Huh?
Sensei disappeared.
Was he being thoughtful?
There's no such thing as a perfectly
square rock with perfect holes!
It's totally obvious!
Just what you'd expect from
the man I respect!
You are my rival, aren't you!
Hey! That's too much gunpowder!
I knew it was Konohamaru
and friends.
Huh? Why are you all wearing goggles?
We're just copying what
you used to do, bro!
Oh...
What's with the oh!
Your reactions have been
pretty cold these days!
So, did you want something?
See? Cold.
So, leader!
Do you have some free time now?
Nah!
I have to train!
What?! You said you'd
play ninja with us today!
Oh...? Is that right?
Hmph! Why would a ninja play ninja?
You are making me blush
with those stares...
She's been staring at him with eyes
like she's gonna kill him!
Oh!
You've been busier
than I thought, bro...
Huh?
Is she your?
This?
Shucks, you guys are
pretty sharp for kids!
Bro!
What are you doing?!
No! Leader!
His pulse, his pulse...!
You ugly wench! Ugly wench!
Huh?!
Nooooo!
So, I have formally received
the report from you.
Is Naruto getting along with the others?
Hmm?
Well, he's doing okay.
I've been busy lately.
I haven't had a chance to see him
even once since his return.
I'm a little concerned...
As you know, Iruka Sensei,
Sasuke is also in our squad,
and Naruto sees him as a rival,
which is a little straining.
But, the result is that his abilities
are developing significantly.
Almost to the point that
he might surpass you!
I see...
Are you all right, Konohamaru?
Oweee...
Darn that broad foreheaded ugly wench!
Is she a girl for real?
Yikes!
That hurt...
I wonder what it is?
Shoot!
Right now?
That hurt, little punk!
Stop that. You'll get yelled at later!
I'm sorry...
I was fooling around...
Hey stop!
Let go of that hand!
Huh! So these are Leaf Village's genin...
Let's play with them before
the strict one comes around.
Let go!
You're pretty lively,
you little punk...
You jerk!
Wha?!
What was that?
Leaf Village's genin are
weaker than I thought.
T-These guys are foreign...
Why are they here?
Konohamaru...
Hey! If you don't let go of him,
I won't forgive you! You fool!
You're the fool!
What are you gonna do
by getting him worked up!
You're ticking me off.
It's not on me.
Well, after this little squirt,
it's the little runt that won't shut up!
You!
What do you think you're doing
in someone else's Village, you...
Sasuke!
He's pretty cute.
Another little punk to tick me off!
Get lost!
Wow! So cool!
Naruto, you're lame!
S-Stupid! I would've quickly
taken down that thug too!
Hmph!
Sasuke, you!
Why're you always,
always meddling like this!
Hey, come down here,
you little punk!
You're the kind of smart aleck
little punk that I despise the most.
Wait! You aren't thinking of
using Crow, are you?!
Kankuro, stop that.
Huh?
You're an embarrassment
to our village.
Why do you think we came all
the way here to Leaf Village!?
P-Please listen to me, Gaara.
T-They lashed out first...
Shut up!
I'll kill you.
U-Understood, I was wrong.
I-I'm sorry...
I'm really sorry.
I'm sorry about that...
This guy...has a nasty look.
To think he was able to hit
that Kankuro
with a tiny rock with great ease.
This guy's...good.
Let's go.
We didn't come here
to play around.
I know.
Hold it!
What is it?
Judging from your headbands,
you're ninja from the Village
Hidden in the Sand, right?
Without question, the Land of Fire and
the Land of Wind are allied nations.
But the arbitrary coming and
going of shinobi
is supposed to
be prohibited by the treaty.
State your purpose!
Depending on circumstances...
Don't you know anything about it?
My permit!
We came to this villagerto
take the Chunin Exam.
What is the Chunin Exam anyways?
You really don't know
anything, do you?
Bro, if you pass the exam,
you can become a chunin from a genin!
I see! Then, maybe I'll try taking them!
Heh!
Hey! You there...
What's your name?
Huh? M-Me?
No! The gourd next to you!
I'm Gaara of the desert...
I have an interest in you as well...
What's your name?
Sasuke Uchiha.
Say! Say! What about me?
What about me?
Not interested.
Heh! Things have gotten interesting.
Konohamaru, do I look weak?
Compared to Sasuke, yes...
Sasuke, I won't lose to you!
What's gotten into you,
all of a sudden?!
What do you think?
I don't think they're anything special.
But the black-haired one from Leaf Village
and the gourd from the Sand Village...
those two need to be checked.
Now then, in conjunction
with beginning the Chunin Exam,
let us first have those in charge
of the rookie genin come forward.
Kakashi and Kurenai and Asuma...
So? Are there any genin from
your squads
you wish to recommend
for these exams?
It goes without saying,
but if it's a genin who has carried out
eight or more formal missions,
you can recommend them
for the exams if you wish.
Then, you first Kakashi.
The Kakashi led Squad Seven...
Sasuke Uchiha. Naruto Uzumaki.
Sakura Haruno.
I, Kakashi Hatake, recommend these
three for the Chunin Exam.
Huh?
The Kurenai led Squad Eight...
Hinata Hyuga, Kiba Inuzuka,
Shino Aburame.
These three, I, Kurenai Yuhi,
recommend the same.
The Asuma led Squad Ten...
Ino Yamanaka, Shikamaru Nara,
Choji Akimichi.
These three, I, Asuma Sarutobi,
recommend the same.
All three recommended...
To think rookies will be
in the Chunin Exam...
Hasn't it been five years
since that's happened?
Hmm...
Wait a minute!
What is it, Iruka?
Lord Hokage, please let me
say one thing.
This may be presumptuous,
but as for the nine names
that were given,
I was in charge of them at the Academy.
Admittedly, they were all students
with ability,
but it's too soon...!
They should be tested after
having gained more experience!
I became a chunin when I was
six years younger than Naruto is now.
Naruto is different from you!
Is it your intent to crush Naruto?!
They always do nothing but complain
about important missions...
Teaching them a lesson
once would be fun.
Trying to crush them
would be interesting, too.
W-What did you say?!
Well, joking aside...
Iruka Sensei...
Kakashi...
Don't do it.
Stay out of this!
They're not your students anymore!
Now they're my subordinates!
Man...troublesome people.
B-But the Chunin Exam
is also known as...
Iruka...
I understand your point.
Master Hokage...
Therefore, I have decided to conduct
a special preliminary exam
for these rookie genin.
P-Preliminary exam?!
Say! Say! Say!
Why is it that he's the one who
always calls us out,
and then makes us wait?!
That's right! That's right!
What's he going to do about
the feelings of a maiden
who accidentally overslept and resigned
herself to no blow drying?!
I overslept, so I haven't washed my face
and didn't brush my teeth.
Y-You...That's dirty.
Why're these guys so hyper
first thing in the morning?!
Hey, good morning, folks!
Today, I got a bit lost on the
path of life...
Right! That's a lie!!
Uh, well...
This is sudden, but I recommended
you guys for the Chunin Exam, so...
Here, these are your applications.
Chunin Exam...
That being said, the recommendations
are not compulsory.
You guys are free to decide whether
you take the Exam or not.
All right! I love you, Kakashi Sensei!
Hey, cut it out. Get away already...
Only those who want to take the Exam,
sign that application and
come to Room 301 of the Academy
at 3:00 p.m. Five days from now...
That's it!
Chunin Exams, eh...
I bet lots of strong guys would be there..
For example, that guy!
And this guy!
I might be able to fight him.
I...don't want to...
Here I can't...
keep up with Sasuke,
and not even with Naruto...
The Chunin Exam, no way...
Sakura, you're late!
Yeah...sorry...
Morning, Sasuke.
Yeah...
Something's strange about Sakura.
So, are you sure you're going
to attempt taking
the Chunin Exam with that skill?
May it'd be best if you runts quit.
You're green assed brats, after all.
Please let us through.
That's...mean...
What did you say?!
Listen!
We're being nice to you!
The Chunin Exam is a high hurdle.
Many times have we seen
people quit shinobi
as well as people who were
disabled for life
just because they took this Exam.
A brat such as this a chunin?
What's so bad about weeding out
those who won't pass anyway?!
A just argument.
However, you will let me through.
And could you also immediately
undo this barrier created with genjutsu?
I have business on the third floor.
What's this guy talking about...?
I don't know...
- Well, well...
- So you noticed, eh?
How about it, Sakura?
You should've been
the first one to realize it.
Huh?
Your analytical strength and
genjutsu know how
has improved the most in our squad, so...
Thank you...
Of course. I realized it ages ago!
You see, this is the second floor!
Yup!
Well, not bad...
But all you've done is to catch on.
Right?!
H-He's fast!
This person...
He's a different person from
when he was getting punched before!
He stopped my kick...
What's with that chakra in his arm?
Hey, this isn't what you promised.
You were the one who said
you didn't want to carelessly
attract attention and be watched.
But...
This guy...
The marks where he was hit
are disappearing.
Was he faking?
My name's Rock Lee.
Your name's Sakura, right...?
Huh?
Please go out with me!
I'll protect you until I die!
Absolutely...not.
Huh?
You're...too intense.
Hey, you there.
Identify yourself.
I'm not obliged to answer...
What...?!
Cute...
So those are Kakashi and
Guy's treasured brats...
Well, for the time being,
their applications will pass.
Yeah...
It appears this year's
test takers will be amusing.
For us proctors too, eh...
Now then!
Sasuke, Naruto, let's go!
Don't pull.
Sasuke...Sasuke Uchiha, eh.
Hmph...
Lee, let's go.
What're you doing?
You guys go on ahead.
I have something I want to check out.
You, with the unpleasant look.
Wait a minute!
Huh?
- Oh!
- Yikes!
What is it?
Why don't you fight with me
here now?
My name's Rock Lee.
When asking a person their name,
I'm supposed to give
my own name first, right?
Sasuke Uchiha...
Hmph...So you knew?
I want to fight with you!
I want to test out how effective
my techniques will be
against the descendant of the
clan reputed for genius ninja.
Also...
Noooo!
Those lower eyelashes are awful!
The hairstyle is awful, too!
Those bushy eyebrows,
just too intense!
Everything is!
You're an angel!
Noooooo!
You are good at it.
Then, how about?
Really...That was super close.
You! Don't throw strange stuff!
I was dodging for my life!
You don't have to resent me that much.
It's Sasuke again!
Darn it! Darn it!
To be honest, you're a naive one,
knowing the name of Uchiha
and challenging me.
Do you want to realize
what this name is, Bushy Brow?
I insist.
Wait!
I am going to take out
the Bushy Brow. Believe it!
Hey, you!
Big deal.
I'll be able to take care of him
in just five minutes!
The one I want to fight isn't you...
It's Uchiha.
All these people...
keep saying Sasuke, Sasuke.
How annoying!
Darn it!
Leaf Whirlwind!
I declare. You are absolutely
no match for me.
Because...
among the Leaf Village genin,
I'm the strongest now.
Interesting. I'll do it.
Stop! Sasuke!
There's less than thirty minutes
until the 3:00 registration.
Don't worry.
It'll be over in five minutes.
Here he comes!
I can't get completely out
of the way...
Guard!
What...?!
W-What's going on?
But...he did guard himself
just now, no mistake.
He got around my guard.
What is it?
Is it ninjutsu...?
Or is it genjutsu...?!
As I thought, he's going to get up!
I'll do it.
Huh?! C-Could that be...?
Sharingan!
Sasuke, when has he...
Why is that in his eyes...
And in both eyes...!
Is that the Sharingan?
Sasuke's awesome, after all!
If this is the same Kekkei Genkai
as Kakashi Sensei's...
he can read Bushy Brow's jutsu!
Huh?!
To not be able to discern the jutsu
with the Sharingan...
Could it be...that his technique is...!
That's right...
My technique is neither
ninjutsu nor genjutsu.
That's right!
My technique is
mere taijutsu...Sasuke.
You may not be able to
believe it just like that, but...
Punk!
In other words, even if you understand
with your eyes,
there's nothing you can do if your
body can't keep up.
There are two types of strong people,
genius types and effort types.
If your Sharingan is
a genius type drawing Uchiha ability...
I'm an effort type who has
patiently mastered only taijutsu.
In a manner of speaking,
your Sharingan and my ultimate
taijutsu have the worst compatibility...
It's my victory!
That's as far as it goes! Lee!
Sasuke!
Sasuke was beaten?!
What happened while
I was knocked out?!
Are you okay?! Sasuke.
He's agitated...
To think he couldn't fall properly.
Y-You were watching...?
Lee! That technique just now
is prohibited, you know!
W-What's with that turtle...?
I-I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to...
He's...getting scolded or something...
Could that be...Bushy Brow's teacher?!
There's no mistake!
Hey-hey.
What...?
That thing...It's a turtle, right?
Right?
Isn't it obvious?!
Say! Say! Can even a turtle
become a ninja teacher?
I don't know!
To think I lost to someone so flippant...
Have you prepared yourself?
Y-Yes sir...
All right, if you will, Guy Sensei!
Man! Life treating you good, huh?
Huh?!
Whoaaa! An even more
intense guy has appeared!
Yo, Lee!
T-Those are some incredibly
raging brows...
I've never seen anything like that
in my life.
H-Hey! You guys!
Don't mock Guy Sensei!
Shut up!
I'm at a loss for a reaction because
of those bizarre things appearing
one after another!
What?!
Idiot!
Lee, you...you...
S-Sensei...!
L-Lee...
Sensei...I...I...
Enough, Lee!
Don't say anything!
Sensei!
Lee!
I lost to a guy like that...
Yes...this is adolescence!
Sensei!
That sort of tone's kind of nice, too.
I-Idiot! That's dangerous!
Very dangerous!
It's okay, Lee!
Mistakes come with adolescence.
Don't worry about it!
You're so kind...Sensei!
Lee, you will be
punished for attempting to
break the prohibition,
on top of fighting...
in principle, after
the Chunin Exam.
Okay!
Five hundred howls of adolescence!
Yes, sir!
If I'm not mistaken, those kids are...
Kakashi's...
Oh! No, he's looking this way!
You guys...how's Kakashi Sensei?
You know Kakashi...?
I know him all too well.
People call us...
eternal rivals.
Sounds like a lie!
What're you saying?!
Guy Sensei really is...
That's fine.
"Action speaks louder than words"
anyway.
By the way, my record is fifty wins
and forty-nine losses.
Huh?!
This guy...
When did he.?
One thing, I'm stronger than Kakashi...
N-No way...
He's fast! He's faster than Kakashi!
Is he human...?!
How about that?!
Guy Sensei is awesome, isn't he?!
Darn it...
This time around,
Lee caused the trouble.
Out of consideration for my face,
forgive him.
Out of consideration for
this pleasant face.
He's better than that Kakashi...?
Darn it! He's...
not just all talk...
You guys and Lee should probably go
to the classroom pretty soon.
He...!
Then, do your best, Lee!
Farewell!
Yes, sir.
What?!
Sasuke...
I have one last thing to tell you.
I lied before.
The strongest man of the
Leaf Village genin might be on my team.
I'm entering in order
to defeat that person.
And, you are one of my targets.
Please prepare yourself for the Exam!
Sasuke...
Ha! So...
I guess Uchiha clan's not all that, huh?
Shut up!
I'll knock him flat next time!
Ha! That from someone
who just got whipped.
You saw it, didn't you? His hand...
That Bushy Brow probably did a heck
of a lot of special training.
Day after day...
More than you have...
I see. Sakura, you've come, too.
Now you can formally register
for the Chunin Exam.
What do you mean?
Actually, from the start,
only three man squads could
apply and take the exams.
But Sensei, you said that the decision
to take the exams
was up to the individual.
Yes...I said that.
Were you lying?
Yes, I was...
If I said that,
Sasuke and Naruto would probably
forcefully convince you to take it.
Even if you didn't have
the will to apply,
if Sasuke asks you
you would attempt to take
the exams half heartedly.
For Sasuke's sake and,
well, Naruto's.
Then, if...
it had only been Sasuke and
Naruto who had come here?
I would've stopped the Exam here.
I wouldn't have felt like letting
them go beyond this point.
But...you guys came here
on your own will.
Sakura!
Naruto!
And, Sasuke!
I'm glad you came.
You're a team I'm proud of.
Now then, go on!
Okay! Let's go!
I was born with strength that
surpasses Elder Sister's.
This is my destiny!
That's why…
I must get stronger…!
More, more, more…more!
Look at all your injuries…
Couldn't you be overdoing it a bit?
No such thing.
I must protect the Hyuga Clan.
Oh, that's right!
It seems Lady Hinata is doing
very well as a genin.
I hear she will be taking
the Chunin Exams.
The Chunin Exams?
Yes. It's a test one must pass
in order to be promoted from
genin to chunin rank.
But I understand it's quite rigorous,
and there are even fatalities.
There are so many of them...
Could it be that they're all applicants?
They...all look...immensely strong...
Sasuke, you're late!
I thought I'd be able to see you
for the first time in awhile,
so I was waiting in excitement.
Get away from Sasuke!
Ino Pig!
Oh, my. It's Sakura.
Your Billboard Brow hasn't changed, eh...
Ugly!
What did you say?!
What's up with this?
Huh?
Are you guys going to take
this bothersome Exam, too?
Oh, it's the idiot trio.
Quit calling us that!
Man, this is a freaking bother...
Yahoo, I found you!
My my, everybody's here.
H-Hello...
What did you say?
You guys, too?!
Man.
Ha! I see.
This means all nine genin rookies
are taking the Exam, eh...!
Now then...
How far can we go?
Eh...Sasuke?
Hmph!...
You're mighty confident. Kiba.
We've trained a great deal, so...
We won't lose to you guys!
Shut up!
Hey, you guys!
You should be a little quieter.
You guys are the "rookie nine"...
fresh out of the academy, right?
Carrying on like that
with cute faces...Man.
This isn't a field trip.
Who're you? Acting all haughty!
I'm Kabuto Yakushi.
Anyway, take a good look around you.
Behind you...
They're from the Rain Village.
They're hot tempered.
Everyone's tense before the Exam.
I thought I'd warn you guys
before you get your butts whipped...
I guess it can't be helped.
You're rookies who don't know
left from right...
You remind me of my old self.
Then, is this your second time?
No...
It's my seventh time.
Huh?!
This Exam is only held twice a year,
so it's now my fourth year.
Then that means you know
a lot about these exams?!
Kind of...
Leaf, Sand, Rain, Grass,
Waterfall, Sound...
There are lots of exceptional genin
from those villages
who have come to take
the Exam this year as well.
As far as the Village Hidden
in Sound goes,
it's a village of a small nation that
just sprang up in recent years,
so there isn't much information...
At any rate,
they're all Hidden Villages
with nothing but crackerjacks.
That kind of makes you lose
your confidence.
Why are you saying that now?
In other words...
all of the applicants who
have gathered here...
They're all choice top elite
genin from each nation.
Hmm.
This isn't going to be easy.
I can't go along with this!
They may be your subordinates now,
but they are children
who were my students.
If it's about them I know...
It's as you say, Iruka.
It's not going to be that easy.
You're too eager.
I postponed my team's test taking
for one year
and took care to build up
their skills.
Have them take the Exam after they've
enjoyed their life a little bit more.
Hmph...
They might be too easygoing.
But they will surpass
your guys in no time.
That's enough.
That's as far as
the rookie matter goes.
Now then, next...
I'll take recommendations for genin
other than rookies.
I said that, nevertheless...
I wonder if even the fearless ones
are frightened just this time around.
My name's Naruto Uzumaki!
I won't lose to any of you!
Got it?!
Say! What's with him?!
That idiot would never
get depressed! Absurd!
It won't do any good to
provoke everyone!
Don't tell me!
If I don't tell it to you,
who do I tell it to?!
What did you say?!
Oh, I feel better.
Hmph...
Isn't that the guy from before...?
The dog's bark is
bigger than its bite.
Is he an idiot...?
He's mighty high-spirited.
He's hot-headed, eh.
Lee, maybe you did
not bully him enough.
Did you hear?
Sound Village is a minor
Hidden Village of a small nation.
That's offensive.
Maybe I'll...play with them a bit.
Yes, being referred to as something
like leftover shinobi and all.
These guys...are the Sound Village...
I can see through that speed.
I see...It's that kind of attack, eh?
Huh?!
Oh! He puked?!
K-Kabuto?
Huh?!
Hah!
Hey, Kabuto!
Are you okay?!
Yeah...I'm okay.
Really?
Oh, so he's not so special.
Even though he's a veteran who's been
taking the exams for four whole years.
The three from Sound village...
Doubtless chunin.
Kabuto should've totally read the attack..
But why did he vomit?
Lee. How about that technique just now?
I had no problem reading the speed.
There's some kind of trick...
Silence! Degenerates!
Sorry to keep you waiting.
I'm Ibiki Morino, proctor for
the first test of the Chunin Exam.
You, from Hidden Sound Village!
No doing as you please
before the Exam!
You want to be failed
at the get go?!
Sorry. It's our first time taking the
Exams, so we flipped out...
Hmph. This is a good opportunity,
so I'll say this.
There will be no battles,
competitions and the like
without the permission
of the proctors!
And even if you get permission,
actions that could lead to the death
of an opponent will not be permitted.
Any pig that screws with me
will be disqualified immediately.
Got it?!
This Exam looks to be easy!
Now then, we will start
the first test of the Chunin Exam!
Turn in your applications,
take one of these number cards
in exchange,
and sit in the seat
matching that number!
After that, we will hand out
the paper for the written test!
Written? Paper?
Paper...
A paper test?!
Everyone's seats are all scattered...
What should I do?
Naruto...
Oh! You are Hinata!
Since when have you?
L-Let's both do our best.
Y-Yeah.
There are several important
rules to this first test.
I will take no questions,
so listen well accordingly!
Rules? No questions will be taken...?
First off is the first rule!
You are given ten points
each from the start!
The written test has
ten problems in all!
Each problem is one point.
And, this test is a
point deduction system.
You are deducted one point for
each problem you get wrong!
If you get three wrong,
you'll have seven points!
The second rule.
Pass or failure will be determined
by the total points of
the three person teams.
W-Wait a minute!
What do you mean...
total points of the teams?
Shut up!
There's a perfectly
good reason for this!
Shut up and listen!
If you've got it,
here is the most important next rule!
Those who are deemed by
the sentinels
as having committed an act of
cheating or something similar to that...
will have two points deducted
for each act.
In other words...
there may be those who will be
dismissed during this test
without waiting for test grading.
This means they're deducting points
from things other
than the written test problems.
Know that those who
commit awkward cheating...
will bring ruin upon yourselves.
I'll check you anytime.
If you aspire to become
a chunin at all,
know that shinobi should act
like exemplary shinobi.
Relax!
Yes...yes!
Naruto aside,
Sasuke and I are okay!
Even if Naruto gets zero points...
if we cover that...
And, in the case of even one person
on the team getting zero points...
Everyone on that team will fail!
Wha?!
What did he say?!
I feel two menacing stares...
Naruto?
By the way, the last problem will
be given forty five minutes
after the start of the test!
The time for the test is one hour.
Begin!
Could it...
Could it be that,
the fat is really on the fire now...?
Naruto!
Just don't get zero points!
Naruto isn't getting jitters
from the get go, is he...?
This is bad...
As if!
I know I've cleared many obstacles
like this before...
At times like this, one should
look at all the problems
without feeling pressed
or making a fuss!
And then with utmost effort
I should tackle the problems that look
easy to understand!
Let's see, the first problem...
is a code text, eh...
Excellent, I say!
Next! Next!
Let's see...the second problem...
The parabola B in the diagram illustrates
the greatest possible distance
Enemy ninja A can throw his shuriken
from a tree seven meters high...
Predict and answer the enemy ninja's
character inferred
from the ellipse this shuriken forms,
also answer the longest firing range
in battle on flat ground
and explain your basis.
T-This is an...integrated problem based
on predictions
of uncertain conditions and
dynamic energy analysis application!
There's no way
Naruto can solve this!
I mean...
hardly anyone except me
can solve this problem!
Okay, next!
Next!
These other problems...
are nothing but difficult ones.
I see...
I don't...understand even
one of these problems.
Oh, no, this is bad!
For real! For real!
What should I do?
What should I do? What should I do?
If about ten of all fifty one teams
are able to pass,
it will be bad if I didn't stretch myself
and get a considerable amount of points.
It's like a system inviting cheating...
I hope Sasuke and Naruto
won't panic and cheat.
Don't panic...
For now, all there is to do is to be
very, very cautious...
and cheat without being found out!
At any rate, this elaborate fuss...
It's like a trick assuming
that we're going to cheat.
They probably check with that paper...
Somebody got nailed.
Cheating deducts two points.
Two point deduction, huh...
Ordinarily, it'd be failure the moment
the cheating was discovered...
A test to see the ability
for intensive information collection
with the full use of deception
and concealment techniques.
"Shinobi should read
the double bluff," eh...
In other words, the true intention
of the proctor is...
if you're going to cheat,
not "awkward cheating,"
but "like exemplary shinobi",
don't get caught.
Viewed in this light, the extraordinariness
of the point deduction system,
the lenience of only deducting two points
for each discovery of cheating makes sense.
In other words,
what's being tested here is how
we can gather the correct answers
without having our cheating detected
by the proctors or
by the one being cheated on.
Realize it quick, Naruto!
It'll turn into a fatal mistake!
Realize it!
This is bad. Believe it...
So Gaara has also started, eh...
Hmph...l'm counting on you, Crow.
Yahoo, good boy, Akamaru!
Next is problem four!
Judging from this rhythm...
The stroke order...
and the number of strokes...
I see.
Okay! Please tell me.
Eight, huh.
Lee, if you can see it,
wear your headband!
Time is rapidly going by!
Oh, man! I'm afraid all there
is to do is cheat...
But, if I'm discovered,
it'll be trouble for Sakura
and Sasuke.
On the other hand,
if I get zero points...
Sakura and Sasuke will be
my companions in failure.
Naruto...
I'll show you...my test.
Huh...?
What is Hinata saying...?
Why would you show me?
Uh...uh...actually...
I don't want you, Naruto...
to leave at this stage...
Y-You see...
the nine of us are the only rookies...
and I have many anxieties about
what's to come, so!
I get it now! I was kind of
strangely suspicious of you!
Anyhow! This is crazy lucky, I say!
Thank goodness I'm next to Hinata...
You made five mistakes. You fail!
N-No way...
His two buddies, both of you get out
of the classroom, right now.
#23 fails!
#43 and #27 fail!
Noooo!
Hey, hey! Do you have proof that
I cheated five whole times?!
Really, are you guys properly checking
this number of people?
Listen up...
Even among us chunin, we're elite
who were selected for this Exam.
We don't overlook you blinking once...
In a matter of speaking,
this strength is the proof.
Naruto?
Hurry...Look...
Hinata...You don't get it, do you?
What?
An awesome ninja like me
won't cheat. Believe it!
N-Naruto.
B-But...
Also, if something went wrong,
you'd be in a hot spot for
helping me cheat, right?!
What?!
Naruto...
I'm...sorry...
I-I did something uncalled for...
I...went and acted big.
What should I do?
I'm extremely stupid.
Byakugan!
Sharingan!
I'll copy all his movements!
My hand is moving fluently...
I hit the jackpot straight away
with this guy.
#59! Fails!
#33! #9!
This is the thirteenth group to fail.
#41 fails.
#35, #62 fails!
No way!
That brat...
He coolly proceeds through this
ruckus without moving an eyelash.
Very well done considering he's new.
The optic nerves are connected...
The third eye...open!
Ugh! There's dirt in my eye...
Dang it!
Excuse me.
What is it?
I need to go to the bathroom...
We will accompany you
to the bathroom.
I see...
Anyhow...the proctors are
nothing so special!
They don't realize that the proctors
have increased by one...
Eh, don't you think so...
Crow?
Forty minutes have passed
since the test started...
Twenty minutes left...huh...
Since it's come to this,
it's the last problem to be given forty
five minutes after the start of the test.
All there is to do is bet on this.
Believe it!
All right!
Here is the tenth question!
Here it comes!
I have to put everything on
the line for this question!
But before that,
I'm going to add
some rules for the last question.
Aren't you lucky?
It looks like playing with
the dolls wasn't a waste, after all?
This guy.
He's figured Crow out!
Anyway, sit down.
Let me explain!
These are
the hopeless rules!
Well, anyhow.
There's nothing to do when
the subordinates are gone, huh?
Well, it'll get busy soon enough.
Why?
This year's first proctor...
I hear it's that Ibiki Morino.
Well then, passing the first exam
already seems iffy.
Of all the people, that sadist...
Sadist?
Kurenai, you're a new jonin,
so you wouldn't know.
Who is this person?
He is a pro, a professional.
Professional? Of what?
Torture and interrogation.
What?!
Well, there maybe no physical torture
in the exam itself,
but he's sure to use his
his skills as an interrogator
to torment them psychologically.
That is...
Leaf Village ANBU's
Torture and Interrogation Unit Marshall,
Ibiki Morino!
Hopeless rules...?!
First, you guys will have to choose
whether or not you will take
this 10th question!
Huh?!
Choose whether or not
to take the exam?
What, choose?!
What happens if you choose not
to take the 10th exam?
If you chose not to take the exam,
then your score will be zero.
And of course, the same goes for
the two others in the same group!
W-What does that mean!
Of course, everybody is going to
choose to take the exam!
This is ridiculous!
As if we have a choice!
And...one more rule...
If you chose to take it and
are unable to answer it correctly,
then you will have to...
relinquish your right
of taking the Chunin Exam forever.
What kind of ridiculous rule is that?!
Besides, there are plenty
of people here
who have taken the
Chunin Exam many times!
I make the rule this year.
But I did give you
the option to go back!
For those of you who aren't confident,
you can choose not to take it
and take the exam
next year or the year after that.
Oh! How terrible!
If one out of the three
chooses not to take the exam,
then all three will be failed.
If you do choose to take it,
but get the wrong answer...
then that person will be a
genin for the rest of their life!
No matter what,
the odds are against us!
It's an impossible choice
for anyone with normal nerves!
Then, let's begin...
The 10th question...
Those who will not be taking it,
raise your hands!
Once I confirm your number,
I'll ask you to leave!
I...I...
I'm quitting!
I'm not going to take it!
#50 failed!
#130, #111 will be
failed as well...
I-I'm sorry...
Gennai! Inaho!
Darn...
M-Me too!
Me too!
Naruto...
Why don't you raise your hand?
That guy...
I am the super elite ninja
who will be carrying
the name of the Hokage!
My name is Naruto Uzumaki,
remember that!
Shut up!
I'm prepared to do anything
to become a Hokage!
I will surpass the Hokage!
And I will make all of
the people in the village
acknowledge my presence!
He's always got such a one track mind.
Saying Hokage, Hokage
all the time like a fool.
I'm sorry, Naruto.
It seems like...
I don't want to...
crush your unachievable dreams.
Don't underestimate me!
I won't run!
I'll take it!
But even if I'm stuck being
a genin forever,
I will become a Hokage
no matter what it takes!
I'm not scared!
That guy, he wasn't even
thinking of us at all.
Such audacity!
That's right...
That's exactly the kind of fool you are!
I'll ask again.
It's a choice that will alter your life.
If you want to quit, now is your chance!
I'm not going to take back
my words!
That is my way of ninja!
Huh...What a funny kid.
He completely brushed away
those kids' anxieties.
78, huh? Much more left
than I expected.
It's going to be the same.
No matter how much more I push it.
I like your determination!
Then...
For those who are still here...
The first exam...
You have passed it!
Huh?
H-Hey, what does that mean?
All of a sudden you're telling us
that we've passed!
What about the 10th question?
There wasn't such
a thing to begin with!
Well, you can look at the choice you
just had to make as the 10th question!
What?!
Hey!
Then, what were all
those nine questions for!
It was just a waste of time!
Not a waste...
The objective of the nine questions
were already accomplished.
To test your individual ability
to gather information!
Ability to gather information?
First...
The focus of this test was
on the system of determining
the pass or failure
based on the three person groups
that was proposed in the first rule.
By grading the exam on
a group basis,
I added the unimaginable pressure
of dragging down your teammates.
I see, I see.
I kind of felt that was
the point of this test!
No, you didn't!
However...
The questions on these tests weren't
things that
you genin ninja would
have been able to solve...
So in that case...
I imagined that most of you here
would have come to this conclusion:
"In order to score points,
I'll have to cheat."
In other words,
this exam was created under the premise
that you all would cheat!
That being said,
I had two chunin in the group
who knew all of the answers
from whom you could cheat.
What?! That's what it was?
I had a hard time figuring
out the guy.
Yeah. Really...
It was so obvious!
There's something wrong with you
if you didn't notice!
Right, Hinata?!
He...didn't realize it...
However...
those who just foolishly cheated,
naturally were disqualified.
That's because...
Information, depending on
the time and situation,
it will be more valuable than life.
And in a mission or on a battlefield,
you will always have to risk your life
to fight for it!
Horrible burn marks, nail punctures
and scratches...
Those are signs of physical torture!
When information is gathered
and the enemy or a third party
finds out about it,
that information is no longer
guaranteed to be correct.
Just remember this.
To be given the wrong information
can bring a catastrophic blow
to your friends and town.
So that is why, out of necessity,
we forced you guys to cheat
in order to test your ability
to collect information.
And we filtered out those who
were clearly lacking in those abilities.
But...
The last question doesn't
make any sense.
It really is an unfair question.
Then, how about these two choices?
Let's say that you guys did
become a chunin.
The mission is to steal
a secret document!
You have no idea how many
ninja the enemy has,
their ability, and other armament
they may have.
On top of that, there maybe
the pitfall of an enemy trap.
Now this mission...
Will you take it? Or not take it?
Because you want your life spared...
Because your partners will
be put in danger...
Can you get away from
dangerous missions?
The answer is...
No!
There are going to be missions
you cannot avoid
no matter how risky or
dangerous it may be!
Showing your courage to
your teammates in a tight spot,
and the ability to get through
the hardships...
This is the quality that is needed
in a chunin troop leader!
In a pinch, there are
those who cannot risk their own fate,
and those who waver and give up
their chances
because they think they
will have another chance.
I believe that such fools who don't have
strong determination
have no right to become a chunin!
You've passed through the gates!
The fist exam for the Chunin Exam
has been completed.
I wish you well!
All right! Wish us well!
I did it! I did it!
Yeaah!
What a funny guy...
Gosh, this one...
You guys!
This isn't the time to be
celebrating!
I'm the proctor for the second exam!
Anko Mitarashi!
Let's move onto
the next stage! Next!
Follow me!
Read the atmosphere.
This proctor...
Is kind of like Naruto.
78?! Ibiki!
You let 26 teams slide by?
I guess, the first exam this time around
was too easy.
It seems like this time,
there are a lot of excellent candidates.
I'm getting excited.
I'll give you the details tomorrow.
We'll be changing locations,
so get information from your jonin
about the location and the time!
That's it. You're dismissed.
I didn't think that there would be a guy
that would pass with a blank sheet.
Naruto Uzumaki...
He really is a funny guy.
W-What is this place?!
This is the location for
the "second exam",
the 44th Training Field.
Also known as...the Forest of Death.
The Forest of...Death?!