I was nervous and couldn't sleep.
First...it's him...
in the first match.
Not even my Sharingan
can see chakra points...
The strongest genin in the
Leaf is on my team.
It is that...Neji Hyuga!
Neji...Neji...Neji...
At last...
The first match is Neji Hyuga, right?!
Yeah. He's the number one rookie
from last year, right?!
We can't miss the first match!
Neji...Hyuga...
Now I can summon a frog...
It'll be okay.
They all...look nasty.
Hinata!
Ah! N-N-Naruto.
W-What are you doing here?
Today is the final round, isn't it?
I...Just something...
I came to check out this training field.
This is the place where
I became a genin, so...
Really? W-Why?
N-Nothing...That doesn't matter!
Y-You're right. I'm sorry.
Say, Hinata...
Neji's a relative of yours, right?
Y-Yes.
Is he really strong...?
Yes...
I see.
B-But you might be able to win, Naruto.
Yeah. I'm strong, after all!
I bet you can win, Naruto.
What?
You know...
I...when you cheered for me,
I felt like I was able to become
stronger than before.
Hinata! Hang tough!
When the preliminaries ended,
I became able to like
myself just a little.
From someone else's standpoint,
it might not look like anything's changed.
but I feel like I was able to change.
I've been thinking that it was...
thanks to you, Naruto.
Say, Hinata...
Did you really think so?
What?
I may look strong to you,
but all I do is mess up...
And I act tough because
I'm frustrated.
It's not like that!
Even when you messed up,
in my view...you were always
a proud failure.
W-When I look at you,
it impacts my heart.
You're not perfect, so...
So...
It's because you mess up...
that you have the strength
to rise up from that.
I think such strength is
true strength.
I...I think you're an
incredibly strong person.
Thanks, Hinata!
Even though I was always
the bottom one...
I was tense in the shoulders, somehow!
I was depressed,
which was totally not my character.
But I feel better now!
Naruto...
Okay! I'm off to the match!
Hinata...
Huh?
I kind of...thought you were...
W-What...?
...gloomy, hesitant and weird.
Naruto...
But I quite like...people...
like you!
Oh, yeah! Be sure to come watch me
kick that Neji's butt!
Uh oh. Time to run!
I-I'm late, late!
See you later, Hinata!
Sorry I'm late, Hinata.
Well, Shino's match isn't until
quite a bit later, so...
Hm? Hey? Hinata?
Hmm? Where's Sasuke?
That Dosu guy I'm supposed
to fight isn't here, either.
Hey, you guys over there.
Throw out your chests and
show your faces to the spectators!
You guys are the stars
of this "final round"!
Sasuke hasn't been found yet?
A team of several ANBU members
are searching all over,
but they have found nothing.
He might already be in
the hands of Orochimaru...
If that's the case,
we may never find him.
I understand.
Well well...Lord Kazekage.
You must be tired having
come all this way.
No...I'm glad the arena
is in the Leaf Village.
Even though you're still young, it would
probably be a tough journey for you
if you had to go to the trouble
of traveling someplace else.
Shouldn't you decide on
the Fifth Hokage soon?
Please don't treat me
like an old person.
I'm still planning on
being Hokage for another five years...
Now then, I guess it's
about time to begin.
Everyone, thank you very much
for coming
to the Village Hidden in Leaves
Chunin Exam.
We will now begin the
"final round" matches
for the eight who made it
through the preliminaries!
Please watch until the end!
If there are supposed to be eight,
it looks like there's one missing.
I have something to tell
you before the match.
Look at this.
Huh?!
There was a slight change
to the tournament.
Check who you'll be facing
one more time.
Before I had more preliminary
matches than the others...
So that Dosu guy dropped out?
Say...
...say.
What?
Umm...Sasuke still hasn't come.
What'll happen?
In case a competitor does not arrive
by the start time of his match...
he or she will lose by default!
It doesn't make sense.
Knowing his character,
he'd come even if he had to drag himself.
Where are you going, Gaara?
To verify my existence...
one more time.
Sasuke one more time...
What happened?
It's obvious that you're there
standing with the thirst for blood.
Why don't you come out?
So you're called Gaara...
What is it that you want to say
to him before the final round,
by pursuing him so far?
A battle is where...
another's existence and one's own
existence are put on the line...
and each tries to kill the other!
Only the winner can actually feel
the value of his own existence.
In other words,
what you want to say is...
"Let's have a killing bout and
not a match"?
Uchiha...You really should
be wanting it, too...
in the depths of your soul...
You want to confirm
the value of your existence.
Am I really, truly powerful?
Is my existence more powerful
than my opponent
who faces me with eyes
filled with intent to kill?
Could it be...?
Even after I warned him to avoid
doing anything to stand out...
He didn't kill Sasuke Uchiha
also, did he...?
Listen up, you guys.
The terrain is different,
but the rule is that there are no rules,
the same as
in the preliminaries.
The matches will continue until one
or the other dies, or acknowledges defeat.
However, if I judge that it has been
settled I'll stop the match there.
Arguments will not be allowed.
Understood?
So the first match is...
Naruto Uzumaki.
Neji Hyuga
Just those two remain and
the rest of you go to the waiting room.
Hey, Hinata! These seats are open.
Uh huh.
This match will be quite interesting
But to think that brat would
survive until this point...
I wonder if this is
as far as it goes
for those who survived
just by luck, after all.
That Naruto.
This is not a good opponent at all.
No matter how you look at it,
he can't beat the Hyuga clan.
Well, that's what I thought
at the beginning...
But you'll all be surprised
if you underestimate him.
Akamaru, what's wrong?
What did you say?!
What?! Where?!
There!
What's ANBU, the Black Ops,
doing here?
Is something going on...?
You seem like you want
to say something
I said it before, didn't I?
I'll win, no matter what!
He has the look...
of being sure of himself...
It's as if he's not all worked up...
That makes it
more worthwhile for me.
I look forward to your look
of disappointment...
when you know the true reality...
Stop whining.
Let's...get started!
Now then, round one.
Begin!
Watch carefully, Hanabi.
Nobody has inherited such
a strong Hyuga kekkei genkai.
To say nothing of your older sister.
More than big sister?
Perhaps more than you, too.
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
You used your head,
didn't you, Naruto?!
With the Shadow Clone Jutsu...
Heh. He's an interesting kid.
Shadow Clone Jutsu is
a jonin level technique.
To think he could use
such an jutsu...
Who knows how this'll turn out?
Shadow Clone Jutsu?!
I get it. If chakra is evenly distributed
among the clones,
indeed, I can't detect the
real one even with my Byakugan.
But there's only one real one,
after all!
Heh. Don't be acting tough!
If you're going to come,
then come.
It's pointless.
In front of that Neji's defense,
it's not just all attacking.
Damn it!
I'll get you next time!
Here!
This guy...
Does he have eyes behind him?
You're going to become...
the Hokage...?
With this level, it's impossible.
I can generally tell
with these eyes...
Intrinsic abilities are set.
Figuratively speaking,
everything inherent about people is set.
Why...?
Why are you always so
judgmental like that?
Then...are you going to say
that anybody can become the Hokage...
if they just work hard?
Only a very small percentage of
shinobi are chosen to be the Hokage!
Look more at reality!
Those who become the Hokage
are born with a destiny.
It's not something you become
by trying to become it.
It's determined by fate.
People must live within
their different respective currents
that can't be defied.
The one single...
destiny everyone has equally...
...is death.
Those eyes...
He still holds a grudge
against the head family, huh?
So...
So what?!
I don't know when to give up!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
His opponent is that Neji, huh...?
The Final Round is altogether different
than the preliminaries...
After all, Naruto may not be able to...
Entertain me a little, Naruto.
I've got a tough job waiting
for me now, so...
Damn it. I can't catch him at all.
I told you I'm not
such a fool, didn't I?
I already know...
which one is the real one.
Oh.
That is the body
that has least attacks
due to its fear of having
chakra points attacked.
The more you attack,
the more that one body
becomes clearly evident.
This is as far as it goes.
I said it was pointless.
I've been telling you not
to frivolously assume things.
What?
It can't be.
All right! Go, Naruto!
Naruto!
He foiled my idea and purposely
and drew one of his clones back?
I've been striking from the beginning,
prepared for an honorable death!
Believe it!
I did it.
W-What was that?
Did you think you'd won?
That...
Rotation...
You punk.
Don't make a fool of me.
The largest range of vision of
Neji's Byakugan is nearly 360 degrees.
And he detects all of his opponent's
attacks with the Byakugan.
His defense technique,
the 8 Trigrams Palms Rotation,
will begin from here.
The moment he's attacked,
he discharges a large amount of chakra
from the chakra holes in his body,
blocks the enemy's attack with that chakra
moves his own body in a circular motion,
dodges, and repels.
Essentially, it's difficult to control
the chakra discharged from chakra holes...
To the extent that even jonin utilize
the discharge from a part of the body,
like the hands and feet,
in techniques.
But Neji, who has mastered
Gentle Fist, discharges chakra
from his entire body and
shuts out physical attacks
just with that discharge power.
In other words,
that's one more absolute defense
that has more power
than that Gaara's Sand Shield.
T-That's father's...
Rotation is a secret art passed down
from generation to generation
only to the Hyuga head family.
He created that on his own?
He's quite the guy...
To think he'd come this far.
It's much too soon to be surprised.
Neji's true power is still to come.
Damn it.
This is the end.
You're within the area of my 8 Trigrams.
Gentle Fist Art:
8 Trigrams 64 Palms.
It can't be.
That pose.
8 Tetragrams...
...2 Palms!
4 Palms.
8 Palms.
16 Palms.
32 Palms.
64 Palms!
The branch family exceeds
the head family?
Hizashi...You should have
succeeded the Hyuga family.
I pressed the 64 chakra points
all over your body...
You can't even stand.
D-Damn it.
Are you frustrated?
Kneeling down before power
that can't be changed
and knowing your powerlessness.
Bushy Brow...
Hinata.
D-Damn it.
Oh.
Naruto.
He...No way.
I told you, didn't I...?
I don't know when to give up.
Hey, you're bleeding!
What's wrong?
You've still got damage
from the match.
I'll take a look at her.
Who're you?
I'm not suspicious or anything...
Stop already...
It'll be the same even if
you fight more than this.
I don't have a grudge particularly
against you.
Even if you say so,
I have something against you.
What are you talking about?
Mocking Hinata, selfishly labeling
her a failure as you please.
Head family, branch family...
I don't know what happened to you.
But I won't forgive the jerk who'd
call another person a failure.
Hey, you.
It's okay. I'm a doctor.
Okay...Fine.
If you insist, I'll tell you about
the Hyuga's destiny of hatred.
In the Hyuga head family,
there's a secret ninjutsu
that's been passed on
from generation to generation.
That is the Curse Mark.
Curse Mark?
The Curse Mark represents
a bird in a cage...
and it's a mark of those who are
bound to a destiny they can't escape.
W-What's...
...that mark?
One day when I was four years old,
this accursed mark was inscribed
on my forehead with the Curse Mark Arts.
A large ceremony was held in
the Village Hidden in Leaves on that day.
It was also the day when the
head ninja of the Land of Lightning,
the land that the Leaf had
fought with for many years,
came for the conclusion
of the allied treaty.
However, there was one clan...
who didn't attend the ceremony
that was attended
by everybody else,
from Leaf jonin to genin.
It was the Hyuga clan...
And it's because that day
was the day of hope
when the head family heir
was to turn three.
Miss Hinata's third birthday!
My father, Hizashi Hyuga,
and Miss Hinata's father,
Lord Hiashi Hyuga were twin brothers.
However Miss Hinata's father,
Lord Hiashi,
was born into this world first
and became part of the head family.
My father, who was the second son,
was born into the branch family.
So Miss Hinata is already three...
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Lady Hinata…
is a cute child.
Neji...
It is your destiny to protect her,
and to protect
the Hyuga bloodline.
The Hyuga...bloodline?
Father!
Then...
I'll be taking Neji
under my care, Hizashi.
Yes.
When the head family heir grew
and became three years old,
I had the Curse Mark imprinted on me
and I became the bird in the cage.
This Curse Mark is the absolute fear
called death so to speak...
that was given to the branch family
by the head family.
And this mark only goes away
at time of death.
Sealing away the power
of the Byakugan.
The Hyuga clan possesses
the most distinctive kekkei genkai.
There's no end to those who target
the secret of that distinctive power.
In other words, this Curse Mark
keeps the branch family alive
only to protect the head family
and does not allow disobedience.
And it's an effective system created
to defend for eternity
the kekkei genkai called Byakugan.
And then, that incident occurred.
My father was killed by
the head family.
One night, Miss Hinata was
snatched up by someone.
At that time, Lord Hiashi immediately
rushed off and killed the abductor.
Who do you think that person was...
who was in the shadows,
and also wearing a mask?
It was the head ninja of
the Land of Lightning
who had just completed
the allied treaty.
It was clear that he came targeting
the secret of Byakugan from the start.
However, the Land of Lightning
exploited the killing of their own ninja
due to a botched plan...
and set an outrageous condition in
violation of the treaty.
The Lightning demanded the body
of the head Hyuga
who possessed Byakugan,
the kekkei genkai...
In other words,
the body of Lord Hiashi.
And the Leaf accepted the condition.
What? But, father...
And war was safely avoided.
Thanks to my father who was killed
as a body double of Hiashi Hyuga,
to protect the head family!
Other than dying, there's no other way
to escape this accursed Curse Mark.
Even though they were twins
with nearly equal power,
their destinies were already set by
who was born first and born later.
And then, this match...
Your destiny was decided at the point
when I became your opponent.
You don't know until you try!
Your father was killed a long time ago
and I don't know the extent
of the pain you've felt...
But it's a huge mistake for you to think
that has determined your entire destiny!
You're hopeless...
Proctor...it's over.
You failure...
Don't...run away.
I won't...run...
I'll...stand by my own words...
That's my Ninja Way!
I think I've heard that line before...
You with your destiny stuff...
I won't lose...
to a jerk with cold feet like you,
no matter what!
A brat who knows nothing
shouldn't lecture arrogantly!
You can't possibly understand
the destiny of being burdened with
a mark that cannot be wiped off for life!
Yeah...
I do understand it.
So...what of it?
This brat!
Don't be acting cool...
It's not just you who's special!
Hinata was also...
suffering the same as you!
Even though she's the head family,
not being acknowledged as such...
trying desperately to change herself...
She fought you while coughing
up blood with that in mind!
You too!
The branch family that
protects the head family...
Doing all that to Hinata
just because it's an exam.
In actuality, you were just as frantic
in attempting to go
against destiny, right?
Vitality has returned to Hinata's face!
Just what I'd expect of
the ANBU Black Ops...
She'll be okay.
Now she needs bed rest.
Your chakra points are now shut...
How are you, who can't use chakra
for awhile, planning to fight?
You possess two kinds of chakra...
You must extract and utilize, at any time,
the other huge chakra that
has rested inside you from the start...
That's it. The Nine-Tailed Fox's chakra...
I'll use that...
Stinking fox...Help me out!
This is as far as the talking goes.
Proctor...I'm going to fight with
the intent to kill him!
If you're going to stop me,
please feel free.
Jeez.
It's futile...I closed the chakra points
Oh, yeah! Be sure to come
watch me kick that Neji's butt!
A failure beats down
a genius with effort...
Why do you try to go against
your destiny that much?
Because I was called...
a failure!
It's twisting...
What's that?!
Is that even chakra?!
Here I go!
Rotation!
You!
You're confident in close combat, right?!
I don't know what the
Hyuga destiny of hatred is!
But if you're going to say it's futile,
you don't have to do anything
This is bad! I must use the Rotation!
After I become the Hokage...
I'll change Hyuga!
What chakra...
That kid showed some enormous strength...
The Hyuga kid is probably...
Failure boy...
Sorry, but this is the reality...
Now this is really the en-
My body...
In those conditions,
you used the Shadow Clone Jutsu
just like that...
The ninjutsu that you're good at, huh?
I was careless...
I've...failed the graduation
exam three times...
As luck would have it,
the ninjutsu tests that appeared
on the graduation exam were always...
infallibly the ninjutsu I stunk at.
Clone jutsu was the ninjutsu...
I stunk at.
Don't be whining about boring stuff
like destiny and what not,
and how it can't be changed!
Because unlike me...
you're not a failure.
Winner of this match is Naruto Uzumaki.
That was awesome!
Well done!
That was a great fight!
Yay!
And he still has the energy
to run around...
Man...He's got crazy stamina that guy...
That Naruto...
He keeps getting stronger...
He did it...that kid.
Yeah! He's on the right track!
And he's a little cute...
Something about it...
I'm envious of you...
Watching your battle makes me think
that I have to work really hard too...
That's amazing, you know?
He won. Is it for real?
I thought he was the same as me,
in the not going anywhere class...
Not going anywhere?
Now people are squealing...
Looks like he's part of the group
that's going somewhere.
Maybe I couldn't beat him...
This is really bad.
It kinda depresses me...
To retain himself and draw out
the chakra of the Nine-Tailed Fox...
Yeah...Most of the Leaf Village people
here are surprised.
That Naruto...
When did he learn to control the strength
of Nine-Tailed Fox to that extent?
Even a bird who gets caught,
once it learns how,
will open the lid of its basket
with its own beak.
He won't give up, for he wants to
fly freely in the sky again.
This time you lost!
It's buzzing.
That's because it was a good battle...
Certainly, there's that too, but...
It's likely that, for the curious heads
of ninja and the feudal lords,
there is no match they look forward to
more than this next match.
There's been no news of Sasuke.
And there's the issue of Orochimaru.
Before everyone starts to make noise,
we should disqualify him...
What's going on?!
Hurry up and start the next match!
How long are you going to
make us wait!
Before night falls!
I wonder what's going on
with the next match?
Is Sasuke here?
Sasuke...
That guy...
What in the world is he doing?!
Is he planning to not show up?
A wise man never courts danger...
A wise judgement...is it?
What are you saying?
He'll definitely come! Believe it!
But seriously, what is he doing?
Keep this up and he...
he'll be disqualified.
There's no choice...
Sasuke is...disqualified.
Yes.
Lord Hokage...
I want you to consider waiting a little
bit for Sasuke Uchiha's disqualification.
I understand your point, but...
No matter how excellent the shinobi,
to make light of time is not
a qualification for chunin.
If there's no clear reason to satisfy
the heads of ninja and feudal lords
who are here,
there's no reason to wait for him!
I see...
Well then, there is a sufficient reason.
Including myself...
most of the heads of ninja and
feudal lords that are here...
came here because they want to see
the next match specifically.
However...
He's the remaining survivor
of the "Uchiha."
Land of the Wind too, absolutely,
is hoping for a bout with our Gaara.
Lord Hokage...
There's no guarantee that
Sasuke will come but...
All right then...
We shall specially postpone
this match and wait.
Lord Hokage! Really...
Inform the Proctor!
Y-Yes.
However...
It's rare for you to insist like that,
Lord Kazekage.
Well...
To show off the shinobi's qualities
of our village to the feudal lords...
there's no better opponent
than an Uchiha.
It's a chance for us as well.
C'mon, what happened to the match?!
What happened to Uchiha?!
I understand...
Everyone! The candidate for the
next battle has not arrived here!
We'll briefly postpone this battle and
start the following battle ahead of it.
What is he doing...that Sasuke?
Great,
so Sasuke didn't get disqualified!
That's good...
Hey! That means my match
is one match closer!
Then, onto the next pair!
Kankuro and Shino Aburame!
Come down!
My match...doesn't matter at all.
More importantly...
I'd rather not expose the Mechanism
of Crow to the enemy before the plan...
Proctor!
I abstain!
What?!
Please advance the matches!
Due to Kankuro's abstention,
Shino Aburame wins by default!
What's that all about?!
Have a proper match!
You are...?
It's my turn, isn't it?
It seems that you're really fired up.
Okay, let's go to the next match.
Hey! The last one, come down!
Hey! Hey! What are you doing,
frivolously building things up?
I mean, why does only
my match have to be modified?
Shikamaru Nara! You!
Damn...
If it's like this I'll abstain too...
C'mon! Shikamaru, fight hard!
That damn Naruto...
- C'mon!
- Hurry up with the match!
Finish it up already!
Stand up and start the match!
Evidently, people don't want to
see the minor players matches
since they were really looking
forward to Sasuke's match...
What? You're giving up, too?
My opponent's a girl again?
That kid has had zero fighting spirit
from the beginning...
C'mon! What is he doing?!
C'mon Shikamaru!
Get it together and do it!
If you don't come, I'll go!
Hey! Haven't started yet...
Man, that girl is so gung ho.
It doesn't really matter if
I become a chunin or not.
But there's no reason why
a man should lose to a woman.
Well...let's do it!
This guy's quick to run away...
Nor any reason why a man should
rough up a woman.
But I don't want to be
roughed up either.
He's probably trying to lure me into the
trees where there're lots of shadows...
but I won't let him.
Why am I the only one who always
gets a woman for an opponent, cripes?!
Shikamaru! You get her with
a torrent of 16 combination...!
Mind if I sit here?
Huh?
What...you?
Your stomach okay?
What? Wasn't Sasuke's match next?
Shh!
Everything's fine, right, Sakura?
After all, it's Sasuke, right?
R-Right now, I should leave her alone.
It looks like Shikamaru taking part
in this final battle,
it seems like he's in the wrong place.
Don't say that!
I certainly don't think that
he has any great techniques,
but that Shikamaru is
always good at strategizing.
That's why I feel like we ended up
in the preliminary round the other day.
Hmm, yeah well...
And after all, he jumped down
into the arena himself.
He seems uncharacteristically driven.
Even he can be passionate
once in a while!
Go! Shikamaru!
Geez, I envy a cloud being so free...
I guess I pretty much
am completely without desire...
Even the reason why I became a ninja...
was because I thought
I would have a fun life, ya know...
But...of course, it's not that easy.
What's going on with that stupid face?!
Is he underestimating me?
Ninja Art: Wind Scythe Jutsu!
That's right, with this attack,
my armed attacks also were beaten down.
I see...
Shadow Possession Jutsu!
I've seen that true identity!
Evidently there's a limit to
the stretching and shortening
changing shape of the shadow...
No matter how much you
change the shape of the shadow,
even when you stretch it,
it can only span up to
the size of your own shadow.
That's right isn't it?
You got it...
Even if I assume that he's made up
the distance,
by stretching his shadow from the edge
of the shadow of the arena wall...
This is the limit to how far
the shadow can stretch.
This is the scope of his attack!
15 meters, 32 centimeters!
She took the distance
with the folding fan.
Temari is stronger at long distance
battles than she is at close range...
the outcome has already been decided.
What? What is that sign...?
That's no sign.
That's like, his habit.
Habit?
He enjoys passing time slowly.
That guy's like an old man.
That's why he likes
Japanese checkers and chess
and always makes me be his opponent.
When he's stuck on a move,
he always does that.
Why?
He's working out his strategy.
And, I've never beaten him.
A strategy...
but this is an actual fight.
It's different from a game.
But it's said that formation pieces
that were used to build battle strategy
eventually become
game pieces.
Shikamaru is like a brilliant general.
Wait a minute.
When we grouped the genin,
I saw his scores.
They were at about the
same level of that Naruto's.
He said that moving his pencil during
written exams at the academy is a pain,
and during the tests,
he always sleeps instead.
A pain...?
He was so good at strategy games,
I felt something wasn't right...
so I had him take an IQ test
under the pretense that it was a game.
He was more than brilliant.
With an IQ of over 200,
he's a super genius!
T-Two hundred?!
Looks like you've got some
fighting spirit now...
It's pointless to hide!
I wonder if he's really got a strategy...
M-Maybe...
With that he has no approach!
Shikamaru! Go for it!
It's pointless, isn't it?
He'll give up soon.
He hates things
that are a pain in the butt.
How long are you going to run away!
Cut it out!
It's no use.
As long as I'm on the
outside of this line,
he absolutely can't catch me...
No, wait! Close call!
You caught on well.
So you were dragging your feet
to wait for the sun to set...
in order to make the surface
of your own shadow larger
by stretching the
shadow line of the wall.
As the sun goes down,
the shadows lengthen.
Isn't that so?
Even if I calculate the height
of the sun now
and the limit to the distance
of the previous attack,
there's no mistaking the distance!
Temari! Up!
Darn it!
I won't let you escape!
I didn't expect that he would
create extra shadows to reach me
by making a parachute
with his jacket...!
A skillful technique!
She's dodged this trick too...
If this battle takes too long,
the shadows in the arena will grow,
and his territory will increase.
I'll defeat him with the next one!
Okay!
Clone...
N-No way...!
My...body is...?!
At last...
Shadow Possession Jutsu is a success!
What?!
What's going on...?
That boy...
How much is he planning ahead...?
That's Shikamaru's skill.
Why...won't my body move?!
The shadow shouldn't
have reached this far.
I'll let you
take a look behind you...
T-This hole...!
You saw it too, didn't you...?
That hole is the hole Naruto
burrowed and flew out of.
So it's connected to the
big hole in front of you.
I didn't expect that...
a shadow in a tunnel of a hole...
Right.
The attack that he used
with the jacket,
was it a device to lead me
to right this spot...?
Was that an underplot too?!
Why that?!
Checkmate with the next one.
My body is moving on its own!
I can't resist it!
Before anyone knew it,
they fell under the spell of this match.
That guy with no mark
is quite a darkhorse.
Yes! You did it!
Go! Shikamaru!
Good grief...I give up!
What?!
See I told you...he'd give up.
Ino doesn't know anything
about Shikamaru.
W-What did you say?!
I've used too much chakra from Shadow
Possession Jutsu in rapid succession.
I can't hold it another 10 seconds.
I thought of the
next trick 200 times.
But I'm out of time...
This has become such a pain.
Doing one match is good...
That guy is a strange one.
The winner is Temari!
Oh, I'm tired...
Oh, what a waste!
Why?! He had a chance to
become a chunin!
Shikamaru is Shikamaru...
Really...Does he or doesn't he
have the motivation?
Even I'm not sure about it.
But his intelligence and strategies
are no longer at the genin level.
If it had been an actual mission
for a basic platoon,
the win was decided when
he captured Temari...
So, I suppose he won the competition,
but he lost the match...
In order to evaluate someone
as a leader of a platoon...
it's much more important to
protect the platoon from danger,
than to carry out a mission.
Yeah...it'd hardly be worth mentioning
a completed mission
if everyone was annihilated.
The risks and the mission
should be put on a scale,
surviving should be thought of first,
and then action should be taken.
A person who can't do this isn't
qualified to become a chunin.
Hyuga and Naruto from earlier
fail on that point.
Well, I do feel like Shikamaru
gave up too soon too.
What do you think?
What do I feel...?
He has more of a chance
than Naruto, for sure!
This ticks me off!
I'm gonna really give him
a lecture!
So the one that's gonna
become a chunin is...
You idiot!
Shut up, super idiot!
Why the heck did you give up?!
Let's not talk about that anymore,
all right?
It's not all right! It was a match
you were close to winning!
- Let's just watch the next match.
- But you just gave up! Unimaginable!
Simply unimaginable!
Huh? The next match?
Sasuke...!
I hear Uchiha's gonna
withdraw from this match.
Really?!
I'm counting on you, come on!
As you'd expect, this match
will be won by Uchiha.
No way, I've got high hope
for the new one of the Sand.
He won't let this one slip by.
Lord Hokage, about Uchiha Sasuke,
he has not yet arrived at the arena.
Umm...it's unavoidable...
Why don't we wait just
another ten minutes?
But...
The guests are looking forward
to the next match above all else.
Cancelling it would be cruel.
Since it's come to this,
waiting another ten minutes wouldn't hurt.
There is some truth to what
Kazekage says.
So...let Genma know of this.
Yes!
I see...a ten minute extension...
Sasuke...
Hey, isn't that...
But, what's that idiot doing
He's still not here?!
Good of the two of you to make it!
Come now, hurry into the arena!
Yeah!
All right! Here we go!
Oh! Yeah!
Most of the first round is finished,
and the only one left is
Sasuke Uchiha and Gaara.
H-How about Naruto and
Neji's match?!
Well, the interesting thing is...
Hyuga lost...
Naruto beat Neji...
I see...
You did it!
Naruto!
You're such a...
good guy really...
- What's going on with the next match!
- Let's get on with it!
Isn't Uchiha up yet?!
We want Uchiha! Uchiha!
Uchiha!
Hey, it's almost time.
Is he really gonna come?!
He'll come...
He'll definitely come!
Sorry we're late!
Your name?
Sasuke...Uchiha.
Sasuke…
You're really late!
I thought you chickened out
and weren't coming!
It's too early to celebrate,
you loser.
Judging from that smirk
on your face,
I guess you won your first match?
Damn right!
Oh well, we made such
a grand entrance.
Sasuke hasn't been disqualified, has he?
Not at all. We pushed
Sasuke's match until later.
He's not disqualified.
That's good news. I'm glad!
Don't lose to someone like that!
I know...
I want to fight you too.
Sasuke!
Yeah...
Yay, Sasuke!
Uchiha's match is gonna start!
Shikamaru gave it so much,
but already it's Sasuke...
Poor Shikamaru...
Hey, is that Uchiha?
I'm just second fiddle...
Well, I guess that's just
the way it goes...
I'm looking forward to it too.
Your team is sort of amazing, Sakura.
What is?
Well, Naruto did beat that
Neji Hyuga and...
Sasuke is an elite member
of the Uchiha...
and it seems like everyone's
anxious to see Sasuke's match.
Sasuke will face that Gaara
of the Sand whom I couldn't beat...
And Naruto beat that Neji
that I had hoped to take down.
Why is it so...
Why am I so...
frustrated!
Lee...!
At last...
Gaara, come down here!
Naruto! Let's go up!
Yeah!
When we go up,
we'll leisurely take the stairs.
What's up with you!
Are you still upset that
I pushed you down?!
T-This isn't good...
It's been quite awhile
since I've seen Gaara like this.
H-Hey...Gaara.
Keep the strategy in mind...!
Don't talk to Gaara right now!
You'll be killed.
Right!
Let's go
Hey, hurry up!
Nothing good's gonna happen
in your life if you panic.
What's wrong?
Huh?
Low level tournaments like this
Chunin Examination are ideal
as gambling matches.
A number of feudal lords
are here for that purpose.
So...
would you lose this match for us.
If those two in front of us
hadn't been there,
we probably would've been killed...
This is the first I've seen anyone kill
people without hesitation like that...
This isn't looking good
even for Sasuke.
Sasuke...
The rules are the same as
in the preliminaries.
The match goes on until one of you
dies or admits defeat.
When it's determined that
there's a winner,
the match can be stopped.
But that's my decision.
Hey Guy! You too, Lee...
Is your body all right?
Kakashi!
Kakashi Sensei!
Oh! Sorry, sorry.
You must've been worried.
Sorry for not contacting you at all...
Oh no,
Sakura's gonna get really mad...
I don't really mind that.
Kakashi Sensei...
Hm?
You know about the mark
on Sasuke's neck, don't you?
No need to worry.
So, that's that.
Yup!
Eight of them...
There are eight members of
ANBU Black Ops in this spacious arena...
Two platoons are too few...
What's Lord Hokage thinking?
Well...without knowing how or when
the opponent would make their move...
It can't be helped that the ANBU
are dispersed and deployed
in important areas in the village.
Huh?
It's about to begin.
We shouldn't let our guard down,
but for now...
We need to pay attention...
to this match.
Kakashi, I'll be carefully checking out
what sort of training you gave him...
as your eternal rival!
Huh? Did you say something
Begin!
So this is the sand
Kakashi told me about...
Please don't get so mad...
Mother...
What's he talking about...?
Earlier...Earlier I had you suck
awful tasting blood.
I'm sorry.
But this time it'll likely...
taste good.
It appears he's calmed down.
Come on.
He's fast! It's nearly the same
as Lee's ordinary speed.
And...
It's overlapping with the image...
of my taijutsu!
Is that the Sand Armor?
Come on!
If you're not gonna come at me,
I'll go at you!
What's the matter? Is that it?
A-Amazing...
That armor...I'll tear it off.
His speed is basically the same
as Lee's with the weights removed.
What the heck sort of training
did you do?!
Hm?
To get to that level
in a mere month...
Sasuke had copied Lee's taijutsu
with Sharingan.
So during the taijutsu training...
I had Sasuke image Lee's movements.
Sasuke could make
that movement his own
only because he knew Lee.
Of course, Sasuke had to
work very hard for it.
He must have seen the battle
between the hateful Gaara
and the lovable Lee.
Why is it that he had Sasuke
master only taijutsu?!
Why did I keep living?
But as long as you're alive,
you need a reason...
If you don't have one,
it's just the same as being dead.
What's this guy saying?!
So this is the answer I came to...
I am living in order to kill
human beings other than myself.
After living in the fear of never
knowing when I might be murdered,
finally, I became calm.
Oh?
Shikamaru...
We need to go over to where
Kakashi Sensei is right now!
What're you planning to do?
Hey!
I'm going to...
stop this match!
So he used all the sand
for protection...
I didn't think there could be this
much of a difference in the hardness
with a difference in the density
of the sand.
So it's absolute protection.
Kakashi Sensei!
Naruto!
Huh? What do you want?
Sensei!
Please stop this match right away!
That guy is totally different from us!
He's not normal!
Naruto...
What're you saying?
He lives to kill people.
In any case...
If this continues, Sasuke will die!
There's nothing to worry about...
What?
Sasuke and I...
We didn't just get here late
for no reason.
Withdrawing like that...
I don't know what you're up to...
but the timing is perfect.
This thing of mine also takes time!
Sensei...
Hm?
What do you mean
you didn't get here late for nothing?
Hmm...
You want to know why?
Like I said, this isn't the time
to be talking about that!
Shut up and watch him.
'Cause you'll get a real surprise.
That idiot...
Gaara...we never know when
the signal is going to come!
Yeah...
I'm gonna tear him open.
That's how it comes out.
What?
The contents...
Lots and lots are coming out, right?
I'll give it all to you.
I'm always a good boy!
Yeah, let's do it.
Mother, I'm watching so...
Damn! He's totally useless,
no matter what we do now.
He's not even
abiding by the plan.
He looks like he's just going
to screw things up!
That Gaara!
Hey, hey, wouldn't it
be better if we flee...?
Plan?
D-Don't tell me that...
The reason I decided to
train Sasuke was...
because he was like me.
A physical Activation?!
I see...
That's why he went through
the physical training
and increased
his speed significantly...!
That's right!
Awesome...
The chakra is clearly visible
to the naked eye...
What in the world is happening?!
Don't tell me that
he learned that jutsu...!
So this is the Uchiha Clan...
Exactly...
W-What the heck is that?!
What a sound!
What's that technique?
That's just a jab...
Huh?!
However, it is the one used by
Leaf Villages! Number one technician.
That's the only original technique
of the Copy ninja, Kakashi...
It's the special technique
used for assassinations...
Its secret is in the speed of the jab,
and also the physical aptitude
that gives forth a gigantic chakra,
the ability of the chakra to
focus solely on the target,
and moreover the speed of
the jab makes a chichichichichi sound...
A unique sound attack similar
to the rumbling of a thousand birds.
And that's why
that technique is called...
Chidori: One Thousand Birds!
No way!
That Gaara's absolute protection is...
It's impossible...
Don't tell me...
That's...
Kakashi's...
Chidori...
Also known as Lightning Blade.
Lightning Blade?
Lightning Blade is another name
for the jutsu derived
from Kakashi's ability to cut through
lightning using that technique.
Huh? Cut through lightning?
Huh? That sounds fishy...
A-Awesome...
The real name of that technique
is Chidori...
The secret is the speed of his jab
that surpasses any human limitations
and the intensity of
the chakra on his arm...
And that arm virtually turns into
the equivalent of the swing
of a celebrated sword that
cuts through everything.
But what a reckless technique...
That's not for you to say...
Right, Lee?
The guy who was worrying about
Sasuke until just a moment ago...
is now jealous of him.
What...? This warm thing...?
Mother...? What is...?
Blood!
My blood is...!
D-Don't tell me that...
D-Don't tell me that
Gaara is hurt?!
What is that?!
It's that thing's arm!
Damn! Doing something
careless like that...
Has the Perfect Possession happened?
I don't know.
He seems to be injured...
This has never happened before.
It gives me the chills
just to remember...
When I first saw that thing,
I wasn't able to eat...
I mean, visually it's totally...
What is...
this sensation?
He's hurt, after all...
The shell was broken when
his body was incomplete!
It's different! Those aren't the eyes!
W-What was that...
that look earlier on?!
Huh?
What's this...? I can't see...
Kakashi! This must be!
Yeah...genjutsu!
- Release!
Release!
Genjutsu!
Is Kabuto already moving?
In that case,
it's just about time...
It's coming!
Shall we begin?!
It's the signal!
- Start the operation!