To everyone who has advanced to
the Final Round
of the third test of the Chunin Exams,
there's one person who's missing,
but, congratulations.
Sensei...
Hmm?
I have a question.
About Sasuke?
Well, I'm sorry, but I don't know much.
But don't worry too much.
From here on, it's up to Sasuke.
Sakura, I have to step out
for a moment.
Please inquire about the
details of the Final Round!
Sure.
Here, in our house,
including Sasuke who's not here,
we have five Leaf,
three Sand,
and one Sound.
Well, I will begin the explanation
of the Final Round.
Finally!
The preliminary battles have
ended without incident.
It seems they're now entering
the Final Round.
This land really has become
peaceful, hasn't it?
This peaceful time has put
this country in slumber...
while all the other lands are busy racing
to expand their military.
Would it be possible for us
to take it now?
Hmph, I suppose.
Though, I don't know how much fun
it would be to take out that old man.
To me, it looks like you are still have
a hesitation about it.
From now on, the power of
each Hidden Village will clash
with one another in a long
and violent manner.
The Sound Village is also one of them...
You intend to be the trigger
for all of that...
And use him for a bullet.
Our Sasuke...right?
You guess well.
So well that it's a bit creepy.
The Curse Mark that was given to him...
appears to have been sealed by Kakashi.
Though, that won't matter much.
While there is still some
darkness left in his heart...
I want you to abduct him.
That's an uncharacteristically
hasty request, is it not?
There's a little something troubling me...
Is it Naruto Uzumaki?
According to your information,
contact with that Nine-Tails kid has
altered Sasuke's heart and mind.
So much so, that he possesses
some influence over Sasuke.
The best thing to do is to get Sasuke
away from him immediately...
And quickly turn him in my color.
Well, then...
That face...
I wonder what could possibly
be going on in his head?
The Final Round is where
each one of you
will show off your battle skills
in front of everyone.
I want you to satisfactorily demonstrate
and show off your ability
as representative battle forces
of your respective lands.
Accordingly, the Final Round will
commence one month from now.
W-We're not going to
do it here, right now?
This is so that there's
a suitable period of preparation.
What do you mean?
That is to say...
Along with the announcement of
the conclusion
of the preliminary match to each
country's Daimyo and shinobi leaders,
readying the summons for
Final Round requires preparation time...
not to mention the time it takes
for you examinees to prepare.
This old man always has such
a roundabout way of saying things.
I don't quite get what
you're trying to say.
What do you mean?
In other words,
in order to know your adversary,
in order to prepare yourself,
time is necessary.
Time to analyze what you learned about
the adversaries in the preliminaries...
time to take stock of your successes.
The battles until now were
like actual battles
it presupposed situations in which
you can't know your adversary.
That's for sure...
I never dreamed that this guy
could make sand into a weapon.
However, this is not the case
in the Final Round.
Some of you might have already revealed
everything in front of your rivals...
In the spirit of fairness and equality,
you will have a month to
train yourself to further your skills.
Now, I can't be thinking of this
as some sort of month long
holiday and do nothing! Believe it!
Seriously! Seriously!
It might not be good idea to
excel too much, is it?
We failed to stay out of Orochimaru's
watchful eye,
and it was unfortunate for us both.
Under this gentle exterior,
a seed of evil took root-
and it was this seed that was exploited...
Some day, through that ninjutsu...
this child will as well...
I have to give it you, Kakashi...
Stopping my attack from your blind spot...
But, you'd better ready at least
10 of your men next time.
The ANBU that I prepared were
taken out without difficulty...
You're not an ordinary genin are you?
You caught a whiff of me and immediately
readied your weapon...
you're quite impressive.
No, I'm not all that.
What do you want with Sasuke?
Depending on circumstances,
I'll haul you off to questioning.
I wonder if that's possible
for the likes of you...
Are you looking to take me on?
You are the son of the chief of the
Leaf medical corps, aren't you?
Your name, was it, Kabuto Yakushi?
Are you affiliated with Orochimaru?
If you arrest me here now,
you might never be able to prove
my connection to Orochimaru.
Shut up and confine your answers
to my questions.
What if I say "No"?
I'm the one asking the
questions around here.
Now give me some answers.
You'll find out before long anyway
if you let me go,
so can you make an exception
just this once?
You, willful little brat...
Don't mess around with grown-ups.
Don't be so arrogant.
The circumstances are in my favor...
A Shadow Clone!
Damn...I've let him escape.
Impressive...
As I suspected...
This is the Dead Soul Jutsu,
where one temporarily animates
and controls the heart of a dead body.
Meticulously transforming even the face...
and also stopping his heartbeats and
eliminating all traces of his body odor...
in order to prepare an escape by
impersonating a murdered ANBU...
He wasn't raised as the adopted son of
the medical corps chief for nothing.
If someone this good is working
for Orochimaru...
I can't stay as I am now...
Now that that's done...
I'd like to let you take your leave...
But first, for the Final Round,
there is one more important
matter to take care of.
Let's get on with it,
so we can get to training
Now, now. I want you all to
calmly take one slip of paper
from the box that Anko is holding.
I'm going to go around in order...
take only one.
Good, everyone has taken
a number.
Then, from left to right, tell me
the number on your slip of paper.
I'm eight.
I'm one.
Seven.
Five.
Three.
Nine.
Two.
Six.
In other words, he has number four.
Uh huh.
Very well, I will tell you
about how the Final Round
tournament will work!
Huh?
Is that what these
drawing lots were for?
Ibiki, bring forth the pairings.
Yes, sir.
He's so far away.
Is that all the Final Round is,
a tournament?
Shoot! I have one extra round.
Vendetta for Choji?
Give me a break!
I'm so relieved to know that
I won't be in the same section as Gaara.
Sasuke Uchiha...
Perfect.
Hyuga Neji, right off the bat?
This couldn't be better!
Believe it!
Could I ask a question?
Go ahead.
Does this mean that there will
only be one winner of the tournament?
That only one of us will be
able to become a chunin?
No, on the contrary.
The judges of the Final Round,
of which I am one,
will be made up of the Kazekage,
the Daimyo from various countries
who will assign you your missions,
and the shinobi leaders.
Through this tournament,
these judges will be able to make
a thorough evaluation,
and come to a decision as to
whether each one of you
possesses the qualities incumbent
of a chunin.
Even if someone loses the first round,
they can still become a chunin.
So there's a chance that all
of us will become chunin?
Correct, but conversely, there's also
a chance that none of you will.
To "advance" in the tournament,
means maximizing chances
to appeal yourselves to the judges.
Understood, Shikamaru?
This is all a real pain in my...
Thank you for your patience.
We will adjourn until next month.
The second round will either be
No Eyebrows from Sand or Sasuke, huh?
That guy is so strong he kicked
Bushy Brow's butt.
I want to fight you, too.
Now that it's come to this,
I've got to see Kakashi Sensei.
Lady Hanabi! Terrible news!
I heard Elder Sister Hinata
was seriously injured!
She's been treated and
is conscious now.
There's no need to worry.
She should have expected
this outcome if she faced Neji.
Why didn't you withdraw?
I couldn't…do that.
I know very well what I am.
I'm an indecisive failure…
But I don't want to give up,
I want to become strong…
I feel like I can possibly change.
Watching Naruto makes me
feel this way.
Naruto…
What're you doing here?
You're a curse on all of us!
What? I was only…
I was only looking at the masks!
I never go back on my word.
Because that's my Ninja Way.
Umm, where's the room
that Sasuke's in?
I'm sorry. Mr. Sasuke
is not allowed visitors.
What?! Hey, hey!
What's up with that?!
I'm sorry, those are the rules.
Why, Sis, tell me why?
Naruto, this is a hospital.
Keep it down.
Kakashi Sensei!
Say! Say!
I've got a favor to ask!
You don't need to say it all.
Well, I thought it would
come to this so...
I searched for someone
to watch your training.
Why?! I want you to, Kakashi Sensei!
I have some matters to take care of.
I don't have the time to trouble
myself with you.
Oh! Aha...!
You're going to train
Sasuke, aren't you!
Well, don't say that.
I found a sensei who's
more reliable than I am!
Well...who is it?
It's me!
Huh?!
Oh!
You!
The Closet Perv!
Such insolence!
What did you say?
But you see! But you see!
A long time ago,
with my Harem Jutsu, this guy...
Harem Jutsu?
U-Uh...it's nothing!
I'll treat you to and buy you
whatever you want later!
Just be quiet about that!
You better.
Wow, I didn't know you
were acquainted.
Well, they're unsavory ties, but.
But why this guy?
I definitely don't want him to.
Same here.
If it weren't Kakashi's favor,
who'd teach you for the fun of it?
Then don't.
Now now, both of you...
Don't say that.
Naruto, Ebisu Sensei is a private tutor
who teaches the elite,
a special jonin!
He's truly better
at teaching than I am.
Well, Naruto, of the three kids
in Squad Seven that I taught,
you're the worst at the basic skills.
Get taught with care
this time around.
How the heck am I inferior
compared to Sakura and Sasuke?!
Naruto, it's fact that you
don't have the fundamentals down.
No matter what you do,
the basic skills are important.
If you really want to become strong,
just be quiet and listen to what I say.
Now then, Ebisu Sensei,
I'm leaving him with you.
Yes, yes.
Damn it.
It may appear to be harsh,
but you can become stronger
a lot more.
Do your best.
Okay, then, let's go.
Watch out!
Hey Choji!
This makes it seem like
Shikamaru is my only opponent!
But it's gonna hurt, you know.
I'm strong and I don't
wanna hurt you two.
What makes you think
you're better?
Go ahead, try and hurt us!
C'mon! Cry! Scream!
Stop! You're hurting me!
Damn it...What a drag.
Choji, are you being gentle
because they're your friends?
Asuma Sensei...
If that's the case, you're wrong.
Sparring with a stronger partner
will only help
to make them stronger too.
You don't get it?
Then I'll show you.
We're going to spar right now.
If you're able to strike me, you pass.
But if you're not able to hit me
within one hour, Choji...
Not just you,
but Ino and Shikamaru will be
sent back to the Academy.
Huh? No fair!
Think of me as the enemy and charge,
for their sake too.
Transform your kindness into power.
Miso flavor barbecued pork noodles and
salt flavor ramen noodles!
Here you go!
Naruto, having been shown
your movements and
having further analyzed
what Kakashi has told me...
it is clear that you cannot control
chakra well.
Control...?
That's right.
Now then, comparing you
with Sasuke and Sakura...
I shall explain your
bad points in order.
As you know, in the case of using
ninjutsu, genjutsu and the like,
ninja build up chakra and
activate the jutsu.
I-I know that already!
Is that so?
Then, in the case of comparing
the three of you,
I shall explain specifically
how you are inferior.
That's kind of an irritating
way of saying it.
I'm treating you the ramen
as promised,
so be quiet and listen!
First, let us say that Sakura
uses Clone Jutsu.
Clone Jutsu!
In her case, her build up control as well
her control of chakra is perfect,
so she can make clones without
using wasteful energy.
Cha!
Next, in Sasuke's case,
he is somewhat poor at
building up chakra.
Clone Jutsu.
But, his control of chakra is perfect,
so both he and Sakura can
make five clones.
But, he uses a bit more chakra
than Sakura.
Oh!
So Sasuke's nothing special.
In your case, there's no time
to be laughing at others.
Huh?
You are very poor at building up chakra
and controlling it,
so you cannot make clones
with the same amount of chakra.
In the case where you strain to
make clones despite that,
after consuming a much larger amount
of chakra than Sakura and Sasuke...
Clone Jutsu!
...you can barely make
one clone at best.
By the way,
Sakura and Sasuke can become ten
with the same amount of chakra.
But, there've been times when
I was greater than Sakura and Sasuke...
That's only because you
happen to have
the most outstanding stamina
of the three!
Anyway, there is no mistaking
that you can become strong
if you carry out the training
we will be doing from now.
Huh?! Really?!
I guarantee it.
Now then, let's go.
Sir, your bill.
Oh, that's right.
Wha?!
Thank you very much!
We've come quite a long way...
But, this is a hot spring town, right?
It doesn't look like we've come
here to leisurely soak in a hot spring...
Hey! Naruto!
That's the women's bath!
I simply will not allow
indecent behavior!
What's with that look?
N-Nothing.
More importantly, why've we come
to a place like this?!
Will soaking in a hot spring
do anything for training?
No!
The training will be here
in this hot spring area!
Okay, this is the place.
It's a bath, sure enough!
What are you saying?
I said this is training, didn't I?
Training!
We're going to train here?
What the heck are we going to do?
Walk on this hot water!
What?!
What is it?
Walk on hot water?
Can you really do that?
Of course!
I heard from Kakashi Sensei.
You already did tree climbing training
without using your hands, right?
It's an application of that.
Hmm...
What do you mean?
Besides, I don't really remember
stuff from long ago.
In tree climbing, all you do
is accumulate
only the necessary amount of chakra
in one necessary location
and maintain that amount of
chakra all the while.
Trees are fixed objects,
so you only need to be attached to it.
In other words,
it's training for building up
a fixed amount of chakra.
To float on the surface of water,
you have to discharge on
a constant basis
an appropriate amount of chakra
from your feet to the water
and balance that to the extent that
you can float your own body.
Huh?
This chakra control is
more difficult than maintaining...
and is a control training for
discharge and usage of fixed amount
of chakra for jutsu and alike.
Hmm, I really don't get it!
Well, it would be better to
show you in your case.
First, you build up chakra
in your feet.
Then, while constantly discharging
a fixed amount...
you balance it with your body weight.
And...
well, this is how it goes.
Oh! Okay!
I'm going to try!
First, you build up chakra
in your feet.
Then!
Discharge a fixed amount. Right?
Oh!
I knew it.
Hot-hot-hot-hot!
I forgot to mention it,
but this hot water is 60º C.
If you do nothing but fail...
you will become a boiled octopus!
Damn it!
I'll do it no matter what!
You're unusually spirited today,
honored grandson!
My principle of guidance
has finally gotten through!
This would ordinarily be the
time to go carry out
a surprise attack on Lord Hokage.
I've stopped doing that now!
That's right!
So you have finally understood.
That the shortcut to becoming
the Hokage is to do as I say...
There are no shortcuts!
Huh?
Brother Naruto said it...
If you're to become Hokage,
be prepared for that!
Oh!
I'm starting to get it!
To think he would get the
hang of the chakra control this quickly...
I never thought,
you would grow this much.
Indeed, there are no shortcuts,
in anything...
It appears I had the
wrong idea about you...
You are a much smarter teacher
than I am.
And, you were not just a Demon Fox...
You were a splendid
Hidden Leaf Village ninja!
Oh! Hot!
Hm?! That is!
Humph! I don't know who you are
or where you're from, but...
I will not allow indecency!
Man...
T-That is!
What?!
Don't make a ruckus.
Jeez, it won't do to be found out!
The Closet Perv lost?
W-What's with that
Shameless Perv?!
Hey...Closet pervert.
Leaf Village Secret Finger Jutsu...
One Thousand Years of Death!
He's totally knocked out...
He's weak, sure enough.
What's with that big frog?
What the heck are you?
Thank you for asking me!
Know me as the Mountain Toad...
spirit sage who acquires immortality,
also commonly called the
Toad Mountain Sage.
M-Mountain Sage?
Exactly.
Hey...Pervy Sage,
what're you going to do about this?
Here, he was supposed to
watch my training
You did that to him.
He interfered with my research.
Research?
I'm a writer.
I'm writing a novel.
This is it.
Oh, that is...!
You know this?
I've gotten quite famous.
That's not much of a novel!
In the first place,
what research you are talking about?
You're just peeking at the girls bath!
- Yikes!
- No!
Idiot, idiot...idiot!
My peeking has been found out.
You pervert.
F-Fool! I'm not just a pervert.
I get inspired by peeking
and can write better pieces.
Liar! No excuses.
More importantly, what're you
going to do about my training?
You mean the walking on water technique
you were doing earlier?
You know it?
Then take responsibility
and join my training.
Hmph. I don't care about such things.
Hey, hey wait, Pervy Sage!
Join my training, hey!
Shut up! I hate people who
don't know how to talk properly...
And I don't like men.
Oh, umm, umm...
That Make Out Paradise was
really exciting, cool and interesting.
The purchase or viewing of that novel is
prohibited for those 18 years or younger..
You liar.
The reviews that I've heard are great.
It's useless to flatter me.
I'm a sage!
I'm not the type of fool who can
be coaxed by a fledgling like you.
Oh, hey...wait!
Farewell, kid.
Wow! He's cool even
though he's a pervert.
Fight, Choji, you coward!
That's not the way.
It'll only backfire.
It's not because Choji's scared.
He doesn't want to hurt Asuma Sensei
the way he's hurting now.
He's very kind,
down to his very core.
But as it is...
We have no choice.
Hey Choji! Enough already,
you fatso!
Shikamaru...
Did you just say "fatso"?
Yeah...I said "fatso."
That's what Asuma Sensei said...
Really...Sensei?
Y-Yeah...
Yes! He said that a fatso like you
wouldn't be able to punch him!
You're going overboard, Ino.
I don't care if you're my Sensei.
Anyone who calls me "fatso"
is gonna get it!
I'm sorry...
I can't hit you after all, Sensei.
But...but, please just send me
back to the Academy.
Please don't punish Shikamaru and Ino.
I understand, Choji.
It's my loss.
No matter how angry you are,
you are able to suppress it,
and think of your opponent.
You have true kindness within you.
I want you to continue
nurturing that kindness.
Someday, it will become your strength.
But you know,
when you are sparring...
I know!
I don't want to beat people
like you or Shikamaru
or Ino or my friends from the village.
But if I'm up against anyone
who hurts them, I'll fight them.
Even if Shikamaru and Ino
keep calling me "fatso."
By the way, Shikamaru and Ino,
Choji isn't fat.
He's just pleasingly plump.
I want to have a romantic encounter
with a stacked girl.
How dare you do that to me earlier!
Substitution Jutsu.
Sure enough,
he's not an ordinary old man.
Hmph! That punk...
It's a million years too soon
for that kid to take me on.
Not really.
It seems you have a bit of talent.
Then you'll watch my training?
Give and take!
I'm not averse to listening
to your favor
as long as you listen to mine.
So which is it?
Listen up...
Nice ripe fruit that looks like this,
like this and this.
I'll watch your training
if you bring me that.
You really will, right?
This Toad Mountain Sage doesn't lie.
Okay, wait!
Plans are plans.
They don't necessarily have to happen...
Hello there, you ladies!
Oh my...You're funny, old man.
No, no, this is the solemn truth.
Yeah? And then what happened?
Hey, Pervy Sage!
Oh no! Pervy Sage, he said.
You fool! Who's a Pervy Sage?
I brought the promised item.
Nice ripe fruit...
Idiot, idiot, idiot, idiot!
That's not IT!
I got my fill...
Ladies...
No doubt about it. That's...
Good grief. I've wasted time...
Hold it! Where are you going?!
What about my training?!
I don't care! My precious research
has been ruined thanks to you.
Research, my butt!
I can't be standing around here, either!
I'm going to train hard,
become stronger than anybody,
pass the chunin exam,
and then I'll exceed the Hokage!
Hmph! I don't care about such things.
Here all you do is get in my way...
Jeez, what a repugnant brat!
Stacked girls like the ones
from earlier
are indispensable for
my great writing enterprises!
I see...So I should bring
some stacked girls, right?
Okay.
W-Wow...!
If you gaze at me like that...
I feel embarrassed.
Oh...!
You're really my type of girl.
What's that technique called?
It's called Sexy Jutsu.
Oooh, what an idea. You're a genius.
I get the feeling all adults are
really affected by this technique.
Then you'll watch my training?
A-Always be...in that form
when you're in front of me!
Hey! Sure enough,
you're just a pervert! You Pervy Sage!
No! I'm not just a pervert!
As if you didn't know!
I'm a super pervert!
Damn it...He's gone defiant...
Well, brushing off the stuff until
now as a joke,
I'll watch your training.
You mean it, right?
A sage doesn't go back on his word.
Okay, kid.
Do that training that you were
doing before one more time.
Okay!
Okay.
Totally worthless.
Shut up!
It's pointless to wear clothes.
Hey, build up your chakra
one more time.
One more time?
Just do it, quick.
I see...So this is The Seal Formula.
Two Tetragram Seals
making a Double Tetragram Seal...
Is this an 8 Signed Seal Formula?
Nine-Tailed chakra is leaking
from between the Tetragram Seals...
and is fixed so that it
can return to this kid's chakra.
But after that, it's stopped
with a Five Pronged Seal...
Putting an Odd Numbered Seal
over Even Number Seals...
This kid's chakra and that of the
Nine-Tails are discreetly intermingled
and are not stable.
No wonder he is not able to
build up chakra very well.
That tickles...old man.
Oh, sorry, sorry.
Perhaps someone else...did it...
The formula is rough.
Well, it was probably Orochimaru.
Kid, give me a hurrah.
What?
Just hurrah. Come on, hurrah.
Five-Pronged Seal...Release!
What're you doing?!
Well, I just pushed
the pressure points for relaxing.
Just try walking on
the water once more...
Sheesh!
What?
I don't know why, but it's going well!
Yahoo!
I guess it's about time to teach him
how to control the Nine-Tail's chakra.
Okay, kid. Come on out.
I'll teach you an ace technique.
What, what ace technique?
A deadly technique?
There's something you need to
understand well
before I teach you techniques.
You probably haven't noticed,
but you possess two types of chakra.
Huh? Two types?
Until now, have you ever
felt a special chakra?
Special? Hmm...
Come to think of it...
Come to think of it,
I get the feeling there were times when...
chakra suddenly sprang up
and an awesome power came out.
But...
I don't really remember those moments.
I see.
But I do remember sensing that
it was different
from the chakra I always build up.
If I liken it to colors,
while it's normally blue...
the other felt like
it was red or something.
Okay. That's it for today's training.
What?! Already?
What happened to the ace technique?
I can still train.
With training,
a watched pot never boils.
As long as we're here,
let's have a bath...
Not just falling in...
Warms me up.
A drink after training's the best.
Say, say, Pervy Sage.
What kind of technique is
that ace technique?
You'll find out tomorrow.
Miser!
We'll turn into boiled frogs if
we stay in here too long.
Ebisu, sorry for snatching
your student.
It's okay. More importantly,
I was surprised...
The Hokage has had us searching
all over for you
and we could never determine
your whereabouts.
To think you were in this village...
The Hokage will be pleased.
Did you tell the Third Hokage about me?
Not yet.
I see. That's for the best.
Sure enough, something
about Orochimaru?
No, unfortunately not.
What?
I just stopped by looking
for material for my novel...
My nature is not to get myself
involved in trouble.
What are you saying?!
You should know!
The only way to stop Orochimaru,
one of the legendary three Sannin,
is the power of another Sannin!
Your power, Master Jiraiya!
You don't sleep at all?
What do you want?
I thought I'd crush you now.
I know your Sand attack.
I wonder which is faster,
your Sand or my Sound?
In the full moon...
in the full moon, his blood boils.
W-What the heck...are you?
I see.
So this is the One-Tail.
I don't believe it.
A Tailed Beast,
brought into this village?!
There's no denying its power.
But, are you able to control it?
At that level, yes.
But when the One-Tail transforms
completely and activates his
Playing Possum Jutsu,
there's no stopping him.
Fine. So don't agitate him now.
I'll look forward to seeing him
run amuck when the time is right.
But, are you all right
with what happened?
He was one of the Sound's—
It's fine. He outlived
his usefulness long ago.
I thought he was a guinea pig
in order to see...
the power of the boy
called Sasuke or something...
Why...is he with the Sand ninja?
No, that's not necessary anymore...
Actually, I'd already been ordered
to seize Sasuke.
But I failed...
What did you say?
It's also been found out that
I'm a minion of the Sound.
I heard...
that you're Orochimaru's right hand man.
Being revealed to them and coming
nonchalantly to meet with me...
You must be a fool.
I let them find out.
I wanted to see how far
the Leaf Village would go...
Even after that it wouldn't
be too late to seize Sasuke.
If you guys are going to fail,
we'll back off immediately...
It's a plan that was originally
posed by the Sound, so.
The Sand is invisible until
the last moment.
This is the will of the Kazekage.
Holy smokes...
That's fine.
This is the Sound's instructions.
Okay.
And please...tell them about
this plan soon.
Yeah.
I know.
Okay, I'll be going.
To think our allied nation,
the Village Hidden in the Sand,
has been already associated
with the Sound...?!
I must tell Lord Hokage about this quick.
I'll take care of the clean up.
No, I'll do it...
As the member of Sand Village
of the Land of Wind,
I must do what I can for my allies...
Besides...it's just one mouse.
It'll be easy.
You're mine!
How unexpected.
I thought that it would
be settled right away.
I have to say...
That proctor was very
slick, slipping past me.
He's sheathing his sword?
Leaf Style:
Crescent Moon Dance!
It won't come loose!
Your swordsmanship
is impressive.
However, the blow from
a real sword can be stopped.
But...
A wind sword cannot be stopped,
no matter who you are!
Nice, nice.
Hey...
Okay...I'll teach you a technique.
Do you really mean that?
Do you remember what I told you
yesterday about the two types of chakra?
Huh? Yesterday's talk?
You know, what you said about blue
and red chakra or something.
Oh...What about it?
You said that when a great power
came out, you felt red chakra.
Yeah, it was like that.
Try building up that red chakra right now.
Hmm. Even you say so...
I'll give it a try, but...
How about it?
Hmm, it's not right.
It's the same chakra as always.
Jeez, you have no talent.
Don't be talking all high and mighty!
In the first place,
I really don't understand those
two types of chakra myself!
Just keep trying.
Hmph...So he doesn't understand it...
himself, eh.
It seems Naruto himself still hasn't
realized that
the red chakra is
the Nine-Tailed Fox's chakra.
Well, guessing from his story...
it seems the excitement of danger
and heightened emotion
are the key to summon
the Nine-Tailed Fox's chakra.
No good, not good,
Only the usual chakra's coming out.
Say, Pervy Sage...
What the heck does the red chakra and
the technique you're going to teach me
have to do with each other?
Listen, boy.
For the technique
I'm about to teach you,
the chakra you've had until now
is not nearly enough.
Therefore, you'll have to able to
pull out and use the "other" chakra
that has been dormant within
you at any time you need.
But how do you know that
I have such a chakra?
Oh, just what I wanted to hear.
Actually...
it's because I'm a sage.
Jeez...that's no answer.
Anyway, the special chakra
that only you have
will become your greatest weapon.
Greatest weapon?
Not using that is like wasting treasure.
There's no need to forcedly do
the same training as everyone else.
You, who has two types of chakra
and doesn't exhaust easily,
should release the largest amount
of chakra you can
and train to increase the absolute amount
of chakra that you can use.
Then there are tons of jutsu
and techniques you can use.
What, for example?
For example...the Summoning Jutsu
that I'm going to teach you now.
Summoning?
Right.
It's a type of
spatio-temporal technique
where you sign a contract in blood
with all kinds of living creatures
and summon them whenever
you like with ninjutsu.
Oh! That sounds awesome.
Teach me quick!
Before that...
first, it's necessary to
use up all of your usual chakra.
Okay!
Leave it to me.
Well...So you can use the
Shadow Clone Jutsu.
Listen up. We're going to have
a battle royal now.
The last one left will be
the strongest me...
We're going to determine
the me among me!
- Yeah!
I see.
Good thinking considering he's stupid.
Sure enough, I'm the strongest me.
It looks like you've finally used up
almost all of your chakra.
Now, at last I'll teach you
the technique.
Oh, I've been waiting!
First, I'll show you.
Watch carefully.
Summoning Jutsu!
Ooh, so cool.
Open that scroll.
It's a contract with the
summoning toads
that I've taken over from generations.
Sign your name in your own blood
and stamp the fingerprints of one hand
in blood under that.
Then build up chakra in the place
you want to summon
and set down the hand you contracted.
The sign is
Boar-Dog-Bird-Monkey-Sheep.
U-zu-ma-ki
Na-ru-to.
Okay...This is fine, right?
It's easier for you to release
red chakra right now.
So give it a try.
I already am.
Boar-Dog-Bird-Monkey-Sheep.
Ninja Art: Summoning Jutsu!
A tadpole...
This kid...has no talent, after all.
Hayate...what in the world happened?
Hey! Geez.
Hey, Pervy Sage!
Weren't you going to
watch my training?!
I'm researching now.
Do it yourself!
All right, then I'll summon a frog,
a frog so big you'll be shocked!
Summoning Jutsu!
W-Wait a minute!
What part of that's a frog?!
If you don't get serious,
I won't help you!
Shut up! I am being serious!
Then somehow find your chakra
as if your life depended on it!
That's what I'm doing!
Some of you have probably
already heard but...
Gekko Hayate's corpse was
found near Kikyo Castle...
What...Hayate?
No way...
That's ridiculous!
Is the opponent Orochimaru?
No...we shouldn't jump to
that conclusion so easily.
The one Hayate was following
was likely a Sound spy called Kabuto...
Well, it's certain that Orochimaru
is trying to do something but...
So...we'll cancel the Chunin Exam
and go after Orochimaru...?!
No, he revealed his identity to Anko...
sending us a threat not to cancel.
Not to cancel the Chunin Exam
for which all of the ninja of
the Alliance have gathered!
What does it mean?
Orochimaru possesses enough power
to take down a small Land on his own.
He's a ninja that probably
every land has eyes on.
Moreover, he conveniently holds
a grudge
against this Village Hidden
in the Leaves.
Any Land would desire him.
So could it be...
that any Land in the Alliance
would unite with Orochimaru
and betray the Village Hidden
in the Leaves?!
Well, the Alliance Treaty is at
the same level as a verbal agreement!
As was in the former Great Ninja War...
In any case,
there's too little information
right now.
Let's end these unnecessary
suspicions.
We've already dispatched ANBU,
the black ops to each Land
to collect information.
It's dangerous to act carelessly...
That could be what the enemy
is aiming for.
And also...
When the time comes,
we'll bring all the powers of the
Hidden Leaf Village together and fight!
Huh?
Should I bring get well flowers?
So pretty.
Oh no!
Oh...How unusual for you to come
by to buy our flowers.
N-Not really!
Why would you care?
Besides, isn't it unusual that
you're minding the shop?
I'll choose quickly.
People don't like flowers with
roots when they're in the hospital
since they don't want to
be "rooted" in the hospital...
So cut flowers are fundamental.
W-What are you talking about...?
Playing dumb won't work!
You're going to see Sasuke, right?
Mom! I'm going out for a bit!
I-Ino?!
I won't let you be the first to visit!
I'm going with you!
A get well visit!
Shucks...Ino pig!
I'm taking this flower...
One "rose" of love!
That's so cliché...
Then I'll make mine this.
"Narcissus!"
A noble flower that doesn't
succumb to the cold of the winter,
but hopes for the spring and
waits with dignified presence...
with the wish for release from
the hospital as soon as possible.
You've gotten pretty knowledgeable.
I told you I wouldn't lose to you!
Oh, yes yes, so one narcissus, right?
Uh...I need two.
Why? One is fine.
No...One for Lee too.
More please!
- Huh?!
- Huh?
Ten orders of kalbi!
You sure can eat.
Just watching you makes me feel ill.
Here you are!
It's here!
This is mine, all right?
Don't eat any of it, Shikamaru!
I won't eat any!
What's going on with you guys,
barbecue in the middle of the day?
- Oh...?
- Huh?
Ino and Sakura...
Shikamaru, shouldn't you be going through
some special training or something
to prepare for the final exam?
I am...
Every single day...
Asuma is so persistent.
Actually, Choji's been joining us
in the special training.
Really?
So you took it on?
Yup! In exchange, he's treating me
to as much barbecue as I can eat!
I see...
Oh, I shouldn't have held on
for the Final Round.
Don't be ridiculous!
There are numerous people who
want to participate, but can't!
From what I've heard,
they're doing some awfully
difficult things
over at Guy and Kurenai's team!
W-What's that?
Even though we've made
it this far,
to get totally thrashed
wouldn't be very cool...
Aw man, what a drag...
Whatever the circumstances,
we've exceeded
a human being's limits.
And I've used too much chakra...
Neji, are you all right?!
Summoning Jutsu!
What?! A tadpole again?!
You haven't made
any progress whatsoever!
See how it's bigger
than the ones earlier?!
How the heck should I know?!
So you want to see
Sasuke Uchiha...?
Just five minutes.
I can't allow you to visit
any longer than that.
His body still needs to rest...
Yes...
Sasuke. You have visitors...
Two cute young ladies...
Oh...!
- Huh?
Sasuke, Sasuke?
His clothes are gone!
- What?!
- What?
It's terrible! He's in no condition
to be walking outside yet!
Doctor! Doctor!
Sasuke...Where in the world
have you gone...?
Hey…
So you've finally come.
Kakashi! Make me stronger!
This determination of Sasuke's…
He's dead serious.
Naruto got to
that level so quickly.
I can't waste any time.
I see, so that's what it is.
He finally took notice of
Naruto's immense power.
I have a goal.
I want more power.
That's fine.
Sasuke, you know about
the change-in-chakra-nature
of the five types of chakra,
don't you?
Yeah…
The Uchiha Clan possesses
the Fire Nature
and specializes in the Fire Style.
Why are you bringing that up now?
There are superior shinobi
who possess
more than two
change-in-chakra-natures.
My change-in-chakra-nature
is lightning.
Sasuke, for a long time,
I have sensed that
you are similar to me.
I want to verify what
your change-in-chakra-nature is.
I may be able to pass on
my jutsu to you.
The one-of-a-kind jutsu of
Kakashi the Copy ninja.
Lee, you have visitors.
Two cute young ladies...
Oh?!
- Huh?!
Really...even Lee!
Lee! Lee!
Lee...
Huh?
Look!
200 one armed pushups...
If I can't do them,
100 one legged squats...
190...!
Lee! Stop it!
191...
Lee!
Please don't touch me!
Don't...interfere...
with my training...
I need two...
Why? One is fine.
No...One for Lee too...
Speaking of which, Sakura,
did you hear about Lee?
What? Hear what?
Well, Lee...
his injuries were serious and
he can no longer...
continue as a shinobi.
195...
196...
197...
198...
I'm...not finished...yet!
There's no value in making
an effort for someone
who doesn't believe in himself!
One...one hundred...ninety...nine...
One...One more...
One more time...!
- Huh?!
- Oh!
Lee!
I'll...go get the stretcher.
Please keep an eye on him.
Yes.
Why do boys...
have to push themselves?
Who brought that...?
Today, we'll have
a history lesson outside.
As you know, this rock face has
the faces of the Hokage line.
In order from the left,
they're lined up fom the First,
the Second...
the Third...and the Fourth.
So different from the present old man.
Especially the receding hairline...
Iruka Sensei! Who's the Fifth?
Hmm?
Well, that hasn't been decided yet...
Perhaps it's your teacher here!
Hmm...Weaving an occasional joke
to make for a relaxing lesson, Iruka?
L-Lord Hokage!
Oh, it's the Third.
Hey! Old man!
What did you come to do?
I wanted to see the rock faces too.
You've come at a good time.
Over this way, my lord.
This is the real man of
the third rock face!
The Third Hokage!
You all are quite young,
unlike me!
There might be someone who will
take the name of Hokage is in this group.
You only have one life!
Don't choose an impossible road.
It doesn't matter if you live as
you like and die as you like.
However...
no matter what route you take,
remember to protect the
people important to you!
Important people?
That you acknowledge...
trust and love from your heart.
Do you have people like that?
Y-Yeah...Dad and Mom...
and I hate him a little,
but my big brother too.
And...
my dog Gonta...
For me, it's friends!
Me too!
Lord Hokage, you have
people like that too?
Yes, of course I do!
Really! Who, who?
I have my grandchild...
Konohamaru over there and...
All of the people in this village!
Like you did too, once...
C'mon, open your eyes already.
W-What's that...?
To be clear, you have no sense.
Oh! Pervy Sage!
After you've been training for 3 weeks,
you are still this level.
If you continue like this it's pointless.
That's not how it is!
I'm doing this with all my might!
I understand that, if you really want
to succeed at Summoning Jutsu,
you have to do it like you're going
to die or it's no good at all.
That's what I'm doing!
I drill my chakra every day
like I'm going to die.
If you have time to complain about it,
teach me a trick or something!
A trick, huh...A trick.
What?! You're going to teach me?
You need to risk your life on it.
L-Life?
It's not a joke.
Even so, will you do it?
O-Of course!
I always risk my life!
I see...
Huh?
Well then, follow me.
Hey, if I do this I'll really get a frog
Yes, that's a definite.
Really?
Is there anything you've left undone?
Huh?
None?
What are you talking about...?
To pull out enormous chakra
and use it.
It is certain that it is difficult
to have the control to do it...
It is also certain that this body
is a vessel too small
to absorb the Nine-Tailed Fox's chakra...
It's likely that Naruto's body normally
tends to reject
the strength of the Nine-Tailed Fox
in order to avoid too much strain.
If the excitement of danger and
emotion are the key
to drawing out the
Nine-Tailed Fox's chakra...
he has to learn physically until
he can automatically use that key.
Nothing personal...
Fourth Hokage!
Huh? Where...is this?
Stand up!
W-What's going on?!
Your training ends here.
Huh? I haven't done anything yet...!
Naruto!
Go die and come back.
Die?
From within the dreadfulness of death,
squeeze out enormous chakra!
Experience it with your own body,
and grasp the technique of it!
If you don't want to die,
do something about it yourself...Got it?
Now...we'll see if the strength given
to you is really yours.
If I don't grab onto this...I'll die!
Now!
It's impossible...
This rock surface is slippery
from the seepage of the waterfall.
Besides, falling in that speed
with the control of chakra that you have,
you can't cling to the rock.
Naruto, after this...
you can only depend on
the chakra of the Nine-Tailed Fox.
Open up the key...
This time from your side!
If I go on like this!
If I go on like this! I'll seriously die!
Die...
Huh?!
This feeling...It's that chakra...
This is...
I-It's huge...What is it?
Hey kid, come closer!
I want to eat and kill you,
but this gate won't open...
Bloody seal...
You're...
the Nine-Tailed Fox!
I see...the red chakra
was this guy's chakra.
For you to approach me...
What business brought you here?
Hey! You stupid fox!
Since you're staying in my body,
as your rent, lend me your chakra!
After all, if you die I die.
That's some impressive courage
for threatening me!
That's fine...
As a reward for making it this far...
I'll give it to you!
This is the feeling!
Summoning Jutsu!
Well done.
Where am I?!
I've been saved.
Oh?
Awesome...He's pretty darn big...
Oh yeah...
This is a...frog...isn't it...?
Oopsadaisy...
Let's see now...
No tail!
This is...!
Not like this one.
Or that one.
It's really...
A real...
Frog!
Looks like he extracted the
chakra of the Nine-Tailed Fox
all on his own this time.
But still, one certainly can't
say he's stable yet...
He overused the large charka...
To think that of all the frogs
he summoned that one...
You little brat...
On whose head do you think
you're raising a ruckus!
This is the top of Gamabunta,
the Chief Toad's head! You idiot!
Quiet down...
Oh!
W-What the heck is this guy?!
He seems pretty awesome, but...
Gimme a break!
Just when I'm breathing the air of
the free world after a long time,
some weird kid is raising
a ruckus on top of my head.
Hey! Jiraiya! Where are you?!
What the heck do
you think you're doing?!
Hmm...This doesn't look good...
'Cause even I can't handle
that Gamabunta...
Jiraiya! Hurry up and
show yourself, you idiot!
Hmmm...It would be troublesome if
Gamabunta found me out...
I better get my ass out of here
without any further delay.
Hey, little brat!
Y-Yes...?
Where's Jiraiya?
Huh? Jiraiya?
Who's that...?
I'm talking about that lecher who
calls himself Toad Sage or something!
Where's Jiraiya? Huh?!
S-Scary...
If you just follow my orders,
I wouldn't mind making you
my henchman!
Hurry up and answer me!
Okay! If you're talking about
the Pervy Sage
he's on the cliff up there,
Chief Toad.
Up there, huh...?
Um...Can I ask you one question?
What is it?
What business do you have
with that Pervy Sage?
That's the question I want
to ask that pervert!
What the heck does he want
summoning me to a place like this?!
B-But...
What is it?
I'm the one who summoned
you, Chief Toad...
I fell off the cliff...
and thought maybe you
could come to my aid...
Please...
Hmm?
There's no way a little squirt like
you could summon a guy like me.
It's...it's true...
I really truly summoned you...
Believe it!
You jerk frog!
Huh?
You've been condescending to me
and saying whatever you
please since earlier on!
Since I summoned you,
I'm your master!
Huh? What was that?
Hey, who do you think
you're talking to?!
A little squirt like you,
who isn't even able to exchange cups
of sake as a pledge of friendship,
is saying to Lord Gamabunta,
that you're his master?
I could kill you for that! Hey!
Huh...
Oohhh...
It looks like he emerged on top,
that Gamabunta...
Awesome...
I hate to tell you this, little brat,
but even if I were to concede
a hundred steps to you...
No, concede a thousand steps to you,
and even if it really was true that
it was you who summoned me...
If you're the kind of guy who
falls off my back that easily,
there's no way I could
admit you as my master...
Huh?! Huh?!
Now then...I'm here in the
free world after a long time...
If Jiraiya doesn't have
any business with me,
I think I'll kick back for a while.
Hey! Wait!
Why don't you just go home
and sleep or something?
'Cause it looks like you're incapable
of serving even as my henchman.
Damn it!
W-What the heck do you think
you're doing, you little brat?
If my making you recognize that
I summoned you
depends on my not falling
off your back, then...!
Then I won't get off your back
the entire day today no matter what!
What?!
And by my doing that I'll make
you recognize me as your master!
You little brat! Don't get all carried away
thinking I'll go easy on you!
Huh?!
Fall!
Chakra adhesion!
There's not enough chakra!
Listen carefully, Chief Toad!
My name is Naruto Uzumaki!
I'm a man who will become Hokage
in the future. Don't forget that!
Who cares!
Welcome!
I'm gonna eat my fill!
Huh...Those guys are
eathing barbecue again, huh?
A reward for having trained
earnestly...maybe?
I thought you were told not to
let Gaara out of your sight...
Don't worry...
even somebody like him...
wouldn't dare to do anything
in broad daylight.
More importantly,
that guy Shikamaru or whatever,
he's the first guy
you're fighting, right?
Shouldn't you be formulating
a battle plan?
Humph...There's no way I would
lose to a guy of that level...
Besides...
You botched it, didn't you?
Huh?
If you had taken the exam
one year earlier,
you would have made chunin easily...
Don't say it...
What was that?!
The upcoming Chunin Exam...
I'll have the three of you take the exam..
But the reason for doing that
is not to pass the Chunin Exam!
It is to use the opportunity
of the Chunin Exam...
to crush Leaf Village!
But why? Don't we have
a treaty with Leaf Village?!
That treaty is the problem.
Oh.
What do you mean?
You genin are not aware of
the details but...
At the time the treaty was concluded,
that idiot feudal lord of Land of Wind
not only aggressively scaled down
the arsenal of
the Hidden Sand Village...
he delegated to the Leaf matters that
should have been handled by our country,
significantly cut our country's budget
and slashed the number of shinobi.
When we have an idiot leader,
we, the arms and legs
of the country, suffer.
The only choice we had left
was to improve the quality
of each and every shinobi in order
to maintain our country's military power...
That's why shinobi like
you were created...
Gaara...
The Land of Wind's security is
in extreme danger right now!
But the aides
of that idiot feudal lord...
don't have a clue!
Lord Kazekage detected the
weakening in our military strength,
joined hands with
the Hidden Sound Village
and decided to take down
the Hidden Leaf Village...
In addition to restoring the Sand
Village's authority...
this needs to be done in order
to make that idiot feudal lord
aware of the importance of
crisis preparedness...
If any more time passes,
our Sand Village will totally lose
its military capabilities
against the Leaf Village...
Now is the only chance...
The success of that mission,
Gaara, depends on your work...
Yeah...
This is a super A-rank mission.
See it through with great care!
Okay.
Yes...
A day sure is long when
one's not doing anything.
I guess...
Good work, Baki.
Lord Kazekage, I successfully
moved all three pawns
to the real battle as planned.
The agreement with the Sound Village side
has been progressing with no problem too.
Yes, sir.
This is...
A decisive action plan from
the Sound Village
You still have something you want?
Well...
What is it? Come out with it.
Yes, sir...I was wondering if you
could position some soldiers
near the border on the pretext of
undertaking a tactical exercise.
With only the four of us...
The Leaf Village aren't idiots either.
Their ANBU black ops
are moving about.
If we do that, they will see right
through what we're contemplating.
But with only our current
military capability...
That's why I sent Gaara and
the others out there.
The restoration of the authority of
the Hidden Sand Village is resting on you.
Well...Go.
Yes, sir.
How do you like that, Gamabunta?
I'm still on your back!
It's my victory!
Oh no! If he falls like that he'll die!
Too bad for you...You almost made it.
To think that he could hold out like that
against a tough opponent like Gamabunta...
Hm?!
That, Jiraiya, meddling in...
I am fully aware of the fact that...
this guy here summoned
me all on his own.
I mean, it's the first time since
the Fourth Hokage
that somebody climbed on my head.
As might be expected,
he must be totally drained.
I don't mind dispensing some
of my power to him but...
Taking him to a place of healing
would be best.
Huh? What!
Yo!
You finally woke up, eh?
Where...am I?
In the hospital!
They told me that you've been
sound asleep for 3 days and 3 nights!
Three days...
It's such a drag but...
I bought this fruit basket as
a get well present for Choji.
But the doctor said he couldn't have it.
So let's eat it together.
Choji? Is he that sick?
No, no, don't be fooled.
He got sick from eating
too much BBQ.
That's just like him!
Yeah well, and neither of you are the type
to have female visitors.
So here...
Looks good.
W-What is it?
Since Choji can't have any,
let's eat in front of him.
What a drag this guy is!
Why...save him?
He's an important subordinate
whom I care for.
I'm still hungry!
Are you harassing me, Shikamaru?
My body...isn't moving.
You jerk!
What the hell do you think
you're doing?!
Hey Naruto...
During Shadow Possession Jutsu,
it's moving me too! Okay?!
Sorry! Shikamaru.
Choji, are you better?
Oh, Ino!
All right! The age of
the chubby has arrived!
What were you trying to do
to Bushy Brow here?!
I was trying to kill him.
What?!
How can he be so calm?
Especially when he is not able to
move with my Shadow Possession Jutsu...
Why'd you have to do something
like that?
You beat him in the match, right?
Do you have a personal grudge
against him or something?
I just wanted to kill him, that's it.
How can you say something
so selfish, you bastard?!
You...you had a lousy upbringing,
didn't you?
All you care about is yourself.
There's something weird about him.
It gives me the chills!
If he tries anything, it'll be too much
of a burden for me and Naruto...
What the heck should we do?
If you get in my way,
I'll kill you both too.
What?! Go ahead, if you can!
Hey Naruto, hold on!
Should I try to scare him with a bluff?
I know you're strong from seeing you
in the competition with him...
But...we can keep up with you.
We didn't show you our best skills
in the preliminaries.
And it's two against one!
You're the one who's at a disadvantage.
If you're smart, you'll do what
I tell you and just get lost.
I'll say it again...
if you get in my way...
I'll kill you.
Where the heck do you get off...?!
There's no way in hell
I'll let you do that!
I've been telling you
to back off, haven't I?
This guy has the strength of a monster.
You get it, don't you?
I have a real monster in me!
I'm not going to lose to this guy!
What's worth making him mad,
you idiot!
A monster, huh...?
Me too, actually.
It's just like you said.
I had a terrible upbringing.
When I came into this world,
I took the life of the woman
some might call my mother.
So that I could become
the strongest shinobi...
my father brought his
ninjutsu upon me,
and so I became possessed
by a Sand Spirit.
I was born a monster.
Is it possible...that there could be
something inside him too?
What a thing for a parent to be doing!
Such a twisted kind of love.
Love?
Don't measure me by your standards.
Family, huh...
Let me tell you what kind of ties
I have to my family.
They're ties of hatred,
ties of murderous intent...
My family's just lumps of flesh.
Nourished with the life of my mother,
I was crafted as the
ultimate weapon of the village...
The Kazekage's child.
I was taught by my father
the innermost secrets of the shinobi...
spoiled, over protected,
and left on my own.
And I thought that was love...
Those who are too strong are
apt to become feared.
Born through the jutsu,
my mind was unstable...
I guess the idiots in my village
finally realized that
I had emotional problems...
For my father, Kazekage
at the same time I was
the ultimate weapon for the village
I was also a dangerous,
fearsome presence.
It seems I was labeled a dangerous figure
as soon as I turned six.
And I was treated politely simply because
I was feared.
To them, now I'm just a relic of the past
that they want to see disappear.
So what did I have in this life,
why did I keep living?
When I asked myself that,
I couldn't find the answer.
But, as long as you're alive,
you need a reason...
If you don't have one,
it's just the same as being dead.
What's this guy saying?
I...can understand that...
He...is the same as me.
So this is the answer I came to...
I am living in order to kill
human beings other than myself.
After living in the fear of never knowing
when I might be murdered,
finally I became calm.
By killing assassins, I finally
comprehended the reason why I live...
I live fighting for only myself
and loving myself...
And if I see that all other people
in this world exist
only to make me realize that,
there could be no world
more wonderful.
And as long as there are
others to kill
who can make me feel
this happiness to be alive,
I will never disappear.
W-What's this freak talking about...?
He's real gone!
I was also alone...
And suffered'cause
I didn't know why I was alive...
But Iruka Sensei recognized me
for who I was...
and that was the first time
I realized why I lived...
But this guy...
this guy grew up alone.
And he ony feels alive
when he kills other people.
H-How can there be someone like this?
The worlds we live in
are too different...!
There's no way...
that I can beat a guy like this!
What? Shadow Possession Jutsu should
have stopped him from moving, but...
Naruto!
Naruto! Hey, get yourself together!
What a drag this guy is!
Naruto!
Now, let me feel it...!
Oh no!
Stop right there!
Tomorrow's the final round!
There's no need to rush like this!
Don't leave me alone!
I'm not bleeding, but
it hurts a lot right here.
What...am I?!
I will...kill you all without a fail.