Just my bad luck...
to have lookout duty
on a day like this.
I wanted to watch Chunin Exam too.
Stop fussing.
The Chunin Exam takes
place twice a year.
You'll have many more chances
to see it.
But this year, that kid from
the Uchiha Clan is taking part, right?
And I won't have
a chance to see that...
I won't be able to die peacefully.
What's that?!
Huge boa!
Notify Lord Hokage immediately!
I'm not letting you in the village!
Dispatch reinforcements immediately!
Yes sir!
Sand ninja!
- Start the operation!
Lord Hokage!
Leave it to me!
Gaara!
Squad One, above.
Squad Two, below!
Protect the lords!
You're in the way!
It's finally our time to
come on the scene.
We've been transformed
such a long time.
I'm totally pent up with frustration.
You guys smell all sweaty!
Come on, we're all comrades, right...?
Sound ninja...!
Raido...
We're heading out to
back up Lord Hokage.
Be careful of any traps!
Do it...
Yes sir!
- Ninja Art:
- Four Flames Formation!
Barrier!
Lord Kazekage...
Barrier ninjutsu, huh?!
To think that they could outwit ANBU...
They're not just ordinary...
What are you doing here?!
Lord Hokage is in danger!
What a nuisance...
To think that the enemy was
masquerading as our ANBU...
So it was also that guy
who used genjutsu!
Yeah...there's no mistake.
What's going on?
Stop that, Gaara!
I'll kill him...!
There's no meaning in
continuing this fight!
Don't forget our mission!
Out of my way...!
What are you guys doing?!
The operation is already underway!
What in the world is going on?
Gaara!
What's the matter?!
His wound is deeper than
I thought!
And moreover his chakra
is pretty drained!
Idiot! It's all because
you didn't wait for the signal
and tried to undergo
a Perfect Possession...
What should we do?!
Are you saying we have to do
this without Gaara?
You guys leave for the moment and
tend to Gaara's wounds!
As soon as Gaara's chakra has
been restored...
the operation will recommence!
Got it!
What about you, Sensei?!
I'm gonna suppress those guys!
Is Orochimaru the host of this party?
Dunno...In any case,
let's heat this thing up.
Sasuke...
Sorry, but the Chunin Exam ends here.
You've already achieved chunin level.
If you're a Leaf shinobi,
be of service to the Leaf!
In other words, I'm supposed to
take down that jerk Gaara, right?
A continuation of earlier on, right?
Don't pursue too far.
From here on, it's no longer an exam.
It's the real thing!
What I have to do though...
is the same!
I won't let him through!
Sasuke...!
Boy oh boy...
We intended to take Sasuke
while Gaara was causing the trouble.
But not everything goes as planned.
I see...Is that so?
So Leaf Village and...
Sasuke were the target, huh?
Is the Leaf such a big catch?
More importantly,
if Gaara comes back,
I'll be able to show you something
much more interesting.
Well, anyway...
Your thick-headedness has caused
the Leaf to be outmaneuvered.
It's my win.
Nothing is decided
until the very end.
I believe that's what I taught you...
Orochimaru.
I thought this day would
eventually arrive.
However...
You won't get my head that easily!
I told you, didn't I?
You should have
named a Fifth Hokage...
Third Hokage...
because you will...die here.
That Orochimaru...
What should we do?
Should we send reinforcements?
No...It's dangerous to make a move
when we don't really know
what the situation is.
If the mastermind is Orochimaru...
even more so.
Is Orochimaru...
that dangerous a guy?
Long ago, when I was a kid...
there's one thing I remember
thinking when I saw that guy...
That he didn't seem human...
That he seems to be something
that just took on a human form...
Frightening...
Simply...frightening.
Reporting
A large boa has appeared near
the eastern gate of the Leaf Village!
And behind it, about one hundred
Sand ninja are infiltrating the country!
They are currently engaged in
armed conflict with our shinobi
who were patrolling nearby!
Leave Squad One and Two behind
and make for the eastern gate.
Immediately!
- Yes sir!
We won't let you past this point!
There's quite a large number.
We were careless!
And even Lord Hokage has been...
Kakashi! Look inside the Barrier!
Yeah.
What...?
Orochimaru!
Orochimaru?!
Why is that guy...?
Don't tell me that
they're after Sasuke again?!
Sasuke!
Huh?
He's not there...?
Sakura, stay there for a while.
I'm gonna go reduce
the number of enemies.
Damn! I'm worried about
Lord Hokage, but...
Leave it to the ANBU.
Besides...
Lord Hokage isn't the kind of guy
who can be taken down that easily.
But...
After all, he is the Hokage
of the Village Hidden in the Leaves.
Are you so happy, you're crying?
Or...
do you have an iota of sadness
in your heart to kill me, your teacher?
Since earlier on, I was feeling so sleepy.
but I'm finally awake.
That's what I thought.
I know you aren't someone
who would hold a grudge.
You have neither a goal nor motive.
Hmm...I guess...
I do kind of have a goal.
If I were to explain it...
It's interesting to watch things
that move.
I get no pleasure if
something doesn't move.
Like a windmill that doesn't turn...
Well, it may have some kind
of appeal once in a while.
But usually,
it's not worth looking at it.
Right now...with a wind called
"Destroy the Leaf Village"
I want to turn that windmill.
You're the same as always...
Sakura!
It was worth teaching you
genjutsu survival training
during the genin Exam.
You truly have a talent for it.
Huh?
Release the genjutsu and
wake up Naruto and Shikamaru!
Naruto will be delighted.
He'll be getting a mission
after such a long while.
What do you mean by a mission?
Be careful...
It's the first A-ranked mission
since the Land of the Waves.
I feel uneasy...
about that unusual chakra.
But then,
we should wake up Ino and Choji
and go in a large group.
There may already
be quite a large number
of Sand and Sound shinobi
who have infiltrated this village.
Actions lose quickness when there's more
than the fundamental four in a squad...
and it becomes difficult to
hide from the enemy.
You learned that in the Academy's
patrol practical training, right?
Oh, I see! Then four means
that you'll come with us...
No, I must not leave here.
Summoning Jutsu!
Pakkun here will
track down Sasuke by scent!
C-Could it be...
the fourth member is this puppy?!
Hey! Little girl!
Don't you be calling me a cute puppy!
I didn't say...cute.
Okay, Sakura! Release the genjutsu
on Naruto and Shikamaru!
Okay!
Release!
What is it...Sakura?
Get down!
I'll tell you later!
Just stay down!
Shikamaru...you were...
from the beginning...
Owwee!
You were able to release genjutsu, too!
Why were you pretending
to be asleep?!
Hmph! I don't want to
end up getting involved!
Heck no...
I could care less about Sasuke!
Owwee!
W-What's going on...?
Naruto! Behind you!
F-Fast...
Not just fast...
Guy Sensei!
Now, I'll announce the mission!
As soon as you've heard what
the mission is, go through that hole.
Track down Sasuke,
join up and then stop him!
Then await next orders
in a safe place.
Huh? Did something happen
to Sasuke?!
I'll tell you the reason en route!
Let's go
Jeez...Why me?
Hey, boy!
Huh?
If this mission is a success,
as a reward I'll let you
touch my paw-pads.
So don't sulk like that!
Huh?
See?
They're soft and supple!
Su...pple...?
Yes, very...
Soft and Supple!
Let's just go!
H-Hey!
Will it be okay with just them?
They'll be okay.
Pakkun is with them.
As long as they don't pursue too far...
This barrier can't be broken
unless it's from the inside.
If Lord Hokage would just
take out one of those four,
we could help...
Put up a barrier on the inside, too!
Hm...It doesn't look like
I'll be able to get out this easily.
You don't really mean that.
It'd be tougher for you if someone
came in and got in the way, right?
Something's strange...
All of the Academy's classes
doing self study.
And that smoke...
That's coming from the direction
of the exam arena.
Isn't there some disturbance
to the East?
I wonder if something happened...
This is definitely strange!
But sudden self study is
sure a smack in the eye!
It's been like this for awhile!
Yeah. Iruka Sensei
and everyone are late...
Aren't they, Konohamaru?
There is information that several units
have already infiltrated the village...!
We should evacuate the students
to a safe place right away!
Yes...And without causing panic
among the students!
Then let's evacuate the students
as soon as possible under
the pretense of an evacuation drill!
Did you foresee your final moments?
I won't go easy on you
just because you're doddering.
I look forward to it.
Depending on your jutsu,
I might have you
start over at the Academy!
Please don't disappoint me too much!
Shuriken Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Summoning Jutsu: Edo Tensei!
One!
He is using a Summoning Jutsu
as a shield.
And this dead person is...
Two!
I must stop the third one at any cost...!
Three!
It looks like the third one was no good.
Oh well...
I-It can't be!
Those personages are...!
Those personages are?
Now, what will you do,
Sarutobi Sensei...?
No...
Long time no see...Saru.
Oh, it's you...
You've gotten old, Sarutobi.
I never thought I would meet
the great brothers in this manner...
Please prepare yourselves...
Lord First Hokage...
Lord Second Hokage!
Edo Tensei, huh?
This youth summoned us with
the Forbidden Jutsu, then?
He's something else...
Then, Sarutobi!
Does this mean we must...fight you?
Let's stop the old people
get together talk...
Shall we get started?
There's always fighting...
no matter when you live.
You like that, don't you?
No good will come by degrading the dead
and playing around with time!
I get it! So that's what happened!
That Sasuke, getting all impatient!
So, why am I pulled into this?
This is such a drag!
It can't be helped!
It's Kakashi Sensei's order.
This way!
How long will it be until
we catch up?
I don't know.
He is moving at a pretty good speed.
Dang it!
Hey! Hurry it up, you guys.
Huh? What is it?
Did you find Sasuke?
No!
There are eight people in
two squads behind us...
No...
There's one more...
There are nine people following us.
What?!
C'mon. Already?!
Give me a break!
They're probably all
chunin or higher.
We'll be wiped out
if they catch up.
Wiped out...
Damn it! Since it's come to this,
why don't we ambush them?!
Ambush?
Right.
Indeed, an ambush would
be to our advantage.
Even if the opponent has twice
the people than we do,
if we just catch them off guard...
That's no good.
Our opponents are henchmen
of the former Leaf shinobi, Orochimaru.
In the worst case scenario,
there might be jonin.
I thought it'd work,
but I guess not, huh.
Hold it. Why?
The level of opponent doesn't have
much to do with an ambush.
You guys don't get it.
Listen. Indeed, an ambush is
a very advantageous fundamental tactic.
But two conditions are necessary.
Number one.
The ones on the run must act without
making noise and find the enemy first.
Number two.
One must be able to catch
the pursuers off guard,
capture a point and position
to be able to inflict certain damage
and conceal oneself quickly.
An ambush only becomes effective
when these two conditions are ensured.
Well, the first condition
won't be so difficult
since we have the ninja Hound's nose.
And the second one also
seems advantageous at a glance
since we know the geography
of our village.
Our pursuers must have been instructed
in the terrain of this village
and have gone through
simulated practice for this fight.
And on top of that,
they're probably all ninja
who have mastered the pursuit arts.
So they know what cards we have, huh.
Well, even so, the fact remains
that an ambush is advantageous.
But there are too many elements
of uncertainty.
For starters, the enemy is a
special unit organized for this operation.
While we have...
a fool...
a Kunoichi who's nothing special...
a dog...
and me, the number one slacker!
A tactic is grasping the conditions
that are there without fail
and formulating an optimal plan.
And so, there's only one thing
that we can do now...
One?
A diversion in the guise
of an ambush.
One person will remain,
pretend to ambush,
and delay the pursuers.
If we do that, we'll be able
to shake off our pursuers,
but the one who becomes
the bait will probably...
Die.
So, who's going to do it?
We need the dog to follow Sasuke.
That means...
Fine...
- I'll...
- I guess it has to be me.
Shikamaru?!
W-Why you?!
It's better than
being wiped out, right?
Besides, among us,
the only one who is
best suited to playing the bait
and who has the
best chance of surviving...
is me.
Shadow Possession Jutsu was originally
created as a delay tactic, so...
Well, I'll catch up later!
Now get going
We're counting on you, Shikamaru!
Was Shikamaru ever this reliable
of a character?
Their strides are irregular.
Urgency is probably increasing
their fatigue.
Sorry about that.
I was supposed to be the guy
with the number one cold feet.
It seems my character has
changed just a bit this time.
The fact that I'm tired is true.
Those footprints are wrong.
By the way, this is what
the dog's paw print really is.
Oh, he's still a kid.
To think we'd all get caught like this.
So this is the rumored Leaf Village's
Shadow Paralysis Jutsu, huh?
Huh?
That's an old way of saying it!
The times are changing!
It's called the
Shadow Possession Jutsu now, old man.
1, 2, 3, 4...
5, 6, 7...8.
Eight people...
Eight...No, there's one more...
There are nine people following us.
Sure enough, the ninth person's role
is to protect against an ambush.
That person
stays at a fixed distance,
moves in the back and responds
to an enemy attack.
But...this will make clear where
that person's hiding!
There, huh?!
Dang...The Shadow won't reach.
I don't have the stamina to
send it further with chakra.
It looks like you're at your limit...
This Shadow Possession Jutsu
is going to break very soon.
Prepare yourself!
I wanted to...
become a ninja any which way,
save up money any which way,
get married any which way to
an ordinary woman
who's neither beautiful, nor ugly
and have two kids any which way.
First would be a girl,
and then a boy...
I would retire from being a ninja
when my daughter married
and my son became
a full fledged man.
And then I'd take it easy
in my life of retirement
playing Japanese chess
and Go the whole day.
Then I'd die of old age
before my wife.
Such a life would've been nice.
This was such a drag...
As you said,
it seems I'm at my limit.
Hey, come on out.
While you're at it, cut off his head.
I finally caught up.
A-Asuma?! Why?
Well done, Shikamaru.
Sure enough, out of character.
For the time being, you retire here.
So what's up, Temari?
He's close.
He's just right there.
Damn it! What should we do?
Leave it to me.
That was close.
What was that noise?
An explosion...
Perhaps it was a trap set for Sasuke.
I wonder if he's okay.
Don't worry...
He wouldn't get bumped off so easily.
Now then, shall we get started?
Before that, I must have you both
return to your original forms.
Please prepare yourself,
Sarutobi Sensei.
With every moment,
they are looking more lively...
What is that...jutsu?
Edo Tensei.
It's a Forbidden Summoning Jutsu that
can bring the dead back to this world.
The cost of a regular Summoning Jutsu
is the blood of the caster.
But I've heard that with this jutsu,
in order to summon
a dead soul to this world...
the body of a living person is
sacrificed as a container for the soul.
Perhaps dust and dirt cover
the sacrificial body
and take on the original form
of the summoned soul.
And by way of the charm
embedded in the head,
the personality of the soul is killed
and it morphs into no more
than a killing puppet.
They're complete.
They look like how they used
to look more than ever.
Do you know the joy and sense
of accomplishment
of hurting one whom
you once called Sensei?
I prepared this scenario
so that you might know that joy.
So please enjoy it.
Lord Hokage!
Even if the shape and form
are the same...
they're neither the First Hokage
nor the Second!
I...know!
Here I go!
Fire Style: Dragon Flame Bombs.
True to the title
of the previous Hokage.
Water Style: Water Shock Wave!
Earth Style: Mud Wall.
Same mighty strength as always.
Having two of you is quite a challenge,
as might be expected...
This is bad.
This is the
Hidden jutsu of the First Hokage.
Hidden Wood Style Jutsu:
Deep Forest Emergence.
You're finally caught...
eh, Sensei.
Okay. Everyone's here, right?
Okay everyone,
let's evacuate quickly.
Don't rush and don't panic!
What's the matter, Konohamaru?
Does your stomach hurt or something?
No...it's not that.
Ninja Art: Summoning Jutsu!
Appear!
Monkey King Enma.
Hmph...
Something pesky has appeared, eh?
Old Monkey Enma.
Orochimaru...
I knew this would happen.
You're pathetic, Sarutobi...
If you had just killed him back then.
I'm going to do it now!
It's too late.
Please...Enma!
The Adamantine Nyoi.
Take care of him.
Don't let him transform into that!
Okay...Got it!
Transform!
All right.
Wow...The level of ninjutsu here!
So this is Hokage level combat!
Oh well...
Things have finally gotten interesting.
That's one of his Snake Swords.
Let's do it, Enma!
No matter how strong the body,
the Snake Sword still hurts.
You're mine!
So foolish...
To think you'd strike without even
using the Shadow Clone Jutsu.
Are you okay, Sensei?
Please hang in there.
You are called...
"the Professor" who knows all of
the jutsu in the Leaf Village, right?
Please don't disappoint me too much.
Lord Hokage!
Fool...It is too late.
You...fool!
Orochimaru...
This is the end.
I'll snap your neck.
As I thought...
It looks like there's no point if
I don't do something about the soul itself
that is bound by Edo Tensei.
If so, all I can do is to use...
the Fourth Hokage's jutsu...
Lord First Hokage, Lord Second Hokage,
please forgive me for using this jutsu!
Sensei...it seems you're out of breath.
You've gotten old, haven't you?
I've never seen such a pained look.
What's so funny?
It's quite sad...
Old age beats even you,
once renowned as the god of shinobi.
What's that?!
What the heck is going on?
Who the heck is that youth?
Who on earth are you?!
Is it so sudden you can't tell?
It's me. Orochimaru.
It can't be...Have you completed
your Forbidden jutsu?
I struggled for decades...
after leaving the village.
You're a truly frightening,
inhuman monster!
So, he did it, huh...?
The reason I couldn't select you
to be the Fourth Hokage...
is because of that distorted
consciousness.
I've finally been found out, eh...?
It's too bad.
Orochimaru...
What's the meaning of this?!
Here I'd set that
many booby traps...
so I was quite surprised.
But I see...So it was you.
Recently, there has been a steady stream
of people going missing from the village,
from genin to chunin,
and even ANBU Black Ops members.
There were also tips that
you had been acting strange...
Master Orochimaru...
Why did a shinobi of your rank
do such a thing?
Shall I kill you, too?
Orochimaru! Sure enough,
this was your doing...?
Say it! What were you doing here?!
Alas! I've been found out.
There's no point in acting cute...
It's for jutsu development!
As I thought, Forbidden jutsu, eh...
What is it that you want?
Learn every jutsu and understand
all of the truths of this world!
The one who first mixed
blue and yellow
named the new color made
in that way, green.
I just want to do the same thing.
If blue is chakra, yellow is a sign...
and green is a jutsu.
In the same way that there
are no limits to the kinds of colors,
there are probably also tens
of thousands of jutsu in this world...
But in order to
learn all of the jutsu...
as well as the truths,
a long time is necessary.
It's the one who takes those
long years to know everything,
who can suitably be called
the ultimate individual.
For me, the life span of
the body is too short.
Too fleeting.
Even if I were to be called the Hokage,
if I die, it all ends there.
Orochimaru...Could it be that
the jutsu you're testing here is...
Right...It sure could be...
Immortality Jutsu!
Immortality Jutsu is a technique of
eternally pooling one's own
spirits into this earth...
In other words,
it's a revival jutsu where...
you find a new body, put your own spirit
into that body and take it over.
I assumed my old form until now,
so that you would feel nostalgic
about our reunion...
Aging is an empty thing, isn't it?
I feel that keenly when I look at you.
You'll die here...
and I'll get a younger,
more beautiful, and stronger body...
The Leaf truly lets me
have my fill of fun...
I get it...
You want Sasuke Uchiha, eh?!
Right...Exactly...Sasuke.
A reviving jutsu where
someone else's body is stolen
and the spirit is immortalized, huh?
How many faces and bodies
have you gone through?!
Two, I think...
I plan to take Sasuke over after
raising him a little more to my liking.
But after all, in order to
make you regret your very own life...
and curse destiny as you die...
...perhaps this face is better?
You monster!
Lord Hokage!
Don't lower your guard, Sensei!
You're always too soft...
What's been wrong with you?
This isn't like you!
I'm sorry...
Are you going to...kill me?
Summoning Jutsu!
I wonder if you can...
Sarutobi Sensei!
Kill him, Sarutobi!
Now's your only chance!
Sarutobi...You...
I couldn't kill him...
I'll bury you and correct
my old mistakes, now!
Here I go!
It's too late!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
No way!
Why the Shadow Clone Jutsu?!
To disperse the little chakra
he has left...!
You've gotten old, after all...
To think you'd shorten your
own life span out of impatience...
D-Don't tell me, you?!
Mi, I, Hitsuji, U, Inu, Ne, Tori, Uma, Mi.
This order of Signs...
I knew it, Sarutobi,
you are using that jutsu!
So this is the Grim Reaper
the Fourth Hokage was talking about,
which only the one who has signed
a contract with this jutsu can see, eh?!
Whatever you do now, it's too late...
I've won.
The Leaf Village will crumble!
The Village Hidden in the Leaves
is the home where I live.
The Hokage exists as the pillar
to protect that home!
The Hokage is the one who inherits
and is entrusted the will of the Leaf.
I won't go easily!
Genjutsu! Infinite Darkness Jutsu!
Stupid nonsense...
You're merely a temporal head
in the history of the organization
called the Leaf Village...
Even the face rock that is left
will eventually weather and decay.
Hmph...the Leaf Village is
not just an organization to me!
In the Leaf Village,
every year many shinobi
are born and raised...
and live and fight...
and die to protect the village.
The people of this village...
even if they don't have blood ties...
To me, they are precious...
precious...
family!
Then I shall smash you, the pillar,
and destroy the Leaf.
Hmph! Even if you kill me,
that pillar will not break!
I am the man who carried on the will
of the First and Second Hokage...
The Third Hokage!
No matter how much you target
this Village Hidden in the Leaves...
A new Hokage will carry on my will,
shall become a pillar and defend the Leaf!
Right, Fourth Hokage?
Orochimaru! Now I will perform
a jutsu that even you don't know!
Behold!
Sealing Jutsu: Reaper Death Seal!
Must hurry...
This darkness is dangerous.
I'll have you show it to me.
Please perform that jutsu, quickly.
Not yet...?
It looks like...
I was just in time.
What's the matter?
You're already stumbling...
Now all that's left...
is to catch them!
I got you!
I won't let go!
Appear!
The darkness has disappeared...
What's this jutsu?
I'm sorry...Sarutobi...
We caused you trouble...
Please forgive me...
Lord First Hokage!
Lord Second Hokage!
Seal!
Your own subordinates...!
Toying with even the lives
of your own subordinates...!
The lives of my subordinates?
Stop the endless nonsense!
Come! Enma!
You're mine!
Striking Shadow Snake!
Dang it! You little...!
It's over!
What is this sensation...?
This is bad...
- Die!
Why...didn't you dodge?
There's no need to dodge.
I will die, anyway.
When the sealing ends,
my soul will also be devoured.
It's a jutsu of the hero
who once saved this village.
And now, you will also die...
by this jutsu!
So this jutsu also sealed
the Nine-Tailed Fox., huh?!
Your soul will be dragged out...
and sealed!
My body...
won't listen to what I say!
You'll probably be able to see it soon.
Your soul is already
about halfway out, so...
Those who have their souls sealed
by this jutsu
will suffer inside the belly
of the Grim Reaper for eternity
and will never attain peace...
Those who seal and are sealed
have their souls intertwined,
and will hate each other,
and continue to battle for eternity!
What...?!
This is...the Grim Reaper?!
Knock it off! You old dotard!
I won't let you do as you like!
Hurry up and...die!
I'll get revenge for you
no matter what...
Hayate...
That's the signal. Let's go!
Roger!
We have to hold them off here somehow.
Isn't our backup here yet?!
Ninja Art: Summoning
Bring Down the House Jutsu!
Long time no see, Ibiki.
Jeez, is that body
the only thing that grew?!
I can't stand to look!
Master Jiraiya...
Jiraiya...!
One of the three legendary Sannin?!
Peeps, open up those little eyes
of yours just this once and observe well.
How wonderful!
The devil region beyond heaven
of Jiraiya, the fantastic Toad Sage...
will rage!
Snakes that have been antagonized
by the frog. Begone!
So Orochimaru has finally started, eh?
Where's the Third Hokage?
The Exam arena.
I see...
Don't die...old man.
Okay, everyone. Line up!
Quiet, everyone!
Konohamaru!
Konohamaru, it's not going
to collapse, is it?
It'll...it'll be okay.
The structure of this rock path is old,
but the construction is strong.
My grandpa said so before.
So it'll definitely be okay.
What's this clump of smells
coming from another direction?
Hey! There's something besides us
tracking Sasuke!
What?!
An enemy? An ally?!
I don't know. But...
But?
It's not human.
Huh?!
Temari, you take Gaara
and go on ahead.
What?
You're at your limit...
I don't need a hindrance.
But...!
Go!
Okay...
It can't be helped...
I'll be your opponent!
Hmph! I don't care who it is!
No!
Your opponent is me!
You...!
Shino?
Why are you here?!
I put a female beetle on you
before you left the arena.
The females have almost no smell...
Only a male can sniff out
the subtle smell of the female.
Though the male itself
has a strong smell...
Sasuke Uchiha...
You pursue Gaara.
Because the battle between you
and him hasn't been settled yet.
I'll fight him, because originally
I was his opponent...
You're very confident.
But are you going to be okay?
No need to worry.
I'll go back you up if
I have just ten minutes.
Hmph. I'll be done by then.
None of you know anything at all.
You guys probably don't know
of the real terror of this world.
In that case...
you'll teach me that terror?
No...
If you defeat me and chase Gaara,
you'll be forced to know.
That is, only if you can defeat me.
I'm from the Aburame Clan
of the Leaf Village...
When we fight,
we never underestimate our opponent,
no matter what puny insects
they may be.
I'll advance with full force!
Bring it!
Put me down, Temari.
Can you move, Gaara?
Gaara!
Kankuro is delaying Uchiha now.
We must use this opening...
If we don't get a move on,
the operation will...
Huh?!
Temari, go over there.
What?
Just beat it! You're in the way!
Poison on the blade!
That's...Sasuke Uchiha!
Did he get past Kankuro?!
No...No matter how you look at it,
it's too soon.
Did another assailant come?
I don't know what you Sand ninja
are scheming...
but I'll stop you!
And...
I'll ascertain your true identity!
Gaara!
Don't tell me...!
Is he going to rouse that thing
in a place like this?!
This is no joke...
It's out of my hands.
Stop, Gaara!
Have you forgotten the operation?!
You who are strong...
You who are called Uchiha...
You who have friends...
You who have a purpose...
You who are like...me!
You're...my...
My prey!
It's started...!
You're naive.
All right!
Insects?!
To think you'd make
a clone out of insects and
wrap around behind me...
Not bad!
Your reach encompasses from medium
to long distance and you use a puppet.
I didn't think you would
do well in close combat.
You're very aware of the weakness
of a puppet master!
However, from here on,
I'll show you the essence of
this ninjutsu fighting style!
The real terror of Crow...
my puppet of warfare!
This is poison smoke!
Did I inhale...a little bit?
I get it...
And the caster of the jutsu hides, eh?
Listen, everyone...
Even if enemy shinobi appear,
don't panic.
Go into the hidden room quickly.
Your jonin and chunin Sensei
will protect you all with their lives!
Oh!
Konohamaru...
It'll be okay!
Everyone's doing their best.
They can drive away
the enemies right away.
Cracks in the face rock
of the Hokage...
How ominous...
Now...Let me feel it!
That eye!
That eye...from before!
It doesn't look like this'll be over
by the time you get here...
Shino...
It looks like the poison has
slowly started to circulate.
I'll finish this!
Insects, again?!
But he shouldn't be able to
move in that state...
I'll make things easier for you...
Hey! What's wrong?!
What's happening...?
He stuffed beetles into its joints
so that the puppet couldn't move?
That was his aim from the beginning!
The beetles are passing through
the threads of my chakra...
Why...?
That's it!
As I recall, their food is chakra.
At this rate,
my location will be found out!
He cut the chakra threads himself...?
You got careless!
Instantly reattaching chakra threads
is simple for a first rate puppet master.
It's a big mistake if you think
this has ended...
by simply stopping my movements!
There's lots of poison
on the tip of the needle...
Die!
Just like that, the insects...!
The chakra threads have been
bitten through!
What?! Why...?!
Where did these insects
spring out from?!
By beating away the bait insects
along the chakra threads,
you dropped your guard.
You didn't notice...
the wriggling insects behind you.
The insects were moving
the whole time...
heading for your headband.
W-What did you say?!
The one blow earlier...
I pretended to miss and
stuck one of those beetles on you.
Then, this one beetle on my forehead...
Right...It's a female.
The poison has circulated
through my whole body, huh...
It looks like I won't be able
to back you up...
I'm sorry, Sasuke Uchiha.
No escape!
I won't let you escape!
Sasuke Uchiha!
You've gotta be kidding!
What's with that outrageous strength...?
Are you afraid of me?
It's too overwhelming...
Sasuke Uchiha! Are you afraid?
Are you afraid of my existence?!
Your hatred and intent to kill...
have they given way to fear?
Is that the extent of your existence?!
Fight me...and confirm it!
Your value! Your existence!
Experience it!
If you want an answer...
Come at me!
Now, let me have some fun...
Sasuke Uchiha!
I'll finish it with one blow!
Gaara!
I just realized the reason...
why it's so fun!
This pain...
To take down an opponent
who wounded me...
and thoroughly destroy him...!
That will make me truly feel alive!
Gaara's never had a single wound,
but he got Gaara twice.
Is he...a freak?!
No...the true freak is...
At least the only thing Gaara has
transformed is just his right arm.
More, more!
What?!
What the heck is this guy?!
One after another...
Here goes!
He's even faster!
I can't dodge unless
I read ahead of his movements.
If I didn't have these eyes
I'd have died long ago.
I can no longer use Chidori...
Fire Style: Fire Ball Jutsu!
So the Fire Style doesn't
work against sand...
Not only that,
this level of jutsu won't...
Die!
Apparently...only the Chidori will...
Well! Your limit is two shots.
That's about it...
This is as many Chidori
you can shoot in one day
with your present chakra.
After all, this Chidori is a technique
that can only be used
in conjunction with the Sharingan
during actual battles.
But using the Sharingan and
another jutsu simultaneously means
exploding and using up the chakra
in your body all at once.
Well! But you really are
one of the more impressive ones.
Even with my Chidori...
If I use the Lightning Blade
four times in a day,
I'd completely use up my chakra.
What would happen if I tried
to use more than two shots?
The third shot won't be activated...
Remember this well!
If you try to force a jutsu to activate...
not only will the jutsu
not properly activate,
but your chakra will deplete to zero...
And in the worst case, you'll die!
Even if you were to survive,
absolutely nothing good will come of it.
Especially in your case.
What's the matter?
Does the value of your existence
amount to only this much?
I'll be blunt...
You are...weak!
You're too optimistic.
And it's because your hatred
is weak!
The power of hatred is
the power of the intent to kill!
The power of the intent to kill
is the power of revenge!
Shut up...
Do you understand
the meaning of this?!
Shut up!
That means that you...
You are weaker than me!
Itachi chose me to be the avenger...
to have me kill him!
I am an avenger!
The Curse Mark again...
Damn...! My body...
T-This guy...
Sasuke!
You guys...
T-This...
He probably fought recklessly...
like that time!
Sasuke!
Kakashi Sensei said there was nothing
to worry about with the bruise!
So tell me...Sakura...
Sakura!
What do you want?!
This guy...Who is he?!
His outward appearance
is different, but...
he's that guy called Gaara.
I was born a monster.
So that's what he was saying...
He's the one who hurt Sasuke...
Hey young girl!
I want you to know that
I'm not the fighting type!
I know that just by looking at you!
Sasuke!
I see you're...
the one I failed to kill that time.
L-Let's run! Everyone!
Die! Sasuke Uchiha!
Out of the way!
Sakura!
Why...?
Mommy...
I...
Hey, you're so cool!
Wow!
Can you do food too?
Whoa, grilled squid!
Ramen!
Cherries!
Lobster!
Hmm...Sea urchin and rice bowl!
That's so cool!
Okay then...
How about a big pile of poop?
Can you do it?
Temari...
Kankuro...
Yes!
Gaara...
Temari!
Yes!
Hey, Yashamaru...
I don't get sleepy
even when it's nighttime.
Why is that?
Now, that's a problem.
Normally, when you close your eyes,
you get sleepy.
Really?
Hey...
Why...Why don't I have a mother?
Well...
You have me, Lord Gaara.
Because I am at your side...
...always.
Oh...a boxed lunch?
Yes!
Ready?
Over here!
Power shot!
What're we gonna do?
We don't know any wall-climbing
techniques or anything...
Y-You're...
This...
It's Gaara...
R-Run!
Wait!
Don't leave me alone!
Help me!
I don't...
want to be alone anymore!
Really...
No!
Gaara! Please calm down!
Yashamaru...
It's no use after all...
The sand gets in the way.
Gaara...
Yashamaru!
I may not look it,
but Lord Kazekage charged me
to look after your physical condition
as a member of medical corps
and to be with you.
Please do not do such things
in front of me.
Yashamaru...I'm sorry...
Oh, this.? It's just a scrape.
A scrape...
Is it painful?
A little bit...
But it'll heal in no time.
What is pain?
I've...never once had a wound so...
I wondered what it's like...
Well...
How can I explain it?
It's distressing, or difficult...
In other words, to be hit or cut...
Maybe I should say it's a feeling
of not being able to bear it,
of not being able to stay normal...
I can't say it well,
but I suppose it means a situation
that's not very good.
So...maybe I'm injured too?
The same as everyone?
I'm not bleeding, but...
I've been having a lot of
pain around...here.
Blood does flow from a wound
on the body
and the wound may appear painful.
But as time passes, the pain
naturally disappears.
By using medicine,
the healing is even faster.
But what's dangerous is
a wound of the heart.
Nothing has more trouble healing
A wound of the heart?
A wound on the body and a wound
of the heart are slightly different.
Unlike a wound on the body,
there is no ointment and sometimes,
it doesn't heal for one's entire life.
But there is one thing that
can cure a wound of the heart.
However, this is a complicated medicine.
It can only be given to you
by another person.
What? What must I do to...?
The thing that can cure
a wound of the heart.
That is...
Iove.
Love?
Yes.
H-How can I get it?
What do I need to do for this to be...?
It has already been given to you, Gaara.
Huh?
Love is...a heart that desires to serve
a precious person who is close to oneself,
to love and watch over that person,
just like my older sister did.
I believe that my older sister
loved you, Gaara.
The sand which automatically tries to
protect you is like the love of a mother.
I believe that sand is filled
with your mother's will.
My sister...probably wanted to
protect you even more after dying...
Yashamaru...
What is it?
Thanks for what you did earlier...
for stopping me.
You are welcome.
You are a precious person
who is near me, Gaara!
Can you understand...my pain?
It tastes like iron...
Hey, Yashamaru...
I have a favor to ask!
What is it?
I want some ointment.
Sorry about earlier...
It must've hurt.
This is medicine.
If you want it-
Go home...freak!
As I thought...
Things don't go well...
Why is it...
that only I'm such a freak?!
What...am I?!
The thing that can cure
a wound of the heart is love.
Yashamaru!
Why? Why me...?
Why is it always me?!
Well done...Gaara.
W-Why...? Why is it?!
Why Yashamaru...?
Why did you, why...?
I was commissioned to kill you...
By your father...
Lord Kazekage
My father...?
Why did my father...?
Why...? Why me?
You have been watched over
as an experiment.
Gaara, you couldn't
control the Shukaku..
the Sand Spirit which possesses
the power of the sand.
Eventually, your existence would
become too dangerous for the village.
Before that occurred...
So Yashamaru, you had no choice...
you had to follow my father's order...?
No...That is not correct.
It is true I accepted
Lord Kazekage's order.
But if I had wanted to,
I could have turned it down.
Gaara...
Deep down in my heart,
I probably...
hated you.
You, whose birth took the life
of my beloved older sister.
The child she left behind in death...
Since you were what she left behind,
I tried desperately to love you.
But...I never could.
My sister didn't choose to have you.
My sister became a sacrifice
for the village,
and she died while
cursing this village!
Since then, I probably...
have been burdened with a wound
of the heart that could never heal.
Your name...
is the name my sister gave you.
"This child's name is Gaara..."
"A devil that loves only itself..."
"Love only yourself..."
"And fight only for
your own sake."
"If you do that,
you will continue to exist."
Such was the hope it contained.
However...
my sister did not give you this name
because she was concerned
about you or loved you...
The reason she gave you this name..
...was so that the deep seated hatred
of my sister
who died hating and cursing
this village...
would remain...
and be known to all!
You were never...loved!
Please die...
I believe that my sister loved you, Gaara.
Love?
Love only yourself.
And fight only for your own sake.
So that is Gaara...
That is me.
I finally understand.
I am alone.
I will no longer believe in anyone...
or love anyone.
I am alone!
Yes, I am all by myself.
It's those eyes...
What's the matter?
Weren't you gonna run away?
Sasuke...
Naruto...
What are these two...to you?!
T-These two are...my friends!
Try laying so much as
another finger on them!
I'll clobber you!
So...what's the matter?!
Weren't you gonna clobber me?
Hurry up and come at me...
Damn it!
Dang it!
Damn it! Things will really be bad
if it stays like this...!
I'll have to...
It's come to this...
Though it's gonna use a lot of chakra...
There's no choice
but to summon Chief Gamabunta!
Summoning Jutsu!
What's this?! You're a little kid!
If you want something from me,
give me some snack!
If you don't, I won't play with you!
You know something?
I hate you frogs!
What did you say?!
Don't make fun of amphibians! Really!
Jeez, I don't have time to
play with you, little squirt!
Damn! Why is it...?
I practiced for so long, but with this,
there's no other way...
I need to save everyone!
Everyone...you say?
Don't make me laugh.
I fight...only for myself!
He...he's transforming again!
If you don't take me down,
the sand holding this girl will remain!
Not only that, as time passes...
the sand will slowly squeeze tighter
and eventually suffocate this girl!
Sakura!
He's getting closer and closer
to a Perfect Possession.
That jutsu hasn't been activated yet,
but at this rate, I'll also be...!
Sand Shuriken!
You're...really weak!
Shut up!
But what is that guy?
W-What lonely eyes...
I don't know what happened, but...
This guy's always been
suffering all alone...
Even now,
without ever feeling relief...
Only able to believe in himself...
Even now,
he's battling in hell...
What's the matter?!
Are you afraid of me?
To fight for the sake of oneself?
To fight for the sake of others?
You should just love yourself,
and fight for yourself!
That is the definition of
being strong!
Now fight me!
What happened to
the boldness you had earlier?!
Show me your strength!
I'll throw that strength to the ground!
Now what's the matter?!
If you don't fight me I'll kill that girl!
Damn it!
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Wind Style:
Infinite Sandstorm Devastation!
This isn't good...
He really got me.
First, I'll toy with you
without killing you!
I look forward to seeing
when and how you give up
and abandon your friends!
But...what is it?
It's far from over!
What is this...this feeling?
Sand Shuriken!
D-Damn it!
Damn it!
H-He's...
What is this?!
This feeling that's overcoming me?
For some reason...
I don't want to lose to this guy...
You...
...even if I die!
What's the matter?
After pursuing me like that,
what's up with you?
You're not even able to touch me...
What a joke!
Sakura...
I don't know how far I can go, but...
I have to give it...my best shot!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Here goes!
From this moment on,
Secret Ultimate taijutsu technique!
Naruto Uzumaki...
Clone Body Slam!
- Now!
Okay!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Once again...
Take this!
Leaf Village Secret Ultimate
taijutsu technique,
learned from Kakashi Sensei!
A Thousand Years of Death!
Boom.
Doing all that work...
And managing just one blow, huh?
S-Shut up!
He attacked the base of the tail
which has the weakest defense...
Even though I'm not wounded,
I can't absorb the impact.
Did I underestimate him too much?
Hey, Naruto...
Sakura...Rescue her,
even if it's the last thing you do!
And after you've rescued her...
take Sakura and get out of here.
You, if anyone, can do it!
I still have the ability...
to hold him in check for a while.
I lost everything once...
I don't want to see...
any precious comrades die
right before my eyes again.
Precious...comrades...
I will not allow my comrades...
to be killed, no matter what.
I see...
That's right.
Because he has gone through life
with the same Ioneliness
and sadness as I have...
That guy who continued to fight
in solitude for himself,
I thought...he was strong.
Naruto...
But that's not the meaning
of true strength...
If one fights just for
oneself in solitude...
one can't really become strong...
When a person wants to protect
someone who is precious to him...
it's then that they truly...
become...strong.
You will...become strong.
He's releasing such a
massive amount of chakra!
That's...Naruto?!
No matter what, I will...
protect you!
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
I've kept you waiting
a long time!
The spiraling series of Naruto Uzumaki's
Ninja Handbook starts now!
W-What's up with this...
large number of clones?!
What the heck is this?
T-This is...amazing!
You are pretty promising.
You...This is...
Sasuke, you get yourself
a good rest.
Leave the rest to Naruto Uzumaki!
This guy is...
All right! Everyone! Here I go!
That's Naruto?!
Jump!
Naruto's...Ninja...Handbook!
Everywhere...
Shuriken!
My body hasn't fully recovered...
My only choice is to
use Sand as a defense!
- Na-Ru-To! 2K Uzumaki!
- Barrage!
T-This guy...!
- This time, I'll use both legs...
- and go for a 4K Barrage!
- And go for a 4K Barrage!
Where does that strength come from?
No way!
There's no way...
No way I'll...lose to...a guy like this!
W-What's...that?
It finally...emerged.
The Perfect Possession!
This is...
the monster inside that guy.
Naruto!
Damn...my body!
My chakra has...
with all those clones earlier on...
Sakura!
This will mark your end...
Sand Burial!
Summoning Jutsu!
I will protect...
Sakura!
Naruto Uzumaki...
You continue to give me
such pleasure...
Naruto...
What in the...world...?
Not you again!
What in the world do you want?
Huh?!
That must be...
the Shukaku of the Sand.
Chief Toad!
Come join me in this fight!
No way!
What?!
Why would I go out of my way
and fight a guy like that?
That's idiotic!
Why?!
You told me the other day that you
would make me your henchman!
It's only natural for a chief
to help out his henchman!
That's respect and duty, right?!
It's true I told you
I'd make you my henchman...
But we haven't even exchanged cups
of sake to seal our relationship yet...
Gimme a break!
I'm still underage!
I can't drink alcohol!
Don't say that and just listen
to what this guy says, Pop!
Huh?! Pop?!
Why are you here, Gamakichi?
I had lots of time on my hands,
so I came to visit...
Huh? Huh?
You're father and son?
And that guy over there
tried to bully me!
What was that?!
When that happened,
this guy here rescued me...
He clashed with that monster...
Pretty interesting guy.
I see...
Kid...
I recognize you as my henchman...
and I'll show you what duty
and respect means!
Hang on tight!
How's that?!
Awesome...
What a guy...
He's so heavy,
I could barely manage to
thrust my dagger through him.
If I don't hurry up,
this battle will change
the shape of the landscape.
Hey! Hey! Chief!
Sakura is over that way,
so don't move that way!
Please lure him in this direction.
Sakura...?
That's his girlfriend, Pop.
I've got to take that guy down.
Otherwise, I won't be able
to rescue Sakura!
Interesting!
This is interesting
Naruto Uzumaki!
T-This isn't good!
Gaara...
He's going to do it...
I need to get out of here!
He's done it...!
W-What's gonna happen, Chief?
If a host sets the
Playing Possum Jutsu into motion...
...Shukaku will appear!
I'm finally able to emerge!
Let's do this!
The guy I wanna kill is you!
I'm gonna jump...
Huh?
Wind Style: Air Bullets!
Water Style: Water Bullets!
That practically created a storm...
What kind of a battle is this...?!
Chief! I told you,
not in that direction!
Shut up! I know!
Air Bullets!
Water Bullets!
Too bad...
This isn't good, Chief!
There's one shot left...!
Yeah! I killed it...
I killed it!
That hurts...!
How dare you shoot me
with bullets containing
stupid amounts of chakra!
Even I can't take that many shots!
What should we do?!
For a start,
wake up the host, kid!
It will release the jutsu!
How do we go about waking him?!
Give him a good punch!
Water Bullets!
Like I'll take that!
Chief, I can't hit him
unless you hold him down!
This Toad doesn't have fangs or claws
to hold that guy's movement.
What should we do then?!
We'll use the Transformation Jutsu
and change into something that does!
But with that said...
I'm not particularly good
at transformations.
Huh?
So you will act as my will
and make the Sign!
Whaaaat?!
Time for a combined transformation!
Uh...Okay!
We got to have fangs and claws!
Umm...
Let's go
Wait...
Say, w-wait a second...!
F-Fangs and claws...Fangs and claws...
Fangs and claws!
Transform!
That's the...!
All right! Now!
Okay!
Wake the hell up!
You jerk...
All right!
Not that much time has passed
since the host went to sleep!
In that state,
one blow should be enough!
Shit!
I just got here!
That guy interfered with my jutsu...?!
Sand Coffin!
- Pop!
- Yeah!
Don't take me for a fool!
Darn!
What kind of strength
does this guy possess?
This doesn't look good...!
Both Naruto and I have already
completely disgorged our chakra!
You will be killed by me!
I will not cease to exist!
Twenty!
Twenty-one!
Leaf...Hurricane!
How many did you take down Kakashi?
Twenty-two.
Huh, it seems I win again!
That was my twenty-third.
Yeah, yeah all right...
That poser attitude of yours
still makes you cool!
That's the reason you are my rival!
- Let's go!
- All right!
You're still grabbing my arm...
I can't use my jutsu this way...
Come on,
let go of me once and for all.
I'm not letting your ambitions
interfere with the village... any longer...
There's no stopping my ambitions!
You will die here!
You old dotard...
As the Third Hokage,
are you saying you still have
the power to save this village?
Do you understand...
the current situation?!
Don't underestimate the shinobi
of this Village!
We will not allow you to take
even one step beyond this point!
Sakura!
Rescue Sakura,
even if it's the last thing you do!
I'll protect Sakura no matter what!
Please...
Just a small amount is fine...
Give me...
Some chakra!
What are you doing...?
There's only one opponent!
Hyuga is the magnum force
of the Leaf Village.
Don't forget that!
M-My...body...is immobilized...
Is this the first time
you're experiencing
the Leaf's hidden technique,
Shadow Paralysis Jutsu?
Well, take this too while I'm at it...
The Leaf's hidden technique...
Shadow Strangle Jutsu!
Expansion Jutsu!
Mind Destruction Jutsu!
W-What's this?!
My body is...all on its own...!
S-Stop...
Stop!
Reminds me of the old days!
Yeah!
The original
Ino-Shika-Cho trio reunites!
Kuromaru...let's go
Right!
In order to protect the village,
all the Leaf shinobi
will risk their lives fighting.
Real strength doesn't lie
in mastering all jutsu!
The poison in my body is...
Don't move, Shino.
I inserted my Parasitic Insects.
They are removing the poison.
Dad...
I believe I taught this
to you too, in the past...
It is when one protects
someone important...
that the true strength of
the shinobi will emerge!
I will protect everyone!
Here I come!
You stupid raccoon!
Die...!
Damn...
Damn it!
D-Did he win?
A simple head blow...
His manner of fighting
is incredibly clumsy,
but to think that he could squeeze out
chakra at that critical stage.
I've never seen a knucklehead ninja
like him before, but...
he sure is the first phenomenal kid
I've seen in a long time.
It's too bad that I can't
see this through to the end,
but I've reached my limit.
Gamakichi, let's head home!
Okay! Pop!
As expected, even I...
am empty now...
You are too, aren't you?
We're much alike...
let's make this time the last!
It appears that...
I don't have the strength left
to yank out your entire soul.
However, your ambition ends here!
Not yet!
There's no stopping my ambition!
I have a suitable punishment for you
who has become addicted to jutsu,
and who has overindulged in jutsu!
I will take
all your jutsu away with me!
What did you say?!
Don't tell me that?
Stop that!
Seal!
My...My arms...
Now...you can no longer use
either of your arms.
And since you can't use your arms,
you can't weave signs.
You no longer possess ninjutsu!
You old dotard!
Give me back my arms!
Orochimaru, you fool...
It's unfortunate that
we can't leave together,
but, my disciple...
let's meet in the other world one day.
You old dotard...
whose life is hanging by a thread!
How dare you!
How dare you take away my jutsu!
In places where the Leaf dances,
a fire burns...
The shadow of the fire
will illuminate the Village...
And once more the Leaf will sprout...
Sarutobi...
At the very least this sword...
It was a fitting end
for somebody like you
who has mastered
the Way of the Shinobi.
It feels like my arms are burning...
Lord Orochimaru!
This is where we call off our plan.
Release the Barrier.
We'll head back.
- Yes!
- Release!
We won't let you get away!
Ninja Art: Spider Web Net!
An adhesive type of string
filled with chakra...?
Kakashi! They're on the move!
Do we go after them?
No, wait, Guy.
That's right...
If you make a move without
any data on the situation up there,
you will get caught in
the enemy's trap.
So...are you just going to watch?
Kabuto?
So you did know, after all.
So...what are we going to do?
It's about time that
we made a retreat.
You're going to run away
from me again?
Right now...
if we show our cards,
they're most likely going to be copied.
Then again,
it doesn't seem like you've completely
mastered that eye like the Uchiha clan.
Well then...
Temari...
Kankuro!
I'm leaving Sakura with you.
Why is...this guy so strong?
I told you not to talk to that guy!
Let's go.
Oh, there! That's him...
Go away!
Monster! Monster! Monster...!
You monster! Die!
That's him...Don't get involved, fool!
Don't look at him!
Go away!
To them, I'm just a relic of the past
who they want to see disappear.
So what did I have in this life,
why did I keep living?
And at that moment,
I knew what I was.
That I...
that my existence didn't matter
to anyone else in the world.
D-Don't come any closer!
The pain of...being all alone...
really is unbearable, isn't it?
The way you feel...
I don't know why,
but I completely understand that it hurts.
But I've met people who are
very important to me now.
I won't allow those important people...
to get hurt!
I will stop you, even if that means...
that I have to kill you!
Why...?
How is it that you can
fight so much for other people?
They saved me from the hell
of being all alone.
They accepted me for who I was.
That's why...
they are important to me!
Love is a heart that desires to serve
a precious person who is close to oneself,
to love and watch over that person...
Love...
That is why he's so strong?
That's enough, Naruto...
Sakura is okay.
This guy's chakra must
be depleted as well...
The sand around Sakura
crumbled away a long time ago.
Oh, I see...
I've had enough...Stop here.
Gaara?
I've never seen Gaara in such
a weakened state before...
All right.
Naruto Uzumaki, huh?
One of these days, even I...
Temari...Kankuro...
- Huh?
Sorry...
D-Don't worry about it...
Rain...
The sky has started to weep as well...
We will begin the memorial service
for the Third Hokage,
who lost his life in this battle,
as well as the other victims
of this attack.
Why?
Why did Old Man Hokage have to die?
Why...?
For Hayate?
The Third Hokage's funeral
has already started. Make it quick.
You too, Kakashi.
You here for Obito...?
If you're always thinking of
an excuse for your tardiness,
you should just come earlier.
I do...
I've been here since the morning.
It's just that,
whenever I come here
I want to punish myself
for being such a fool in the past.
There are two bells.
The fact that there are
only two means?
That one of us has to go
to the tree trunk...
You're quick on the uptake, Orochimaru.
All right! I'll make it!
Come at me with the intent to kill!
Jiraiya, I won the bet with you, didn't I?
You got tied to the tree trunk,
after all.
Shut up!
You flat chested like a cutting board.
What did you say?!
You nerdy perv!
Okay, Okay, that's enough.
Tsunade and Orochimaru go home!
Okay!
You are hopeless...
Ninja shouldn't be getting caught in
obvious traps like that over and over agai
But...
Why don't you learn a little
from Orochimaru?!
Sarutobi Sensei, you're always
saying Orochimaru, Orochimaru!
Hm?
When it comes to snooping,
I'm really good at Transparency Jutsu.
Gimme a break...
I don't even wanna know
what level of Transparency Jutsu
you possess...
I've never been caught once!
And that's the truth!
If you're that sure of yourself,
I'll go with you next time...
You're such a lecher, Sarutobi Sensei...
Iruka Sensei...
Hmm?
Why do people risk their own lives
for other people?
When one person dies...
their past, present, and future
disappear along with them.
Many people die fulfilling
their duty in battle...
And shockingly easily, too.
Hayate was one of them.
Those who pass away also
have dreams and ambitions.
But everyone has something else,
just as important.
Parents, siblings, friends, lovers...
Those who are dear to them.
They trust each other
and help each other,
the people whom they've cherished
since the day they were born.
And that string
which connects people
becomes stronger and
thicker as time goes by...
It can't be explained by logic...
Those who hold those strings just do it,
because it's important to them.
Yeah, I kind of get it.
But...
It's tough to die.
It's not like he died for nothing.
He left us something very important.
Well, you'll eventually understand
one of these days.
Yeah, I kind of get that too!
Bye! Iruka Sensei!
Yeah...
Lord Third Hokage,
the Will of Fire you spoke of...
seems to have been passed on
to the young Leaves.
The flame that you lit
in their hearts,
will burn bright and strong...
And it will shine upon this village,
and watch over and protect us.
It will become a new Hokage...
one of these days...