Okay! Let's go!
Huh?
"Let's go,"
with so much energy...
Don't act like a little kid!
Oh? You're in a bad mood.
Because! Because!
It's in the middle of my training!
There are three steps
in the training, right?!
I'm only done with the second step!
You can do the third step
even while walking.
What! Really?!
A balloon?
Here!
What's this...?
An ordinary balloon?
The first step is "Spin."
The second step is "Power."
And finally, the third step is this.
Which one is "this"?!
Watch me, it looks as if
I am simply holding a balloon...
You say it "looks as if,"
but nothing is really happening.
Then, I will do the same thing
on my left hand.
Let's see what's really happening
inside the balloon.
Wow!
The chakra is randomly spinning
and going faster and faster...
But still, it's perfectly round...
It's almost like...
Like a small typhoon, right?
What's happening in your left hand...
is happening inside that balloon
in your right hand, too?
Yeah! That's right.
Cool...
The balloon isn't moving at all
even if he's spinning that much chakra...
There's more power than
that time the rubber ball popped,
and it's spinning a lot more too!
Listen, in this third step,
you've got to use 100% of
what you have learned...
and retain them.
In other words, while keeping
the "Spin" and the "Power" at their max,
imagine creating a single layer
within the balloon
and compressing the chakra within it.
Got it!
So, this training is about keeping
the spin and power that I did
in the second step,
and conversely,
trying not to pop a delicate balloon!
Oh! That's the most perceptive
you've been so far!
Huh?
But, what's the point in going
to all the trouble?!
In short, it means this.
Watch! It's like this up until
the second step of the training.
Next, after you have mastered
the third step!
This is what happens!
If you can keep this small typhoon
the size of your palm,
the force won't disperse.
The spinning gets faster and faster
and the power gets
more and more compressed.
And the destructive power
will reach its max.
Well, so, that's that.
All right! I'll do this, too!
Okay, this feels right...
Now!
Retain it here!
Retain...
No cutting-corners!
You've got to put out 100% spin and power,
and retain them.
You gotta be kidding...
Unless I can perfectly control all my powe
it's impossible!
Now I can see it...
This third step...
It's on a totally different level
compared to the others.
I told you...
With an achievement difficulty of Rank A,
it's a super advanced ninjutsu.
Well, I'm done explaining!
We'll continue as we go on walking.
Hey, hey!
We don't need to rush so much,
until I can properly...
We have already wasted enough time
waiting for your body to recover.
There's no guarantee that
Tsunade stays in this town much longer.
What?!
But, but...
It's not like an old acquaintance
is going to conveniently pop up
and start talking about
the good old times with her...
Come on, let's go!
All right...
Long time no see...Orochimaru.
I'd looked for you everywhere.
What do you want from me
after so long a time?
You aren't thinking of talking
about the old days...?
Actually, I need to ask you
for a little favor...
His heartbeat is fast...
From that complexion,
he must have a high fever.
He must have been fatigued
for quite some time...
And that arm...
Lady Tsunade.
You must have understood by now.
Go to someone else,
I don't treat anyone any more.
That won't do...
You must know how serious
this wound is...
No one can treat this wound.
Except for one of the Legendary Sannin
who won her fame as
a medical specialist, Princess Tsunade...
You...
That arm...
it's not an ordinary wound.
A special Sealing Jutsu or something...?
What have you done?
Well, it just happened...
when I killed the Third Hokage.
You...Really?
Humph. Don't look so scary.
Anything that has a form
will one day decay...
Same goes for humans.
You must already know that too.
For you have let two of
your most beloved ones die...
That was a really terrible way to die...
You!
Poisoned...
She's fast!
Get out of my way!
Calm down, Shizune!
This attendant...is an expert.
Orochimaru...
Your personality's been like this
for a long time.
And you know my personality
very well...
So stop fooling around with me.
I'll kill you, bastard!
We didn't come here to fight.
We just want to negotiate with you!
I've already told you once.
Get out of my sight!
You are the only one
who can treat Lord Orochimaru's arm.
Get out of my sight.
We're not asking you to do it for free.
Let's make a deal!
I'll count up to five.
Leave before I'm done.
Or else, I'll make you disappear myself.
Please calm down.
It won't be a bad deal for you...
Five...
Four...
Three...
Two...
One...
I'll resurrect the little brother
and man, both of whom you loved...
with the Forbidden Jutsu I've developed.
Since we haven't disappeared yet,
I'm guessing that the deal is made?
Don't you want to see those two...
Tsunade?
If I treat your arms,
what do you intend to do with them?
Well, I don't like to lie...
So, I will tell you the truth.
In addition to getting what I want...
This time, I will completely destroy
the Leaf Village!
And your answer is?
No! You must not believe
in their sweet talk...
Your brother and my uncle
wouldn't want any of that!
You don't have to answer right now.
However, I want it in a week.
Also, two human sacrifices are needed
for this Forbidden Jutsu,
so do what you need to do
to prepare them.
Lady Tsunade, let's kill them right here!
It's our chance!
With you and me, now we can...!
Lady Tsunade...
Sure, I am weak now.
However...
I also know Tsunade's weakness.
So he knows that...
I see it's not cured yet...
your fear of blood.
Hemophobia...?
Shall we get going, Kabuto?
Tsunade...I'll be expecting
a favorable answer from you.
W-What the heck is going on here?
Hmm...
Help me!
Excuse me there, Mister!
Wait just a moment!
What in the world is happening?
You should run away too!
There's a monster up there!
A monster...?
What could it be?
This monster thing?!
It's a g-gigantic snake!
It destroyed the castle in a flash!
How big of a snake?!
Me too, at my village before...
I was attacked by a huge snake!
We must hurry, Naruto!
That snake is probably the same one
that you saw before.
Looks like we were a little too late...
Is this that snake's doing, too?!
- Let's go, Naruto!
- Huh?
Tsunade isn't here any more.
Geez, you keep telling me that...!
Heck, she's nowhere to be found!
Dragging me around here and there,
but after all,
we haven't found a single trace!
Hmm?
Well, let's dine here for now.
Huh?
Isn't this a pub?
So what?
I've told you so many times!
I'm still underage!
You fool. Nobody is asking you to drink.
Kids should only be eating snacks.
- Well then...
- Welcome!
There's no need to dine here!
We can go to a ramen noodle shop
or something!
How stupid! You can gather information
in this type of place...
Huh?
Huh?!
Tsunade!
Jiraiya?!
Why...are you here?
I've finally found you!
I'm exhausted...
That gal is Tsunade?!
She's 50 years old for real?
Now, that's a swindle.
I can't believe...
I met two of the Sannin in one day.
In any case...
Today is a day I see many old friends.
You mean Orochimaru...
What happened?
Nothing, really.
We exchanged a greeting.
Is it really true that this gal
is the Kunoichi
who can heal any kind of wound?
What about you?
What do you want from me?
I'll be straight with you.
Tsunade, the village bas demanded
that you become the Fifth Hokage
Hey, ol' man,
gimme the simmered meat with potatoes!
All right, in a moment.
The Fifth Hokage?!
What's this out of the blue?!
What the heck is going on?!
Do you know about the Third Hokage!?
The Third Hokage?
So, he really was...
Orochimaru did it, right?
I heard about it.
Directly from him.
Orochimaru did it...?
Orochimaru?!
Did he really killed the old man,
the Third Hokage?!
Who is this Orochimaru?!
Just like us, he's one of the Sannin.
Why?! The Sannin are all
from Leaf Village, right?
Then why?!
Who's this brat?
He's Naruto Uzumaki.
Hey, you just hold it there!
I am not done talking yet!
This Orochimaru?!
This bastard that killed Old Man Hokage.
Who the heck is he?!
He's a legendary Sannin, right?!
Then knowing that...
why would you, Pervy Sage,
leave such a guy alone?!
Besides...
What do you mean this person
is the Fifth Hokage?!
Naruto, be quiet for a moment.
But...!
Just shut up!
Impossible...
I refuse!
I remember...those words.
You said those same words
when I asked you to go out with me.
What the heck are you talking about?!
You said it yourself!
Didn't you say that
you will bring her back to the village
and have her treat Sasuke
and Kakashi Sensei?!
But what's this demand
for her to be the Hokage?!
And, on top of that, she refuses!
Lady Tsunade...
Could she be thinking of making
a deal with Orochimaru?
Calm down.
There can't be no other Fifth Hokage,
but this Tsunade.
During the dreadful Great War Era,
she contributed tremendously
to the Leaf's victory.
To this date,
there's no one who can rival
her combat and medical skills.
Still more, this Tsunade is
the granddaughter of the First Hokage
So together with her talents,
there's no one else more suited
to becoming the Fifth Hokage
If she becomes Hokage,
that means that
she'll come back to the village
And then, as I'd told you,
she can treat the two.
Besides, this is what the Leaf's
top decision-making advisors settled upon.
Genin like you have no say
on this matter.
Jiraiya...
Unlike your previous apprentice,
this kid not only has a bad mouth and wit,
he's ugly to match.
What?!
It's tough on anyone to be
compared to the Fourth Hokage.
He had all the qualities to be
the greatest ninja in all history.
Brimming with talent in jutsu,
and he had a brilliant mind!
Popular with people and well...
he was as handsome as me.
But even that Fourth Hokage died quickly.
Risking his own life for the village...
Life is different from money...
To easily risk it and lose it,
is a fool's doing!
Did she say "fool"?!
Both my grandfather and the Second Hokage
seemed to want to subdue
the disturbances of war above all else.
But after all, they died in vain,
in the midst of their dreams
for the village.
You have changed, Tsunade...
I don't know what
you thought in your heart before,
but to say such thing out loud...
Although I look young,
I'm already in my 50s...
Years change people.
Same goes for Sarutobi Sensei...
No wonder he died showing off
at that old age!
Hokage is a bother.
No one but a fool would take it on.
Why you?!
- Let go of me!
- Don't! We're in a pub.
I said, let go of me!
Lady Tsunade!
Anyone who makes fun of the old man
and the Fourth Hokage...
It doesn't matter if
you are a woman!
I'll clobber you with all my might!
You're pretty gutsy...
confronting me like this.
Let's take this outside, brat!
Lady Tsunade!
Though I may not look it,
I am one of the Sannin.
Why should I even take a genin seriously.
What did you say?!
An advance notice for a KO?
I don't mean one minute...
With one finger.
This is enough to take you down.
Lady Tsunade!
Well...
Come on, kiddo.
D-Don't make fun of me!
Darn it!
Lady Tsunade!
Forehead poking?!
Why that no good!
She's strong...
Hey, brat!
I'll ask you one thing before you faint.
Why...get so passionate at
the mention of Hokage's name?
Unlike you...
I will be the heir to the Hokage name,
no matter what!
Because Hokage is...
Because Hokage is my dream!
That kid...
What? She's a bit off her guard...
I can't tackle her head on.
Then, I should use that jutsu now...
Concentrate!
Oh, no!
Wha?! This jutsu is...!
I never thought he'd attempt to use
the Fourth Hokage's jutsu.
But it's still just this level...
It's completely different
from the original one.
That Tsunade...
Incredibly strong as always.
I remember a long time ago,
getting punched by her and
knocked back nearly 100 meters...
At any rate, Naruto's hopeless.
Are you okay?
Jiraiya, was it you...
who taught him that Rasengan,
the Spiral Chakura Sphere?
Rasengan...?!
I'm his teacher, after all.
Humph...You and the Fourth Hokage are
the only ones who can use that jutsu.
Are you in your right mind...
showing someone jutsu
that he can't master?
Don't give him false hope.
That's why the moony kid starts joking
about becoming a Hokage!
It's no joke! Stupid! Stupid!
If I have three days,
I'll master this jutsu!
You said it, kid.
Men don't go back on their word!
Hah! I stand by my words.
That's my Ninja Way.
Then...how about a wager?
A wager...?
I'll give you one week.
If you can master that jutsu,
I'll acknowledge that you have
what it takes to become the Hokage
and give you this necklace.
Lady Tsunade! That's the precious...!
I don't need such a sorry necklace!
Don't say such things, Naruto...
That's the only one of its kind in this wo
And you could buy three mountains
if you were to sell it.
It belonged to the First Hokage.
A-Awesome...
Well, that'll be fine!
He'll do anything for money...?
Good...
However, you lose if you can't master
the jutsu in one week!
And you'll give me all the money
you have on you.
Oh! Gama chan!
When did she...?!
Lady Tsunade! Why?
That necklace is...
He won't be able to do it, anyway...
Let's go, Shizune.
She never once used
that necklace for a bet...
You don't have to answer right now.
However, I want it in a week.
Oh, you are already at it, I see!
Hi, welcome!
Why are you here?
You're cold. Don't say that.
Master Jiraiya...
Shizune, could you leave us?
It's been a while.
I want to drink with her again.
Master, sake! And some radish!
Coming up!
I'm counting on you, Master Jiraiya.
Your radish is ready.
Ooh. This looks good.
At any rate, to think you'd still be takin
good care of that necklace...
I thought you'd have lost it
long since to gambling.
It's a memento of those two, right?
Is he on your mind...?
Who?
Naruto.
Not particularly...
Still, it's immature,
taking on that kid as an opponent...
He shouldn't be able to master
that jutsu in a week, right?
That's not what's called a bet.
What's with the fit of despair?
It's not a fit of despair!
Are you going to meet
Orochimaru again?
I can tell by looking at Shizune's face.
I don't know what kind of deal
he proposed,
but don't rush to a decision.
And...let me just tell you one thing.
The successive line of Hokages
have protected
the Leaf Village and those living in it.
They brought troubled times under control
and helped the village to prosper.
They risked their lives
for this dream, this ideal!
You're not someone who can't understand
the feelings of the previous Hokages.
Just try doing something
to betray the Leaf Village
When that happens, I'll kill you myself!
It has nothing to do with me now!
A person who has experienced
the death of people close to them
and doesn't feel anything
is just a butcher.
You're different, aren't you?
No one cared for the welfare
of the villagers more than you.
At that time, too...
That's enough with the lecture!
Why...did you bring that kid?
Becoming the Hokage is my dream.
He resembles him, doesn't he?
His age is about the same, too...
Not just that...
Becoming the Hokage is my dream!
Geez, you do nothing,
but reckless things.
Do you want to die?
You're still a genin,
so on the battlefield just run away.
Don't tell a man to "run away!"
That dream...And his cockiness as well...
Huh? Who is it this late at night?
Okay, okay. I'm coming.
I'm sorry to bother you so late, Naruto.
I need to talk to you...
As for me, I'm going to get
a good night's rest and train tomorrow!
I'm sorry. But I didn't want you
to misunderstand Lady Tsunade...
As well as the necklace...
Nawaki, happy twelfth birthday!
I'm not a kid anymore,
so I don't need gifts on my birthday!
What're you saying?
You're still a kid, aren't you?!
But never mind that.
Hurry up and open your present!
You'll definitely be pleased!
Big Sister, could this be?
Yes...It's the First Hokage's,
our grandfather's necklace!
I love you, Big Sister!
I thought it'd be better than me having it
You've been wanting it all along, right?
Take good care of it.
Not just this necklace!
This village is grandfather's treasure!
I'm going to protect it!
Nawaki...
I'm the grandson of the Hokage who
built the Village Hidden in Leaves, so...!
You said it.
Men don't go back on their word!
Right!
Someday, I'll become just like Grandfather
And the Hokage name will be mine!
Becoming the Hokage is my dream!
Take off your headband, Nawaki.
Just hurry up and take it off.
I have another present for you.
It's a charm to make
your dream come true.
It's best if you don't look
at the remains.
There's nothing wrong with that,
is there?
Even if she were to look,
she wouldn't be able to determine
that it's her little brother.
Enough, Orochimaru!
We are at war, now.
All shinobi end up like this.
There are no doctors on
the battlefield, so...
However, children really get
much too excited, don't they?
Especially on the day after
they receive a present.
Not just this necklace...
This village is grandfather's treasure!
I'm going to protect it!
First, in a mission where
a Four Man Cell must act alone
for a long period of time
in enemy territory,
by deploying one of the four
to be a medical specialist,
the survival rate as well as
the mission success rate
should go up significantly.
Therefore, establishing a framework
to foster ninja possessing
advanced medical skills
and the development of
a medical institution
should be considered
an urgent task for the present!
Yes indeed, it's as you say.
But we're in the middle of a war now.
It takes too much time to
establish a medical framework.
And at present,
we don't have enough knowledge...
Enemies don't wait.
What did you say?! Hey, old man!
Then we'll never...
I agree with her.
I don't want the lives of the shinobi
who died to be for naught.
There should be something
we can learn from that.
Excuse me!
Thanks for earlier.
What you said was right.
Umm...
It's late.
Shall I walk you home?
What? Is that okay with you?
Where's your home?
The other way.
Then don't bother.
I don't mind.
I also want to talk with you.
And I would always use this path
to the Academy to pick up my little sister
I loved this path.
What? You loved?
Yeah. In the battle when the Leaf
was attacked at night one year ago,
my little sister was...
This man...is the same as me.
Tomorrow's mission will be
within enemy lines...
Fighting and losing cherished people
is not the only way for a shinobi.
Uh huh.
I'm living in a world of shinobi
where death always hovers.
I want to risk my life to bring
this war torn world under control.
I love this village and my comrades.
So I want to protect them.
Since my little sister died,
that sole thought has sustained me.
So I'll become the Hokage...
An existence that protects everyone...
Becoming the Hokage is my dream.
Dan...
I'd like you...to take this.
Hang on, Dan!
Tsunade...I don't want...to die yet.
I have many things that I must...do.
Don't talk, Dan!
His kidney has been blown out...
It's futile even for Tsunade
who is known as one of the Sannin...
I...must not...die here.
It'll be okay. I stopped the bleeding.
So it'll be okay...You'll be saved, Dan!
Really?
Thank goodness...
Dan! Hang on!
Dan!
Dang it! Don't come out...
Stop...Please stop!
Stop...Stop...
Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop!
Stop, I say!
That's enough. He's dead!
No good! Dang it! Dang it!
Tomorrow, for sure!
My head hurts.
I totally got sick from drinking,
thanks to her...
It seems Naruto never came home
last night...
He's such a fool.
Why don't we make a deal?
I'll resurrect the little brother
and man, both of whom you loved...
with the Forbidden Jutsu I've developed.
Don't you want to see those two,
Tsunade?
If I treat your arms...
What do you intend to do with them?
This time, I will completely
destroy Leaf Village!
No! You must not believe
in their sweet talk...
Their wishes...
Moreover, Tsunade, your wishes...
And dreams...Did you forget them?!
I'll be straight with you.
Tsunade, the village has demanded
that you become the Fifth Hokage.
Listen, in this third step,
you've got to use 100%
of what you have learned...
And retain them.
In other words,
imagine creating a single layer
within the balloon
and compressing the chakra inside it.
I know that in my head...
But no matter what,
I can't completely hold 100%
of my power in a neat ball...
Don't give him false hope by teaching him
something he can't master.
That's why the moony kid
starts joking about becoming a Hokage!
Not good...
Dang it! Dang it!
This time for sure...no matter what!
Tomorrow, huh.
Come again, okay?
I certainly will!
Are you going to meet
Orochimaru again?
To think she'd be that shaken up...
Something extreme must have happened.
That one week bugs me, somehow...
And Naruto hasn't come back
to the inn for nearly a week.
I guess I'll press Tsunade a little more.
No good...
No good...Why?
Here there's no time...
It'll be too late.
What's this...?!
What happened, Naruto?!
Are you okay?
What do you want?
The moon's out.
How about going out for a drink?
Tomorrow will be the one week
you promised to Naruto.
I wonder what became of Naruto?
Beats me.
I guess I'll have something.
Radish, please.
Coming up.
Oh?
Here you go.
Ooh! This looks good.
Lady Tsunade!
What happened to Naruto?
He's quite exhausted and weakened.
And his right hand is severely burned
with chakra...
As it stands now,
this kid probably won't wake up
until the day after tomorrow.
It's as Jiraiya says...
Why did I make such a stupid bet?
What am I, of all people,
getting so worked up for?
How stupid.
Tomorrow...
Please don't go tomorrow!
Why don't you say anything?!
Lady Tsunade! Please don't be silent.
Please answer!
If you say that you're going...
What will you do?
I'll stop you with my life!
Shizune...Have you forgotten
who you're talking to?
It'll be troublesome if we're disturbed
during the negotiations...
What do you want me to do?
It might be good to kill...
Tsunade's attendant.
Hey!
I said hey!
Naruto?
Oh no! What time is it?
No, what day is it?
It's Monday...
What is it?
Is your body okay?
As I recall, you were supposed
to sleep for two full days...
No matter what the wound,
I'm always able to recover
if I sleep one night!
That's right.
This kid has Nine-Tailed Fox's power...
More importantly,
where's that stupid old woman?!
Today's the promised bet day.
Then, what about the jutsu...
It's still not complete, but I can wing it
Believe it!
That's right. This isn't the time for this
- Naruto, please stay...
- Huh?
You are...!
What?! Oh!
Wait, Shizune!
That darned Tsunade spiked my drink.
I can't build up my chakra well...
And my body is so numb,
I can barely throw a kunai knife.
What was he gonna do
if that had hit me?!
That's lame! Here you're always bragging
about how you're this awesome ninja!
And you're nailed by her perverted attack?
You, Pervy Pervy Sage?!
Shut up!
Even if she's rotten,
she's still a medical specialist.
She's the only one who could concoct
a tasteless and odorless drug for ninja.
But to think I'd be caught off-guard,
no matter how intoxicated I was...
I never thought I'd end up encountering
that Master Jiraiya in a place like this..
Things have gotten difficult.
I guess I'll pull back for now.
At any rate, Naruto...
To think you'd be here, too...
Hey! Shizune.
Y-Yes?!
It's about time you tell me
what the heck she was talking about
with Orochimaru.
Orochimaru?!
I wanted to believe Lady Tsunade...
That's why I couldn't say until now.
But...
There's no time.
Please come with me!
I'll explain as we run!
Okay!
I'm going, too!
What's your answer?
Say what?!
The answer to that is definitely no!
This might be really bad...
She's probably still thinking
of those two.
Perhaps I may have no choice,
but to kill Tsunade...
Dang it!
I'll heal your arms...
In exchange for that,
keep your hands off the village.
Very well.
Now then...
He's planning to once again attack
the Leaf Village if
his arms are healed!
The situation will get
even more dangerous than that
if he's not stopped now.
Him screwing around like that!
I have you.
There's no need to worry...
How is that your answer...
Princess Tsunade?
To think you'd try to kill me...
At any rate,
I have a sincere trust in you, Kabuto.
A trust for your loyalty and your eyes
that spotted Tsunade's attack.
Yes. We're both from
the same medical corps so...
Her chakra was overflowing
with violent intent.
Tsunade...I was really planning
on resurrecting those two people.
And here I went so far as to promise
not to smash the Leaf Village...
I know that your promise of
"not touching the village" was a lie...
Even though I knew that...I...
after all, these are feelings
that won't decay...
So our negotiations have broken down...
It can't be helped.
Since it's come to this, I have no choice
but to ask forcibly.
Come! Orochimaru!
Come to think of it,
we've never gone at it
even once until now.
That's right!
What're you saying?
I'm the one who has
to go at it with her, right?
Now I'm going to kill
you two worthless punks...here!
Incredible strength as usual...
It'll be over if you're hit once.
I can see that...
It's a bit cramped here
for fighting at a distance.
Are you going to change the location?
That would probably be better...
There was another troublesome person
with the Lady Tsunade's attendant.
That person may come
to her aid.
You're going down!
Who is...the troublesome person?
One of Sannin,
the same as you and Lady Tsunade...
Jiraiya!
I won't let you get away,
no matter what!
Wh-What's this?!
Huh...Princess Tsunade tore it up...
big time.
This means that Lady Tsunade refused...
Where did old Tsunade go?
That belongs to Lady Tsunade...!
Tonton...Which way?
Okay!
It looks like you're quite
out of breath, too...Tsunade.
It's just about time.
I'm not that great at taijutsu, but...
A food pill!
This kid can also use medical ninjutsu...
He got my muscle...!
I severed, ever so slightly,
the bicep muscle of your upper arm
and the rectus muscle of your thigh.
Now you won't be able to release
your incredible strength.
A chakra scalpel, eh...
Why don't you target the arteries?
Indeed, with this scalpel,
I could cut the muscles and vessels
without external injury.
But as may be expected,
I can't make a long, delicate scalpel
in the middle of battle
that can reach the arteries
and the heart muscle.
But, even so...
Dang it! My intercostals got hit.
My breathing...
He's no ordinary medical ninja.
His jutsu sense and his edge
exceed even me in my heyday!
It would still be trouble
if you were to die on me.
I won't target your vital spot...
But with this, you can't move anymore...
She's amazing...
Ordinarily, one wouldn't be able
to budge due to difficulty breathing.
It looks like it will be necessary
to rough her up a little more...
Even though I'm trying to move my hand...
my leg moves?!
D-Don't tell me! This is...
You little!
In my present condition,
this seems to be the extent of my power...
I see...
It's...It's not the muscles...
It's the nerves!
It seems you've realized...
That's right. It's the nerves!
I changed chakra into electricity...
made an electrical field and
poured electricity into your nerves.
The communication between
the brain and the body
is all done with electric signals...
Tsunade jumbled up all of
the electric signals that are exchanged
at a velocity of 360 kilometers per hour.
Having left battle and yet such power...
So this is the legendary Sannin?
Healing types use too much chakra...
But in this condition...
If I try to move my right hand...
my left leg moves.
If I try to move my left ankle...
my right shoulder moves.
It's difficult...
But I've already grasped eighty percent
of what moves when I move what.
Don't mess with me...
with this low-level...
jutsu!
What?! In only a moment,
his body movements...
You're scared of blood, aren't you?!
I'll show you plenty from now!
Jiraiya...?
It's been a long time...Jiraiya.
You've got an evil look as usual.
Huh?!
K-Kabuto?
Naruto...
I see...So you know each other?
We took the Chunin Exam together!
Why are you here, Kabuto...?
Get out of the way!
Hey...
I'll take...
these guys!
Just because you've mastered
your body movements...
it doesn't mean...
you can move like normal!
I won't let you get away now!
Too late!
My body movements have
finally returned...
Blood...!
Having two of the legendary Sannin
as opponents is hairy, isn't it...?
So even if it's just one...
I'll stop you!
Lady Tsunade!
Say! Say! What's happening?!
Why's Kabuto fighting
with old Tsunade?!
You're slow, Naruto...
That's why you're no match for Sasuke.
Take a good look at the headband!
He's Orochimaru's subordinate.
Wha?!
That's right...
I was a spy from
the Village Hidden in the Sound.
During the Chunin Exam
you taught us a lot...
And you also saved us.
Well, I wanted to gather data
on you guys.
Naruto, there's something
I understood by gathering your data.
You have no ninja ability.
Unlike Sasuke!
It's the first time
I've seen Lady Tsunade like this...
Please don't push it too far alone.
I'm your attendant, so...
Old Lady Tsunade...
Even with a fierce look,
you're just a cute genin
who's a fish out of water.
Admittedly, I was anticipating
the monster dwelling inside you...
But now,
with the legendary Sannin before me,
you leave something to be desired.
You're just a puny zero.
So if you meddle...
I'll kill you.
You little!
Don't, Naruto!
My body's still...
That hand...
He shouldn't be able to use
that right hand anymore.
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
I'll attack at once with four...
and break him from the right side
where he can't defend!
You little!
Okay!
Poison needles!
Thanks, Shizune!
A plasma pill!
A plasma pill?
So he's trying to replenish
lost blood, huh...
The blood is gushing out nicely,
eh, Kabuto?
Lord Orochimaru...
Please take off the bandage
on your left arm.
That man is Orochimaru...
Shizune, you take care of
the guy with the glasses...
I'll take care of Orochimaru.
Before that, I'd like to have Tsunade
do something about this body.
The effects of that drug
might still last for awhile...
There's nothing that
I can do about it.
What? Really?
Geez. I guess it can't be helped.
I have no choice
but to fight in this condition.
Tsunade...Rest your body
with recovery ninjutsu.
Then...What about me, me?
You guard Tsunade together
with that pig.
What?! I want to fight, too.
Even I can...
No, you won't!
Like that four-eyed kid said, right?
You're on a different level.
The opponent is a Sannin like myself,
and the man who killed
the Third Hokage
An eye for an eye...
I'm the only one who can fight him.
And that four-eyed guy possesses
the same level of power as Kakashi.
Now then, let's get this thing started.
- Summoning Jutsu.
Hi.
- Huh?!
- What is this?!
- Wha?!
- What the heck's going on?!
Long time no see.
It looks like your stupid
still hasn't healed, eh, Jiraiya.
That's too much even for you
with no ability.
It seems Tsunade got you
with something.
To think I'd already have
my handicap spotted.
You are such
a disgraceful guy as always...
Dang it. It kind of ticks me off
when the Pervy Sage is mocked.
Summoning Jutsu!
The Nine-Tailed Fox kid
from the Chunin Exam.
I wonder if I should've killed him then,
after all.
For the sake of the Akatsuki organization,
I acknowledged his achievement...
and let him slide by.
But the only ones who can break
a Five-Pronged Spell
are the Sannin members
and the Third Hokage.
Which means Jiraiya may have
already taught it to Naruto.
Perhaps.
If he's able to control
the Nine-Tailed Fox's power...
It doesn't quite look to be so.
He isn't endowed with shinobi ability
to begin with, so...
He's still got a long way to go,
sure enough.
Why?!
Hello.
Hey, Gamatatsu.
Why did you come out?
Oh, Brother Gamakichi.
It's the first time I've been summoned.
I-I wonder if I can do my best?
Idiot. Get some snacks
or something and hide.
What? I can get snacks?
Goody goody.
Here I go.
I'll take Jiraiya.
I leave the rest to you.
Naruto!
Your opponent is me.
Earth Style: Dark Swamp!
Dang it. I can't completely sink them
with such a puny swamp.
The drug is still working.
But...with this, the snakes can't move.
Ninja Art: Poison Fog!
I'll be up a creek if
I take even one breath.
My leg tendons...!
I won't be eaten twice...!
No way!
Here I go.
Ninja Art: Needle Jizo!
Dang it...The jutsu isn't working well.
Even if we both have handicaps,
you won't one up me...
Give up now.
It's unfortunate...
Here I had respected you
as a fellow medical ninja.
Stop. Stay back!
Please hang on, Lady Tsunade...
The Sannin name, which Lord Orochimaru
is also called, will cry.
My body's heavy.
To think you who were
once called the village madness
would ferry around such a kid
and struggle tirelessly for the village.
You've really fallen, haven't you?
I have a keen eye to discern ability.
And that kid...is mediocrity in my eyes.
It's precisely for this reason...
that I don't need the Uchiha kid.
It's no fun raising a genius
who's good from the start.
So you can't leave him alone
because it's like you're looking
at your old self?
That kid can't beat Uchiha who inherited
the inherent Sharingan shinobi skill.
And that's because Naruto
doesn't possess the Sharingan.
shinobi ability is about whether
one can use and master
all the jutsu of the world.
Ninja refers to one
who can use ninjutsu.
Shinobi ability is no such thing.
You still don't get it?
A ninja...is one who endures.
It's a difference of opinion, huh.
I'll teach you one thing.
What's most important for shinobi ability.
isn't the number of jutsu
one possesses.
What's important is...
The mettle...
not to give up.
Enough already...you jerk!
Heh. I don't know what jutsu you learned,
but you can't hit me with
such a large motion.
No good.
It won't easily hit with
a moving opponent.
Owwee!
And the chakra isn't
completely held, yet...
It seems you got a cracked thigh bone
in your left leg
from the battle with the snake.
Well, you can still move if
it's just the bone.
But it's impossible now...
The lateral vastus muscle
in your right leg is totally cut off.
What should I do...?
That jutsu of mine uses both hands.
If even one arm is taken out, it's over.
Are you scared of me?
Do you want to run away from here?
Naruto, as I recall,
you whooped it up like this
during the first Chunin Exam.
"Don't mess with me. I won't run away."
"I'll take it. Even if I'm a genin for life"
"I'll become the Hokage at any cost,
so it's okay with me."
"I'm not scared."
Can you...
whoop it up in the same way now?
Unlike you...
I will be the heir to the Hokage name
no matter what!
- Hokage is my dream!
You're not a kid anymore,
so you should stop whooping it up...
Depending on the situation,
when you want to give up and run away,
you should run away.
Oh my...What's with that look?
You'll die! If you die,
there are no dreams or anything...
Do you want to die?
You're still a genin,
so you should run away on the battlefield.
Don't tell a man to run away.
Kids think that everything is easy.
That's why they talk about foolish dreams
like nothing at all.
That's why they can't give up.
Jiraiya, was it you
who taught him that Rasengan?
Are you acting like a teacher by teaching
a jutsu that can't be learned?
Don't give him false hopes.
That's why a moony kid starts joking
that he'll become the Hokage!
They chase after foolish dreams...
and then die.
Bastard!
As for me...I stand by my words.
That's...my Way of Ninja!
You should've just
stayed out of this...
Why?!
Old Lady Tsunade...
You're still going to get up?
Just like our wager
I will definitely win
that unlucky necklace from you.
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Shadow Clone won't do anything now.
Enough...Don't protect me, Naruto.
Stop it!
I told you that you'd die
if you were obstinate like that, right?
If you die, there will be no dreams,
no nothing.
Just get out of the way. Run away.
Humph...It's okay.
I absolutely will not die...
until I become the Hokage!
This way, I can hold on to you.
Here I go!
Rasengan!
This is...?!
Way to go, Naruto.
That Nine-Tailed Fox kid...
a kid like that,
doing a technique like that...
I-It can't be...
He can't be, really...
You...Even after you received
that jutsu?!
I gathered the chakra in my stomach,
and before I received the jutsu
I had started healing.
The reason why Orochimaru favors me...
is not because of my use of jutsu
or my sense for jutsu...
It is because my recuperative power.
The power to energize cells
and make new cells.
On the other hand...
I've used up almost all of my chakra.
That jutsu...
seems it was Naruto's last effort...
I-It can't be...
Even with my powers of recuperation,
this much damage.
I don't...have...enough chakra.
Arrhythmia!
Drats! His heart muscle is in tatters...
Why did that happen...?
That moment?!
At that moment of release...
did he shred the muscles
around his heart...?
Stop shaking!
It's all over...for Naruto.
I...cut...his heart's chakra network
which restores the strength...
through the Nine-Tail's chakra...
With all my strength.
In order to eliminate the possibility
that he would heal with his own power.
There's no way he can recover...
Even with you.
Shut up!
I'll kill you later...
He's stopped breathing...!
Dammit!
It's dark...
Dark!
Why is it getting dark?
My strength is...Why...?
What...?
Don't die...
Don't die!
I won it.
I-It's impossible...
Hokage is...my dream, eh?
For the last time...
Just one more time...
I want to bet on you...
Who would have imagined this?
If that child is found by the Akatsuki,
there will be trouble.
In other words,
if I'm to kill him...
now is the time!
Shoot!
He's aiming at this child!
Tsunade...You're the only one
I wasn't going to kill...
If that child lives,
there will be trouble in the future
on a variety of levels.
Don't get in my way.
This is one child...
I will absolutely protect!
Trembling at the sight of blood,
why would you, one of the Sannin,
risk your life to protect that genin kid?
To protect...
my hometown...the Leaf Village...!
To protect the Leaf Village...?
Because...because...
this small child...
is the kid who will become
Hokage some day...
What utter nonsense...
By the way...
to hell with Hokage!
Only a fool does that job.
To hell with Hokage!
The wishes of the two...
More importantly, Lady Tsunade,
your wish...
Have you forgotten your dream?
The successive lines of Hokage
have protected
the Leaf Village and
and those living in it.
They brought troubled times under control
and helped the village to prosper.
They risked their lives
for this dream, this ideal!
Anyone who makes fun of the old man
and the Fourth Hokage...
It doesn't matter if
you are a woman!
I'll clobber you with all my might!
And now,
I also will put my life on the line!
If your life is worth throwing away
for a kid like him...!
Then dying now would be
a fitting end!
All that's left...is Naruto.
Lady Tsunade!
She's still able to move even
after I pierced her down to her lungs!
You mean you'll still protect that kid?!
That's what I said...
From now...
I'm putting my life on the line!
You, half dead corpse!
No matter how cool you try to be,
your trembling doesn't stop.
You can't get away from
the curse of hemophobia.
And yet, why would you
take the blows for that kid?
Why would you battle for the Leaf?
No way!
Tsunade's trembling has...
has stopped?
That is because...I am...
the Leaf Village's...Fifth Hokage!
That sign is?!
Lady Tsunade has conquered
her fear of blood,
but that's...
W-Wait! I'll treat that wound.
So don't release that seal!
Secret Seal Release!
Ninja Art: Mitotic Regeneration!
What is this jutsu...?!
It looks like I'm not the only one
who develops new jutsu.
What in the world is this jutsu?
Well...
For many years I've stored chakra
in my forehead.
The mass of chakra stimulated
a variety of proteins.
The number of times my cells divide
speeds to a dizzying rate...
The cells rebuild...
and all the organs and body systems
are revitalized.
It's not the ability to restore,
it's the ability to reincarnate.
That means I won't die...from battles.
But the number of times a person's cells
divide in their lifetime is fixed...
If that is sped up,
it essentially shortens the life!
Lady Tsunade!
That action is...
Lord Orochimaru!
Come out!
Hurry!
Ino, inu, saru, tori, hitsuji!
- Summoning Jutsu!
Oh! Dad!
This isn't good!
Oh no, Gamatatsu!
Let's get out of here!
What? Why, why?
It doesn't matter, just hurry up!
Manda and Orochimaru,
Katsuyu and Tsunade...
They all bring back memories...
Shall we have a reunion
or something, Jiraiya?
Fool! I summon you after a long absence
and you make these boring jokes.
The time to conclude this long,
fateful confrontation has come.
I'm bringing Orochimaru down,
here and now!
Hey Orochimaru...
Why'd you have to summon me
to a place like this?!
You...I'm going to eat you up!
Don't say that, Lord Manda...
You will be duly rewarded.
Who said I'm talking to you?!
Don't be so flippant, brat!
Hey, Orochimaru...
I expect you to prepare
a sacrificial offering of 100 people later
Though Lord Orochimaru is
Manda's master,
if Manda learns that Lord Orochimaru
can't use jutsu,
Manda will no doubt
double cross him.
Despite the fact that he had
no other choice, in his condition,
it was too risky for Lord Orochimaru
to summon Manda.
Katsuyu...take that kid to Shizune!
Yes, ma'am.
All right! I can fight, too!
Shizune, please take care of this child.
Naruto...
Also, the battle is going to get
quite vicious from now.
Please go far away with my clone
and conceal yourself...
That's what Lady Tsunade wants.
Lady Tsunade...
You...
I'll hang you out until you're dry!
I've been wanting a snakeskin wallet...
Orochimaru,
you've sunk too deeply into vice!
We are no longer comrades.
Comrades?
That word makes me shiver.
Today is the last day that
we are called Sannin!
Acid Slime!
I'll start with this one!
Katsuyu!
Lady Tsunade...
Here they come!
I know!
Tsunade! Stay away!
Bunta! Give me some oil!
Okay!
Fire Style:
Toad Oil Flamethrower!
Humph...How's that?
Did it work?
No, that's...
Molten skin! He shed his skin!
Bunta! Under the earth!
What?!
It's the tail?!
Keep it shut!
They're Sannin, all right.
Dealing with two of them is rough.
Well now, I can kill you
by wringing your neck.
Fine!
It's about time we put an end to this!
R-Ridiculous!
He took a direct hit!
That was it.
Yeah...
Lord Orochimaru...
Putting me in this position!
I want to eat you and kill you,
but I can't even chew you up
with this hole in my mouth...
Next time, if we meet again,
be prepared!
Tsunade...
Even though you won't heal me,
I still have one way.
A way to resurrect these arms.
The Leaf Village...
I'll destroy it...without fail.
At that time, it would be nice
if we could meet again...
My comrades...
Tsunade and Jiraiya.
That face...?!
In some way or another,
he took someone else's body...?!
No wonder,
when we went at it a while ago,
I didn't get the same feeling
from him that I did in the past...
The true elixir of life.
That's my...
my immortality!
Some day, in the future...
Wait!
The bones in my ribs and feet
are broken...
The side effects of the jutsu
are starting...
My body is...already...
Tsunade, you haven't changed.
You're no good at wagers.
Any time now, the side effects...
Lady Tsunade...
You...
It's nothing...If I rest a bit, I'll retu
to my young form.
I'll rest in town.
And when Naruto wakes up,
We'll return to Konoha.
Tsunade...
Starting now, don't call me Tsunade.
Call me...
The Fifth Hokage?!
Old Lady Tsunade is
the Fifth Hokage starting today...
What, you look disgruntled, Naruto.
After all, compared to the old man,
the Third Hokage
there's something...
rough natured and kind of selfish...
Ioose with money, catty and stupid...
Somehow, I'm going to worry
if she can do it properly.
Lady Tsunade, would you like
to order something...
Moreover, a 50 year old lady
transforming into a young lady...
Is it okay for the person who
will become Hokage
to lie to everyone, I wonder?
Go outside, brat!
It's just like before...
Despite how I look,
I'm going to be the Fifth Hokage.
I shouldn't take
this short brat of a foe seriously...
This one is enough...
Don't call me brat!
I may be like this now,
but I'll be Hokage some day!
Here I go!
Another brow flick?!
Become a fine man...
And, a fine Hokage.
Yeah!
Okay! Shall we go home?
To our hometown the Leaf Village!
What? I haven't eaten yet...!
Don't try to distract me by laughing
Nawaki...Dan...
the boy who will inherit your dreams,
my beloved ones,
is right here!