This rock is reserved for me!
Almighty Naruto, the Fifth Hokage!
Naruto again?
Enough with the stupid pranks!
Looks like he drew
his own face this time!
That little...
Look at that!
I can't believe they let him
graduate from the Academy!
Our Hidden Leaf ninja
have really gone downhill...
Is he okay? I mean...
think about what he is...
Don't even go there...
Oops...Sorry.
Oh shut up already!
What are you doing?!
How big a fool are you?!
Huh? Iruka sensei!
Naruto!
You just graduated!
Why would you do that?
I thought it was a nice way to
commemorate my graduation, you know?
You clean all that up right now!
Yes!
Unbelievable...you're about
to become a genin, you know?
I'm worried about your future.
This is the last day you'll
have to worry about me, Iruka sensei!
From now on, I'm going
to work my butt off to become Hokage!
And I'll surpass all
the Hokage before me!
Naruto...
What are you talking about?
Becoming Hokage's not as easy as you think!
Just watch me, Iruka sensei!
Where does all that confidence come from?
I'm going to work my butt off!
You'll see!
Good grief...
Hey, you!
Are you sure you want
to look like that?
Yes, of course!
C'mon! So hurry hurry!
Don't regret it later.
Say cheese!
I couldn't decide on how to look.
It took me 3 hours to decide.
But as you can see,
it's more like a work of art.
Doesn't it look great?
Do it over.
What?!
Stop saying that!
Transform!
Oh please, Lord Hokage...
The Sexy Jutsu...
That's quite a devious technique.
By the way Naruto,
where's your headband?
I won't wear it until the orientation.
It might get scratched.
Well, that's just fine.
But the Ninja Registration Form
is a very important document
held in high regard by our village.
Why do you want to look like this?
Because!
Anyway, how should I know
about all that stuff?
Old man!
Get ready to fight!
I am going to be the Fifth Hokage!
Ouch!
If it's not one thing, it's another...
Drat! Is this a trap?
Are you okay,
honorable grandson?
And may I just inform you that
there aren't any traps here...
Huh? What's with this runt?
What?!
I know this kid...
He's that Nine-Tailed boy!
You must have done this to me!
You tripped all by yourself, stupid!
Hey! Let go of him!
He is the honorable grandson
of the Third Hokage!
He stopped as soon as
he learned who I am...
He's like my four-eyed teacher.
He's just like everyone else!
What's the matter?
Weren't you gonna hit me, huh?
Can't do it 'cuz
I'm the Hokage's grandson, eh?
As if I care!
Imbecile!
What?!
Good grief...
Stop following me!
What is it now?!
You've seen through my disguise...
Your reputation is well earned.
I will allow you to make me
your apprentice.
But you must first teach me that
"Sexy Jutsu" technique
you used to beat Grandpa Hokage.
You gotta be kidding.
I beg you to say yes, boss!
Huh?
Boss?
Boss! Boss! Boss!
I guess I have no choice.
He's gone!
It seems he's gone after Naruto.
Oh no!
This is terrible!
Honorable grandson!
That Naruto...What is he teaching
the honorable grandson...?
Where the hell could they be...?
I am a distinguished teacher
who trains potential Hokage.
All those who interfere
will be eliminated.
You know I've been wondering...
You seem obsessed with beating
your Grandpa Hokage.
My name is Konohamaru.
It was Grandpa who gave me
that name.
He named me after the village.
It should be easy for everyone
here to remember.
But nobody ever calls me
by that name.
When they see me, all they see
is the grandson of Lord Hokage.
No one sees me for who I really am.
I can't stand it anymore.
That's why...
That's why I want the title
of Lord Hokage now.
Idiot...
Who'd accept you as Hokage, huh?
Huh?
You won't win the title
that easily, you know.
What?!
It's not that simple.
If you're really serious about gaining
the title of Lord Hokage...
What?
You'll have to beat me first!
I have found you!
Huh?
That Demon Fox!!
That cold look!
It's always like that!
Honorable grandson,
we have to go now.
No way!
I want to beat Grandpa right now
so I can win the title of Lord Hokage!
Don't get in my way!
A Hokage must first know about virtue,
honor, etiquette, wisdom, loyalty, faith,
judgment, obedience
and all that.
He must be skilled at more than
thousand techniques...
And then...
Transform!
Take this! Sexy Jutsu!
What?
It didn't work!
What kind of a
disgraceful technique is that?!
I am a gentleman!
Such vulgar attacks
will never work on me!
Honorable Grandson!
That punk will only make you an imbecile!
Stick with me and...
you will gain a shortcut
towards becoming the Fifth Hokage.
C'mon, let's go!
No way!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Wow!
Fantastic!
Ha!
That's nothing.
I am a distinguished teacher.
I am not as weak as Mizuki.
Boss...
Transform!
Oh, Master Ebisu...
I call this one,
"the Harem Jutsu"!
He combined the multiple Clones with
his own Sexy Jutsu.
That's another devious attack.
Even I would probably fall for it...
I can't even beat that
four-eyed teacher of mine!
All I want is a name that
will be recognized by everybody!
But I keep failing.
You think it's that easy?
Huh?
It's given only to the greatest ninja
in the village.
Everybody must learn to believe in you.
I've been through a lot already.
It's been one struggle after another.
But after all that,
I found someone who accepts me.
I had to go through all that...
Just for one person.
You had better push yourself.
For what?
The path of becoming
Lord Hokage is a brutal one.
There's no such thing as a shortcut.
Who do you think you are,
lecturing me like that?
I won't be your apprentice anymore.
From now on, you're my rival.
Unfortunately for you, I
graduate from the Ninja Academy tomorrow.
But, one day we'll fight as equals
for the title of Lord Hokage.
Look forward to that, Konohamaru.
You still have a long way to go
to become a real ninja.
They're supposed to
be five years apart in age.
Lady Hanabi is quite amazing...
How was training today?
The same as usual...
You seem depressed.
You used to have
so much fun in the past...
Yeah...
I observed for a while...
It's going to be difficult to
let Hinata succeed the main family.
A decision has to be made.
I understand.
However, I'd like to
make one request.
You two will participate
in a mock battle today.
Huh?
I want to see all the skill and
power you've gained until now.
Do not go easy on each other.
Fight with the intent
to defeat each other!
Hinata...
You are the successor of the Hyuga Clan.
Show me that
you are worthy of that.
Yes.
But I'm just supposed to fight...
Begin!
Elder Sister Hinata!
They're both amazing!
There's no end to this!
Right there!
Oh no!
Stop!
Father...
To fall to Hanabi who is
five years younger than you...
Enough. You may go!
Hinata will probably serve
the village as a genin.
I see.
As sad as it seems,
we cannot allow a failure
like that to be our successor.
This is her destiny.
That you were born stronger
than your sister is also destiny.
Hanabi,
you must hone your skills
to the utmost for the sake of the Hyuga.
Yes.
Stand, Hanabi.
Hinata will be under
my command from now on.
But, are you sure about this?
Hinata is the successor
of the Hyuga clan.
Genin missions carry
a high risk of death.
Do what you will with her.
She couldn't beat Hanabi
who is five years younger...
The Hyuga have no need
for such a person.
Father has turned his back
on elder sister...
Is that all you wanted to discuss?
If so, you may go.
We are busy here.
Alright.
Continue, Hanabi.
Yes.
If elder sister can't do it,
I have no choice but to do it.
I will protect the Hyuga.
This is my destiny!
I wonder if he's going to be okay...
He's a bit of a coward.
He finally became a genin,
but he doesn't like confrontation.
He'll soon go out on missions
and may have to face foes
in life-or-death battles.
As it is...
Choji will be killed because
he was too scared to make a move.
I doubt that
he'll ever become a chunin.
Your son is not a coward.
He's just kind.
In the shinobi world,
it's the same thing.
Then let him be kind.
"Be kind"?
Yes. His kindness
is a unique weapon
which he, and he alone, possesses.
Weapon...
He's just a boy.
It can't be helped if it's
viewed as cowardice.
But, some day, his kindness
will be a thing of greatness.
The time will come when the
Hidden Leaf will need his kindness.
However, he will require
strength that rivals his kindness.
He needs the intensity
to recognize other's pain,
to feel and accept their pain...
Or reject it...but still
envelope them in kindness.
That boy has those qualities.
Asuma...
Choji will experience many things.
This is the shinobi world,
the hardships will be many.
But with each experience,
he will grow stronger and kinder.
Today's...a special day, so...
Time to eat!
Sakura!
Shouldn't you be heading out soon?
I was thinking of leaving now!
Cha! How long are you planning
on treating me like a child?!
That's right...I'm not a student
of the academy anymore...
I'm a Kunoichi of the Leaf Village,
Sakura Haruno!
I'm off!
Morning, Sakura.
Morning...Ino.
Who would've thought you'd
be able to graduate.
Ancient history
has nothing to do with it.
As of today,
we're both full fledged ninja...
I won't lose to you anymore, Ino!
What the...Why are you here?
Today's meeting is for graduates only.
Hey, don't you see the headband?
As of today, I'm a ninja too!
How can I put it, it really suits me.
So Naruto...was able to graduate.
Goal!
I won again, Sakura!
What're you saying?
The tip of my foot got in
one centimeter faster!
You must be blind.
It's Sakura.
Oh...
Sakura's looking at me...
Hey, Sakura!
M-Morning, Sakura!
Get outta' the way!
M-Morning, Sasuke...
Mind if I sit next to you?
Hey! I'm going to sit
next to Sasuke!
First come, first served!
I got in the classroom sooner!
I did!
If that's the case, then I did!
I was first!
I'm sitting next to Sasuke!
How annoying...
Naruto! Don't glare at Sasuke!
Sakura...
Everyone's all, "Sasuke! Sasuke!".
What's so great about this guy?!
Just beat him up, Sasuke!
Yeah! Yeah!
What? Really?
Oh! Sorry!
Wha?
Whoa!
Cha! I was planning on
seizing Sasuke's first kiss!
You jerk...
Naruto! I'll kill you!
- My mouth is rotting.
- Huh? Was that my fault?
What? I feel rage...
Naruto...
You...
An accident...
It was an accident!
You are annoying!
Yikes!
As of today, you all have become
full fledged ninja...
However, you're still genin.
The tough part's still to come!
From here on,
you'll be in a squad of three
and carry out missions
under your jonin teachers.
The teams have been determined
so that the strength of
the teams will be balanced.
Now for the assignments!
First is Team Seven...
Naruto Uzumaki!
Sakura Haruno.
Hooray!
I'm with...Naruto?
And...Sasuke Uchiha!
Hooray!
I'm with...Sasuke?
So I'll be in a different group
from Naruto, huh...
Next is Team Eight. Hinata Hyuga!
Y-Yes...
Kiba Inuzuka!
Shino Aburame!
Why is this happening?
Team Nine.
Cha! Love will be victorious!
Man...
Why do women think that
kind of guy's so great?
Don't you understand, Shikamaru?
Well, I'm not a woman...
That's why you are
not popular among girls.
I wouldn't want to be grouped with you.
Team Ten. Ino Yamanaka.
Shikamaru Nara.
It appears we've been
grouped together.
And Choji Akimichi.
And fatty on top of that...
That's all for the group division.
Iruka Sensei!
Why does an exceptional student
like me have to be
in the same group as this guy?!
Sasuke has the best grades
of the graduates.
Naruto, you're at the bottom!
This is how it is when trying
to balance the strength within groups.
Just don't get in my way, loser!
Hey, what did you say?!
You want to fight, loser?
Knock it off, Naruto!!
In the afternoon,
I'll introduce you to your jonin teachers.
You're dismissed until then!
Damn. This is no fun!
I'm finally in the same group
as Sakura and it has to be like this...
I wonder if something good will happen...
That's it!
Is that you, Naruto? You jerk!
Just be quiet!
No need for me to feel rushed...
From here on out I'll be in
the same group as Sasuke...
But...
Even if I were to use my feminine charms,
my proportions are below average...
All that's above average
is the width of my forehead...
What should I do?
Huh? No way!
Sasuke is looking this way!
And with such a passionate look!
You...have a charmingly wide forehead.
It makes me want to kiss it.
That's what its surface area is for.
Yeah right...
I'm not just some kid
who believes in fairy tales...
There's no way.
You...
have a charmingly large forehead.
What?
It makes me want to kiss it.
Cha! This fairy tale is for real!
Well...that's what Naruto would say.
I've got something to ask you.
What do you think...of Naruto?
He's quite at home interfering and
enjoys it when I make mistakes.
Naruto doesn't understand
one thing about me...
He just annoys me!
All I want...
is for you to accept me, Sasuke.
For me to accept you?
I'll do anything for the sake of that.
I was careless!
I'm desperate, so...
I finally know why I...
like Sakura so much.
Diarrhea at a time like this?
What's wrong?
I-I'll be right back!
Sasuke's so shy!
I guess he needs to
prepare himself mentally...
That was close!
My stomach hurt so much that
the jutsu was about to wear off!
Why does my stomach have
to hurt at such a good time?
I'm annoying, huh?
She said it again...
And I transformed into Sasuke and
had got a little closer to Sakura...
Oh Sasuke,
you're such a shy bad boy!
Are you prepared?
I'm raring to go!
H-Hey, Sasuke!
Where's Naruto?
Oh, there you go changing
the subject again...
Just leave Naruto alone!
All he does is pick fights with you!
It's probably because
he wasn't raised right!
You know!
He doesn't have any parents, right?
He always does whatever he wants!
My parents would get mad at me
if I did something like that!
There are no parents to nag
you it it's just you alone!
So his selfishness comes
out at various times!
The loneliness.
Huh?
It's something worse than getting
scolded by parents and...
W-What's gotten into you?
You...annoy me.
So this is Naruto's room...
And Sasuke Uchiha is also
in the group you'll be in charge of.
I wish you luck!
The expiration date...
This milk went bad quite awhile ago...
He'll get sick if he drinks this.
It seems that things are
going to get disastrous.
Naruto!
Stay still.
Why's it that only
our squad's teacher is late?
The other squads have gone off
somewhere with their new teachers,
even Iruka Sensei left.
Don't look at me.
Hey! What're you doing, Naruto?!
Hey!
This is what he gets for being late!
Man! You're asking for it!
I like stuff like this!
A jonin wouldn't get caught
in such a lame booby trap.
That's right. You're such an idiot!
I got him! I got him!
I-I'm sorry, sir.
I tried to stop him,
but Naruto did it on his own...
It's all good.
Get real.
Is he really a jonin?
How should I put this?
My first impression of you guys?
Well, I hate you.
Let's see.
First off, i'd like
you guys to introduce yourselves.
Introduce ourselves...?
What should we say?
Your likes, dislikes, your future dream,
hobbies, things like that!
Hey! Before that,
you should tell us about yourself.
Me? My name's Kakashi Hatake.
I don't feel like telling you
guys about my likes and dislikes.
I've never really thought
about my future dream...
As for my hobbies, I have many.
So in the end,
all we know is his name?
Yeah.
Now it's your turn.
Let's start with you.
My name's Naruto Uzumaki!
I like instant ramen,
but what I like even more
is the ramen from Ichiraku
that Iruka Sensei treats me to.
What I dislike is the three minutes
after pouring hot water
in the instant ramen.
My hobby is eating and
comparing ramen!
And my future dream...
is to surpass the Hokage!
And then the entire village
will have to
acknowledge my existence!
I see...
This kid's grown up in
an interesting way.
Okay, next.
I'm Sakura Haruno.
What I like...
I mean, who I like is...
And, my hobby is, I mean...
My future dream is...
And?
What about your dislikes?
Naruto!
And lastly.
My name's...Sasuke Uchiha.
There are lots of things I dislike,
and not much that I do like.
Oh...
And...
I don't believe much in "dreams",
but I do have an ambition!
The ambition to restore my clan,
and...
to kill a certain man!
I knew it...
Good!
The three of you are very distinct
and interesting!
We'll have a mission tomorrow!
Yes, sir! What kind of mission?
A survival exercise.
Survival exercise?
We've had more than our share
of survival exercises in the Academy!
This is no simple exercise.
Then...then what kind of exercise is it?
Hey! What's so funny, Sensei?
Uh, well, if I tell you,
I know you'd chicken out.
What?
Of the twenty-seven graduates,
only nine will be accepted
as genin.
The remaining eighteen will
be sent back to the Academy.
In other words, this exercise
is an extremely difficult test
with a 66% rate of failure!
See, see?
You're chickening out!
That's crazy!
To have suffered that much!
T-Then, what was
the graduation test for?
Oh, that.
It was just to select those who have
the potential of becoming genin.
Whaaaat?!
Well, In any event...
I'll be determining whether
you pass or fail.
Bring your complete set
of ninja tools!
We meet at five in the morning.
N-No way am I going to be
dropped now!
I've got to have my strength
recognized for real.
I'll be separated from Sasuke
if I fail this test.
This is an test of love!
Okay! You're dismissed.
Oh...and you'd best skip breakfast.
You'll throw up.
Morning.
Hi folks. Good morning!
You're late!
Well, a black cat crossed
my path, you see.
Ahem! Oh well...
Okay, the alarm is set for noon.
Your assignment is to take
these bells away from me before then.
Anyone without a bell,
doesn't get lunch.
You'll be tied to that stump...
and I'll eat your lunch
right in front of you.
So that was the point...
in having us skip breakfast...
But, hold on.
Why are there only two bells?
There are only two,
to ensure at the very least,
one of you will have to
go to the stump.
Also, that person will be disqualified
for failing the mission...
and will return to the Academy.
It might just be one of you...
or it could be all three of you.
You can use your shuriken.
If you don't attack with the intent to
kill me, you'll never get the bells.
But, that's dangerous, sir!
Y-Yeah, that's right!
You couldn't even evade
a chalkboard eraser!
In this world,
those who are weak
speak the loudest.
So, let's just ignore the loser...
Begin when I give
the "ready-go" signal.
Loser...Loser...Loser...
Don't be so hasty.
I didn't say start yet.
No way...!
I didn't see him move at all.
So this is a jonin.
But, that's fine.
At least you came at me
the intent to kill.
How should I put this?
I feel like I'm finally starting...
to like you guys.
Start!
Fundamentally, ninja must mask
their presence and hide.
Well, everyone is hidden pretty well...
Alright! Let's face off
fair and square!
Oh?
That fool...
Say, aren't you a bit
off kilter?
What's off kilter
is your hairstyle!
I'll teach your first
Shinobi Battle Skill...
Taijutsu.
Taijutsu...?
That's hand to hand combat...
So why...is he reaching for a weapon?
What's the matter?
Why don't you come at me?
But...hey...
why do you have a book?
Why, you ask?
Because I want to know
what happens next.
Don't mind it.
With you as my opponent,
it makes no difference
if I'm reading or not.
I'm going to rip you apart!
Darn! This time a spin kick!
Man!
Ninja shouldn't let the enemy take them
from behind multiple times, loser.
The way his hands are positioned...
Is that the Sign of the Tiger?!
No way!
With Naruto as his opponent,
that's too strong a ninjutsu
no matter how you look at it.
That sign...
He's going to use a fire style ninjutsu.
That idiot teacher's doing more
than just running around?
Naruto, get out of there quick!
You'll die!
Leaf Village Secret!
Ultimate Taijutsu!
One Thousand Years of Death!
That's...not a ninjutsu.
Those two are idiots.
Alright...
Even so,
isn't that against the rules?
What're we supposed to do
about his strength?
Damn it!
It wasn't supposed to be
like this.
What's the matter?
You won't get lunch if you can't
take the bell by noon.
No matter what...
I'm...not...
turning back now!
I'm going to become a ninja!
Security is your greatest enemy!
Now for my specialty,
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Seven...Narutos?
What? They're not just images?
Are they all real?
The real thing?
Not the clone,
but the shadow clone, eh.
Judging from your ability,
that jutsu should have
a one-minute limit.
Even if you talk trash,
Naruto is Naruto
after all is said and done...
W-What?! Behind me?!
"Ninja shouldn't let
the enemy take them from behind."
Right, Kakashi Sensei?
I had one of my Shadow Clones
sneak out of the water,
and circle behind you!
Here's payback for
what you did to my ass!
Naruto, not bad!
So...a diversionary tactic, eh?
Now...allow me to punch you!
What?!
Ouch!
You!
You're Kakashi Sensei, right?!
You used the Transformation Jutsu
to change yourself, didn't you?!
It's you!
You're Kakashi Sensei, I say!
You smell like Kakashi Sensei!
The smell of an old guy!
Why you!
Hey!
Why not just undo the jutsu?!
If we do that,
only the two will remain...so...
Why didn't you think of that
sooner, idiot?!
Because i'm you, idiot!
Just undo the jutsu!
Naruto...
You're embarrassing to watch...
That was the Substitution Jutsu,
you fool.
Essentially, it's a skill used
to quickly switch one's own body
with an object or animal.
This makes your enemy think
you're being attacked,
he used Naruto's own attack on him.
A bell?!
You really must have been in a hurry.
You've dropped a bell!
What the heck is this?!
Of course it's a trap...
That jonin doesn't lower his guard
even when he's fighting Naruto.
You have to think when using jutsu.
They can be used against you.
Also, don't get caught
in an obvious trap, you fool.
A ninja must see
through deception...got it?
I know that!
You clearly don't know it,
that's why I'm saying it.
Your movements are wasteful.
Now!
He finally dropped his guard!
You're so...
No way!
You jerk, Sasuke! You overdid it!
Damn! Another substitution?
And I just gave away my position
with that attack!
So he's over there, eh...
Sasuke...Where are you?!
Don't tell me,
Kakashi Sensei already...
No!
That couldn't happen to Sasuke, right?!
Safe! He didn't notice me.
Sakura, behind you.
Huh?!
"A ninja must see
through deception", my ass!
I'll never fall for one
of his stupid traps again!
I fell for it again!
What was that?! Huh?!
Hold on! Where's Sensei?!
Huh?! What's going on?!
Huh?! What's what?!
Sakura...
Sasuke?!
Sa...Saku...ra...
P-Please...help...me...
Maybe I went a bit overboard...
Was that voice...Sakura's?
Shinobi Battle Skill #2, Genjutsu.
Sakura was easily lured.
Genjutsu, huh...?
An illusory mind controlling technique.
I'm not surprised she got lured.
However...
I'm different from them.
Why don't you say that after
you get a bell...Sasuke?
It's no use just using
straightforward attacks.
A trap?!
This guy's...?!
What a guy.
There's no time
to read "Make Out Paradise."
What?!
That's right! I saw Sasuke on
the verge of dying and I...
Sasuke!
Don't die and leave me here!
Where are you?!
So that's what it looks like
behind the stumps.
Oh!
There are box lunches on the stone!
A ninja must see through deception...eh?
Well, I'll acknowledge that
you're different from those two.
Horse!
Tiger!
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
What?! That's not a jutsu
that a genin can do...
He shouldn't have
enough chakra for that yet!
He's gone!
Is he behind me?! No, above me?!
Shinobi Battle Skill #3, Ninjutsu.
How's that? You can't move, heh?
Although, you're...already starting
to make your mark.
Oh well.
They say the nail that sticks up is
the one that gets hammered down, so...
I don't have to bother with those bells.
I'll just eat in secret right now!
Let's eat!!
Hey.
I was just joking...
Too late!
Damn it! There was this much of
a difference in our strength?
Sakura...
This time it's a freshly severed head?!
What's up with her?
Sasuke?
You're okay!
Hey, cut it out!
Don't cling to me!
There's not much time left until noon.
I'm going.
Sasuke, you're still going
after the bells?!
I was able to touch them last time.
Next time I'll be able to take them.
What?!
I-I see.
Sure enough,
you're awesome, Sasuke.
There's no way I can take
a bell from Sensei.
At this rate, I'll be
separated from Sasuke...
Uh...say.
There's really no time left...
So let's just take it easy and
try again next time.
I'm the only one
who can kill that man.
Huh? What?
You mean Sensei?
That day...I was crying.
Crying?
My...
What? What is it?
I'm an avenger.
I must become stronger than him...
I don't have time for setbacks...
Damn it...
I wasted my time talking.
Oh oh, your stomachs are growling...
By the way, about this exercise...
Well, there's no need for you guys
to go back to the Academy.
Yahooooo!
Then, then!
That means the three of us...
Yes. The three of you...
should quit being ninja!
What do you want to know?
I don't think you invited
me here to just drink tea.
The jonin in charge of
Naruto's Team Seven...
What kind of teacher is he?
Is he strict?
You mean Kakashi?
Does he concern you?
I heard a rumor that concerns me.
What's this?
It's a pass-fail list of
the junior ninja
Kakashi has been
in charge of up until now.
Let me have a look.
T-This is!
Quit being ninja?!
What do you mean?!
Uh, well, it's true we weren't able to
take the bells...
But why does that mean
we should "quit"?!
Because not a single one of you
has what it takes to become a ninja.
Oh!
Sasuke!
I'm saying you're squirts.
Don't step on Sasuke!
Man, are you guys brainless or what?
Did you ever consider the point of
the three-man squad?!
How the hell are we supposed to know,
we didn't pick the teams!
It's...teamwork!
You might've been able to...
take the bells if the three of you
had come at me together...
Well, it's too bad.
Now wait a minute.
Why use teamwork if
there were only two bells?
Even if the three of us worked together,
one of us would still be held back.
That wouldn't be teamwork,
that'd create internal discord!
Of course!
This is a test set up to purposely
place you against each other.
To see if, under such circumstances,
you could set aside your own interests.
The intention was to select those
who could prioritize teamwork...
Yet, instead of that...
Sakura!
Your only concern was Sasuke,
though you didn't even know where he was.
All while ignoring Naruto,
who was right in front of you...
Naruto!
All you do is run solo...
And you labeled the other two as
hindrances and acted on your own too...
Missions are carried out in teams!
Yes, ninja do need
to have individual skills...
But "teamwork" is considered
more important than that.
Individuals that disregard teamwork
expose the team to danger...or death...
For example...
Sakura!
Kill Naruto, or Sasuke dies.
What?! What?! Whaaat?!
That is what will happen.
On top of having a hostage taken,
you're faced with two impossible choices
and end up being killed.
On every mission,
you're putting your life on the line.
Look at this...
At all the names engraved
on this stone...
These are all ninja who are
considered "heroes" of our village.
That's it! That's it!
That's it! That's it! I like thaaat!
I've decided now to get
my name engraved there, too!
A hero! A hero!
I'm not going to die like a dog!
But...they're not just ordinary heroes.
Really? Then, what kind
of heroes are they?
Hey! Hey!
They are heroes
who were killed in action.
This is a memorial.
The names of my best friends
are also engraved here...
I'll give you guys one more chance!
However, it will be far more
difficult than our last game.
Those who want to take on
the challenge can eat lunch.
But don't let Naruto have any.
It's his punishment for
attempting to eat lunch on his own.
If either of you feeds him...
that person will be disqualified
on the spot.
My word is law here.
Got it?!
Here.
H-Hey, Sasuke.
Sensei just said...
It's okay.
There's no sign of him now.
The three of us are going to go
take the bells together.
It'll be trouble for me
if he becomes a hindrance, so...
Sasuke...
It...can't be!
This is more than just a rumor.
Kakashi's test might
be a bit difficult...
Difficult is one thing, but...
No one? Absolutely no one has passed?
That's right...
Kakashi has never passed a student.
They have all...
been annihilated...
You three!
Yiiikes!
You defied the rules!
Do you know what's coming...
Do you have...anything to say?
You pass!
What?!
We passed?! Why?!
You guys are the first.
Up until now, it was always just dunces
who would meekly listen to what I said.
A ninja must see through deception...
In the world of ninja,
those who break rules and refuse orders
are scum...
But...
Those who abandon their friends
are worse than scum.
He's...He's...kinda...cool...
That's it for the exercise...
Everyone passes!
Team Seven starts our
first mission tomorrow!
Yes sir!
I did it! I'm a ninja!
Ninja! Ninja!
Let's go home.
Cha!
I...
knew this is how it'd turn out!
Untie the rope!