Hey...don't you want to see it?
It's about time.
What?
You know what I'm talking about.
Kakashi Sensei's...real face!
What are you doing?!
That's stupid!
I'm not interested.
Today's mission is over,
so I'm going home...
Yeah, I agree...
Aw geez...It sounds like fun.
Maybe he has...
Lips like cod roe?
Lips like cod roe...
Take one more push!
Or maybe buckteeth?!
Buckteeth?!
Buckteeth?! Buckteeth?!
Now this is rare...
Here you go! Thanks for waiting!
All three of you treating me...
Snow might fall
- Great success!
You know what I mean?
Here! Thanks for waiting!
All three of you treating me...
Snow might fall today?
Or if it's not that...
- Great success!
Maybe it's that...
Here! Thanks for waiting!
All three of you treating me...
Snow might fall today?
Or if it's not that...
are you guys up to something...
or not?
- Great success!
...like that.
Or if it's not that,
are you guys up to something?
Wh-Wh-What are you saying?!
K-Kakashi Sensei, we're celebrating
your release from the hospital!
N-Now! P-P-P-lease eat, eat!
All right...
Then I'll eat it without hesitation.
Thank you for waiting.
The pork slices are our treat.
Thanks for the treat.
Oh! Sasuke...
What a coincidence!
Get away! Ino Pig!
Wha?!
Aw man! I can't see at all!
I'm finished! That was good...
- So fast!
Huh? Something wrong?
N-Nothing's wrong!
Hey!
- Huh?
- Wow! I'm really curious!
What?! We're going to catch
another cat?!
Not quite.
It's actually a Nekomata.
Our mission is to get
the paw print of this Nekomata.
Nekomata, or whatever!
Let someone else go on
D-rank missions like that!
Right, Sasuke? Aren't you tired
of missions like this?
Speak up and tell him.
Sasuke?
If you don't like it, don't come.
This is an Uchiha...
or rather, my mission.
Why?!
I'm glad you came, Sasuke boy.
It's been a long time, Granny Cat.
My, how you've grown.
You know her, Sasuke?
What is this place anyway?
This is the shop where
the Uchiha clan buys weapons.
Granny Cat is the source of
invaluable data for the Uchiha.
She is also our client
for this mission.
Tamaki...
Bring me the Paw Encyclopedia.
Here you are, Granny.
You turned that into a book?!
Sasuke...
You seem to know a lot
about this mission.
Care to explain why?
Originally, this book was a game between
Sasuke and his older brother Itachi.
Don't talk about him!
I'm going to start preparations
for the mission.
What's with him?
They used to be so close back then.
Itachi often came by on errands
with little Sasuke in tow.
But Sasuke would get bored,
throw tantrums,
and give Itachi such a hard time.
So Itachi came up with the game
of gathering the paw prints
of quick and nimble cats.
You mean a kid's game.
Well yes.
But he already had the skills of a genin
even before entering the Academy.
He was an Uchiha all right.
Anyway,
it was a cute game at first.
But things began to escalate.
Sasuke completed nearly all the quotas
that Itachi half-jokingly assigned him.
And his collection of paw prints
became this book.
But even after Sasuke stopped,
it's bothered me.
As for one of two remaining quotas
that Itachi assigned,
I asked Ni'i of the Hidden Cloud,
and she kindly agreed.
Ni'i of the Hidden Cloud?
What's that?
And so, you're asking us to
get the last one?
However...
Nekomata is a big shot in
the ninja cat underworld
that never shows his face in public.
He hides in an impregnable fortress.
The number of ninja cats
who guard Nekomata is unknown.
Can a three-man cell
of genin manage this?
Just leave it to us!
Right, Sakura?
Even Itachi thought this was
too difficult for Sasuke
and wouldn't allow him to go.
You'll have to
exercise extreme caution.
So that's what was bothering Sasuke.
I'll go beyond the boundary he set.
Hey, Sasuke. Let's change into cats
and infiltrate that fortress!
I guess the best way to infiltrate
a fortress of cats is to become one.
Transformation Jutsu!
How is that supposed to be a cat?!
I thought I looked pretty good.
You don't have to transform.
Besides, transforming won't make
you understand cat talk.
And so! If you put these on,
the cats will think you're one of them!
If it's that simple, why didn't you give
me these from the very start?!
I-I'm expected to wear this?!
We're known in these parts,
so we can't go any further.
No ninja cat has ever
seen Nekomata's face.
Will you be able to find him?
Thanks to these,
infiltrating will be quite easy.
You look so cute, Sasuke!
If we can get in successfully,
the rest will be easy.
Let's go!
Hold it.
Sasuke, we're supposed to be able
to talk to ninja cats with this thing.
Meaning there's no need
to start a fight.
Let's just talk it out with him.
I'm sure he'll be happy to give us
one or two of his paw prints.
Impossible.
Why's that?
Having your paw print taken is
extremely embarrassing for a cat.
For humans, it's like being
stripped naked, then photographed.
Is that all? A nude photograph?
Just coax them gently.
I mean, even Sakura would allow it.
Right, Sakura?
As if! You pervert!
I think talking will be useless.
Thanks for showing us the way.
Get going, pervert.
Next!
I don't recognize you guys.
We're newbie cats!
Here.
For someone new,
you're quick to catch on.
What gave us away?!
Like I know!
This is a reward for you.
New cats that get
the idea are welcome!
What's the matter?
You're welcome to it.
W-We have to play along or
they'll get suspicious.
I must do this to get
Nekomata's paw print!
Hey, this is kind of fun.
Stupid sneeze.
This is fun.
A human! There's a human in our midst!
Huh?! W-What're you saying?!
You idiot! Let's go!
Hey, those two are suspicious too!
They're impostors! Alert! Alert!
S-Sasuke! Sakura!
O-Okay, I get it!
I'm guessing you're telling me
to leave, right?
Okay, I'm going.
Damn it.
It's back to the drawing board!
What's with all this security?
What's going on?
I heard some human slipped in.
A human?!
If he's nearby, I'll snare him!
We don't have to worry about Naruto.
We'll take advantage of the commotion
and search for Nekomata.
Sakura, you start from the east tower.
I'll take the west.
Huh? At the very least,
we need a two-man team for this.
They already know we've infiltrated.
Time is of the essence.
It's smarter to split up for the search!
O-Okay, I understand.
What's all the commotion?
Boss! A human! There's a human
who slipped into the fortress!
A human infiltrator?!
Kick him out this instant!
Right!
A human? It's been seven years since...
No, it couldn't be.
If I can't get past the front gate,
I'll just sneak in from
the side like a ninja.
The best place to
get information is a bar.
Your Matatabi drink, miss.
Oh...I didn't order yet.
It's from that customer over there.
May I join you?
Oh, yes.
A new acquaintance.
This occasion calls for...
You've gotta try this, it's so good!
Say, do you know a cat named Nekomata?
You mean, Boss?
He always stays in
the main fortress tower.
Oh, thank you.
You can have this.
Rigged plastic bottles?!
These are supposed to be used
against cats! Not by cats!
B-Boss is in the main tower.
We've been beaten!
So you made it all the way here.
Kid, who are you?
Are you Nekomata?
It'll be easy if you willingly
offer your paw.
If not,
it'll probably be quite painful.
You have the guts to stand before me
and make such threats.
What is this?
Who are you?
Disappear!
Mission accomplished!
You drew an unlucky number
that time, Nekomata.
I wanted to have a go with him
since he was Itachi's kid brother.
Besides, I couldn't refuse
a request from Itachi.
M-Monster!
In time, my kid brother will come.
When he does,
fight him with all your might.
Although, with your strength,
my brother doesn't have it
in him yet to beat you.
Then why?!
Growth occurs when one
goes beyond one's limits.
Realizing that is
also part of training.
I hate to admit it, but Sasuke passed
Itachi's test with flying colors.
Indeed.
But how unfortunate...
Those two brothers were so close.
Now, I will not allow myself
to be denied a glimpse of him!
But how are you going to see it?
That's...
We'll see it somehow...
I'm asking you how! You idiot!
Then, then, do you have
a good plan, Sakura?
That's...
We'll follow by completely marking him.
If we do that, he'll eventually
take his mask off.
Sasuke, you are really bright.
What's that big deal?
That was so average!
Did you say something?
Well, that's fine.
What's Kakashi Sensei doing?
I'm disappointed in him.
He noticed us!
Stupid Naruto!
We were found because of you!
I tell you it's not my fault!
What?!
I-It's being made into a movie?!
I'm going to go buy
an advance ticket.
Hey, he's begun to move!
We'll follow his track!
Yeah!
What? He's gone!
Damn, he got away...
Darn it, where did he go?
What are you guys doing?
Do you guys have
some business with me?
- N-Not really...
Seriously, those eyes.
They look like they want
to devour me.
Oh, come on!
I think it's kind of cute.
Anyway, you got the luck of the draw.
So you have to take care of it.
Don't worry.
You two make quite a pair.
I don't know how you can say that!
Ow! Hey, cut it out!
Ow! Ow! Ow!
A stray cat, a stray dog, a stray pig...
And now, a stray ostrich?
We may be going up in scale,
but I don't see how these silly missions
will improve our skills.
Missions, eh?
The purpose for this
isn't to improve skill.
You're not undergoing training.
Although I understand
why you're impatient.
In that case, use this ostrich
to improve your skills!
Hey, what're you doing?!
- Shut up and improve your skills!
- That's your responsibility!
I'm letting you have it! Oww!
Oww!
Oww! Oww!
We'll find an inn for the night.
Mr. Ostrich looks worn out too.
Jeez...If it were just us,
we'd be able to make it back
to the village by nightfall.
Huh? What's that?!
I'm gonna take a look!
Naruto! Not again!
Oww!
Let's go.
What could it be?
Not you too!
Huh?
A fight?
No, it seems to be a vendetta.
A vendetta?
You mean like when
someone fights for revenge?
Revenge...
Revenge...on a busy street
in the middle of the day?
Is that okay, Kakashi Sensei?
A vendetta permit, huh?
Depending on the land,
if someone is murdered,
the family members are given
permission to seek revenge.
As long as he has
an authorized permit from that land,
other nations will allow the vendetta.
I heard that man Tsukado
had a distant relative.
And the killer over there called
the relative out late at night.
Then he ruthlessly hit him from
behind with a rock, and killed him.
Awful story, huh?
The killer escaped and
the family wanted revenge.
And that man was chosen for the task.
What a villain.
Boss Kanabun,
it looks like a vendetta.
Now this is interesting.
Who do you think will win, boys?
Well...They say the hunter is
usually stronger than the hunted.
Nah, I'm not with you there.
The hunted one has a pretty mean look.
He's going for it!
No!
Whoa...
Huh?!
Hmm...
Looks like he won't be
getting his revenge.
What?!
Hey! Hold it!
Hey! You bastard!
Damn you...
Here!
Oh, thanks.
I almost had him.
It didn't look that way.
Amateurs can keep their opinions
to themselves.
I may not look it,
but I am a veteran of 34 vendettas.
Oh...
What?!
You mean you've failed 34 times?!
Next time, for sure!
I think not!
There is no way to know
that unless I try.
Next time, on my 35th attempt,
I may just successfully complete
my vendetta. Isn't that so?
All right, I understand!
Huh?
I'll help you!
I'll mobilize every ninja skill there is
and help you become a vendetta pro.
Huh?
Stupid Naruto!
Getting carried away like that!
Well,
let's leave Naruto to handle this.
We'll take a break at the inn.
Ridiculous.
Mister, leave it to me!
Lesson One!
You don't have enough anger
towards your enemy!
You have to be able to explode
with anger at any moment.
Then you'll never be caught
off guard for a vendetta!
Right...
Hey, you there!
Watch it, old lady! Cripes!
Hurry up and get on my back!
Huh? So where're you headed?
Cripes!
Huh? The next town?
Cripes, that's close!
- I don't care if it's far. Cripes.
- Um...That's not what I meant.
Lesson Two!
Take all vendettas seriously,
even the easy ones.
Get used to taking revenge!
Uh-huh.
Hey...
I shall assist!
Huh?
This one's for the shoulder!
- The shoulder! The shoulder!
- S-Stop it!
- That's not what I meant either.
Lesson Three!
Fill your mind with images of
your enemy until it's ready to burst,
then manifest your anger on paper.
Uh-huh...
How... How come your hated enemy
looks so nice?
You know, I don't think
you're cut out for vendettas.
And you're not cut out to be a coach.
Do you have to carry out the vendetta?
Yeah. I can't return home unless I do.
I want to finish this and go home.
To my aging mother and father.
An ostrich is running wild!
M-Mister?
That guy...Was he hiding his skills?
Boys!
Right!
Sorry. The ostrich bit through
his rope leash.
As I had suspected,
you are a master swordsman.
Huh?
What's going on?
If you're that strong, how come
you can't finish your vendetta?
I don't know.
It's just that, when I look into his eyes
the strength drains out of me.
It's those eyes.
It's those eyes that...
Mister...
I wonder what happened to that man.
He probably set out in pursuit
of his enemy.
Will he be doing that
the rest of his life?
What's going on?!
How's that, Mr. Vendetta?
Your tenacity won me over.
I want you to get your revenge,
so I brought your enemy to you.
Now, let's see you pay him back
to your heart's content.
Mister...
Whoa!
However, we of the Kanabun Gang
will oversee this vendetta.
All right, one and all!
Who's gonna win this vendetta?!
Place your bets now!
Who's the stronger one?
It's gotta be the one taking revenge!
He looks so hopeless.
No way he'll win!
I bet 500 ryo on his foe!
Me too!
If you're short on cash,
the Kanabun Gang will place
a bet for you!
If that guy uses his real strength,
this fight...
Yeah. We'll make a tidy profit.
That's terrible.
Making a buck off of his vendetta.
It all ends here.
Well...I can't die yet.
On guard.
What?! He's going to fight without
looking his opponent in the eye!
He just might win!
Don't tell me
Naruto's lessons helped.
I...I don't like this fight.
I wonder why...
It's him. Just like Mister said.
That guy's face...His eyes...
Those eyes again!
How can you be like that?!
You could be killed by me, so why?!
Why doesn't that guy
try to kill Tsukado?
Well then...
Wait!
The reason why
you couldn't kill this guy...
Deep down, you know why, don't you?
Yeah...I realized it just now.
I see...The blade has been dulled.
This man can't kill anyone.
I have a twin brother named Kageki.
A twin...brother?
Kageki had loaned money to Shikazo,
a member of your family.
But then, my brother had
a child and he needed money.
So he went back to ask to be repaid.
Shikazo ignored my brother
and tried to go back on his loan.
A scuffle broke out and
they both fell to the dirt floor.
At that moment, Shikazo hit his head
on a pickling stone and died.
Are you saying it was an accident?
Kageki said he was going
to turn himself in.
But there were no witnesses.
Considering the circumstances,
he'd probably have been
accused of murder.
So I offered to switch places with him.
What?
I took his identity
and sent him and his wife,
who had just given birth, into hiding.
In order to buy them time,
I purposely attracted
the attention of his pursuers.
I couldn't let a great guy
like him ruin his life.
Whereas I've been a scoundrel
who's caused nothing
but grief to my family and to society.
I figured it was a way to
make amends.
I only have my
kid brother's word for it.
There's no way to prove it,
but I trust him.
Mister...
It's up to you whether
you believe me or not.
If you don't...Then kill me.
Well then, I'm going to believe you.
- You...
- Mister!
Actually, I'm sick and tired of
this thing called revenge.
If you've pretended all these years
to be my foe...
Well, starting now,
I'll just pretend that I'm on a vendetta.
The way this ended...
It was okay, right, Kakashi Sensei?
Well...
That's for those two to decide.
Revenge is a hard thing, isn't it?
What would you know?
Huh?
Sometimes, a vendetta must be carried out,
no matter how hard it is.
Hey, how did he find us out?
Isn't it because there
are too many of us?
If the presence is erased,
the number of people shouldn't matter!
Or...have you forgotten the jutsu?
Sakura...
That's you!
It will be good
training to shadow him.
From now on,
we'll go about it individually.
Y-Yeah,
let's just leave Naruto here!
What?!
And Junko then says...
"Oh, I am losing you."
What? What?
He got away...
Clumsy as usual...
You idiot...
Sorry.
Gosh, what is Kakashi Sensei doing?
He hasn't moved for
such a long time...
No way!
Sasuke! How did it go?!
No more shadowing
People of the Leaf Village.
I am here to offer you a moment's respite
with some song and dance.
Hanare...
Hey. Good job on
another mission.
Now I can finally
eat Ichiraku ramen!
Sounds good.
You're treating, Naruto.
Huh? Oh, fine already.
But you know...
How about you treating us
for a change, Sasuke?
I'm off to train.
Then, maybe Kakashi Sensei can...
Huh?
Wow...
She's beautiful.
Was she arrested?
I'm told she's a kunoichi who
disguised herself as a street performer
to gather information
about the Land of Fire.
What's going to happen
to her now?
Well, she'll be interrogated to
see just what she found out.
They'll use whatever
means necessary.
Until she starts talking.
Welcome.
To the "Honesty Room."
She is well trained to be able to
resist your interrogation.
Not even a single moan, sir.
Only the sound of
her gritting her teeth.
What an impressive kunoichi.
Well then...We'll have to reach into
that silence and find her inner voice.
I understand.
Then please summon Inoichi.
They look...like clouds.
Just like the ones
from that day.
We're done with the pain.
Time for a more humane approach.
Hanare...
Infiltrate the Land of Fire and
investigate the Hidden Leaf.
The Hidden Leaf Village?
Our nation has survived through the years
not with military might, but espionage.
We use the information we gather to
plan strategies and gain the advantage
in diplomatic negotiations with
other nations to avert conflict.
The fate of our nation rests
in your hands, Hanare.
Yes sir!
I will not fail you.
What's that?
That headband...
It belongs to the Hidden Lock Village
in the Land of Key.
She was captured before
she had infiltrated the Hidden Leaf.
She didn't learn anything
of importance.
Sorry, but now it's my turn to get
some information about your village.
What's going on?
She has no memories
about her village at all.
Was it my imagination?
What?
Memories of me as a kid?
Yeah, do you remember anything?
No, I've never met her.
I see.
Did you learn anything else?
Nothing significant.
And she had no memory
regarding the Lock Village.
She probably purged it.
Purged?
But, something is bothering me.
Just something...
Part of it is the fact that
she had memories of you.
But she's hiding something.
Something that even I can't dig up.
And that, Kakashi, is what
I want you to find out.
Huh? Me?
But I'm not a member of
the Intel Division.
You may be able to see
further into her psyche.
Are you a fool?
You're showing me around the very
village I infiltrated for espionage.
You won't find anything different
here than in any other village.
And besides, I thought you could use
some air after being in that stuffy place.
Which flower should I choose?
What?
Uh-huh...
What? No way!
What?!
Kakashi Sensei?!
Kakashi?
Are you curious too?
It's not like that.
It's that lady!
What's Kakashi doing with
someone like her?
Hey!
Come over here.
It's not like I'm trying to
draw out information from you.
I was just asked to spend
the day with you.
Once the day is done,
so is my duty.
What will happen to me?
Who knows?
That cloud resembles Naruto.
And next to that is...
Sasuke maybe?
I see...my mother and father,
who gave me life.
Although I never met them.
When things got hard, when I was sad,
I always looked up at the clouds.
I'd stare at the clouds
and imagine.
Life in the village...
And my parents who
supposedly live there.
Otherwise,
I couldn't have endured.
Not knowing who my parents were,
and not knowing about my village.
Or my fate of being born simply
to become a spy.
I can't hear them.
But they seem suited
for each other.
How silly.
I'm going to get closer.
I don't know my village.
I was raised outside the village,
so that I couldn't divulge any
information in case I was captured.
And to this day, I risked my life
to carry out missions
for a homeland
I've never even seen.
That's why it meant everything...
To have a home.
To have people who would accept me.
Why tell me?
You've remained silent
all this time.
That's because...
you taught me.
I knew the moment I saw you.
That you were the boy
from back then.
I wanted to see my parents
and I set out for the village.
But I got lost and
was feeling helpless.
You told me to look up at the clouds
whenever I'm feeling lonely.
Because clouds change their form so you
can envision the things you wish for.
You said as long as you have hope,
the clouds will always answer your call.
I always searched for
your likeness in the clouds.
So I recognized you immediately,
even though you've changed quite a bit.
Because you've always
been in my heart.
You were my hope.
Whoa...Things are
starting to heat up.
Wait, Naruto! You'll...
Hey, you three!
Huh?! Uh...
You see, this is...
Give me that!
C-Congratulations!
Huh?
Thank you.
The Lock Village has captured Riichi,
one of our jonin.
The Lock Village?
You mean the village where
that kunoichi is from?
Yes...
And the other side has proposed
to exchange Riichi for Hanare.
Fortunately, it seems Hanare
holds very little information
about the Land of Fire and
the Leaf Village.
So releasing her
would be harmless.
No, you can't!
I'm opposed to returning
Hanare to them!
It's not a Transformation Jutsu.
That is definitely Riichi.
All right! One man from each side
will accompany their prisoner,
and the exchange will be made
at the center of the bridge.
Agreed?
Agreed!
Kakashi Sensei...
I never thought it would
turn out like this.
I won't let you go.
Hanare!
Bring back information on
the Hidden Leaf without fail!
Retreat!
It's begun!
Old man, give up!
Don't underestimate us Lock ninja.
Once a key is locked,
not even death could open it!
Kakashi Sensei!
Where's Hanare?
I guess she felt cornered
and gave up.
She jumped off the cliff.
An admirable ninja.
- No...
- Are you okay with this, Kakashi Sensei?!
What if that lady
really did love you?
Enough!
It's pointless.
Off we go!
Today's mission is to help at a farm.
The mission itself is not a big deal.
We're definitely going to look at it...
- Kakashi Sensei's real face!
What's the matter?
You guys seem to have
lots of energy today.
- I have lots of energy!
- I'm ready to go!
Oh, that's excellent.
I've finally found you...
Kakashi Hatake!
Kakashi...
It has been a long while,
but I will settle
my long standing grudge!
Boss, what is your grudge?
Fool! Have you forgotten?!
I cannot forget.
It happened in the spring
of three years ago...
No!
You don't need to be that scared.
Our boss says he has something
to talk to you about...
Your boss?!
I love you...Please marry me!
- Boss is so cool!
No...
There's no need to be embarrassed.
You can be honest and
fly into my arms.
No...
Don't worry.
Even though I look like this,
I have a tidy sum of money!
I am telling you, no!
What? You're turning me down
in these surroundings?
When I say no, I mean no!
I made it such a romantic setting,
but why?
I don't like what I don't like!
Why don't you stop it around there?
- Huh?
Hey, the girl doesn't like it
and no matter how you look at it,
you're being rejected, buddy.
Yeah, yeah.
You're pretty gutsy.
Do you understand who we are?!
Are you challenging us, knowing that
we are the Moya Ninja Threesome...
fearsome enough to silence
a crying child?!
Moya Ninja? Never heard of it.
You don't know Moya Ninja?!
How dare you make fools of us!
Who the hell are you?
It's not worth
enough to introduce, but...
Well, my name is Kakashi Hatake.
- You're introducing yourself!
Hey you...
You're going to regret it.
For getting in the way of
someone's romance!
Romance?
Isn't it just an annoying,
one sided love?
Enough!
Men! We're going to attack!
- Yes, sir!
4...3...2...1...
- Hustle! Hustle!
Please! Somebody help me!
Hey! I can't stand heights!
I'll take you back to the village.
Stop talking! Hey!
Hey, quit sighing!
What, are you just leaving us here?!
That's how it went...
- Don't be so proud!
- You lost!
So it means revenge from
three years ago
Boss has become stronger
in the last three years,
and he's going to beat him up
in a face to face match!
That's so dramatic!
Fool! Who would take such risk?!
Huh?
If we're going to do it,
we'll do it stealthily from
the shadows! Stealthily.
- D-Dirty!
Welcome!
Welcome! Welcome! Welcome!
Incredible!
Looks delicious!
How extravagant.
Please take your time...
Kakashi...
Now eat, this will be
your last dinner party.
That meal contains
a tasteless and odorless medicine
that causes uncontrollable hiccups.
Just keep on having
the ceaseless hiccups and die suffering!
It's a fitting end for you!
Something wrong?
Not one of you has
even laid chopsticks on the food.
Not really, but why don't you,
Kakashi Sensei, hurry up and eat?
Well, I'm on a diet.
Figured he'd say something like that.
Then I'll strip off that mask
if it kills me!
My hands slipped...
How could you!
Oh, sorry, sorry, I unintentionally...
- What do you mean "unintentionally"?!
What a pity! The meal...
- How could he do such a thing
Hey, what's the next move?
Don't worry. I have an idea.
- An idea?
I see, this is pretty good thinking
for Sasuke.
A person would normally
take off the mask here.
Never mind that.
Just be quiet, you idiot!
Kakashi, you will die here!
From this needle on the blowpipe arrow,
coated with medicine I prepared
that will make you laugh uncontrollably...
You'll die laughing...
That is the fitting way for you...
Darn...
I wanted to see it too,
but this is a hot spring...
But I want to see!
Kakashi Sensei!
Aren't you ready yet?
All right, I'm coming in now.
I do want to see it!
Here he comes!
Great!
Oh, I can't see at all!
Thanks for waiting.
I'll just soak for a little while.
- Why is it like this?!
Now!
Huh? Something wrong
And slowly, I sink in.
What the?!
What happened?
I want to know!
What in the world is
Kakashi Sensei thinking? Huh?
Darn, I'm completely flushed...Huh?
- Our clothes are gone!
Please come again!
Thank you for coming!
Crap...I'm going to
definitely defeat you, Kakashi Hatake.
But it was great that
we brought spare clothes.
I wonder who took them away...?
Our clothes!
All right,
each of you work at your own posts.
Now, break up.
I can't stand it anymore...
I have too much stress stored inside.
I'm almost at the end of
my patience as well...
Sasuke...actually, me too...
Then, it's the last resort!
- Last resort?
What is this?
Can't you see? It's shinobi outfit.
When did you get this ready?
Well, well, never mind that,
never mind that.
What do you do with this?
We'll strip away the mask.
Even if we have to use force!
Damn Kakashi...
Boss! Look at that!
Hey, Kakashi Hatake!
Hey, what are you guys up to?
W-What are you talking about?
We are simply ninja.
It is not that we want to see
what is behind your mask!
Fool!
Don't say unnecessary things!
That's...!
Boss! There's somebody else besides you
who holds a grudge on Kakashi!
Now is the chance!
Right! Let's go
- Right!
Stop right there!
Kakashi! It's time for you
to pay for your crime!
You shall die!
With this medicine I prepared
that will make you cry...What?!
Oh, just when I thought how long
you guys were going to sneak around...
you finally come out.
Ah, well, you know...
But before that,
Sasuke, Sakura, Naruto!
Why are you guys dressed like that?
Huh?! Well, yeah, so...
Oh no...
We have to make up an explanation,
whatever it is!
Caught you!
We were well aware that
you three were targeting Kakashi Sensei!
What?! Then our plot was exposed
from the beginning!
Of course!
This was a trap to lure you guys out!
We caught you off guard!
So we were completely caught
in the trap.
Darn! We underestimated you,
thinking it was kids!
I never heard that story!
Nice, Sakura!
I don't quite get what's happening,
but oh well...
- Please forgive us!
There's no use talking...
- O-Oh no!
- S-Stop!
It's the same as three years ago!
This time, we're hung by just one rope,
combined with the same movement.
By the way, who are you guys?
- And he doesn't even remember us!
Hey, Kakashi Sensei.
Yeah?
What is behind that mask?
What? You wanted to see
what's behind this mask?
Yeah!
Then you should have said
that from the beginning...
Well, can you show us?
I don't mind...
What the?!
Sure thing.
All right...
Is it like cod roe?
Buckteeth?
Or a tiny mouth?
Behind this mask...
- Behind that mask...
There happens to be another mask!
- What?!
What?!
What in the world is that?!
According to our Intel,
the thieves who took the golden statue
are either traveling on land
through this forest path
or sailing by boat and will land here.
We're going to split up into
two teams and lie in wait for them.
In terms of balance,
I guess I should go alone and
the three of you will be together.
What do you mean by that?
Are you saying Sasuke needs
all the help he can get?
No, you're the hindrance.
I'm not up to your level yet,
but surely 3 to 1 is too much.
Why don't you take Naruto
off my hands?
Subtract his skill from yours,
and we'll be even.
Huh?!
Sasuke, is that just
a clever approach
so that you and I
can be alone together?!
You've got to be kidding!
Why would you subtract my skill?!
Because you have nothing to add.
What?!
Sasuke wants to be with me so much,
he's getting impatient!
You're just as irritating!
Okay, pay attention.
I'll watch the pier.
And you three will keep an eye
on this path in the forest.
If the thieves appear,
notify me immediately.
Do not take them lightly.
Our mission is to retrieve
the golden statue.
We must proceed with utmost caution.
If the thieves appear on my side,
I will send a signal with this.
When this lightning barrel
is tossed into the air,
it will release one thunderbolt.
Once you verify it,
rush straight to that location.
You better handle that with care.
Now remember.
You are not to act alone.
It's the gang of thieves!
Why you...
Idiot!
Careful with the treasure!
I'm sorry, Boss Jako!
Shape up!
Yes sir!
Treasure?! In that wicker box?
This is...my chance!
Amazing, Naruto!
You showed up Sasuke real good!
Don't tell me he's up to the same...
I won't lose to him!
W-What's this?
Damn! The treasure!
What are those two doing?!
We have to notify
Kakashi Sensei first!
What? There's another?
Let go of the treasure!
No way!
Take this!
I won't lose it.
Huh?
Damn it.
Pursuers from
the Hidden Leaf, eh?
Were those two
the only ones with you?
There must be others.
That's why you tried to get word out
about this location.
Cool, huh?
I'm a natural-born thief
who's rotten to the core.
So as you can see,
even my chakra is foul.
Those two escaped downriver.
We'll split up and concentrate our search
along the river and we'll find them.
And we'll take back the treasure.
What about her?
We might be able to use her
as a hostage.
Bring her with us.
I can't believe they stole
something stupid like this.
The thunder...
Huh?
The thunderbolt to signal Kakashi
didn't go off, did it?
No.
Maybe Sakura couldn't release it.
Sakura's been captured?!
- Huh?
Wha-?
- What is this?!
W-What's going on?
We're stuck together.
- Ready...pull!
Why is it always with you?!
That's my line!
Don't worry.
You'll see your friends soon.
After they return the treasure
I'll send you to
the afterlife together.
Even ninja are helpless
if their hands are bound.
Sasuke...Naruto...
Sakura...
While we're stuck like this,
Sakura could be...
You idiot, Naruto!
Sakura...I'm coming to save you!
Wait! You fool!
What the hell are
you doing, Sasuke?!
Don't you care what happens
to Sakura?!
We will save Sakura!
But we can't do anything if
our hands are like this.
We're going to save her despite that.
It's what friends do!
I...I don't want to be some scum who
doesn't give a damn about his friends!
Those who abandon their friends
are worse than scum.
Then joining up with Kakashi
is the right move to make!
It will increase Sakura's chance
of survival!
Don't talk about
her chance of survival!
It just depends on how hard
we want to save her!
We can't let Sakura die
over something this stupid!
You idiot! Stop it, Naruto!
Damn it...Damn it...Damn it...
You know, a guy who doesn't take
his mission seriously is also scum.
Gotta pee.
What?!
I said, I need to take a leak!
Hey, what the hell?!
Uh...well...
Okay, one hand then.
Cut it out! Not so close!
What if you spray me too?!
I don't care what you say.
If I gotta go, I gotta go.
Hold it in!
Can't.
- Just let me finish, okay? Come on.
- Zip up, you idiot!
You're in my way, Naruto!
You're the one who's in my way!
Give back the treasure!
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Like you can weave a sign
with one hand!
Didn't I tell you?
At this rate,
we don't have a chance,
even against guys much
weaker than us!
Naruto...wait!
I'm going.
If you refuse...
I'll cut off my arm, then go.
I'm going to beat this guy
and save Sakura!
You're so reckless!
I'm going to save Sakura.
Since the enemy came this far,
we'll probably be found before
we catch up to Kakashi.
If that's the case,
it'll be faster if we make this guy
tell us where Sakura is and save her.
Sasuke...
Though it'll depend totally
on us working together.
Right!
Oh, I just remembered.
I gotta pee.
Me too.
What? Suguro hasn't come back?
I wonder if he...
You're wondering right.
Yeah!
Sasuke! Naruto!
Huh?
Free at last.
Only a Feudal Lord's sister
could own a gold statute like that.
It managed to pull us apart.
Their hands are free now?
You can have it
in exchange for our partner.
If you don't agree
I'll pulverize every one of you,
now that my hands are free.
Surely you don't think that
mere robbers can beat two ninja?
How come you're gritting
your teeth so hard?
Your veins are popping out
and you're sweating.
If you're free,
come over here.
Come on!
Their hands are still fused!
There's nothing to fear!
Get them!
He called our bluff!
Can't help it!
Why you...
Wha-?!
- Naruto!
- Right!
Oh no!
Look out, you two!
The treasure is mine!
We can stop at least one of his hands.
- Let's go!
- Right!
Oh no, you don't!
Fire Style!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
What?! A seal?
Even if we can weave signs together,
we can't mold chakra.
Why you...Taking me for a fool!
But we do have a combination attack!
What?!
Pachinko Jutsu!
Well, I guess it can be
melted down and re-cast.
Just maybe.
Thank you, Sasuke!
Hey, I did my best too.
This is ridiculous!
How come you, of all people,
can't undo this, Kakashi Sensei?!
Remember, that boss said so too.
It'll crumble apart in
two or three days.
Like I can put up with him
for that long!
That's my line.
Uh-oh...I think I need to go.
Not again.
This time it's number two.
You've got to be kidding.
Don't you dare, Naruto!
Aw c'mon, we already peed together.
This is worse!
"Those who abandon their friends
are worse than scum."
These three overcome it so easily.
With that being said,
our mission is over.
You're dismissed.
We're done already?
But it's only ten in the morning!
Lately, all of our missions
have been so boring!
When are we gonna get
an S-rank mission?
"S-rank"?
A loser like you?
What are you talking about?
We're still genin!
I want something with
more pizazz...more oomph!
Uh, there aren't any.
Okay, dismissed!
You heard him, Sasuke.
So how about today,
just the two of us...
I'm going home.
Just hold on a minute.
There's only one S-rank mission
that we can do.
A mission that's
failed numerous times...
One that only we can pull off...
...to see what Kakashi Sensei's face
really looks like!
Let's find out what the best-kept
secret about our target is!
Why are you trying to act like
you know what you're saying?
Just forget about that already.
Right, Sasuke?
This is the perfect mission
for a day like today.
I couldn't agree more!
I got tricked!
Cha!
But what do we do?
Every time we try,
it never goes well.
I already have a plan!
What is it?
Photos!
If we go through every single photo
Kakashi Sensei is in,
there's bound to be at least one...
I never told you this,
but I already checked once before.
He has a mask on in every one.
The photo submitted to the Hokage
for the Ninja Registration Form...
...should be one of him
without a mask.
But it's an extremely classified,
top-secret document...
Accessing it would be no easy task.
Who are you?
I'm Sukea, a photographer.
I travel to the east and west
looking for scoops.
What about north and south?
Naruto!
You've been getting hung up on
insignificant details since earlier!
Anyways,
I was searching around for a scoop
and happened to overhear
an interesting conversation...
He did hear us!
Should we get rid of him?!
You idiot!
Ouch!
He's right.
There's a rule that the photo for
the Ninja Registration Form
must be of your entire face.
It's so obvious, we didn't even
think about looking there.
Will you let me join you
in this adventure?
What's your motive?
If I'm able to capture
this Kakashi guy without a mask,
I'll have the biggest scoop since
the Hidden Leaf was established.
Even if it's hushed up, I'm sure to
make a lot of money out of this.
Hey! Hey!
When you get the money, you have to
treat us to ramen! Promise?
I'll even throw in some dumplings.
So it's settled then?
This is getting interesting...
Oh, you guys...
I'm getting kind of
excited for this!
Secret documents are stored here...
This is an infiltration mission...
Mr. Sukea, will you
be able to keep up?
Before I started taking pictures,
I was a rank-and-file ninja...
All right! Let's begin the mission!
Not done yet, Sasuke?!
Shut up... Wait!
Can we switch?
It opened! Wow!
Sukea...
What division did you belong to?
The Intel Unit that reported
directly to Lord Hokage.
That's the...
ANBU Black Ops.
Things happened
and now I'm retired.
Considering your past,
is it wise for you to be doing this?
You'll be targeted by the ANBU.
Don't worry about it.
C'mon, let's go.
We have to search in all of these?
Let's hurry.
Found it! This is it!
Okay, let's open it.
The moment is finally here!
Don't move!
We're taking you in.
Make a move and
we'll take that as resistance...
Depending on the situation
we may have to take you down.
I-I feel like I'm going to sneeze.
Idiot! Hold it in!
Damn it...we were so close!
Really? An infiltration mission?
I'm so sorry...I tried to stop them,
but they insisted...
Huh?! What a jerk!
So you planned on blaming us
from the start if this failed?!
They wanted to see
what you really looked like...
You're a former ANBU Black Ops,
aren't you?
Honestly!
Who cares what I really look like?!
You've got some nerve blaming us!
I thought it was strange.
You're skilled,
and you're a former ANBU.
You could've done this alone.
I can't stand guys who are handsome,
but do nasty things.
Sorry! Sorry!
I'll make it up to you by helping you
photograph Kakashi Sensei's face.
This time with
my photography skills.
What? You're still gonna do this?
Why? You're already giving up?
What's your plan?
Let's go for Kakashi himself.
We'll lure him out to a meal,
then photograph him while he eats.
We tried many times and failed.
Every time, at the very moment
we have a chance to see his face,
we get interrupted.
With this multi-exposure
camera I built,
we should get at least one photo.
Sensei! I need to talk to you about
something very important, ya know?!
What is it?
Well, why don't we eat
some dumplings while we talk?
I'm ready!
All right, I'm gonna
take you up on your offer!
Hey, Naruto!
Were you guys
out taking a stroll too?
Don't bother us! We're doing
something really important!
What is it?
I'm about to find out.
He already ate it?!
But this time,
we got you on camera!
This is...impossible...
You're kidding...
Not a single one?
I feel like some divine power
is at work here.
I guess this means...
the mission is over
and dismissed, huh?
I guess I'll be...
Hey, Naruto!
What are you guys up to?
Kiba...
And everyone!
Kakashi Sensei!
P-Perfect timing!
U-Um...
O-Over there...
What's wrong?
Calm down and tell me.
A woman's drowned...
O-Over there by the river...
What?!
This isn't good.
Her pulse is weak.
Good job, Sakura!
Her medicine's even fooled
Kakashi Sensei!
This calls for...
He definitely has to
take his mask off now!
This woman's in danger!
We can't waste any time!
We have to get her to the hospital!
Plan A...failed.
Understood.
Everyone, switch to Plan B.
Mr. Sukea, please get into
position as well.
Roger.
All right, he's coming!
Just as Shikamaru predicted,
he's gonna pass this way
to the hospital.
Everyone get in position!
Expansion Jutsu!
Human Boulder!
Roll! Roll! Roll!
What're you doing?!
We have to get her to...
Go!
Hidden Jutsu: Beetle Sphere!
Now!
3...2...1
Scatter!
Mind Transmission Jutsu!
Look, you guys...
I get that you want to see
what I look like,
but think of the situation
at hand here!
She needs to get to
the hospital ASAP!
Shadow Possession Jutsu!
Complete!
Do it now, Sukea!
It finally worked, Naruto.
You can have ramen
and dumplings now!
Hey guys, the plan worked!
Finally...
You guys should all be
grateful to us.
That's because...
Okay, Kakashi Sensei...
Get ready!
Do it, Shikamaru!
It's time for the unveiling.
Wait, wait, you guys.
Let's just talk things over.
H-Hey!
Stop! Stop!
C-Calm down!
Keeping this a mystery makes it
more alluring, don't you think?
Ramen and dumplings at Ichiraku
sound way more alluring to me.
So you were bribed!
Checkmate!
Hey! Wait!
I mean, please wait!
You're being annoying, Lee!
Please spar with me!
Neji!
What?
Don't interfere!
Enough is enough, you two!
Hey! Wait!
Sorry!
Ouch!
A S-Shadow Clone?
What's the hell is going on?
Does this mean Kakashi Sensei was
on to us from the very beginning?
It was too bad...But I'm really
grateful to all of you.
Nah...Thanks to you Sukea,
we had a great time!
Thank you!
I'd better get going.
Let's team up again
if something comes up.
Hope you get your scoop!
They really seem like
they're having fun!
It was sheer coincidence that Kiba
came to the dumpling shop...
But who would have thought
everyone would team up.
But something like this is good,
once in a while.
But it really wears me out...
...using this many Clones
and Transformations.
It was a close call with my mask...
because of everyone's teamwork.
Even if they got the mask,
it's no harm done.
Because I'm wearing
a back-up mask underneath.
Food is the best way!
That has the highest probability...
But the problem is, how do we get
Kakashi Sensei to eat with us.
Bad timing!
They're coming this way!
Hey!
Excuse me,
but did you notice any kind of
trouble going on around here?
Huh? No, there wasn't anything...
Kakashi...
I heard him and his team were making
a commotion all around town.
Sorry for stopping you.
N-No problem.
Hey.
Uh, can I help you?
Don't I know you from somewhere?
N-No...
I don't think so
Really?
Well, excuse me. Later!
I could have sworn
I've met him before...
Changing your voice
really puts a strain on the throat.
It turned out to be
a good mission after all...
Their teamwork's gotten
much better than it was
during the bell-snatching mission.
Oh well...
I can probably only keep this up
for about two or three more attempts...