I overslept!
Hey, hey! Where is everyone?
Naruto. Your Sensei wanted you
to rest and relax today...
I knew it.
They left me behind.
I'll be back.
W-What the heck is this?!
What is going on?
What's happened?
It can't be...
Inari! Give me a hand.
Inari!?
I'll be right there.
This mist...
Sasuke! Sakura!
They're coming!
I knew he was still alive.
Making an appearance so soon, eh...
Say, Kakashi Sensei.
This is his...
Hidden Mist Jutsu, right?!
Sorry to have kept
you waiting, Kakashi.
I see you've got those brats
with you as always.
He's still trembling. Poor thing.
I'm trembling with...excitement.
Do it, Sasuke.
I can see it!
Well well. So he could
see the Water Clones, eh.
That brat's grown quite a bit.
You might even have a rival, Haku.
So it seems.
Damn it!
They could've woken me up!
Well, well...It seems my prediction
was right on the money.
Prediction?
That little mask...
Oh!
I knew it...Heh!
So the Elite Shinobi of
the Hidden Mist thing
was a bald faced lie!
No matter how you look at it,
he's gotta be a comrade of Zabuza.
Standing together with him and all...
How dare he show up like that
after what he did!
I hate brats who
think they're so cool...
He's better than you, Kakashi Sensei.
Oh...really?
I'll do it.
Huh?
With his bad acting...
I hate brats who think they're so cool!
Sasuke, you are so cool!
That Sakura doesn't
take stabs at Sasuke...
He's an impressive kid.
Hmm...
Even though those Water Clones
have only 1/10th the strength
of their original...
To think he did so well.
However, you made
the preemptive move.
Go!
Right!
Are you Tazuna's daughter?
Sorry, but you're coming with us.
Mom!
Don't come in here!
Get out, quick!
What's with you, brat?!
Should we take him, too?
One hostage is fine.
Hostage...?!
Then...
Shall we kill him?
Wait!
If you lay a hand on that child...
I'll bite off my tongue
and kill myself!
You want a hostage, right?
Thank your mom, kid.
Oh, man...
It's not enough...
Knock it off.
You just tried out your sword earlier.
Forget it already and
let's take the woman.
Mom, I'm sorry...
I'm so sorry!
I'm weak, so I can't protect you...
I don't want to die...
I'm scared!
You crybaby...
So you're just gonna cry all day
like the lead in a tragedy?
An idiot like you can just
cry forever! You crybaby!
For the things I truly hold
dear to myself...
I'll protect them until the end
with both these arms,
even if it looks like
I might lose my life!
Inari...
Dad!
Looking at that beautiful skin
of yours makes me want to cut you.
Hey...walk faster.
Wait!
Inari!
What?
It's just the kid from before.
Get...get away from my mom!
Man...This brat's hopeless.
Let's do it!
If you do that, I'll bite off
my tongue and--
Shut up. Go to sleep.
I...na...ri.
The Substitution Jutsu...?!
The woman...Hmm?
Sorry I was late.
Heroes usually appear
on the scene late, so...
Naruto!
Inari, you did well!
Huh?
Thanks to you distracting them,
I was able to save your mom.
Naruto...how did you know that
those thugs were here?
In the forest, there was a boar that
had been cut up with a sword.
And on top of that,
there were trees with lots of cuts.
They headed in
the direction of your house...
so I got worried.
I see.
Well...
If it isn't the no good ninja
that Tazuna hired...
Let's do it...
Yeah...
Here they come!
Hah!
Something like that won't work!
Fools.
W-Wow...!
I'm...sorry about yesterday.
Huh?
Calling you a crybaby...
Forget I ever said that.
You're strong!
Dang it!
I...decided never
to cry again, but...
Now you'll laugh at me again
and call me a crybaby.
It's okay...when you're happy.
It's okay to cry when you're happy!
Naruto...
Now then.
I can leave the rest to you, right?
Yeah...
Okay, I'm going to hop over
to the bridge for a bit.
Man, it's tough being a hero!
Sure is!
Well, well...
He can keep up with that speed, eh?
Yes...
Sakura, surround Tazuna and
don't move away from me.
Let Sasuke handle him!
Okay.
I don't want to have to kill you...
I'd like for you to back down.
Nonsense...
I figured...
But you won't be able to keep up
with my speed.
And I've already made
two preemptive moves.
Two preemptive moves?
The first one is the scattered water.
And the second one was
blocking one of your hands...
Leaving you only one hand to
defend yourself from my attacks.
A one handed Sign?
I've never seen such a thing before...
A Thousand Needles of Death!
So he doesn't want to kill him...eh?
Remember...that training...
Build up chakra at one point...
He vanished...
You're surprisingly slow...
To think Haku would
lose in a battle of speed...
It seems that I'm faster than you...
I can't have you mocking our team,
calling them brats...
He may not look it,
but Sasuke is the number one rookie
of the Hidden Leaf Village.
And Sakura is our sharpest...
And the other one is
the number one hyperactive,
knucklehead ninja, Naruto Uzumaki.
Haku, do you know what this means?
At this rate, you'll be defeated
by your intended victim...
Yes...
What...?
It's unfortunate...
Is this...cold air...?
Hidden Jutsu:
Crystal Ice Mirrors!
Are these...mirrors?!
Damn it!
I'm your opponent, aren't I?
Now then...I'll start.
I shall show you...
my true speed!
If you make a move,
I'll kill those two!
I'm sorry, Tazuna!
I'm stepping away
from here for a bit.
Sure. Go!
Take this!
What?!
That idiot...what a showoff...
The number one hyperactive,
knucklehead ninja...
Naruto Uzumaki...
is finally here!
Oh...
Naruto!
The hero of a story generally appears
in this kind of situation
and takes out the enemy in no time!
Heh...That brat, eh...
Man, that idiot!
Making such a conspicuous entrance...
There's no point if you don't
catch the enemy off guard!
That boy...
All right, here I go!
Shadow Clone...
Whoa!
What?!
Haku...what are you doing?
Zabuza, leave this kid to me...
Please let me fight this battle my way.
So, you don't want me interfering?
You're naive...as usual...
I'm sorry...
Naive, eh...
True enough...
Judging from these wounds,
there's no mistaking that
I was attacked with a senbon.
But no vital areas have
been targeted so far.
It's impossible.
He's too much for Naruto!
I should be the one to...
Hey. Don't get any ideas...
If you move,
you know what'll happen
to that old man, right?
True...
How about it?
Let's just see how those young guys
fight against each other.
That mask...
You were Zabuza's comrade, after all,
weren't you!
You've got nerve to deceive us!
I'm sorry.
Things like deceiving and catching
one off guard is a shinobi's duty.
Please don't take it personally.
You don't have that luxury, either!
I haven't...forgotten about you.
Sasuke?
I would rather you had
just gone down quietly.
But it looks like it won't work
that way.
Fine. I'll put an end to you first.
H-Hey!
Naruto. I'll get to you later.
This is it!
So the real body is over there, eh...
Okay!
I'm over here.
He moved? How?!
What kind of jutsu is he using?
It's possible that he has clones
hidden in the mirrors and
has them all throw
senbons simultaneously...
No, they're too fast...
I can't even see...
the trajectory of his attacks.
Also, if was a mere Clone Jutsu...
I don't see a need for
these ice mirrors...
Looks like our best bet...
Is for me to attack from the inside
while Naruto attacks from outside...
Yo! I came to save you.
You okay, Sasuke?
Y-You idiot!
If you're a shinobi,
you should move more cautiously!
What's with you?!
I came to the rescue, you know!
If we're both inside the mirrors...
Forget it!
I've had it, you idiot!
Idiot?
What do you mean idiot?!
As to be expected of the
number one unpredictable ninja.
Him "helping" just made the
situation far worse...
It looks like, our only
option left is to smash the mirrors!
Fire Style:
Hey! What're you going to do?!
These are mirrors made of ice...
So...
Fireball Jutsu!
It's not working at all!
They won't melt with that
level of firepower.
Damn! Where'd he attack from?!
Are they all clones?
Where's the real body?!
It's useless for you to even
attempt following with your eyes.
I absolutely will not be caught.
Humph.
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Don't!
Even so, I'll find out which is
the real body by hitting them all!
This is a teleportation Jutsu that uses
mirrors reflect only my image.
I move so quickly...
that to me, you two might
as well be standing still.
Is that Jutsu...a kekkei genkai?!
Kekkei...genkai?
It's the same as my Sharingan...
Deep blood ties...
Lineage of paranormal individuals...
A type of jutsu that is passed down,
generation to generation.
It's impossible for even me
to copy something like that...
Damn it...
So...what?!
I can't die here like this.
'Cause I have a dream
that I must turn into reality...
The dream to have my strength recognized
by everyone in the village...
and become the Hokage!
A dream...
I find it difficult to
completely embrace being a Shinobi...
If I can help it,
I don't want to kill you two...
And I don't want to be killed
by you two...
But if you guys are
going to come at me...
I'll kill my feelings with my blade,
and completely become a Shinobi.
This bridge is the battleground
that connects each of us to our dreams.
I, for the sake of my dream.
And you, for the sake of yours.
Please don't hold it against me...
I want to protect the person
I care for the most...
I live for the sake of that person,
I fight for that person,
and I want to make that
person's dream a reality...
That's my dream.
For the sake of the dream,
I will completely become a Shinobi...
and kill you both!
Sasuke! Naruto!
Don't lose to a guy like that!
Stop it, Sakura.
Don't encourage them!
What?
Even if there was a chance that
we could break that technique,
they won't be able to defeat that boy.
W-What do you mean?
They don't have the mentality
to kill their feelings...
and take another's life.
Exactly...
No real shinobi will come out of
a peace-addicted village like yours.
Because they are not able to learn
the "experience of killing"!
I'm sorry but...
I'm going to have to finish
this in an instant.
The Sharingan again?
Such an unimaginative guy!
You might call me
"an unimaginative guy,"
but at the end of the day,
you're just afraid of the Sharingan.
The secret technique of a shinobi...
isn't something that you show
your opponent so many times.
Be appreciative.
You're the only who has had
the chance to see it twice...
And there will not be a third time...
Even if you were able to defeat me,
you can't defeat Haku...
Since he was a kid,
I've been painstakingly teaching him
the battle techniques of the ninja!
All of my techniques.
On top of that...
He has been polishing up
his own skills as well!
His jutsu surpasses even me!
That's the terrifying ability of
his kekkei genkai.
Thus, I have
forged the ultimate tool.
He is...
He is the best tool!
There's nothing more boring
than listening to someone brag...
It's about time...
I make my move.
Now, now.
As long as we're talking...
Let me brag about another thing...
I know...
Zabuza...
I'll finish them off soon enough...
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
You just don't learn, do you?!
He read my movement...
There's no way he could do that...
This is good!
Bit by bit, I'm figuring out
the timing...
Damn! We were so close!
Naruto, can you still move?
Of course! I'm totally fine!
He's exhausted,
and it's no wonder.
Shadow Clone Jutsu uses
a lot of chakra.
But thanks to him,
I found our way out.
Hah! Impossible!
It was just a coincidence.
Naruto! Run!
What?
Run out of here and
attack from the outside!
A-All right!
I won't let you!
I-I'm not going to lose!
There!
Fire Style: Fire Ball Jutsu!
Damn!
T-That was good just now!
What?
We're doing it one more time!
All right!
There has to be a limit
to that guy's chakra, too!
This won't go as you've planned.
First, I'll get you!
I've been anxious to copy your line.
"I'll tell you now, the same jutsu
won't work on me twice."
Was that it...?
Ninja Art: Hidden Mist Jutsu!
This is?!
Sakura! Stay with Tazuna!
Huh?
Oh! Sakura!
Mr. Tazuna, no matter what,
don't move away from me!
Yeah...you got it.
I know it's called Hidden Mist,
but this fog is way too thick...
Even Zabuza himself shouldn't
be able to see anything...
Good job on dodging it...
Just what I expect of Kakashi
of the Sharingan...
He's...
closing his eyes!
But...the next time you see me,
will be the end.
You overvalue the Sharingan.
What...?
You spoke as if you saw through
everything, but...
Your foresight was wrong, after all.
Kakashi...
You can't read my mind or
my future...
You're a fruad.
First I vanish into the thick fog,
and make your
perceptive eyes useless...
With my eyes closed, I shut down your
ability to use your hypnotic eye
in a close distance battle.
But...
That also means that
you can't see.
Did you forget?
That I am a master
of Silent Killing,
and can find
my target just by sound.
Damn! It's been a while since
I've fought in such bad conditions.
And I'm worried about
Sasuke and Naruto, too...
Be calm...Think...
Who will he target now...
Oh no!
What?!
Too late!
That was Sakura's voice!
Did something happen?
What's Kakashi doing?
Sa...kura...
Can you stand up, Naruto?
Y-Yeah...
From now on,
don't waste your chakra!
You'll be playing
right into his hands.
I know.
Crap!
If things continue like this,
things are going to get really bad.
I...
I have to do something.
My eyes have begun to adjust...
It's about the time I put
an end to this for you...
What?!
Stand up, you idiot!
I was aiming for a vital spot...
but he blocked them all.
I know...you're so persistent!
A coincidence...
No, that's not it.
On the contrary, he's fighting
while covering for his friend.
That boy...he can see something.
What in the world...?
Okay, in that case...
He disappeared.
Where, where did he disappear to?!
Naruto! Don't faint!
I can't take care of you
any more than I am now!
Who asked you to take care of me...
It seems that kid has
reached his limits.
You move well...
Wha?!
But I'll stop you
with the next one.
Calm down...
Focus!
He saw through
absolutely everything?!
No way...
Those eyes...
It can't be...
Sharingan...
You're...
It was just for a moment...
But I was able to see!
I'm sure, to a certain extent,
his eyes can already see me.
It would be foolish to aim
straight at him.
In that case...
I'll use that kid as bait.
What?!
Let me make it in time!
Your desire to help
those kids has gone to your head,
and it seems to have clouded
your Sharingan
with even heavier fog.
Even though you have
those impressive eyes,
your ability to read your enemy's
movements is getting cloudy.
Amuse me more, Kakashi...
I want to repay my debt in
an amusing way.
Don't worry. Haku should be
finished with those brats anytime now.
You better beg for their forgiveness...
when you reunite in the after-life!
Sasuke...defeated...?
That's not true!
Sasuke is...
Cha!
Not by that guy!
He won't be defeated!
Cha!
Naruto won't be either!
That's right.
Huh!
I...believe in their strength.
Naruto is the number one,
hyperactive, knucklehead ninja...
And Sasuke is a member of
the most prestigious clan
in the Hidden Leaf Village!
You don't mean?!
Yes...
His name is Sasuke Uchiha...
He's a ninja genius.
He's the sole survivor
of that tragic clan?!
No wonder he grows so quickly.
But...
That's the same for Haku.
Nobody has ever beaten
Haku's secret jutsu.
Not a single person...
Well then...
It's about time
I put an end to this, huh?
No, I'm going to put
an end to this!
For God's sake, you...
just won't quit...
getting in my way, will you?
You did it!
Sasuke...!
W-What kind of expression
is that...
You...idiot...!
W-Why...
Did you protect me...?!
How the hell...should I know?
Hmph...
You know...
I hated you...
Why? Why...?
Why...me...?
I don't know...
My body just...moved on it's own...
Idiot!
Sasuke!
That man...
Until I defeated...my brother...
I wouldn't die...
That's what I swore, but...
Don't you dare die.
He was a shinobi worthy of respect.
Is this the first time
a friend has died?
This is the way of the shinobi...
Shut up!
I'm going to kill you!
What is this chakra?!
Impossible...
His chakra is
physically manifesting itself!
A-And...what a ghastly chakra it is...
The wounds on his hand...
are healing instantly...
This boy...
What the hell is he...?
It can't be!
What is...this chakra?
It feels foul...
Kakashi?
No, it's too big to be Kakashi's...
Who is it?
There's murder in his eyes!
He looks nothing like he used to!
He's coming!
What?
His chakra repelled my attack!
Then...
This should do it!
Why?!
It can't be!
Could...Naruto's seal
have been broken...?!
No.
This feeling...
It hasn't completely broken...
The chakra of the Nine-Tailed
Fox is escaping...
But the seal
has only slipped a little!
I still have some time!
Do you hear me, Zabuza?
We're both busy people.
I know it's against your style,
but how about
we stopped playing around.
Why don't we settle this once
and for all with one final move?
Interesting.
What can you possibly
do in this situation?
Kakashi, go ahead.
Show me.
No good...
I can't hold this chakra down!
Zabuza...
I can't defeat this boy.
I'm...
You're...that kid...
Why?
Why did you stop?
I just killed your dear friend,
and you can't kill me?
Damn it!
What happened to all
that power from a moment ago?
You can't kill me with
that kind of strength.
Wasn't he someone
special to you?
Is there someone special
in your life?
I want to protect someone
special to me.
I want to make that
person's dream a reality...
That's my dream.
People often misunderstand...
They show pity and don't finish off
the enemy they ought to finish.
They let them survive.
To me, that isn't compassion
or anything.
Do you know...
How it feels to
not be needed by anyone?
To live each day without a dream.
The pain of it all.
What are you saying?
Zabuza has no use
for a weak Shinobi.
You took away
my reason for existence.
Why?
Why do you have to
serve a guy like that?
He gets money from thugs
to do bad things!
Is that No-Brow really
the only person special to you?
A long time ago,
I had other people special to me.
They were...my parents.
I was born in the Land of Water,
in a small village heavy with snow.
My parents worked on a small farm.
We were very poor,
but my parents seemed to
be satisfied with it.
I was happy then...
They were loving parents.
But...
When I was old enough
to understand things,
something happened.
Like what?
What happened?
My blood...
Blood?
Go on!
Tell me what happened.
My father...
He killed my mother.
Then he tried to kill me.
Huh?!
For generations, the Land of Mist
has seen endless civil wars.
People with kekkei genkai were
hated and feared in the Land of Water.
Kekkei genkai?
It's a special power or jutsu
passed on through certain clans,
from parent to child,
or from grandparent to grandchild.
Because of their special powers,
those who had kekkei genkai
were exploited in all sorts of battles.
As a result, all kekkei genkai
were feared
as harbingers of disaster
and death.
After the wars were over,
people with kekkei genkai
were hunted down and killed.
To survive, we were forced to hide
the existence of our bloodline traits.
I'm sure that boy went through
something similar as well.
The greater your power,
the more you were feared.
My mother had a kekkei genkai.
She kept it secret from my father.
She hoped that--
No, she must have thought that
they could have a simple life forever.
Look, Mommy! Look!
Isn't it fantastic?
Not you, too!
Why? Why him, too?
That hurts, Mommy!
Sorry...
I'm sorry, Haku...
I'm sorry!
However...
Father had discovered our secret.
My father...
Was killed by my own hands.
And at that moment,
I knew what I was.
That I...
that my existence didn't matter
to anyone else in the world.
That's...how I felt.
You told me that...
You'd be the best ninja in the village,
and make everyone respect you.
If someone comes along and
accepts you for who you are,
no one could be more important
to you than that person.
Even though he knew I was from
a clan with a kekkei genkai,
Zabuza took me in.
The power that everyone hated...
He wanted it, needed it.
Brats like you won't be needed
by anyone and die like dogs.
You have the same eyes as I do...
Brat...
Do you want...
to be needed by someone?
Are you willing
to give everything for me?
From now on,
you belong to me.
Come with me.
I was so happy...
Haku, bad news.
I have to leave the
Land of Water tonight.
But, I'll be back some day.
I will rule over this land.
To do that...
what I need isn't consolation,
encouragement or empty words.
What I really need is...
I already know.
You have nothing to fear.
I am your weapon, Zabuza.
Keep me by you as a mere tool
that heeds your every word.
You're a good boy!
I apologize, Zabuza.
I wasn't good enough...
Your tool failed you.
I want you...
to kill me.
Ninja Art: Summoning!
Earth Style: Fanged Pursuit Jutsu!
Whatever you're doing won't work!
You have absolutely no idea
where I am now.
On the other hand...
I know exactly where you are.
Kakashi...
You are completely
in my hands now.
If you can't use your eyes or ears,
simply use your nose.
That's what happens
when you're closing your eyes
in the midst of fog.
This is the Summoning Jutsu
specialized for pursuit.
I deliberately shed my own blood
while stopping both of
your attacks before.
Your weapons have a thick scent of
my blood on them now.
Those are my adorable Ninja Dogs.
And their sense of smell
is without equal.
You're the one who
was playing into my hands.
The fog has lifted already.
And your future is...
death.
I've had enough of your bluffs!
Don't act tough!
There's nothing you can do
in this situation.
Your death is certain.
Zabuza.
You were too full of yourself.
You're too ambitious
for your own good.
You assassinated the Mizukage,
but failed to pull off a coup.
You left the service with
few men under you,
and became a rogue ninja.
Soon after, your name reached
our Hidden Leaf Village.
You needed to raise funds
to strike back.
And you needed to hide from
the Tracking Unit's
pursuit and retaliation.
Isn't that about the reason
why you hired yourself out
to scum like Gato?
Zabuza.
Do you really believe I've managed
to survive with just the Sharingan?
Here's something I didn't copy,
a jutsu of my own...
To enlighten you!
Lightning Blade!
What the...?!
His hand is visibly overflowing
with chakra!
Your future is...death!
Naruto...
I want you to kill me.
Please, make it quick.
What are you hesitating for?
I just don't get it!
The only reason you are allowed
to live is because you stay strong?
There must be something other
than just fighting...
There must be some other way
for you to make
the others accept you!
Remember when we met at the forest?
Do you know what I thought?
That you and I are much alike.
I'm sure you can relate to me.
I apologize for dirtying
your hands with my blood.
Is that it?
Is there really no other way?
Correct.
If only...we had met under
different circumstances,
we could've been friends.
I...I hope your dream comes true.
Him too...
Sasuke also had dreams of his own!
Thank you...
You will become stronger.
Hmm...
The super thick fog
has finally begun to clear.
There are two over there!
They are facing off each other.
Huh?
I can't see well...
Which one is Kakashi Sensei...
One moved!
Huh?
Forgive me, Naruto...
I cannot die yet!
Is this the end...?
Zabuza...
Didn't you say my future
was death?
You're off the mark again, Kakashi!
Old man!
Old Man Giichi!
Please open up!
Let's go to the bridge!
If we all do it together,
we can beat Gato and
his men this time!
Inari...
I made up my mind not
to fight anymore.
Your father...
was a hero...
But even he's not with us anymore.
If we were to fight,
we'd just be throwing our lives away.
None of us wants to lose anymore...
No one wants to regret again.
I finally realized...
Nothing is accomplished if
I just cry all the time!
That's why I have to fight!
Inari...has grown into
a fine man.
Will you just let Inari go
there by himself?
Open up!
Hey!
I'm asking you to fight with me!
Old man! Please listen to me!
I went all over the town,
but no one wants to come.
I have no choice!
Wait!
You're just a child!
I may be a child, but I already
know what it means to fight.
Because I'm my father's son!
Wait a moment, Inari!
Where did he go...?
I didn't see him,
but the fog is starting to lift...
Huh? Is he over there?
What the heck is going on here?!
Isn't that the masked boy?
The boy...is already dead.
You did great, Haku.
Kakashi Sensei!
He intends to cut right through
the boy to get me!
I really did find a treasure back then!
Even in his final moment,
he gave me such
a perfect opportunity!
You were able to move
cause Haku was already dead, huh?
I won't forgive you!
Naruto!
You just stay there and watch!
This is...
my battle!
Naruto!
It's good to see you!
Sakura...
Where's Sasuke?
Naruto!
Where is Sasuke?
Kakashi!
Don't get distracted now!
Why don't I go with you?
That way, you won't be going
against your orders.
Right...
Sasuke...
Huh?!
He's cold.
This isn't genjutsu, is it?
Don't mind me.
There are times when it's
alright to let out your emotions.
I always got perfect scores
at the ninja academy...
Huh?
I memorized all the
hundreds of shinobi rules.
All the tests were a breeze.
Until one day,
this question came up...
State Rule #25 of
the Ways of the Shinobi...
As always, I simply wrote down
the answer without batting an eye.
"A Shinobi must never
show their true feelings
under any circumstances,
no matter what...
The mission always comes first.
A ninja must have the strength
of character never to shed any tears..."
Is this...
what it's like to be a Shinobi?
How unbearably painful...
Sasuke...
Why...?
Why can't I keep up?
Damn you!
Why you...!
You can't possibly defeat me
the way you are now.
What was that?
You still don't know...
What true strength means!
Goodbye, Demon!
Both your arms have
now been disabled.
You can't even weave a hand sign.
Huh?
Oh!
You really got beat good this time.
You disappoint me, Zabuza.
Gat, why did you come here?
And who are those henchmen?
Our plan has changed
a little...
I'm sorry about this Zabuza,
but you will die here.
What?!
Since hiring a regular shinobi
costs a lot of money,
I hired rouge ninja like you.
And, it would have been even
more ideal
to save my money and effort if
ninja-to-ninja battles
ended in each killing the other off.
Well, you are certainly not worthy
of being called
the Demon of the
Hidden Mist Village.
If you were to ask me,
you're just a cute little demon!
Who are those guys?
So many of them...
Kakashi...I apologize.
Our fight ends here...
I no longer have a reason
to assassinate Tazuna...
so there is no reason
for us to continue.
Yeah...you're right.
That reminds me...
I owe him something.
He squeezed my arm 'til it broke...
Huh, he's dead.
You bastard!
What do you think you're doing, hey?!
Stop! Don't act so recklessly...!
Why don't you do something too?!
He was your comrade, right?
Shut up, punk.
Haku is dead.
What...?
Don't you feel anything watching
him disgrace Haku like that!
Weren't you with Haku for a long time!
As Gato used me...
I was simply using Haku.
I thought I'd told you...
We shinobi are merely tools.
What I wanted were his skills,
not Haku himself.
I have no regrets...
Do you...
Do you really mean that?
Naruto, stop.
There's no need to fight
him anymore...Besides...
Shut up!
He's still my enemy!
He...
He really liked you!
Do you have somebody
precious in your life?
He was devoted to you!
When a person has something
precious they want to protect...
that's when they can truly
become strong.
But you think he was nothing?
Don't you feel anything?!
It's difficult for me to completely
become a shinobi.
You really...honestly...
don't feel anything at all?
I'd like to make that person's
dream come true...
For that, I could completely
become a shinobi.
Is that really how you get...
when you become as strong as you are?
He threw his life away for you!
I'd like to make that
person's dream come true...
That is my dream.
He died without any of
his dreams coming true.
I was happy.
To die as a tool...!
That's...
That's...too cruel...
Kid...
Don't say another word...
Haku wasn't...
He wasn't just thinking of me.
He was feeling pain inside
while he battled you guys too...
I know.
He was too kind...
I'm glad our last battle
was with you, boy.
Huh?
Yes, little punk,
it's as you say, after all...
Shinobi are human too...
Maybe it's impossible to become
an emotionless tool...
I've lost.
Kid! Give me your kunai knife!
Okay...
What?!
Enough! What are you waiting for?
Kill them all!
Right!
Are you crazy?
Do you think you can win by yourself
against this many of us?
Demon!
If you're so anxious
to join your friend...
Then go...alone!
Unfortunately...
I don't...intend on going...
to the same place...as Haku!
W-What?! Pretending to be so tough...
You're going to hell with me!
It's no big deal...
When the Demon of
the Hidden Mist Village
dies and goes to hell,
he can become a real demon!
Look forward to it!
I'll let you find out
for yourself
if I'm a cute little demon
or not in hell!
Haku...
Now...it's goodbye, Haku...
Thanks for everything...
I'm sorry...
Don't look away.
This is the end of
a man who lived fiercely.
Yeah...
Did I...die...?
Sasuke!
Sakura...
Am I...am I...?!
Sakura, you're heavy.
Huh?!
Sasuke...
Sasuke, Sasuke, Sasuke!
Sakura...
That hurts...
Things turned out well,
didn't they, Sakura?
Stop, you shouldn't move!
I'm fine. Where's Naruto?
And what happened
to that masked guy?
Naruto's fine.
And...the masked kid,
he died...
Died? Did Naruto get him?
Well...I'm not really sure,
but he protected Zabuza...
I had faith in you.
You are awesome, Sasuke!
You avoided getting inflicted with
any mortal wounds!
From the beginning...
he never intended to...
Naruto!
Sakura...
Sasuke's all right!
He's alive!
Huh?
He was feeling pain inside
while he battled you guys too...
He was too kind...
I see...He...
So, Sasuke's all right too...
That's a relief...
Hey, hey, hey!
Aren't you guys forgetting something!
Damn ninja!
Killing our source of money!
Now that it's come to this,
there's no choice but to attack the
whole town and take everything valuable!
Shoot, this isn't good!
Kakashi Sensei!
Don't you have a jutsu
to annihilate them all at once?
That's impossible!
I've used too much chakra!
Here we go!
Enemies who come any closer
to the island...
With the might of
all the island's people...
We will not allow you to live!
Yeah!
Inari!
Heroes always arrive
on the scene late!
Inari...You guys...
Okay, I'm gonna help out, too!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
I can't do much
with my current chakra...
but a bluff should be enough.
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Kakashi Version!
So...are you ready to fight?!
No, we're not!
We've done it!
Sounds like it's over.
Yeah...
Kakashi...
I'd like to ask you a favor.
What is it?
His face...
I want to see his face...
All right.
Huh?
Snow...
Snow at this time
of the year?
Haku...
Are you crying?
Thanks, Kakashi...
You were at my side from the start...
At the very least...
I can be at your side in the end.
If it's possible...
I'd like to go...
to the same place...
as you.
This guy...
He was born in a village
where it snowed a lot.
I see...
He was a boy as pure as snow...
You can go with him, Zabuza...
The two of you...together.
But you know, Kakashi Sensei...
Hmm?
I wonder if the way a ninja
should be
is really as these
two were saying.
Shinobi should not seek
the reason for their own existence.
What's important is to
exist merely as tools.
That's the same in the Land of Leaves.
I wonder if that's what
it really means
to become a real ninja.
I guess...I guess!
I don't like that!
Do you think so, too?
Hmm...
Well...That's why all ninja live
trying to figure that
out without realizing it...
Like Zabuza...and that kid...
Okay!
Huh?
I've just decided!
I'm going to pursue my
own Ninja Way!
I'm gonna sprint straight
ahead and pursue
a way that I absolutely
won't regret!
Thanks to you the bridge
was safely completed,
but we will miss you very much.
Take care.
Thank you for everything.
Now, now!
We'll come back for
a visit again, Tazuna!
For sure?
Huh?
Inari...you're gonna
miss us, aren't you?
It's all right to cry.
Go ahead and cry!
I won't cry!
It's all right if you cry, Naruto!
Oh, is that so?
See ya!
Oh...!
You are so stubborn.
That boy changed Inari's heart...
and Inari changed the hearts
of all the people in the village.
That boy created a bridge
linking us to hope,
a bridge called courage.
So a linking bridge...
Speaking of bridges,
we need to name
this bridge, don't we?
That's true.
In that case,
I have a perfect name
for this bridge.
Yeah, what is it?
The Great Naruto Bridge.
How's that?
That's a good name.
Alright! Let's get back soon
so I can have Iruka Sensei treat me
to ramen to celebrate
us completing the mission!
And! And! I'll tell Konohamaru
tales of my heroic exploits!
Then I...
Hey! Sasuke, do you want to go
on a date
when we get back to the village?
No, I don't think so.
Just like that...
You know! You know!
I'll go with you!
Be quiet!
Shut up! Naruto!
Haku said to me...
When a person has something
precious they want to protect,
they can become truly strong.
I see...
So do you feel the same way?
Yeah!
After watching Haku and Zabuza,
I think I believe that.
Hey, hey...
Kakashi Sensei,
what do you think about them?
What? Are you sure
that name's okay?
This name will ensure that
this bridge will never collapse...
And someday, it'll be the name
of a very famous bridge...
A name heard around the world.
That's truly what I hope.