Do you already know
his whereabouts?
Yes.
In that case, it will be easy...
Let's go.
Here it comes, here it comes.
Oh goodie, it's just like I thought.
Hidden Leaf Village...
has a high average score.
You're still doing such
a ridiculous thing?
Well yes, this is my research.
Old Man Homura and Koharu Sensei, huh?
I wonder what you advisers
want from me.
This is it.
Th-This is...
Alot of time has passed since the death.
It's probably before
the Chunin Exam began.
I see, so that's it...
That Orochimaru!
After the murder of Lord Kazekage,
Orochimaru...or someone
like Kabuto played Kazekage...
How thoughtless we were...
That damn Sarutobi...
Well, it's not that easy.
The one who was your opponent
was the renowned Hokage
deemed to be strongest of
all five great nations.
However...you've done well.
Two out of the five Kages...
Stop...
Stop giving me words of sympathy.
I will kill you!
Of course, I didn't mean to...
It's true that we didn't succeed
in bringing the village down...
On the other hand, another objective
of this plan, Sasuke Uchiha...
Your leash is now on him.
In exchange for these arms
and all of my jutsu...
If we could have gotten our hands
on that Itachi Uchiha from the beginning,
it wouldn't have been a problem.
However that's a dream that
can no longer come true.
He is stronger than I am.
That is why...I pulled myself out
from that organization...
The Hidden Village in the Sand
announced that
everything was Orochimaru's handiwork.
In addition, at the moment of their
complete surrender to us, the Leaf Village
that wasn't a very important issue
any more.
Leaf Village has no choice but
to accept their surrender and proposition
in order to restore national power.
However, the current strength of
Leaf Village has dropped drastically.
Under these conditions,
our top priority must be to prepare
for any unpredicted crisis.
We don't know when any of
the neighboring nations
will come out in a bold move.
Therefore, we've decided that until
the village gets its strength back,
we should assemble the top few men
from each troop,
and form an emergency
executive committee to handle this.
But first...
We need a strong, trustworthy leader.
You can find the seeds of trouble
rolling around everywhere these days.
It's not just Orochimaru.
You didn't have to go through
the trouble of informing me that.
Well...I'll continue gathering materials.
I'm going to tell you the basic plan.
We need the Fifth Hokage right away.
And yesterday at an emergency meeting
with the feudal lord of the Land of Fire,
we decided
it would be you, Jiraiya.
I'm sorry, it's not my nature.
It has been decided.
Besides, if a shinobi like you,
renowned as a Sannin, is not...
then who is?
If you want a Sannin,
there is one more left...
That Tsunade.
Certainly that child probably
has that capability, but...
However, no one knows where she is.
I'll find and bring her back.
If I do that there's no problem, right?
But...
A wise one like Tsunade is meant to
be Hokage more than I, with no motivation.
What do you want to do?
All right.
We'll give it urgent consideration.
However, we'll have three members
from ANBU Black Ops to accompany you
as the search unit for Tsunade.
Don't worry, I won't escape from this.
The guards are not necessary.
However...
There is one guy that I want
to take with me on my trip.
I've found an interesting egg...
Yo, you two!
You seem to be getting along well.
Fool, Anko asked me to
buy rice dumplings. That's all.
What are you doing here?
While I'm here to buy offerings,
I've made plans to meet here...
with Sasuke.
Huh, it's rare that you wait for people.
Is the offering to Obito?
Obito?
Well...that's about right.
Kakashi, it's strange for
you to be here first.
Well...once in a while.
I don't do natto or sweets.
Oh...Is that so?
I...
I put it under my headband
in order not to drop the important ticket
during morning training.
Okay, that's fine...
Eat well and do your best.
Hmm?
You're going to do it again
after this, right? Training?
Of course! I'm full of motivation.
Good! Here you go.
Another serving for free! Go for it!
Thank you, sir!
Welcome.
Just like I heard...
I had to come and see it.
It seems that you really
are just eating ramen.
Oh, Pervy Sage!
I haven't seen you for
a while Asuma, Kurenai.
If you know about us,
are you former Leaf shinobi?
- Huh?!
Y-You are?!
Humph, without a doubt...
Uchiha...
Itachi.
You are acquaintances of Itachi?
If so...
I'll introduce myself as well.
I'm Kisame Hoshigaki.
Hereafter, I hope to be familiar with you.
Never mind later,
I'm going to beat you now!
Itachi...
It seems you're pretty unpopular
in the village too.
I know you, too.
Kisame Hoshigake,
originally a shinobi
of Hidden Village in the Mist.
Suspected of national covert activities
and of killing a feudal lord,
a Rogue ninja from Land of Water,
on the wanted list in all nations.
You're a major S-rank criminal
listed in the Bingo Book.
This guy is pretty annoying.
Should we kill him?
It doesn't look like we are able
to leave the village so smoothly...
But don't overdo it,
your techniques tend to stand out.
They're done for then.
This is...
Genjutsu.
Pressing down with the tip of his sword...
What strength.
My large sword, Shark Skin...
doesn't cut, but lops it off!
Kurenai...You're late.
It's over!
Genjutsu of that level doesn't work on me.
This is...genjutsu reversal?
Kurenai!
There's no time to look away.
That's what's expected from you, Kurenai.
But...
"But this is as far as it goes..."
For you.
What?!
Water Style!
- Water Shark Bomb Jutsu!
The same jutsu as me?!
Why have you shown up too?
Well...I asked you to take care
of them earlier.
But I kinda felt uneasy, you know.
Hatake...
Kakashi.
Those eyes are exactly the same
as they used to be in the past.
That being said,
he is a true inheritor of the Sharingan...
I have to assume the worst case scenario,
just in case.
This is a surprise...
No wonder you copied my jutsu...
So there really is a fellow
besides Itachi who has that eye.
Your name is Kakashi,
the copy ninja, wasn't it?
I'm the one who was surprised.
I saw strange men in the tea house
and wondered who they were...
There they were, Itachi Uchiha and...
the Mystery Man of Hidden Mist Village
Kisame Hoshigaki.
Well, well...You know even my name.
It's an honor.
I see. You're one of the
"Seven Ninja Swordsmen of the Mist."
That huge sword is the "Shark Skin," right
I heard that kid Zabuza
had it out with you?
Yeah...
You are someone who's
well worth lopping off...
Stop it...Kisame.
If you were to go at it with that man,
it won't end without cost.
And if you spend too much time,
another shinobi would come running.
However...
Don't lose sight of the goal...
You didn't come here to get injured!
Let me hear that goal then?
Just came to find something
we're looking for.
Something you're looking for?
I'm different from Kisame,
I won't take time.
Water Style: Water Wall!
That's some jutsu speed.
My eyes couldn't follow his signs.
That shuriken in the right hand
was a decoy...
to use a Water Style Jutsu to launch
an attack below my foot...
That's what to expect from you, Kakashi.
Your power of analytical eye...is great.
A Shadow Clone?!
His jutsu speed is too fast!
A Water Clone?!
The copy ninja has done well this far
with jutsu of my village.
Nice! Kakashi!
Get down, Kurenai!
This one is the Shadow Clone...
Huh?
Kakashi! Kurenai!
He made the Shadow Clone
body explode?!
Kakashi!
Don't lower your guard...
He's the guy who became a division chief
of ANBU Black Ops at 13 years old...
I didn't expect that someone
not of the Uchiha clan
would have mastered
the Sharingan to that extent...
But your body isn't the Uchiha clan body
that goes with the eye.
That's right. As a result,
my stamina doesn't last...
There's a reason why the Uchiha Clan
was deemed the strongest and feared...
I-It can't be!
This is bad!
Both of you! Don't look at his eyes!
Both of you,
absolutely do not open your eyes...
It's all over now if your eyes meet.
Only people with Sharingan
can have a go with that technique.
Indeed with Sharingan,
you can resist this Mangekyo Sharingan
to a certain extent.
However...
this special visual jutsu of Sharingan,
Genjutsu: Tsukuyomi, Nightmare Realm,
is unbreakable.
The only person who can bring me down
is someone
using the same kekkei genkai,
a Sharingan user...
Sasuke...
I wonder how much you can take
without the kekkei genkai?
In the world of Tsukuyomi...
Both space and time...
and mass...
I control them all.
For the next 72 hours...
I'll stab you continually with swords.
What happened, Kakashi?!
Are you saying we should keep
our eyes closed still?!
N-Not...yet...
What happened?!
Just as that guy finished speaking,
you suddenly fell over!
Three days in that world is less than
a moment in the actual world, huh...
But...why doesn't he kill me?
He could easily do so, if he wants to...
Whoa...To take that jutsu without causing
his spirit to collapse.
But Itachi...
it's also dangerous for you
to overuse those eyes.
The thing you're looking for...
is it Sasuke?
No...the legacy of the Fourth Hokage...
These guys.
What the heck are they planning...?
So, Naruto, is it...?
It's been a long time...
How many years has it been
since you returned to the village?
Kakashi...
I will keep Naruto under my care.
I can understand why
the Third Hokage
appointed you to
the role of watching over Naruto...
But even at your level,
you may not be able to handle it properly.
What in the world are you saying?
I've been observing Orochimaru
ever since he left the village...
It was obvious that he would return
to this village sooner or later.
All told, at first I was concerned
only about him, but...
What is it?
The guy joined an organization.
What are the details of the organization?
I don't know much of the details,
but it's a small organization known
as Akatsuki made up of nine shinobi.
Until recently, they weren't making
any dramatic moves
except some cloak and dagger activities.
The biggest concern is
the members of that organization.
Almost all of them are listed
on the Bingo Book,
all S-rank deviant criminals.
That Itachi is among them.
If the nine of them get together,
their intent will not be charity work.
But recently, Orochimaru pulled out
of the organization.
And at that time,
other members of the organization
went in to action in different areas,
in pairs gathering jutsu and things.
Is there proof that one of those
things is the Nine-Tailed Fox?
It's possible.
Kakashi...
Sooner or later, Naruto will have
to live watching his back...
That's his destiny.
For now, you should keep
your eyes on Sasuke.
It's necessary for you to teach him
how to use his Sharingan.
I'll take care of Naruto for a while.
The Nine-Tailed Fox inside Naruto
is your target?
I know that you two aren't
the only ones on the move...
The name of your organization is
Akatsuki, right?
Akatsuki?
Kisame! We'll take Kakashi.
Erase the other two.
Severe Leaf Hurricane!
Who are you?
The Leaf's noble, blue fierce animal...
Might Guy!
What a sight...
Shouldn't you be called a strange beast?
Don't underestimate that man...
That man is Itachi!
You did this to Kakashi...?
Don't look at Itachi's eyes, Guy!
You'll be caught up in his jutsu!
I know that already!
In order to fight Kakashi,
I devised ways to battle the Sharingan.
Open your eyes, both of you!
B-But...
When you battle with the Sharingan,
it's not a problem if
you don't look at those eyes!
You work around it by
gaining insight into his movements
by looking constantly at his feet.
Now that you mention it,
you're probably right, but...
You're the only one who can do that.
That's true...
There's a knack to reading
all of your opponents movements
only by his feet.
But I can't teach it to you
in this emergency.
Just get used it right now!
What should we do?
Kurenai, get Kakashi to the medical team.
Asuma, you are my back up!
Okay!
And until the reinforcements of
ANBU Black Ops I arranged for arrive,
I will hang out with you guys.
Interesting...
That's some nerve...
Kisame...We're pulling out.
We didn't come to have a war.
It's too bad,
but no more of this nonsense.
We're leaving.
Too bad...I was finally feeling motivated
It can't be helped.
What?! Why?! Why?!
Why do I have to go on a research trip
with you, Pervy Sage?
Oh no, this isn't just any research trip.
There's a woman whose data
I want to collect.
So we have to look for her first.
I really don't have time to accompany you
on your perverted research trip!
Because I have training
Hm? Training
I will take lessons from Kakashi Sensei
and learn a variety of things, like Chidori
Kakashi Sensei has been
playing favorites lately!
Well, I think that technique
is impossible for you to learn.
More importantly...
That woman is really beautiful.
You want to meet her, don't you?!
Not at all.
I'm not some kid who can
be cajoled by you, Pervy Sage!
Anyway, no!
Well, it can't be helped...
Oh, well...I know jutsu more amazing
than Chidori, but...
It can't be helped...
Maybe I'll take Sasuke?
Of course I'll go!
I'll pack my bags right away.
Pervy Sage, don't move!
I'll be darned...He's really a cute kid.
All right!
Hey, Pervy Sage. What jutsu are you
gonna teach me this time?
The last time was Walk on Water Jutsu,
so is it gonna be Walk on Fire Jutsu?
Or maybe Walk in the Air?
Hurry up and tell me, Pervy Sage!
You keep calling me Pervy Sage.
So you have no idea that
I'm a superb person, huh?
Huh...? A superb Pervy Sage?
Nhaagh...Listen carefully!
Toad Sage is only a disguise!
As a matter of fact...!
North and South and East and West!
I'm the white maned toad charmer,
and one of the legendary Sannin whom
even celestial beings can't defeat.
Such a stud!
That he strikes fear...
in the hearts of people!
I am no other than "Master Jiraiya"!
Yes...
I'm talking about me!
Huh...
Atafuku Town?
That's ten kilometers from here!
It's "O" tafuku Town!
Hey...hey...
Hey, Pervy Sage!
I'm telling you, it's Jiraiya.
Gimme a break...
So the fact that such
a bigwig Pervy Sage like you
is taking me along as
his travel companion means...
that I'm potentially a genius?
Just as I thought!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Why did you choose me?
A long time ago
the Fourth Hokage was my disciple.
And you resemble the Fourth Hokage
so much, it's almost funny.
That's the only reason...
I...?
The Fourth Hokage...?
Yeah!
Yeah! Yeah!
W-What is it?
Yeah!
The fact that I resemble
the Fourth Hokage means
that I also possess genius
of his level, right?
I'll become the Hokage, after all!
All right!
W-Wait...
I stepped on some dog poop!
I wasn't...
I wasn't able to do anything...
I don't want to watch a precious comrade
die right before my eyes ever again...
No matter what,
I will protect you!
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Summoning Jutsu!
Naruto is getting stronger and stronger.
Compared to him, I...
While you may able to
manage against him,
I couldn't possibly...
He's in a completely different level...
Yeah...
If we go at each other,
we'll either both be killed or at best,
kill each other simultaneously.
Even if we increased the numbers,
that wouldn't change
I didn't expect the kid's guard
would be a legendary Sannin.
With him as the opponent...
the names of Leaf Village's Uchiha Clan
and the Seven Ninja Swordsmen
of Mist would be tarnished.
Yeah. However...
Every one has a weakness...
It appears that they haven't
found Naruto yet.
But don't you think that's strange!?
Those guys had already
infiltrated the village.
It should be easy to find Naruto
in this village.
Itachi knows Naruto's face.
Kakashi...
Why is Kakashi sleeping?
Besides, only jonin are gathering here...
What are you doing?
What in the world happened?!
Nothing...in particular...
Is it true that that
Itachi has returned?!
And moreover,
that he's after Naruto?!
Oh...
Idiot...
Why does this always happen?!
So that guy returned to this village?
And moreover, he's pursuing Naruto?
What does all this mean?!
If Naruto is caught by him
he's as good as dead.
I'm not gonna let that happen!
Hey old man!
Naruto must have come here!
And do you know
where he went after that?
Oh, Naruto, right...
If I remember correctly...
Master Jiraiya came here
around noon and...
They ate ramen together,
and he said he was going somewhere...
Where?!
Hmm...I think he said to a post station
some distance from the village...
And then he left with Master Jiraiya.
Jiraiya?
Jiraiya - one of the genius Sannin.
Well, in appearance,
he just looks like
a big white haired old man.
Big and white-haired...
Candies are here.
Naruto!
Huh?
We're staying here tonight!
What?! I can still walk!
A disciple should obey his master!
I just want to learn the jutsu!
That's what's called a disciple!
Huh?!
Oh, oh...!
Naruto!
Yes?
Here, this is the key to the room.
Go to the room ahead of me,
practice chakra,
train some and go to sleep!
Got it?!
What?!
"The adult world is gonna begin
from this point on"...
Is that the vibe, Pervy Sage?!
That's not fair!
That post town isn't that far...!
This! Somehow this always happens
when I'm with that Pervy Sage!
Darn...
Here...
Candies are here!
I've got to check door by door!
Do you have a blonde kid with
a dumb-looking face, about my age
and a big white haired old man
staying here?
White haired...?
Are they here?!
Eh...Do I remember seeing
some people like that earlier
when shifts changed...?
This tastes bitter...
are you all right with it? Cheers!
Oh! A blond kid and
a white haired old man!
They're here?!
What's their room number!
Um...
Room number one at
the end of the hallway
on the second floor...
What's up?
Has she already dumped you?
Okay, Okay!
Okay, Okay, I'll open up!
Naruto!
It's not him...
Sasuke...?
No...Who is he?
He's got the same Sharingan
as Sasuke.
Really...
who'd believe a kid like you to
have the Nine-Tailed Fox in him.
Why does that guy know
about the Nine-Tailed Fox?!
Naruto, you will come with us.
That guy is...close by!
That guy!
Shall we go outside...?
These guys aren't just anybody...
Itachi, it'll be a pain in the neck
if this kid moves around and...
Maybe I better chop off
a leg just in case...
W-What did he say?!
Now then...
Long time no see...
Sasuke.
Itachi Uchiha…
I will…
Kill you!
Oh…the Sharingan.
Just who is he?
My little brother.
I had heard that the Uchiha Clan
had been annihilated…by you.
So this is the man
Sasuke was talking about…
The one he wants to kill!
It's just as you've said.
I've hated you and resented you.
For the singular purpose
of killing you…
I have lived my life!
Sasuke!
Damn it!
Maybe I should cut off those arms!
Master Jiraiya…
So your target is Naruto, after all?
To take Naruto is the overriding mission
we have been assigned by the Akatsuki.
I can't let you have Naruto.
I wonder about that…
Perfect timing. I will get rid of
both of you right here.
Don't interfere.
If anyone is going to kill him,
it will be me.
I have no interest in you right now.
Sasuke!
Damn it!
Naruto!
I said not to interfere!
This is my fight!
Revenge…
Fine!
Why? I haven't closed the gap at all.
What is this difference?
I've trained for so long,
just to kill him.
For so long!
What have I been doing
all this time?!
Just what…?
You are weak.
From now, for 24 hours…
Go back to that day.
That's enough…
outta you!
Ninja Art: Toad Mouth Trap.
Too bad, Itachi…Kisame.
You are in my belly now!
I've summoned the digestive tract
of the Giant Toad of Mount Myoboku.
You are wanted criminals anyway.
I'll just feed you to the rock toad.
You are weak
because you don't have enough…
hatred.
Come, Kisame!
Damn!
Wait!
Why you—!
No one's ever escaped
this jutsu before!
Pervy Sage!
What's the matter?!
Huh!
They're gone!
I cannot believe that this wall
has been torn through...
Why must we retreat?
You would be...
We have no reason to rush to
get Naruto in the current condition.
Besides, I have to rest
my body somewhere for a while.
Not just Tsukuyomi,
but he also made me
use Amaterasu as well...
What is this fire?
It's black...
Don't get so close!
How did those guys manage to get out?
Not only that...
What are these black flames?
The stone toad who has the ability
to blow fire had its intestine's burned...
Huh?
All right!
Sealing Jutsu: Fire Seal!
All right! It'll be okay for now.
Now for Sasuke!
Sasuke!
Sasuke...
Dynamic...
Guy?!
Entry!
Well...Eh...
I'm sorry to have kicked you so directly.
I was in a rush and I forgot my mirror...
I used this headband instead,
but it was hard to see.
And I assumed this rough hewn face
was the enemy...
I just let the flames of
the burning juvenescence take over me...
I'm sorry!
Is that...supposed to be an apology?
I'm a simple minded guy
just like how my face looks.
It doesn't really matter.
More importantly, we have to get Sasuke
to the Medical Team!
Yes!
He's broken his arm and ribs.
Not only that, he's lost consciousness
from some kind of mental blow
he received from the visual jutsu!
This boy also experienced that jutsu...
Hey Pervy Sage!
Is Sasuke going to be all right?
Seems like he's received
a significant amount of mental damage.
Darn...Why?!
What did that guy do to Sasuke?!
Hey, Pervy Sage!
We've gotta change our plan!
I got scared earlier,
but this time I'm going to chase
those black capes and get them!
It's me that they want, right?!
Then, I'll be the one to
make my way over!
Humph, you're only going to be killed
if you go now.
They're at a totally different level
from you.
I just managed to get you
away from them...
Then, are we just going
to keep running away?!
Are we supposed to keep living in fear?!
Shut your mouth for a second!
You are weak.
I'm sorry, Guy.
I thought that I had spared
the boy's feeling, but...
I should have saved him much sooner.
Kakashi has also come down
with the same jutsu...
We don't know when
he will regain consciousness.
Kakashi Sensei?!
When my students are hurt...
I always wish,
from the bottom of my heart...
If that person,
who is a medical specialist, were here...
That's why we're going to
go find her now.
What?
You mean, her?
Could it be...?
W-Wait...!
C-Could this money be...?!
Yup, that's right...
The one who uses the slug
and drives illness away,
and who is also
one of the Sannin like me...
All right! We're going to turn around
our luck with this!
Princess Tsunade with
the letter Gamble on her back!
Well then, Guy.
I'll leave Sasuke to you.
Master Jiraiya...
Hmm?
Be sure to find Mistress Tsunade
and bring her back to...
You bet we'll find her
and bring her right away!
Naruto! I like kids with guts like you!
I'm going to give this to you!
This made Lee stronger...
Huh?! What?! What?!
This is it!
Wow!
They're breathable and
moisture wicking,
and perfectly designed for free movement,
all in a beautiful, stylish package.
You'll notice a difference immediately
if you train with them on!
They're going to grow on you!
Before long, you'll be wanting to
wear them all the time like Lee!
Of course, I have a thing for them, too!
Woooow!
Why couldn't you bring a mirror
or something
instead of carrying around
those things, you dork!
Do you think they'll look good on me?
Don't even think about it.
Get a load of that...
Your target is Naruto, after all.
To abduct Naruto is the No. 1 priority
placed by our organization, Akatsuki!
What's wrong?
Pervy Sage...Why are they after me?
You know, don't you, Pervert Sage?
Tell me why...
They're not really after you...
They're after what's inside of you.
What on earth is this thing?
It's a horrible demon that
attacked Leaf Village, right?
And was dreaded by all.
So why do they want it so much?
Indeed, the Nine-Tailed Fox
is a demon
that appears at each critical juncture
throughout the ages
destroying everything in its path...
And people feared it like
an act of nature.
The reason they want that thing...
for what purpose.
Honestly, I can't quite say.
Just that now that Nine-Tailed Fox
is sealed up inside of you...
they might be thinking
they want that power in their control.
It must be harsh to know
that ninja like them
would keep coming after you...
But well, that's your destiny!
Now don't you worry,
I'm going to protect
Then there's nothing to do
but hurry up and get stronger! I've got to
Okay! Let's go find that Tsunade person,
have her save Sasuke
and get down to some serious training!
That's just like this kid...
Th-This place has the highest antes...!
Don't go fretting over
every little thing!
Let's go!
Oh dear! Please wait!
Hmm?
What?
The beautiful woman you
want to "research" on...
That's this Tsunade person?
Whoa! That's sharp coming from you!
And what about it?
She's part of the Sannin thing
like you, right, Pervy Sage?
Yes, and what of it?
How...old is she?
My age.
Heck, she's an old lady.
Yikes!
Huh?
Th-This woman is...!
Would you mind changing all
of this money into chips for me?
Oh no! She's really going for it!
Just who is this? This lady...
You don't know?
She's that woman with
the famous alias...
Famous alias?
So, well...what kind of person
is this Tsunade like?
Oh, you want to know?
Yeah.
Let's see...
Put simply, she's an unpleasant type.
Besides that, she's a diehard gambler
and her face is known far and wide for it.
Then we should have no problems
finding her!
If she's that famous!
She's famous, all right...
Legendary, you might say...
Boss, what's this alias?
The Legendary...
Legendary?
Oh dear! They're all laughing!
- Legendary...
Sitting Duck!
Yup! But no matter how famous
Legendary Sitting Duck is,
I doubt we'll find her right away.
Why not?!
She hates growing old so much
she's probably used some special jutsu
to change her appearance.
She's actually 50 years old,
but no doubt she looks like
she did when she was 20...
And not just that,
recently I heard that...
she transforms into her teens or
30s or 40s as the situation calls for
to escape moneylenders.
What?! That's a horrible thing to do!
Tsunade has always loved
to gamble more than anything
But she has terrible luck and no skill.
She was always being played
for the Sitting Duck and the name stuck...
Then she was always borrowing money
and skipping out on her debts, too...
Ah, it brings back memories.
This is no time to be
getting all nostalgic!
Tell me, how do you propose
we go about finding her?!
Well...
We may very well have to
put our noses to the ground,
but we're not without our little tricks.
What?! So you have no idea
how long it's gong to take?!
We won't be wasting any time.
All of our time on the road
will be your time.
My time?
Time to make you strong...
Training!
Okay!
No, no...I told you that is definitely ou
I won't be seen walking with someone
dressed like that.
Come on, Pervy Sage!
Let's hurry up and start training!
Now now, don't get ahead of yourself...
The training won't mean anything
unless it's done in the process of
gathering information on Tsunade.
Huh? Gathering information?
In this town.
Wow!
Cool! This is my first time
for this kind of thing!
Down time is important, too!
You go have yourself some fun
before we start training.
The festival should continue
for some time.
We'll stay here in this city
for the duration.
We'll train here, too!
All right!
Whoa! That's a fat wallet!
You're rich!
I have quite a bit!
I've saved it little by little
throughout my missions.
Well then!
- Wait! Naruto!
- Huh?
I'll hold on to your wallet for you!
Wh-What do you think you're doing?!
You can spend this much...
What?! Only 300 ryo!
No complaints!
Remember, shinobi must honor
the "Shinobi's Three Taboos"!
Shinobi's Three Taboos...?
What's that?
What?! You don't know!
The "three taboos" are
the three temptations
that will bring shinobi to ruin!
The three temptations are
booze, women and money...
Oh, then this doesn't really apply
to me all that much!
I'm minor, so I can't drink yet!
I don't quite get the women thing!
And I worked so hard
to save all that money,
I don't really feel much like using it...
You fool! Don't you underestimate
the desire for money!
Once you start using it,
it goes really fast!
Money has a frightful power.
This Tsunade we are going
to be looking for
has ruined herself over it!
Your desire for women is always
getting the better of you, too, Pervy Sage
I'm going on
an information gathering mission!
Here, you hold on to my bag for me!
If you get lost,
my tracking Toad
will follow my scent!
He's really just a child after all,
contrary to appearances...
Last one!
- All right! Perfect!
- Oh! Amazing!
That's the fruit of hard training
throwing shuriken.
You stink, sonny!
Hah! Gosh darn it!
Well, just watch this!
Hold it!
Huh?
Attention: Shinobi!
Ninjutsu strictly forbidden!
Thanks now!
You shouldn't try to walk around
with the mask on.
It's Pervy Sage's bank saving book.
One, ten, one hundred...
L-Look at all those zeros!
He should be treating me now and then
if he has this much money.
Stingy old geezer!
There's only a little left...
One more stand and that will be it...
Time to make you strong...
Training!
Two grilled squids please, sir!
Make one of those an adult size!
Okay! Someone sent you
to buy some squid, eh?!
I'll throw in a child size for free!
Coming right up!
Hurray for you, sir!
You're a man among men!
Oh, you can tell, eh?! All right!
I'll give you the adult one for half price
Thanks!
Good grief, where did he go to?!
Huh? The voice of Pervy Sage?
Young ladies are so nice.
Oh, Naruto! You've already had
you're fill of the festival?
Repeat those three Shinobi Taboos again!
You're breaking all three at once!
You bastard!
W-Wait, Naruto...
N-No, I won't wait!
You used all my hard saved money!
- Take this and this and this!
- N-Naruto, stop!
I'll pay it all back!
I'm sorry, p-please!
You! You!
You made my froggy wallet all flat!
Hey! Look what you did, you urchin!
You stained Leader's designer suit!
You'll have to pay for it!
Fork over 100,000 ryo!
What?! You're telling me
that suit cost 100,000 ryo?!
Yeah, really, that's quite a stretch
to say a dorky suit like that
cost 100,000 ryo.
Are you asking for it?!
You better put a lid on it
if you know what's good for you.
The leader used be a chunin from
the Hidden Village of Stones,
the legendary dark ninja, feared by all!
Come again? Legendary what?
You seem to want to get hurt!
Naruto.
Perfect timing.
I'll show you a jutsu now...
Watch very carefully!
Now you've done it!
A-Amazing!
I was holding back quite a bit...
You guys are so weak.
A-Are you? The...legendary...
I'm sorry...
We kind of destroyed your stand...
H-Here...Fix. It with this.
Oh! Thanks.
Would you mind if I bought all
your balloons and water balloons
at the same time, my man?
Fine by me...
That wasn't an ordinary hand move...
What in blazes was that jutsu?
Naruto!
Come with me! It's training time!
Yes, sir!
Finally, the mood is right
for a little training.
- Here! Water balloon!
- Wha?
Eh?! What is it for?!
You saw that jutsu I just used, right?
Y-Yeah.
What jutsu did it look like to you?
It looked like you made
your opponent spin violently.
His perspective's off...
But I guess that's to be expected.
Right, okay...Yes, spinning
He's spinning the water in the balloon
without moving his hand?!
Whoa!
The tree climbing exercise
to learn to gather and
maintain chakra in necessary places...
The Walk on Water exercise
to learn how to release
a set amount of chakra...
You did both of these, right?
And now with this water balloon exercise,
you'll learn how to create
a stream of chakra...
In other words, spinning.
Create a stream of chakra...
I'll give a more detailed explanation
of the jutsu
once you get these first steps down.
First, you must gather
and maintain chakra in your hand
using the tree climbing technique.
Then you must continuously
release chakra
using the Walk on Water technique.
Then you push and churn the water
in the balloon with the chakra!
I get it!
Then you spin the water
in the balloon faster and faster
until the balloon pops!
You're catching on
more and more quickly!
Okay, today we're going
to train until evening
Yes, sir!
Now, what will happen?
It's something to be concerned about...
Mister!
Why don't you stop by?
This month is our special service month.
Whoa! It's a special service month?
The more you visit,
the more you benefit.
Here you go, a stamp card!
I'll give you lots and lots of service!
I'll come, I'll come!
Hey! Come on down, Shu!
Hey, hey, where is the toilet?
All right now!
Training, once again today!
I'm gonna work hard like a blaze!
Break! Break! Break!
Why won't it break?
Little Jiraiya, you're so naughty!
Men are all naughty!
Dang it!
Three days have passed since
I got the tip from that Pervy Sage...
The rubber is stretched this much,
but why won't it break?
What am I doing different from
that Pervy Sage?
This is great! This is so great!
What the?
Whoa, he stinks of alcohol.
I'm gonna eat now!
Huh?
What's the matter?
Oh dang it!
Darn it! Why is it like this?!
No need to learn a finicky hand sign!
It's okay to be stupid!
He said that there's no need to form
a hand signal, but...
Hey! That's not your toy...
This is it!
Hurry up and wake up!
Hey, you Pervy Sage!
Uh...G-Good timing.
Why don't you bring me some water...
Water?
The first step is cleared!
Cleared...?
Well, let's have you show it to me.
All right! Watch it carefully!
Left hand?
Go!
All right! See that?! See that?!
You're sleeping!
Sorry, sorry.
I'm tired from the days and nights
of gathering information.
But that seems suspicious to begin with!
You still stink of alcohol too!
Nevertheless...
You rotate the water inside the water ball
that you hold in your left hand
by repeatedly applying it
with your right hand...
It seems little strange of an idea, but...
You're an interesting kid.
You understood the trick pretty well.
It's all thanks to me, though.
It's thanks to this guy!
Huh?
I realized after I saw this cat playing
with the water balloon.
He kept on flicking it with
his paw many times
and the water inside shocked
in all different kinds of direction...
Then it came to me like "bingo!"
How did it come like bingo?
The time when the Pervy Sage
first showed me breaking it...
I remembered how the water balloon
surface was not smooth.
Until then,
I was always only rotating the water
in the one same direction...
I realized that the Pervy Sage's
water balloon was not smooth
because the water inside was rotating
in different directions.
And after doing it in my own way,
it broke!
It seems it's still not possible for you
to rotate it violently with one hand, but.
I suppose you thought it out
in your own way.
That's just what he expected of me!
Anyhow...
The first step is complete for now.
All right!
Do you want to see it one more time?
One more time!
Oww!
You used too much chakra and
it gradually reached the point
where there's burden
on the chakra network...
But the next one won't be like this!
Okay. Now, we will proceed
to the second step.
Yeah!
It seems like we can finally go
into some serious training!
- Here you go
- Huh?
Rubber ball?
Something like this again?!
Now, you'll break this one!
It's one hundred times harder
than the water balloon!
It's hard...
The first step is rotation,
the second step is force.
Since there is no water inside,
it's more difficult to imagine
the rotation of chakra,
so it becomes more difficult
to rotate the chakra as well.
That's true...
I'll leave that to your own judgment.
I need to learn a trick again
to do this, don't I?
Well then,
I'll go gather some information.
Hey! Wait, wait!
Let's train together for
the first time in a while!
I don't mind if you take a nap.
Don't depend on me!
You must have some kind
of misunderstanding!
I did say that I'll teach you the jutsu,
but I don't have the obligation
to teach you every step of the way.
If you can't do it by yourself,
then that's it.
Don't be childish forever...
Become more respectable like a shinobi!
Well, well then.
If you can at least teach me...
the trick again...
Money!
Money...money...money...
W What do you mean
"be respectable like a shinobi"?!
Even though you say that,
you're an dirty and greedy adult!
You're not a respectable shinobi at all!
It's way more difficult than
the time with the water balloon...
A-And...
My hands and arms hurt.
Dang it! How many days am I
going to be doing the same thing!
Second from the top in
the difficulty of mastering...
Don't depend on me!
You must have some kind
of misunderstanding!
Dang it!
Hey, Naruto.
What did you come here for?
Go buy some food from the town below.
What?! Why me?
Hey you...
Even if for a while, you're still
learning the jutsu from me.
Here you go, thanks for waiting
Thank you.
How dare he put on a master's face
only at a time like this
when he doesn't teach me anything...
Dad, buy me some ice cream.
I want this one that cracks.
Here.
Why? I can eat all of it by myself.
Nope, when you get home,
your mother will have supper ready.
Okay!
Hey...you know...
Huh?
Can you be around my training
for just a while...today?
I don't have time for that.
I have to immediately go to town.
Unless you think for yourself and
get a grip of the trick for yourself,
it'll never work.
I thought I told you three weeks ago!
Don't be spoiled like a kid.
You are a ninja.
I know that without
your telling me!
Just thought I'd ask.
Hurry up and go,
you Pervy Sage!
Oh no, little Jiraiya,
you tell so many lies!
What do you mean?!
Everything is true!
Dang it! It doesn't break
no matter how much I try...
I'm just wasting away
my chakra doing this.
Also...
The more I increase the amount of flow,
the worse the pain gets.
But...How do I say it?
If I don't go all out as if
to explode the chakra,
it's not going to break!
That's it!
If I understand the amount of chakra
that flows from the pain I feel...
Then I can bear the pain to the limit
and all at once...
No, not yet...
Not yet!
Not yet...store it!
Now!
Oww!
Hmm...There seems to have been
a little progress.
Humph!
I've still only opened a hole
and it hasn't popped with a bang!
Hey, don't pretend to be so tough. Here!
You've done well,
all on your own power.
It's so good!
Yes...
Oh yeah. Maybe we'll test a bit.
What, what?
Give me your right hand.
What's this?
Here.
It's the same one...
But this is the trick?
You're the type who was yelled at
at the academy
for not having concentration, right?
That doesn't have anything
to do with me now.
Look at this paper.
Uh?
I've seen it.
Fine, then.
Look at it again.
Hmm?
So what is this?
It's not something that
I need to explain in length,
but when you first looked
at this blank piece of paper,
you just glanced at
the whole thing, correct?
Probably.
Then where do you look on this one?
Most likely the point in the middle?
When a human being looks at
just a blank piece of paper,
he doesn't know where to look,
so the eyes wander.
But if you put even a single point on it,
the mind focuses there...
This is concentrating at a single point
and as you focus your mind,
you become spiritually stable and
you are able to extract unexpected power.
Huh?
When you opened a hole
on the rubber ball,
you must have been
concentrating desperately
to fill up the chakra
in the palm of your hand.
Yeah, yeah.
When you concentrate,
power emerges.
But without a target,
it is difficult to concentrate.
That's why we have this...
Listen Naruto, from now on,
when you store up the chakra
you build in your right hand,
try to store it up by concentrating
on that mark.
Concentrate...
All right, I'll try it!
Sasuke...
My, my arm!
Are you okay, Lord Orochimaru?
Please take this medicine quickly.
Oh, my...
Just as I get back,
I have to clean the room.
Please make sure you to take
your medicine.
I don't need that kind
of lip service.
It's medicine that I prescribed.
The pain should subside
at least slightly.
The pain on this arm
that seems to burn...
I never thought that it cause
this much suffering.
Sarutobi...known as Third Hokage.
It's his last curse, after all.
Enough of the talking...
More importantly,
has that individual been found?
Yes...She seems to be at a place
called Tanzaku Town.
Tanzaku Town...
Is that so...?
But the opponent is one of the Sannin,
the Legendary Three Ninjas.
It won't be that simple.
Good medicine tends to taste bitter.
Concentrate!
Darn it. It's not supposed to be like this
It has to break like "pang."
Concentrate!
Hello...I'd like to make a little inquiry
Dang it.
Concentrate.
Concentrate!
No good.
Dang it. What does it mean
to concentrate?!
Damn you, Sarutobi!
All right then...
I'm going again to gather
some information.
What...? But you just came.
I don't have any time to waste.
Hey, hey...!
Isn't there going to be even
a little soulful game of catch
between the master and pupil?
You scoundrel.
Strike!
Here, the game of catch is over.
See you later.
Humph...I'll forget about that Pervy Sage
and work hard by myself.
That's the only way, Naruto...
You have to do this training alone.
You have the ability to approach
the Fourth Hokage's level...
Grasp it by yourself!
Hmm...Never seen her.
If that's the case...
Sorry to bother you.
I know the person.
As well as where she is right now.
I'll buy you a drink.
There's no need.
I was able to win a tidy sum...
Thanks to that lady.
Yeah...you are indeed
the Legendary Sitting Duck.
She lost again, huh.
Her losses started to pile up...
So she was talking about
changing her location.
Where to?
Seven, seven, seven...
Here it comes!
Congratulations to the customer!
Fever has started
on machine number 44.
Now, please keep on getting it out
like a flood.
Lady Tsunade, a rare thing does happen
once in while.
A 37 for me?
I have a bad premonition.
I also have some knowledge
regarding Lady Tsunade...
I did use to be part of
the Medical Corps, after all.
She was the first person to propose
what is now an accepted practice
of assigning one medical specialist
to a small squad of four.
This was a very revolutionary idea...
A small combat unit that doesn't
even have emergency medical skills,
what would happen to them in a battlefield
is clearer than seeing fire.
Countless experiences in war
simply became knowledge
to equip themselves with.
Many who were sacrificed
led to the creation of that style.
A person understands the nature
of things for the first time
after losing them.
And the thing created by
one of the legendary Sannin,
who is known as the medical specialist
is that sacrifice.
Hey!
You guys, we're in class right now.
You...fools!
You guys have no concentration at all...!
This is not the way to
become fine ninja.
How can we stay still at a table,
right, Akamaru?
I'm hungry.
Sensei, if it's a scolding,
do it quickly.
What the?! You, you guys...
From now, we will have
an after school lesson
to teach you guys more concentration!
- What?!
What's this?
You guys are going to do from now
what the predecessors of
the Leaf Village
used to perform every day
as a concentration method!
It is training to build up chakra
by concentrating your entire energy
on the leaf on your forehead.
It's an ancient way of learning
how not to become distracted
from anything else
by concentrating on a single point,
the leaf.
The one who hones his concentration
is truly a great ninja...
This is the origin of the Leaf Symbol
on the headband.
That sounds like a lie.
Aren't you making that story up
to force us to try harder?
I'm not making this up!
It's a true story.
Anyhow, can you really become
a great ninja
by just polishing your concentration?
At any rate,
a great ninja is a guy who's strong.
Hey, you have a point.
This stuff...
Bye, bye Sensei!
Hey, hey, you guys wait a minute.
- We won't wait!
- We don't have time for that!
Hey! You misfits!
This is the same thing.
I should have paid more attention
to what Iruka Sensei was saying...
I'm so stupid.
But nothing will start
if I just keep on regretting.
All right, I'm going to master this!
Concentrate, concentrate...
Wow! Tanzaku Castle sure does have
a commanding presence!
It's worth being designated
as the cultural heritage.
Don't dally...
We're going to hurry up
and leave this town.
Lady Tsunade, please look more carefully..
It costs nothing to view.
Lady Tsunade?
What is this chill?
Now!
What a kid...
Raising the density in chakra
to the point that it burns the palm.
He never ceases to amaze me.
It broke.
Good! The second step seems
to be complete.
Hurry...The third step.
That will come later.
We'll now go meet Tsunade.
That's...
Orochimaru.
I found you.