Wh-Why...
Why does such
a good man have to... die?!
It's sad...
It's so sad!
I remember now...
I don't remember when,
but you showed it to me, didn't you?
With a twinkle in your eye,
you proudly told me
it was a memento from your father.
That pipe box, right?
It was an amazing piece of work.
No wonder you were so proud of it...
Even though I took it and smashed it,
you only laughed.
You were still smiling when
we kicked and threw you around.
It was a great smile.
Really...
Hold it in, Rokusuke!
They'll all be gone.
If we let this moment go,
there won't be another chance
to get out of the village!
But Kanpachi is!
It's for the village,
we have to do something and
make our way to that village!
Yeah...
Funerals are the best, aren't they!
I want to do that again.
One... two... three of them...
got away again...
Looks like we can have
another funeral.
This is...
The Hidden Leaf Village.
You are...?
Naruto Uzumaki! I'm in the middle
of my training right now!
The Hidden Leaf Village...
H-Hey! I said hey!
Hang in there!
This is training too...!
I can't give up yet! Not yet!
The escort mission for the ruler of
the Land of Swamps, Lord Chichiyasu,
was completed without incident!
Well done.
That's Lady Tsunade's...!
The best dumplings always come from
the Leaf Village, don't they?
That was my last one!
Mission Accomplished!
I've come to strike down
the pirates of the Have toni Channel
with the fist of love!
If they take this opportunity
to rehabilitate themselves,
it makes shedding these
tears of youth worthwhile!
I'll have your team do it for me.
Yes?
Just when we're busy enough,
Naruto goes and brings in more work.
After this, Guy has that S-rank mission.
The client picked him,
so he must depart today.
So, you'll do it without Guy.
That's pretty straightforward...
I called Neji, Tenten and Lee.
Ohh!
My pupils are more than capable of
completing this mission without any trouble!
Wait...
Take Naruto Uzumaki, too.
Why can't it just be my pupils,
who are adored by the heavens?
Please answer me, Lady Tsunade!
It just is.
Those three people that Naruto saved
came all the way
from the Katabami Gold Mine
to request a mission.
The Katabami Gold Mine is one of
the Land of Rivers' greatest mines,
but about half a year ago, a group
calling themselves the Kurosuki family
appeared on the pretext of guarding it,
and took control of the village...
killing villagers for
no particular reason.
How vile!
Your mission is this:
Once those three have
regained their strength,
escort them to the Katabami Gold Mine
and eliminate the Kurosuki family.
It's a simple mission.
Anyway, they're probably just
a bunch of punks after money.
Why did you call me for
such an easy mission?
Who do you think you are?
I'm busy training and searching
for Sasuke, and—
You forced your way into missions
that you weren't called for.
It's not a genin's place
to pick and choose missions!
Would you like to be sent back
to the Academy? Well?!
Neji Hyuga.
Yes!
You're the leader!
It'll be good training for you
to handle someone so unruly.
I'd rather not... but I accept.
I'll go continue my training!
Hey Naruto!
Please excuse them.
They have no manners...
Wait!
Those little brats...!
What do they think a mission is?!
Umm, excuse me?
What?!
The Kurosuki Family...
What did you say
their boss' name was?
Raiga!
That's what I thought...
What?
Well, on a previous mission,
I heard a rumor about him.
A rumor...?
Pervy Sage isn't back yet... and
now I'm being forced on a mission...
Oh, this is irritating...
Sakura!
Naruto?
What's going on? A bird?
Yesterday I found it injured
and treated it, but...
Sakura, that's amazing!
But poor thing.
It's separated from its friends.
Naruto!
Oh, sorry, did I intrude?
You intruded big time!
No, no!
You mustn't look back! In youth,
injuries are an absolute must!
Sakura, Hello!
Hello!
What did you come here for?
Just to have a word.
Huh? What the—?!
Oh, Sakura, goodbye!
- Hey! What was that?!
- She went wild, didn't she?
She should act her age...
What?! The boss of
the Kurosuki family
is one of the
Seven Ninja Swordsmen of the Mist?
Yeah, it's exclusive information
from our respected Guy-sensei.
Who are the
Seven Ninja Swordsmen of the Mist?
Naruto...
you fought in the Land of
the Waves mission, didn't you?
At that time...
Oh, Zabuza! And?
And Guy-sensei and Kakashi-sensei
fought Kisame Hoshigaki.
I heard that
you met them there too, Naruto.
Oh! I know that guy!
Those two were once called
the Seven Ninja Swordsmen of the Mist.
And at that time,
who was with Kisame Hoshigaki?
Oh!
The man called Itachi! So?
You still don't understand?
If Raiga is one of the
Seven Ninja Swordsmen of the Mist,
then he's probably tied to Itachi
who was with Kisame.
Oh! And?
Tell me, who's after Itachi?
I know! Sasuke!
That's right!
We can probably get a clue
about Sasuke's whereabouts
at the Katabami Gold Mine!
But...
If that's what Guy-sensei said then...
Don't say anything rude!
It's information that's
100% reliable!
Starting now,
while guarding Rokusuke and the others,
we head toward the Katabami Gold Mine
to fulfill our mission to
wipe out the Kurosuki family.
There's a shop I'm familiar
with close to the gold mine.
Let's make that the base.
What do you mean
a shop you're familiar with?
That's something to look forward to
on our journey.
That aside, Naruto is late...
If the source of the information
is Guy-sensei,
maybe he couldn't quite trust it?
That's not true!
Naruto will definitely come!
That's because Guy-sensei's
information is correct!
Whatever.
Here I am!
We're all here so...!
Is that for you to say?!
Let's go!
So... which way?
Don't be so anxious, Rokusuke,
Those kids will save our town.
It's post meal training!
I won't lose!
How long do you intend
to rest here?!
If we hurry, maybe we can still save
Kanpachi from being buried...
Give it up...
How long do you think
it's been since that happened?
It's painful but...
I remember... this sleepiness.
The shop is close by.
You say you're sleepy,
so are you walking in your sleep?!
It's okay.
I slept while on a marathon on
this road for three days straight.
You're joking, right?
It's true.
A youthful marathon with Guy-sensei.
My body still remembers it.
I've gotten sleepy.
Hey, Bushy Brow,
are you really okay?
That's right. In this area,
there's the scent of spicy curry.
Curry? Now that you mention it...
That's right!
Over there!
It's the Curry of Life Shop!
Grandma Sansho!
Oh my...
Oh goodness!
I haven't seen you for a while!
- Oh my my my!
- You're looking well!
So this is the shop Lee was talking about?
That mountain is
the Katabami Gold Mine.
Grandma Sansho's curry saved my life.
So you're saying
it's delicious curry?
No, it really saved my life.
I'm indebted to this curry.
It was when
I'd just become a Genin...
When Guy-sensei gave me
a special training routine.
Oh my, that's right.
I remember.
Do your best!
Oh my...
Hey Grandma Sansho!
Oh my, they've come again!
Those people are running in their sleep.
Karashi! Karashi!
If you had that kind of energy,
you wouldn't lose to the bullies.
Oh my,
I might have said too much.
Oh my! It's the third day.
They've been running the whole time.
Oh my. What a problem.
I wonder if he's hungry...?
What a pickle! He's not waking up!
Maybe I didn't use
enough spice?
Karashi...
I've never seen a person
who works this hard.
Oh really... so you want to help
this young man too?
This is the Curry of Life.
Now! Grandma Sansho went to
the trouble of making this curry.
Let's eat!
I'm digging in!
Delicious! This is super delicious!
Delicious! The use of spices
is wonderful!
And this rice
goes perfectly with the curry!
Delicious!
By the way, I don't see Karashi.
Karashi saw how hard you worked
and became a bright kid
full of energy, but...
He got too much energy
and left for town.
What?
I was wrong to keep telling him
to be stronger.
"I'm going to be a man!
I'm going to be part of
the Kurosuki family, he said.
Oh my! I'm not blaming you.
Don't worry.
It's too late.
I'm responsible...
Oh my.
Neji!
Please add Karashi's rescue
to our mission objectives!
We'll bring him back from
the road of evil!
It's fine.
We'll use this shop as a base
and take a good look into the village.
Then we'll come up with a strategy
and spring into action.
Yes!
You guys await orders here.
Because it's dangerous
if the Kurosuki family finds us.
It's a disaster!
Rokusuke! Rokusuke!
He's gone!
I'm sure he went to town alone!
That's not good!
If those guys find Rokusuke...!
Now that it's come to this,
we don't have time
to come up with a strategy!
Let's get right to it!
No!
We'll get right to it!
Let's hurry.
Wait for me, Kanpachi,
I'm coming now...
Someone... is coming...
Oh, another one...
Looks like it's time for a funeral!
Please don't die...
I'll get you out now.
Hey!
What are you doing there?
One, two...
Hope they're all right.
I'm sure they'll be able
to bring Karashi back.
Definitely, Definitely.
One, two...
That's the Katabami Gold Mine...
Instead of just getting
Rokusuke and Karashi back,
let's finish the Kurosuki Family
once and for all!
Don't get carried away, Naruto.
So, what's the plan then?
I'm kind of worried about
what Guy-sensei told us.
The boss of the Kurosuki Family
may be
one of the
Seven Ninja Swordsmen of the Mist.
Who knows what
they'll do to Rokusuke?
Yeah, but how reliable is
Guy-sensei's information?
What are you talking about?!
Guy-sensei is always right!
Calm down, Lee.
We should investigate first.
Yeah!
Lord Raiga, we were able
to capture Rokusuke,
one of the three that
slipped out of the village.
Well done.
It seems that they went to ask
for some help from a ninja village.
Where did you go?!
I'm sorry.
Stand down, rookie.
Yes sir!
Rokusuke, I thought we had
a good relationship
with everybody in the Gold Mine.
Well, that's...
Why would you do that? I'm so sad
to hear that you left the village.
I can't remember how things
were in the past,
when everything was going well.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I won't do it again!
Yeah, I have a good idea.
I'm going to arrange for your funeral.
Please don't! Please let me go!
I won't do it again,
so please forgive me!
Why? Don't you like funerals?
No, I don't want to die yet!
You know, I really like funerals...
Think about it.
When they are alive, humans speak ill
of each other,
they betray each other,
and they hate each other.
But at a funeral,
they forget all the hatred
they had for the other.
They even remember
the good times they had together.
Right?
You have to be kidding me!
No! Please don't do it.
Hey!
Let me go!
It's a done deal then.
Let's have a big funeral for Rokusuke.
- Yeah!
Come on!
Hurry up!
Is that gold?
There's nothing shiny about it.
They have to melt that ore with mercury.
After that, they evaporate the mercury,
and only then do they get pure gold.
I don't get it.
Well, there is no need
for you to understand it.
Oh!
Huh? What are you doing
Hurry up!
If you don't hurry up,
I'll ask the boss to hold
a funeral for you!
Please forgive me!
I'm getting really mad now.
I won't forgive them!
Calm down, Naruto...
We don't know anything
about them yet.
That's right. We should do
what Neji is telling us.
Yeah, but...
if we don't do something,
that poor old guy is going to die!
Naruto, leave this to me.
Wait, Lee!
Hey, hey.
Hurry up and pick them up!
Yeah! Way to go, Lee!
Are you okay, old man?
Oh my gosh!
What have you done?!
Here. Drink some water.
What are you doing?!
I beg you.
Please punch me, kick me.
Please knock me around
like the way you just did
with those guys.
What are you saying?
If you won't do it,
I'll do it myself!
What are you doing?!
Stop!
I'm scared.
Just think what they'll do
if they find out I was
the only one who was safe.
What was that sound?
Did they find us?
Oh my, that's the sound
of the funeral bell.
Funeral?
Yeah.
Raiga, the boss of the Kurosuki family
which rules this town,
arranges a funeral for
those who betray him.
He buries them alive.
What? They bury them alive?
That's so cruel!
Yeah, but...
Raiga always cries sadly
during the funeral.
That's one weird guy.
But...
That doesn't seem to be
the sound of the bell for you.
Yeah, I heard that Rokusuke
was caught this morning, so...
What?!
I'm so happy, I remember
the first day I met that guy.
Yeah? That's nice.
Yeah... When I told him we were taking
over the mountain from the magistrate,
he was so relieved to be freed from
the high taxes that he was paying.
He was laughing out of pure joy...
He was a really nice guy.
I like funerals.
Makes me feel nostalgic.
Would you put on
a big funeral for me too?
Fool! I'm not putting on
a funeral for you.
You are not going
to die before me.
I don't have to have a funeral for you
to think of the good times
because you are always a good boy.
Raiga.
What is it?
They're coming.
They'll show up anytime now.
Yeah... I'm excited to see
what kind of help he sought.
Okay! Let's save the guy.
Let's do it, Neji.
Okay.
Byakugan!
It's all right. He's still alive.
If we can get rid of
the guys around him,
we can save him.
Okay! Let's get rid
of them quickly!
Yeah!
Okay, let's go!
No! Let me out!
An enemy attack!
You...!
Tenten, you take the right!
Okay!
Gentle Fist!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Na-ru-to...
Uzumaki Barrage!
That's the way!
- Watch out!
- Huh?
There are three more!
Here comes the Leaf Village's
handsome devil, Rock Lee!
I found the last one!
You are...
Who is this guy?
Well...
This is Karashi.
The one Grandma Sansho
was talking about...
This is Karashi?
Karashi, was it your own decision
to join the Kurosuki Family...
just like Grandma Sansho said it was?
So what if it was?
What?!
Lord Raiga is great!
He overthrew the corrupt magistrate
of the Katabami Gold Mine,
and he liberated everybody
from the village!
Karashi, did you know that
Grandma Sansho worries about you
everyday while cooking curry?
Naruto, leave things to me here.
Karashi, you saved my life
with your curry of life.
If you can make such
a wonderful curry,
how can you serve a man
who has no respect for life?!
Why?
Nobody cares to compliment me
even if I can make that curry.
As a man born in this world,
I should gain more power and
try to take over the world!
Instead of rotting away in that shop
that no one ever goes to.
What? I can't take this anymore!
Lee!
Karashi, not only did you and
Grandma Sansho's curry save my life...
But you also taught me that
if you make it from the heart,
just one serving of curry
could save lives,
and that even someone like me could
achieve anything if I just work hard enough.
You looked much stronger
and dignified then than you do now.
Please promise me...
Please get out of the Kurosuki Family!
You're right...
I'm sorry... I'm so sorry!
Oh, I'm so relieved.
Hey! Please get me out of here.
It's dark and I can't breathe.
Oh yeah!
We almost forgot about Rokusuke.
Mmm? You guys...
Sorry to keep you waiting.
It's all right now.
I'm sorry. Thinking that maybe
I could still save my friend
who got buried alive...
I just couldn't stay still.
Yeah, I understand.
Neji, what is it?
What is this?
This ominous presence...
Hey Neji, what is it?
We are being watched.
It's probably Raiga.
What?
From the top of that cliff...
Okay. Let's go!
Karashi, please take care of Rokusuke.
All right.
No one's here.
Where did he go?
Mmm? What is that?
This mist...
Ninja Art: Hidden Mist Jutsu!
Neji, try to find the enemy
with your Byakugan.
I've been trying...!
I... can't see a thing!
That's impossible.
Even Neji's Byakugan
with its 360-degree vision is useless!
What's going on?
There shouldn't be a jutsu
that can defeat the Byakugan!
What do you think, Ranmaru?
It's amazing...
One of them can see
the chakra network itself.
He probably has some sort
of Kekkei Genkai power.
He can see us?
It's all right,
my power is superior to his...
So, what are you going to do?
Everybody in the Katabami
Gold Mine is depending on me.
I am the one who must maintain
peace in this village.
Are you going to hold a funeral?
No, even if I hold a funeral,
I have no memories of them.
I'll just get rid of them!
Watch,
Ninja Art: Lightning Fang!
Wh-What is it?!
Lighting, strike!
They blew up...
They blew up and died!
As I expected, I'm not sad.
I suppose you can't hold a proper
funeral when you feel nothing...
Four of them are still alive.
Can't be! After being hit
by my Lightning Fang...
No...
If you say so, it has to be true.
He's going to be a problem...
The enemy was nearby...
But I couldn't see anything.
It's strange...
Even if it's the Hidden Mist Jutsu,
my Byakugan should be able
to see through it.
Byakugan!
For sure this time...
I can see it!
Two targets, 52 degrees to the southwest!
Three targets, 12 degrees to the southeast!
One target, 8 degrees to the southeast!
Another target at 24 degrees
to the northwest!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Let's go!
Leaf Hurricane!
No way!
Why?!
Uzumaki Barrage!
I missed!
H-Help me!
Bushy Brow?
Th-The enemy disappeared!
It can't be...
False images with chakra networks?
One at the middle of the cliff,
one at the bottom of the cliff,
one on the right, one on the left.
We can't hold funerals,
but I'll take care of them
without a trace.
Thunder Funeral: Banquet of Lightning!
The corpses are warm.
We're strong... you and me.
No, it's you.
Ranmaru, you're strong.
With you, I'm also strong.
Wait... They aren't dead yet.
They're just unconscious.
They're stubborn.
Alright, if frying them doesn't work,
then we'll chop them to pieces.
Flesh and even bone...
I'll crush them nicely.
Ranmaru...! Are you all right?!
Hang in there, Ranmaru!
Ranmaru...!
I'm okay.
Raiga...
This person... is still unconscious.
What did you say?
It's amazing...
He's fighting
with only muscle memory.
What a fine face.
It's seared into my very soul.
Let's hold a funeral for him...
I am sure it will be one
that will make me cry!
From the right!
What's with this guy...?
He's hard to read his moves...
But for your sake, Raiga,
I'll do my best.
Together, okay!
Left!
Right!
From the front! Jump! Now!
You... you... you!
What?
How is this guy... still moving?
B-Bushy Brows...
Lee...
Could he have lost consciousness...?
Tenten! Neji!
Raiga! Turn around!
What? That voice just now...?
Wha—?!
Raiga!
Ranmaru!
This is...
Neji...
Ranmaru!
Move!
Huh? Somehow... it felt like
I was fighting in my dreams...
Ranmaru...
You!
Heh! Naruto Uzumaki arrives!
Naruto...
Just die already...
Hey! I have something
I want to ask you!
You... I heard you're one of
the Seven Ninja Swordsmen of the Mist.
So what if I was?!
You know Zabuza, right?!
You also know...
someone called Kisame, right?!
I despise them!
I don't want to remember them!
I hate you too!
Then!
Then I'll make you talk by force!
A clone?!
You... You're weaker
than you were a moment ago.
Wh-What...?
Lightning Ball!
Damn...
Huh, you are tough...
Lightning Ball!
Naruto!
It's not... working at all.
I'm not going to
remember your smile!
Die!
Ranmaru... where are you?
What's in this bag...?
Byakugan!
There's... someone...
Could it be?
This powder...
was it obscuring their chakra networks?
It's even creating the chakra network!
Naruto!
Do the Shadow Clone Jutsu!
But he saw all the shadow clones...
Don't worry.
His eyes are right here!
Ranmaru! I'm going to come save you
after I defeat this guy!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Bring it on!
Lightning Ball!
What? Was that last one just a lucky shot?
Stop messing around.
All I have to do is defeat you all, right?
Let's go!
We're not done yet!
You...
At this rate... my chakra will...
The mist...
The Hidden Mist Jutsu is fading away...
Damn it! I'll finish them all at once!
Damn it!
I'm not going to let you get away!
Wait!
Ninja Art: Boulder Avalanche
Naruto!
Naruto...
Did you see that?!
Yeah, I saw it!
Prepare yourself!
Stop it!
I can't stop!
I... did it.
This is Raiga's eye...?
Such a big eyeball!
Huh?
Idiot...
It's a human being!
Huh?!
In my dream...
I guess you were the one
I was fighting against.
It wasn't me...
It was Raiga and me together...
Together...?
Always... since back then...
Don't act like you're asleep.
You are going to die...
Don't move!
There is a spy in this village
who snuck into the Hidden Mist Village...
We came to kill those guys, but...
I lost track of who I was supposed to kill.
So, I just started killing randomly...
Wh-What are you saying?
It's fine...
If I am going to be killed by you.
Huh...?
Why is it fine for me to kill you...?
You were... always crying...
Huh? Me... cry?
In your heart... you were searching
for a reason to live.
I was always watching... you.
What... are you?
I am the same as you...
living is painful.
I don't understand
the meaning of living.
Because of my sickness,
I couldn't go outside...
Shunned by everyone,
all I could do was to take
a peek of the world from this blanket...
But... if with my death,
if you are able to feel
the meaning of life even a little...
My life was not needed
from the beginning.
Please...
Are you... alone?
Come with me.
From now on,
you and I are two as one.
From that day on,
I became Raiga's eyes and ears.
Raiga became my hands and feet.
The outside world that I dashed
into for the very first time...
it was filled with things
I had never seen or heard before.
It was fun.
Whenever and wherever,
I was with Raiga.
No matter when it was,
there wasn't a time
that we were separated.
We were trying to find the meaning of life
by living for each other.
We were convinced that was
our reason for living.
That's why...
If Raiga is not around,
I no longer have the power
to live by myself.
I've lost the purpose to live...
Do you have someone
precious to you?
I want to protect
someone important to me...
I want to make his dream come true,
and that's my dream.
I no longer need to live.
Don't say such stupid things.
What are you doing?
Now, quickly.
Why are you hesitating...?
With no arms or legs,
I have no way to resist.
You should carry out your mission...
Hurry and deliver your finishing blow.
Our mission is to drive the
Kurosuki Family out of this village...
Without Raiga, he cannot be
of any threat to this village.
The problem right now is that
the Kurosuki Family members
have lost their leadership.
With their leader gone,
there's no telling what they'll do.
For this mission...
this is the finishing touch.
Yeah, but what are we
going to do with him?
Is he a villain worth tying up?
No, he is not.
He might kill himself, right?
Once the mission is over,
we will come save you right away...
A chakra sealing tag?
We can't help it.
He is an enemy, after all...
We should assume he has other jutsu.
Just in case!
Hey...
Here they come!
Naruto! Don't come...
If you value your life,
be quiet.
Karashi...
I heard that you were deeply sorry
for your actions...!
How can I go back to the curry shop
with no shame?!
Now!
Did you see that?!
Even without Master Raiga,
the Kurosuki Family is eternal!
Hey... what are you looking for?
Isn't it obvious? The brats!
Are you referring to us?
What?!
What you crushed were our forms
made by the Shadow Clone Jutsu
and the Transformation Jutsu.
Take formation!
Ninja Art: Black Tornado!
Wha?
Those were also made by
the Shadow Clone Jutsu
and the Transformation Jutsu!
We saw through everything!
Here I go.
Leaf Hurricane!
Disperse!
Byakugan!
2 Palms! 4 Palms!
8 Palms!
16 Palms!
32 Palms!
8 Trigrams 64 Palms!
Here I come!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Clone Spinning Axe Kick!
Huh?! Oww...
It's already over...
What?! Not fair!
Man! You could've saved
some for me!
Just when I thought
I'd try the new jutsu!
Man, you never learn, do you!
Karashi, are you prepared?
I was just kidding!
How dare you torment us!
You really think we'll let this go
as a joke?
I couldn't help it! If I didn't listen,
I would have gotten killed
by the Kurosuki family.
In place of the Kurosuki family,
I'll crack your head
with this hammer!
Yeah! Yeah!
I'm sorry...
Please move, Lee!
Please hit me until
you guys are satisfied.
Why you?
It's partly my responsibility
that the once kind-hearted Karashi
went and joined a gang.
Yours?
Because of me,
he got the impression
that power is everything.
Right, that's right!
Though I knew that it's a bad thing,
I just had to...
You be quiet!
Karashi is still inexperienced.
But he has skills to make curry
that can save people's lives.
Please give Karashi the opportunity
to make amends by making curry.
If Karashi goes astray again,
then I will...!
Punish him with my fists!
Everyone, what do you think
about letting Lee and Grandma Sansho
take care of this situation...
After all, he was just
an underling of the Kurosuki family.
It's not like he directly
attacked us or anything...
Let's have Lee educate him harshly...
In that case...
Thank you very much!
Th-Thank you...
And with this, our mission is complete.
No, not yet...
Huh?
Are you all right?
What's the point of being all right?
I can't live alone.
Don't say that!
Why don't we just leave this weakling
behind!
Everyone has to live alone!
But don't you need friends
who can help you and stuff...?
I'm talking about the basics!
I hate people who are indecisive!
I was frail from the time I was born.
That shabby cabin was
the entire world for me.
I have no memory of my parents...
I survived only by
the small amount of food
that the villagers sometimes
brought me...
But even someone like me
had a power that no one else did.
Here you go.
Thank you...
Is your leg okay?
The one you cut with the scythe?
D-Did I tell you that story?!
No... I kind of found out...
How? No one else besides me
came today or yesterday, right?
No, I just saw it from here...
Scary!
As time went by everyone began
to fear me since I had the power
to know what was happening outside
even from my room.
Did you know?!
I heard that Ranmaru has
the ability to see everything...
Were we being spied on every day?
Get out of the village!
You monster!
And so I had no more visitors...
All I could do was to wait to die.
That's when Raiga saved me...
I see. What a bitter past.
Yes, it is.
Hmm...
Raiga took me out to
the unknown world.
Ranmaru, try opening your eyes...
This is the outside world where
we'll be living from now on... okay?
Okay...
If Raiga isn't here,
it's the same as losing my body.
Perhaps Raiga became known
as one of the
Seven Ninja Swordsmen of the Mist
because he was able
to borrow your power.
It seems like you two
helped each other to live...
Yes.
That's not true!
You were being used for
Raiga's evil deeds!
I might have been... used...
But good or evil doesn't matter to me.
I was just his senses...
Then that won't mean
that you're really living!
Huh?
See, you have to do your best
to live from now on!
First, eat the Curry of Life
and get your strength back!
That's right!
You will get nourishment.
Won't that just make him sicker?
Naruto, you can't eat it either, right?
Actually, the more I eat it,
the more energized my body feels...
That curry saved my life, you know!
Until the day you're able
to walk alone,
I will become your body!
Okay?
I have one favor to ask...
Huh?
Byakugan!
As I expected...
I can no longer see life in Raiga.
Can you see, Ranmaru?
Yes.
Is this okay?
Yes...
Let's go... The mission is complete.
Hey!
What?
That's!
One, two, one, two.
Grandma Sansho!
What's all this ruckus?!
Dust will go into the curry.
L-Lee and the others came back!
K-Karashi is with them!
Is it worth the ruckus?
Grandma, aren't you happy?
One, two... One, two...
Your snot will go in!
Grandma Sansho! I'm back!
Karashi is here too!
M-Mom, sorry!
Please forgive me!
Please forgive him...
He says he'll devote himself
from now on,
and train to take over
the Curry of Life Shop, so please...
First you have to eat...
Huh...
Wow, it looks good!
If you're not going to eat, I will!
I've prepared some for each of you...
Oh my, that's a very pale child.
Yeah, can you prepare
some for him too?
Especially mild...
I prefer mild too...
Oh my...
Mom... thanks for the food!
This is the "Punishment x300" curry...
It's spicy, it's spicy...
But it's good! It's good, Mom!
Here, I have some for everybody!