Genjutsu?
You're going to teach me genjutsu, Pervy Sage?!
To be exact, I'm going to teach you
how to break a genjutsu.
How to break... a genjutsu...?
Listen up, Naruto.
There's a trick to breaking out of a
genjutsu if you get caught in one...
Pervy Sage.
You should know that trick very well...
Hey, Pervy Sage!
What?!
I want to know about
how to cast a genjutsu,
not how to break out of one!
Huh?
Wh-What's up with that reaction?!
Listen up, Naruto...
A genjutsu works on
an opponent's five senses.
You can control the chakra flowing
through their cerebral nervous system.
It's a type of jutsu that requires
a high level of intelligence.
Hmm... I don't really get it...
I didn't think so...
Nobody is telling you to
master genjutsu.
You're not the genjutsu type
to begin with...
Huh? Really?
Then forget about genjutsu!
Let's get to the next training!
The next training!
That won't do!
Why not?!
Some enemies use genjutsu,
after all.
For example, Itachi Uchiha!
Come to think of it,
even Kakashi-sensei
was beaten by his technique...
That's why you need to know
how to deal with genjutsu!
Fine.
The enemy takes control of
your inner chakra. That is genjutsu.
If you can create a disturbance
within your own chakra,
the genjutsu itself cannot work.
I don't know if
I can do such a thing.
You've already had experience doing it.
Huh? I did?
During your Rasengan training,
you learned to release chakra
and rotate it in your palms.
All right! Just watch me!
So, that's it?
Yes. Instead of releasing chakra
into your palms,
you disrupt it inside your body.
That's easy.
All right then.
Let's get some real practice!
Huh?!
Summoning Jutsu!
Oh, if it isn't Jiraiya Honey!
Thanks for coming all this way, Gamariki.
Oh come on, no need to be so polite.
I-I can't breathe.
Oh, who is this cute boy?
He's Naruto.
Huh?! What is this guy?!
Hello, Naruto boy.
He's kinda creepy.
I have a favor to ask,
Mr. Gamariki.
I want you to teach him
how to break a genjutsu.
What should I do?
Well, since none other than
Jiraiya Honey is asking me.
- Naruto! Come on, you must ask him too!
- H-Hey, stop it! What are you doing?
So cute!
Let's train right away, Naruto boy!
What?!
I'll be very gentle.
What is this place?
Where exactly am I?
Huh?
Pervy Sage?
Hey, Pervy Sage!
What the hell is this?!
You're in my genjutsu world, my boy.
D-Don't come near me.
I'm not letting you escape!
I've have to break this genjutsu fast
and get out of here!
Let's see...
Disrupt the chakra inside my body.
These dumplings are awfully good.
Oh?
Seriously! What are you releasing?
I told you,
disrupt the chakra inside you!
No!
You fool!
Release!
Huh? What happened?
You tried to disrupt chakra
inside the genjutsu world,
but in reality, you released it
outward and it exploded.
Oh, I failed then.
This means it's back
to basic chakra control,
rather than actual combat training.
I don't think Naruto boy
and I are compatible.
Disrupt inside my body.
Once more!
This is harder than
doing the Rasengan.
Rotate it inside my body.
Yes! That's the way!
You keep releasing it.
You've got a ways to go.
I can't do anymore...
My head feels like it's boiling!
Yeah... Everyone feels that at first.
But once you overcome it,
you will find the true secret ninjutsu:
the bond that ties our three families
together.
Then even Shikamaru and Choji are...?
No way...
There's no way those two
are training this hard.
The recent incident with Sasuke
wounded everyone badly...
in both body and spirit.
But because of that,
we will grow.
Without a doubt,
it will take several years
to master the secret ninjutsu,
even if you continue training.
However... it's so you can
keep up with them...
and in order to protect
the Ino-Shika-Cho tradition,
as well as our own...
That's why I must pass on
our secret ninjutsu to you.
That's why I was really happy
when you came
and asked me to train you.
W-Wait a sec...
Did you just say it would take
several years to master it?
Hmm?
There's no shortcut
to this training.
But I believe that you can
see this through...
O-Oh right! I just remembered
I have something to do!
I'm not finished talking to you!
In fact, have you forgotten
the meaning
behind those piercings?
The oath you took when Sarutobi
presented them to you?
That you will keep that vow,
and pass on new piercings
to the next generation.
You will eventually lead
the Yamanaka Clan...
and entrust a new earring to
your child who will be born.
Not this story again...
O-Oh, that's right!
Choji's being discharged today!
What? Choji is?
I have to get a present and
get things ready, so I have to go!
I-I see. I guess
it can't be helped then.
Yeah... See you later.
Several years?
You've got to be kidding me!
I just wanted to quickly get stronger
and show those guys!
What's the point if
it takes so many years?
Sakura!
Ino!
We're celebrating Choji's discharge
from the hospital.
Want to join us?
Oh... Choji's well enough to leave?
That's great news!
But I'm sorry!
I'm in the middle of training.
Please congratulate Choji for me!
Huh? Where's Shikamaru?
He's seeing off the Sand ninja.
Thank you for the food!
Only the three of us here
to celebrate is pretty lame.
Hey, Asuma-sensei...
So does that mean I can eat the rest?
Hey Choji, I heard all about it!
How you were flirting with
all the nurses!
Ino... I'm going to tell you
the one truth about men.
There isn't a man alive who
doesn't go crazy over nurses!
Right, Asuma-sensei?
Hmm? Y-Yeah, I guess...
What kind of nonsense is that?
Asuma-sensei only has eyes
for Kurenai-sensei!
Huh? Is that true?
I'd like three more orders
of the special beef fillet!
Right now!
Score!
But...
Open wide, Sasuke!
Thank you, Ino. I owe you my life!
That might work...
Why am I feeding you?!
I never refuse food
that's offered to me.
That's my Ninja Way!
Another helping please!
Right when you were discharged,
you were still skinny.
That sure didn't last long.
With that kind of appetite,
I'd say you're back to normal.
When I'm done eating,
can you help me train, Asuma-sensei?
Hey! Are you stupid?
You just got better!
Man, everyone's so stuck
on training...
How come you're so eager
to get back to training, Choji?
For starters,
I want to catch up to Shikamaru
who beat me to becoming a Chunin.
After all, together
we're the Ino-Shika-Cho trio.
Do your best too! Okay, Ino?
I don't need you to tell me that.
All right!
Don't get too confident because
of one or two successes.
You have to become faster
and more efficient.
No one waits for treatment
on the battlefield.
Yes!
Who's there?
Lady Tsunade!
Please make me your apprentice!
You belong to the Yamanaka Clan...
Sakura was able to revive
that in three months.
I'll test you... and see how far
you get in three months.
I understand. Please let me try!
This thing?
Usually, the way to resuscitate
a creature that has asphyxiated
is to stimulate the heart
or brain with chakra.
Octopi generally have one systemic heart
and two branchial hearts.
And separate from the brain,
they have eight nervous systems
in their arms.
It has many organs vital
to resuscitation.
In other words,
it has a lot of parts that need
to be taken care of.
Oh...
You can quit if you don't like it!
And you, Sakura! You are completely
deficient in the knowledge of healing!
I have to learn... all of this?!
You can quit if you don't like it!
That happens because
your chakra control is too rough.
You have to fine-tune your method,
or you'll rip the octopus apart.
Control your chakra more delicately!
Y-Yes!
She's having a hard time.
She's made some mistakes,
but in this short time, she's...
Sasuke said he was going to
sever his bond with me
and become stronger.
He said I could never understand
his feelings.
You were friends with Orochimaru
long ago, right, Pervy Sage?
Why did Orochimaru desert the village
and decide to destroy the Leaf?
Orochimaru changed after
his parents were killed.
He became obsessed with
the Forbidden Jutsu.
Maybe he longed to see his parents...
Or maybe he sought revenge
on the Leaf,
who he held responsible
for their deaths.
My parents weren't killed.
So like you,
I was accused of not being
able to understand.
Perhaps he was right,
and I didn't understand
a thing about him...
However...
Even I can see there's too much hate
in our ninja world.
Hate?
And I've wanted to do something
about this hatred,
yet I'm not sure what must be done.
But I have faith...
that there will come a time
when people can truly understand
one another.
It all sounds kinda complicated.
And if I can't find the answer,
perhaps I'll entrust you to find it.
Yes, sir! I can't turn you down,
can I, Pervy Sage?
What? Why are you laughing?
Your smile is my salvation.
I'm glad I made you my student.
R-Really?
But I haven't given up yet.
I'm going to change the world
with my books!
With those books that don't sell?
You fool!
They'll be bestsellers before
you know it!
And when that day finally arrives,
I won't autograph your copies
even if you beg me!
I don't need any of that!
Well... We have lots of time.
Pervy Sage.
Let's call it a day.
Here. Eat.
Say! Say! Why did you choose me?
I guess when it comes to
amazing sage jutsu,
only someone with my level
of talent can inherit it, right?
Long ago, I taught the Fourth Hokage.
And you have an uncanny
resemblance to him.
I guess that's the only reason.
I resemble the Fourth Hokage?
Good! I guess we can move on
to the next step in training.
– I'll never lose to you!
It's three months today.
Try it, Ino.
Yes!
You did it!
H-Hey, Sakura!
You took too long, and made
a lot of pointless errors.
While it took me three months too,
I was able to complete it more smoothly.
Shut up!
You broke my concentration since
you kept peeking over at me!
What did you say?!
What yourself!
You pass!
What made you start
learning medical ninjutsu?
Huh?
I wanted to create...
a place where I belong.
Naruto...
Naruto kept his promise
to me and got beat up.
He acted reckless
all because of me...
I was always in the back,
following them...
But I'm a member of the team too.
I wanted to walk
shoulder to shoulder with them.
So I promised myself...
That from now on, I would.
It's so you can keep up with them...
... and in order to protect
the Ino-Shika-Cho tradition,
as well as our own...
That's why I must pass on
our secret ninjutsu to you.
After all, together
we're the Ino-Shika-Cho trio.
Do your best too! Okay, Ino?
Team 10 is where I belong.
And... I also want to walk
shoulder to shoulder with them.
But...
Without a doubt,
it will take several years to
master the secret ninjutsu.
Maybe I was running away
and taking the easy way out...
Hey, those wounds!
Oh, I must have scraped it earlier.
– This is nothing.
– That's not good!
Ino...
Thanks, Sakura...
I'm going back to
the place where I belong...
Say, say. Why are we changing
locations to practice?
Is there a decent genjutsu master
some place else?
A sea of forest surrounds
the village where we are headed.
A special magnetic field exists
in that area
that affects a person's chakra flow
in the brain.
If anyone traveling through
the region takes the wrong path,
he could end up in a situation
similar to being under a genjutsu.
It's the perfect location to
wrap up your genjutsu training.
Wow! Sounds like fun!
All right! Let's do it!
Pervy Sage! When are we going to
reach this village?
We're almost there.
Huh? I don't see a thing.
If you wander,
you'll end up in a genjutsu.
Oww! What the hell?
What's this?
I don't know! There was nothing like
this the last time I came.
Hey!
Chili pepper? That's powerful.
Go away!
What's the big idea?!
We're not enemies.
Huh?
Aren't you Tanishi?
t's me, Jiraiya. Your parents
showed me great hospitality
when I last visited here to
do research for my novel.
What?!
You're Tanishi, after all.
I remember that mole
on your forehead.
What's going on?
You know this kid, Pervy Sage?
How are Sukune and Yone?
Shut up!
Don't come near here!
No one can come near this village!
Why not?
Shut up!
What's wrong, Tanishi?
Did something happen?
Hurry and go!
There'll be trouble if they see you!
Hey! What's going on?
Let's take our leave for now, Naruto.
Seriously, what the hell?
It was a peaceful village
when I last came here.
But something made those
once friendly villagers put up a wall
to keep strangers out,
and even arm themselves.
This isn't something
we can simply ignore.
I'll take over guard duty.
Thanks.
There are two suspicious individuals
hanging around.
Be careful.
Got it.
You must be tired
from all-night guard duty.
Go and get some rest, Tanishi.
Yeah.
Don't make any noise.
We just want to help.
Tell me what's going on in the village.
Okay...
Okay, just put that down.
Sorry. But I didn't want to
start a commotion.
Where is Sukune?
Please leave.
If they find out you're in the village,
the other villagers will get killed.
What do you mean?
We've come to borrow
the power of this area.
In order to perfect our genjutsu!
Your villagers can live inside
my genjutsu.
Mom!
Dad!
Our village has been protected
by illusions
and we have lived in harmony
with them.
We discovered a way to
get out of illusions
using these red balls made
from chili peppers.
Don't worry, everyone!
I, Sukune, promise to protect you!
You guys!
Get out of our village!
It would be smarter to help me.
The illusions made by the trees
are blessings from the gods
to protect our village!
They are not for your protection!
He's right! Get out!
Get out!
Change!
What?
Starting now I, Kandachi,
will rule this village.
The women and children
are hostages!
If any word about us
leaks out of the village,
consider the hostages dead!
Don't be ridiculous!
As if we'd let you have
your way with us!
Dad!
This is nothing.
Defying me is useless.
Dad, stop!
Don't fight anymore!
This village...
Don't be stupid! Stop!
Does not belong to you!
Stop!
Dad was murdered.
The women and children
were taken hostage.
So there's no way
the men can fight back.
So that's what happened...
Your dad was a great man.
Shut up! Dad was a fool.
What are you saying?
He's a brave man who tried
to save the village!
I'm not going to be a fool like him!
He threw his life away fighting
someone he couldn't possibly beat!
Hey, you.
If we don't do a thing,
we won't get killed.
That's our only option!
So please...
Don't do anything more.
Just leave before those guys find you!
And you call yourself-
Understood!
Pervy Sage?!
Then you'll leave?!
Forgive me.
I can understand his reasons,
but I can't just leave
the villagers I'm indebted to.
That's more like it!
Tanishi?!
Tanishi! Is he one of the two
suspicious men you mentioned?
Damn right, he--
I mean, yes, he is.
And they call me the Great Jiraiya...
I was so careless.
Let's take him to Lord Kandachi
right away.
Yeah.
The other one should be
wandering around nearby.
So stay on the lookout here.
- Right.
That island is...
Looks like the hostages are
being kept there.
Lord Kandachi!
It appears our real enemy is finally
making his appearance.
Lord Kandachi...
We captured the suspicious fellow
who trespassed into our village.
Kid, did you catch him?
Y-Yes, sir.
You actually caught Jiraiya,
one of the Sannin of the Hidden Leaf?
Oh? I know that ugly mug.
You're Kandachi, Hanzo the Salamander's
right-hand man!
What a place to run into you.
Don't tell me you deserted your village?
The Village Hidden in the Rain
has no leader anymore.
In fact, it's no longer our village.
Oh?
If we hadn't hidden ourselves,
we'd probably have been killed
as rebels too.
Kid! You'll be rewarded for
bringing Jiraiya here.
Tell me what you want.
He's not me! He's a fake!
Huh?!
T-Two Tanishis?! What's going on?
Who are you?!
Why did you have to show up now,
of all times?!
You're...
Yup... I figured as much.
Kid, you let Jiraiya enter
the village, didn't you?
Huh?!
You're going to pay
a hefty price for that.
Mom!
Wh-What are you going to do?!
I'm going to keep my promise!
And feed your friends
to the Conch King!
My word...
Ninja Art: Conch Whip!
Stop! Please stop!
Damn him!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
What an unusual jutsu you use.
Here I come!
Rasengan!
What?!
Naruto!
That's why I told you
to stay out of this!
I beg you! Please spare the lives
of my village friends!
Not likely.
Because I made you a promise.
Please! Please spare everyone.
Tanishi...
You're asking the wrong person.
It made no difference whether
we came or not.
Do you really believe that
he'll release the hostages one day?
Remember your father Sukune!
Think about why he chose to fight!
If you keep believing that your father
died a senseless death,
this village will never be saved!
Pervy Sage! Get everyone
out of the cages!
Right, leave it to me!
I don't think so!
Whoa!
I'm your opponent!
Fire Style: Flame Bombs!
All right! My side's done!
Got it!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
You're still coming at me?
You're a fool who doesn't know
how weak you are.
Shut up!
I can't sit still until I pulverize
cowards like you!
You're a glutton for punishment.
Conch Spear!
Rasengan!
Conch Whip!
Give it up, Leaf brat.
Nope, not yet.
Until I bring you down,
I won't give up!
If I went against my word,
I wouldn't be who I am!
It's useless!
D-Damn it...
Conch Spear!
This is nothing.
No, not yet.
Why?
Why?!
This village... does not
belong to you!
Why?!
Desperately charging at a foe
you have no chance of beating.
You are such a fool.
Yeah... If that's what fools do,
I'm a fool.
I'm a super-fool who never gives up
once I've made up my mind!
If you keep believing that
your father died a senseless death,
this village will never be saved!
Damn... Damn... Damn!
H-Hey...
I... I... I...
Tanishi, get everyone to safety!
You can do that much, can't you?
I'm going to beat that guy!
What are you doing? Hurry, go!
O-Okay.
Tanishi, what are you going to do?!
I'm going to save everyone!
You're going to defy Lord Kandachi?!
Obeying him only meant
he kept us alive.
Now you're talking! Spoken like
a true son of Sukune!
I'll leave the rest to you!
Right!
Okay, everyone.
I'll let you out now!
Honestly, don't blame me
if things get worse!
Ready, pull!
Sorry to keep you waiting, Kandachi.
I thought I could kill some time
with this kid, but I guess not.
How are you doing, Naruto?!
Oh... I've got lots left in me.
Hurry, this way!
Ninja Art: Needle Jizo!
What?!
I'll back you up.
Finish him off, Naruto!
Time for your payback.
Right!
There's no way he can beat me.
So both of you are fools, eh?
Well then...
I'll take care of both of you
with this jutsu!
Water Style Genjutsu:
Mystic Fog Prison!
What is that?
Wh-What?
Pervy Sage?! What's going on?
Damn it!
M-My hand...
You can't weave signs, can you?
I-It's no good.
I can't move my body at all.
We're almost there.
Hurry, everyone.
What happened to them?
Lord Kandachi...
They were touched by the breath
of the Conch King
and are under a genjutsu.
We'll finish them off.
Take it easy.
But...
We chose this site because
the special magnetic field
created by the trees surrounding
this swamp
greatly increases
the genjutsu power of the Conch King.
Even someone like Jiraiya
cannot break this genjutsu.
These two will be overcome
by fear due to their paralysis.
It's just a matter of time before
they have a mental breakdown.
Damn... I can't move.
Instead, go and get the runaway villagers!
Yes sir!
They won't find you here.
Stay put until I come back.
But where are you going, Tanishi?
You're not going out there!
You'll be killed this time!
I finally understand...
that you can't just keep running away.
But against those monsters?!
Don't be a fool!
A fool?
I'm a giant fool who never gives up
once my mind is made up!
Yeah... So I'm a fool.
If I went against my word,
I wouldn't be who I am.
That Hidden Leaf fellow taught me.
Dad probably felt the same way.
If we just do whatever
they tell us to do,
we'll lose sight of ourselves.
Well said, Tanishi!
Mom!
You're Sukune's son, after all!
Please look after the others!
You bet!
Be careful.
Yeah!
Wh-What happened?!
We were caught inside
a genjutsu until now.
Naruto, it's a chili pepper ball.
Close your eyes!
Impossible...
They broke out of the genjutsu?!
H-Hot...
Naruto, wake up!
Y-You?!
Why didn't you run away?!
I decided to become a big fool like you!
That's great!
Now leave the rest to me!
Then you take care of
the big one by yourself.
Huh?!
A shadow clone?!
What?!
How did you escape my genjutsu?!
You see...
It was just a clone that fell
under your genjutsu.
Pervy Sage!
Naruto! Do you have any chakra left?
Yeah! I have loads and loads of it.
Then we'll start with the big one!
But Rasengan won't work on him!
That was a failed attempt.
Remember your training.
You should be able to release
a huge Rasengan,
like the one you created that
sent Gamariki flying!
I get it!
All right!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Here we go!
Right!
Hey, are you serious?
That jutsu won't work
on the Conch King.
All right...
Just like the last time,
but outside my body.
You don't know when to give up,
do you, fool?!
I'll get you first!
Well? How's it coming along?!
Just a little more.
Give me a little more time!
All right! I'll confine it!
Ninja Art: Raging Lion's Mane!
How long do you think
you can hang on?
Hurry!
Getting tired, eh?
Naruto...
What? What is that?!
Pervy Sage!
Right!
Damn it!
Repel him!
Here I go!
Giant Rasengan!
Well done!
Why?! Why'd you take hostages
and try to rule over the village?
You could have asked the village
to hide you guys!
Like I'd trust strangers.
I am Kandachi of the Rain.
And I am no fool.
If you had been one,
things would've been much easier!
We did it.
Dad, the village is at peace again.
The power of the trees
will protect us again.
Dad...
I'll protect Mom and the village,
just like you did, Dad.
I promise.
Since we found out,
I doubt that those Hidden Rain fellows
will return to this village.
I've been able to repay Sukune
for his hospitality.
Thank you so much.
We're the ones who should
be thanking you.
If Tanishi hadn't come that time,
we'd have been finished off
in that genjutsu.
You're probably right.
Oww!
He gets so carried away!
Such a fool, this one.
Minato...
Naruto has grown up.
Far better than I imagined.
He's just as gutsy and tenacious
as the both of us.
You were more than a teacher.
You were like a father to me.
Sensei, I know he too will
love you like family.
Then I guess that makes Naruto my grandson.
What are you muttering about, Pervy Sage?
Oh, nothing. A grandson like you...
A grandson like me? What the hell?!
Are you going senile?!
Now, now, don't say that
and come closer, grandson!
What? That's creepy! Cut it out!
Get away from me, Pervy Sage!
Aw... Don't say that.
Then I say I'll go this way,
and you can go that way, Pervy Sage!
Are you all right? Rin...? Kakashi...?
I don't think... I can make it...
Kakashi...
Obito... Rin...
I wasn't able to protect either of you.
But I will protect
the Hidden Leaf Village...
no matter what.