So, I told my classmates...
that they were lucky to have
so much free time.
It's been a month since I got here.
Isn't it about time I get to supervise
a big assignment on my own?
Oh, Lord Hokage!
Where was yesterday's report again?
Third pile to the right,
the second one.
Oh, here it is.
Didn't this come with
some attachments?
Second pile, the third one.
I don't know what
I'd do without you.
Oh right, Lord Hokage.
About next week's inspection...
I keep telling you to
just call me Kakashi.
You're way too stiff
and formal, Senpai!
And don't forget to take a break.
Efficiency gets compromised
if you don't.
Roger!
Anyway...
I didn't become a shinobi
to be chained to a desk.
Senpai, how do you not get bored
doing this sort of work?
Senpai?
I haven't looked up at the clouds
in a long time.
You know... sometimes you talk like an old man.
Senpai, is something bothering you?
Huh?
No.
And, I'm done for the day!
Man!
We cruised through today!
Thanks, and see ya tomorrow!
Oh, Lord Hokage!
See ya...
Thanks for today.
Why'd you pick a guy like that?
The adult world is complicated.
I don't like that kind of stuff.
Oh?
I thought you became
one of us a while back.
Give me a break!
Having more shinobi like him
just goes to show we're at peace.
It's been two years since then.
I'm starting to get a belly...
I don't want to hear it.
Do you keep up with training?
Here and there.
You say it like that, but I bet
you're as diligent as ever.
Why can't you just
humor me a bit?
I told him to double-check it!
By the way, how is it going?
Regarding that issue.
It's on the back-burner.
No contact then?
I feel bad burdening you
with it.
I was never really
cut out to be a shinobi.
The fact that
I continue to be one...
Is to make Naruto
the Hokage one day, right?
To make sure that happens,
I can't be a child forever.
Naruto's still a child, even now.
He is who he is.
Oh...
How about we go grab
a bite after you're done?
After this, Lord Tsuchikage
and I have a game.
Oh right, I saw him
at the conference yesterday.
All he talked about was how
he would beat you this time.
Anyway, please go easy on him.
Well, half of it is work for me.
Hey, Shikamaru...
I wonder what it means
to become an adult?
No, wait... This one?
How's that, young 'un?
You're speechless now, eh?
Please excuse me...
Hey, don't think
I'll let you win and run!
Tsk...
I have to work twice
as hard tomorrow.
Welcome!
Oh, there he is!
Over here!
Sorry I'm late.
That's the meat I was grilling!
Here you go.
This one's done too.
Another order of kalbi please!
Anyway, I keep teaching this newbie
and she just doesn't get it.
There's one on my team too.
He reminds me of myself
and I just can't ignore him.
I wonder if Asuma felt this way.
You two have totally embraced
your roles as instructors.
Well, you're Lord Hokage's
right-hand man, aren't you?
But I don't have anyone
under me to mentor.
You're the type that prefers
to just do things yourself.
Being a loner suits me.
You two are the only ones
who are special to me.
I miss the old days.
Hey, we're not old enough
to be saying that.
Back then, it was normal for us
to be together 24/7.
Now, we have to set up
a time and date just to eat together.
It's kinda sad, huh?
Maybe that's what it means
to become an adult.
That's for sure.
Your temperament's changed.
Huh? You've got to be kidding.
Lately, you never say,
"what a drag."
Haven't you noticed?
Really?
– Thanks for the food!
– Thank you!
They gave me gum when
I was at the register.
Doesn't this bring
back memories?
I always chewed this
when I was a kid!
Oh, it's so sweet!
Was it always this sweet?
Okay, where to next?
You still want to eat more?
Let's go BBQ hopping!
Sorry, I have to go.
Huh?!
Shikamaru...
Is something on your mind?
Your mind seems to be wandering.
It's nothing.
I have to leave the village for work,
on Shinobi Alliance business.
Is it the same thing Temari
and Kankuro attend?
So Temari is more important
than us?
Oww...
What are you talking about?
And so, we hope that
it grows even more.
That concludes my activity report.
Are there any other questions?
Regarding the long list of
missing persons after the Great War...
How is the search going?
It's currently under investigation.
How about the drop in shinobi requests
for three consecutive periods?
It's currently under investigation.
You know, if it keeps dropping,
it'll affect how we administer
the villages.
We should have a more
detailed report by the next meeting.
I understand the view
that a decrease in requests
for shinobi poses a concern.
But remember,
this is a consequence of peace.
If there are no more questions,
we'll meet again in one month.
Hey! Wait, Shikamaru!
What's going on, Temari?
You're hiding something, aren't you?
Huh? What makes you say that?
See?
When you answer a question with a
question, it's proof that something's up.
What's going on in
the Hidden Leaf Village.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
It's something you can't talk
to me about?
I said there's nothing going on!
So there's nothing I can help with?
Nope.
I see...
Hey, Temari...
Both you and I are representatives
of our villages...
We shouldn't pry too much
into the other's—
What the hell—?!
I misjudged you!
So that's what made
you remember your old man.
Yes.
He often got yelled at by
my mom for staying out all night.
Sorry you had to go through that.
Temari is very intuitive.
She's going to find out
sooner or later
about the Land of Silence.
Many of the missing from
the Great War
and rogue ninja are filtering
into this mysterious land.
And there's a deep, dark rumor
that it's undertaking
shinobi missions illegally.
By rights, the Shinobi Alliance
should deal with this problem.
It'll be troublesome if
they find out that
we're independently
investigating this.
But taking action on
the Land of Silence
in the name of the alliance
will be touchy.
Just when we finally
achieved peace.
It's already been two weeks
since Sai left word
that he was infiltrating
the Land of Silence, right?
We can't just stand by without
taking action any further.
It's finally here.
The state of affairs is more serious
than we previously thought.
If the Land of Silence is left
to continue as is,
the Shinobi Alliance will
be threatened at some point.
There is one leader
at work in this land.
His name is...
Gengo.
I've never heard that name before.
It's possible,
he will become the one
who may very well change
the pitiful existence of shinobi...
In fact, he may change
the whole framework of this world.
I don't even know
myself anymore...
This isn't good.
Right?
Sai led a team of ten,
comprised of the cream of
the crop among the ANBU.
It would take a formidable enemy
to wipe them out...
Probably...
Sai's instincts were right.
Many of the shinobi who
disappeared after the Great War
and rogue shinobi are
in the Land of Silence.
I hope Sai is all right.
He's not one to get killed
so easily, but...
There are hints in
his message that sound
like admiration for
this man named Gengo.
You don't think Sai has...?
He's very pure hearted, so...
If we're to get Sai out of there
and nip the Land of Silence
in the bud...
we have just one option.
Could we be thinking
the same thing?
Yes.
However, you can't go.
Right...
To go unnoticed,
a three-man squad will be best.
Could you get two good shinobi
from the ANBU?
A three-man squad...
You already have someone in mind
for the third member?
What we're attempting is
a clear breach of faith
toward the alliance.
If worse comes to worst,
we would have to disavow
any knowledge of this team.
I'll go.
You carry a big part of
the responsibilities within the alliance.
You can't...
I'm simply adding another job
to my plate.
It's useless to try to
stop you, isn't it?
Still, I would have thought
you'd pick Ino and Choji.
For this mission,
we need someone who can
control chakra and can hide us.
And someone who has a jutsu
to make a direct hit on the target.
Besides...
Besides?
Those two have
their own lives now.
I think I know just
the ANBU for this.
They're both easy to work with...
So I'm sure you'll like them.
What?
Going on a business trip, Senpai?
Yeah. Hold down the fort for me.
It must be nice!
I wish I could go too!
Damn it.
Please bring me back a souvenir!
Yeah sure, I will.
This is Soku of the ANBU.
Easy to work with, huh?
And where's the other one?
I am right here.
When did you—?
He's Ro.
He has the ability to freely manipulate
his own and others' chakra
to erase all signs of his presence
or become another person.
If I were to put it simply,
it's a modification of
the chakra from
the point of view of
what others perceive.
I do not actually increase
the chakra of the target,
I create a discrepancy
in their perception.
Like, that's even more confusing.
This one's still a kid.
Like, unthinkable, right?
In the world of shinobi,
ability is, like, everything.
You don't mince words.
After the Academy, we noticed Hinoko's
talents and scouted her for the ANBU.
She's only 14, but she's already
highly regarded in the ANBU.
I asked you to like,
not to use my real name, Lord Hokage.
Your name's Hinoko?
That's a really cute na—!
I, like, hate to be called that name.
I'd like you to be careful
about that.
So, what can you do?
My weapon is a chakra needle.
Once my needle hones in
on a target,
it will not stop its pursuit until
it pierces its target.
Very suitable for assassination.
I don't like, needlessly kill.
I pierced its chakra stimulation point,
so it's like, several times
more active now.
We'll infiltrate using Ro's jutsu,
then I'll immobilize the target
with my Shadow Strangle Jutsu,
and Soku will finish him.
A true collaboration indeed.
The synergy in this plan is ideal.
Like, that sounds tedious.
They're exactly what you wanted.
I have no objections...
Then, like, what's the issue?
Can you drop the "like" thing?
Like, absolutely not.
Well, it's decided.
So once everything's ready—
Would it be okay to leave
tomorrow morning?
It's not shogi again, is it?
I have some business
to take care of.
So anyway, looks like
I'll be heading back a bit later,
so I won't be able to visit next month.
I have two subordinates under me.
It's not like me, huh?
Both you and my dad had someone
you'd give your lives to protect.
But, I haven't found anyone
like that yet...
Big Brother Shika!
Mirai!
Whoa, there!
Shikamaru, you're so busy these days,
you don't need to
come every month.
I'm not that busy.
This is our babysitter.
She occasionally watches
Mirai for me.
Hello.
He may not look it, but he's
Lord Hokage's right-hand man.
Please...
Oh, I see!
I'm sorry, I still don't know
these things yet.
She just started living here.
People are moving into
this village
all because of people like
you and the Lord Hokage.
Please, don't mention it.
I hope this peace will last
for a long time.
Big Brother!
Flowers!
Oh really?
You brought them for your daddy?
You're so clever, Mirai!
Mirai, you really love
Big Brother Shikamaru, don't you?
Uh-huh!
This peace will last.
I'll make it last.
Why now?
Damn it!
Such bad luck.
Hey, Shikamaru!
You're up awfully early.
Naruto...
I could say the same about you.
I got up and couldn't
go back to sleep...
I'm on my way home
from Ichiraku Ramen.
That shop opens that early?
It's open 24 hours now!
Yeah but, who eats ramen
for breakfast?
I could eat it for breakfast,
lunch, and dinner.
Half of my body's made of ramen!
Hmm?
Do I smell like garlic?
Oh...
Chew this.
This brings back memories!
I love this stuff!
See ya.
Work?
Yeah, just a little.
Don't just sit around
and eat ramen.
Do some work.
Well, a certain someone somewhere
keeps assigning me
annoying missions...
So I won't have a break
for the next six months.
This is the most critical time
in your life.
I know that.
But you know—
No buts!
Take on as many missions
as possible,
make it so everyone says,
"It has to be Naruto,
no one else will do."
If you think
they acknowledge you now
because you're the hero
of the Great War, you're wrong.
Yeah, yeah.
– Hey, Naruto.
– Hmm?
You're going to become
the Hokage.
Don't ever forget that.
I never go back on my word.
That's my ninja way.
You mean "our" way.
Yeah.
Naruto...
Always stay
just the way you are.
That's the reason why I'm here.
Anyway...
I guess it's time to go to work.
That's the inn that Lord Sai
last stopped by...
Yeah.
Also, look slightly above it.
That's the only checkpoint leading
into the village of Tobari.
Unless we get past it,
we can't get to the village.
Sure, but is this get-up, like,
really necessary?
It looks very becoming
on you, Soku.
Look, I had to bend over backwards to
get a coal vendor's traveling permit.
If you have any better ideas on getting
past the checkpoint, let me know.
We can humbly assure you that we will be
able to deceive the enemy's eyes with this.
Like, if we kill all the lookouts,
it will be easy to pass
through the checkpoint!
It would spell trouble if we do that
and they found out the Leaf's involved.
Besides, Sai's entire team
was killed around here.
Don't underestimate the enemy.
If we linger too long,
we'll only, like, increase the chances
of the enemy noticing us.
Both of you, listen up.
Look, I think it's crucial that
we trust each other.
And trust first begins with
having faith in your partner.
Did you get that out of, like,
some weird book?
Lord Shikamaru is doing
his utmost to act like our leader.
Quit trying to analyze me!
Anyway! This mission
requires teamwork—
Huh?!
What's the big idea?!
Like, take a good look.
Land of Silence shinobi?!
Soku!
Don't take action by yourself!
I'm better at, like,
this sort of thing!
I did it!
Hey, c'mon.
You just ruined our disguise.
This has turned out to be
a troublesome situation.
Well... I guess it's back to
square one for our strategy.
What'll you have?
Can I have water?
You can have all you want.
Anyway...
I heard the checkpoint
to Tobari is around here.
I've got nothing to say to outsiders.
The "demon killer"?
Oh... You know the game?
May I sit in?
What luck finding an opponent
in these parts.
A welcome sight indeed.
Are you traveling alone?
I've come to the village of Tobari
to request shinobi assistance.
But they're checking
my background and what not,
so, I've had to wait,
as you can see.
The Village of Tobari?
I've been wanting to do
some business there.
Going in and out of there
is such hassle.
Unless you have this pass,
it's probably impossible.
You got me!
Didn't expect that move!
Time's up...
By the way...
Why did you choose
the Land of Silence?
There are other lands that
accept shinobi requests.
Well, it's the price.
After all, I don't mind
who does the work itself,
whether it's the Silence
or the Hidden Leaf.
After all, shinobi are merely
appendages that you use,
then discard.
Please excuse me!
Are you trying to sabotage
our strategy?
It's because we let guys like that
say whatever they want that,
like, shinobi are always
looked down upon.
That's no reason to kill him.
I just wanted to
shake him up a little.
Like, you're the one
who doesn't trust us.
Then act with more caution.
Got any complaints?
No way I'll mess up a mission
by being, like, overcautious!
That girl...
Isn't she acting too rash?
More than anyone,
Soku fears that peace in the land
will spell the end of
the existence of shinobi.
I presume she is determined
to make this mission a success
to prove the value of shinobi
to the world.
So much blood was shed
to achieve this long-sought peace.
It's ridiculous that
some people can't stomach it.
Lord Shikamaru, you proved
your mettle and worth as a shinobi
in the last Great Ninja War.
But she's never had
a chance to do so.
Such is the sorrow of
the generation that came too late.
Ro, what about you?
You've experienced a lot,
haven't you?
I simply escaped death,
that is all.
Everyone, do not move!
We're going to confirm
your identity.
You will not be allowed
to leave the building!
Hey!
What happened?
The shinobi in the ravine were,
like, discovered.
They move faster than I thought.
Don't!
– We can't make a scene now.
– I'm just waiting for my shogi partner!
– Then what do we do?!
– Move!
– I'm thinking...
– You two!
Over here!
How dare you!
What are you doing?
We owe our lives to you.
No thanks necessary.
I hate those guys from Tobari.
They're always so arrogant.
I'm Komori. Nice to meet you.
Uh, we're...
Whoa!
You don't have to tell me.
We all have a thing or two
we keep hidden, eh?
Komori, we want to go
to the Village of Tobari.
Do you know of a way
to get past the checkpoint?
Now that's a tough question
to answer.
But why do you want to go there?
We've got some minor business
to take care of.
Someone's here!
What? It's just a mouse.
Don't scare me like that!
What don't you understand
about waiting until we find a way
to get through the checkpoint?
Like, if we take our time,
we'll lose the chance to kill Gengo!
It's too dangerous to go alone.
You are not to act alone!
I just want to,
like, prove my ability.
And I won't be held back
by stupid rules!
Grow up!
This isn't some kind of game!
What a drag.
What?!
Maybe I'll have more freedom
in the Land of Silence.
You mustn't say
such reckless things.
Hey, you're not...
getting any weird ideas, are you?
Deserting the village is
a serious crime.
Rogue ninja are hunted down
to the ends of the earth
and are always punished to
the harshest extent of shinobi law.
You're aware of that, aren't you?
Shikamaru, Soku isn't serious.
Isn't that so?
Like I care!
Hey, we're not done here!
Oh?
In a bad mood?
Like, it's none of your business.
I don't know what happened,
but it's over if
you get discouraged.
Look at me.
I'm forced to do jobs like this...
But one day, I'm going to have
a huge inn of my own!
Like, no one asked you.
That kid...
I hope she knows what
she's supposed to do here.
There's no need to worry
about Soku.
I just wanted to, like,
make my power useful.
So, you were a shinobi.
It's a secret.
I-I know that!
Everyone in the village
has gotten used to peace,
and they're too timid.
Like, at this rate,
I should have just gone to
the Land of Silence.
Surely, you're not going to
desert your village?
Isn't that a serious crime?
Like, yeah, I know that.
I feel a little better
after talking to you.
I'm going back to the guys.
I see...
I'll come with you!
You don't have to.
I'm used to getting scolded,
so I'm really good
at apologizing!
Ro, you saw her eyes too, right?
You are overthinking this.
If Soku is serious about
deserting the village...
we have to silence her.
Can you do it?
I'm asking you,
would you be able to do it?
Desertion is a serious crime.
If Soku is serious,
I will not hesitate.
I knew it!
Like, they're not comrades
or anything!
Wait!
Soku!
I don't have a place
where I belong anymore.
What if...
I told you that
there's a safe route
to get to the checkpoint
without being discovered?
Are you willing to risk it?
It's the long way,
but if you follow the river,
you'll reach the checkpoint
without being seen.
Hey!
What are you doing here?
U-Uh... I was looking for
the mouse that got away.
Have you seen Soku?
I-I didn't see anything!
What is going on?
Hey!
Look at me in the eye
and answer me again!
Where did Soku go?
I'm tellin' you I don't know!
Don't tell me...
Is she heading for
the checkpoint?
Did she desert?
That's it, isn't it?
That's inconceivable!
Soku would not desert the village!
To find out, we need to catch Soku
and ask her directly.
Stop!
Why you—! Who are you?!
I deserted my village!
I want my skills to be of use here,
for this land!
If you interfere, you're dead!
A rogue ninja?
A kid like you?
Like, age doesn't matter.
Ability is everything.
Well, at least you talk the talk!
You won't walk away with just
a wound on your leg the next time.
D-Don't take this the wrong way.
We've had a lot of rats
sniffing around lately.
Just recently...
Yeah...
It was ANBU from
the Hidden Leaf.
You intend to desert
your village at your age?
I'm just sick of
old-fashioned rules.
Like, with my skills,
you won't regret making me
one of you.
Great! I like you!
Well, you certainly have
an interesting technique.
Two of my men who were
on reconnaissance were just killed.
Your technique inflicts the same kind
of wound that killed them.
I wonder why?
Would you care to explain?
Things aren't looking good for you...
are they, young lady?
She's okay.
Komori?
Sorry I didn't say anything.
I had to test you to make sure
we could trust you.
She killed our comrades.
We can't trust her.
They attacked out of nowhere,
I had no choice.
I had a fight with my partners,
and I've made up
my mind to leave.
Captain, I've watched her
all this time.
She really did split off
from her group.
But I can't just take
your word for it.
Like, if you don't believe me,
I don't mind if we fight it out,
right here.
We found you, Soku!
So, you were pulling the strings,
all this time, Komori!
You were pretty quick.
But take a good look around you.
There's no way you can win!
Hey!
Even you understand the gravity
of deserting a village, don't you?
Hand her over to us right now.
If you interfere,
I won't go easy on you!
Will you turn her over, or not?
Interesting...
This is your chance to prove
that you're serious.
I'll help you!
I don't need your help!
This is my problem!
Shikamaru,
I implore you to think it over!
Soku has her reasons.
Don't be reckless!
Are you going to betray me too?
Y-You misunderstand!
Then you're... first!
Lord... Shikamaru!
You two... together—!
Soku... You didn't...
You did well!
I don't sense any chakra.
He's dead.
You did it, Soku!
You'll be quite useful. Come.
You're one of us now.
You'll have to go through
some rounds of questioning,
but you'll be released right away.
In exchange for the intel
that you possess—
I'm going to have you, like,
sleep for a while.
Damn it, that was rough!
It went quite well.
Soku said she'll make it
seem like we're dead.
But that hurt a lot.
We owe that kid some thanks too.
What? It's just a mouse.
Earlier, I used chakra to fake
a shinobi's presence.
And his unexpected reaction
was our lucky break.
An ordinary kid wouldn't have
reacted to chakra like he did.
And he performed unerringly
as we predicted.
But what Soku bemoaned...
She meant half of what she said.
If she had been really serious,
she could have killed us both
at any time.
Were you not aware of that risk?
This thing about trust...
You have to have faith
in your partner first.
Isn't that what I said before?
As I'd expected of you.
But don't tell Soku.
Or it will just go to her head.
Like, I just heard everything.
Your logic's pretty naive, Shikamaru.
What do you mean?
Don't tell me you really
meant to hurt me?
Like, I can try again.
Maybe next time.
Anyway, how's it going?
I kept the lock open.
As long as you return quickly,
no one will notice.
Perfect.
Are you all right, Lord Shikamaru?
I thought I might have
heard you groaning.
I've been having
strange dreams lately.
Don't tell me...
Is it some memory from the past?
You too?
The memories one wishes to forget most
tend to stick like glue.
It must be old age.
I'm only 19!
Have you noticed?
Even since we came here,
there's been no wind.
Yes, it's totally still.
I don't have a good feeling
about this at all.
Hope she's faking
her death smoothly.
To be killed with her own jutsu...
Talk about luck.
Anyone foolish enough to get killed
during an initiation test...
wouldn't have been any good.
You don't have to worry about Soku.
What is it?
Intel on Gengo, the guy
that controls this village.
Looks like it was collected by ANBU.
Want to read it?
It's smart to know
about one's target.
Let us see then.
This is... blank!
It means they couldn't learn
a single thing.
Just this one sheet?
Ten shinobi lost their lives for that.
It just doesn't make sense.
Let me have that.
I think it will be more useful
in the fire.
Oh, the dead have returned.
Looks like you pulled it off.
Pretending to be dead is like, creepy.
Otherwise, you would have become
a shinobi of this land.
You should be happy...
Now you can move around freely.
So? Did you learn anything?
Regarding Gengo, we have,
like, nothing.
And no one knows anything about
the inside of the castle.
It seems the man known as Gengo
rarely appears before others.
I learned one thing though.
That castle is known
as Fushu Castle.
Fushu?
As in prisoners of war...
A derogatory term used by
the mainstream for savage tribes
along the border.
Like, I can't believe anyone would
name their own castle such a name.
What of Sai?
Nothing at all.
Tsk... Well, it seems this Gengo
is a very cautious man.
He's worth looking into.
Okay, why don't we go
have some yakiniku...
Hey Pops! You call this yakiniku?
You can leave if you got
any complaints!
I didn't say I wasn't going to eat it!
Everyone's short of supplies.
That's way better than nothing!
Like, there are guys from
all over the place.
People without money are probably
lured here by these requests.
How long since
you opened up shop?
About the same time Gengo came,
so around ten years.
This village was doing
worse back then.
This Gengo fellow is
an outsider too?
He and his gang showed up
out of the blue,
and kicked out
the domineering Feudal Lord.
Feudal Lords are all useless.
And did living conditions improve?
Well, what do you think?
Take a look around!
They're all Gengo's followers.
They boss everyone around.
It was great that he kicked out
the Feudal Lord...
but after that, he just took over.
I've seen that face somewhere...
I was just thinking the same thing.
There's no mistake.
That is Minoichi,
a former member of the ANBU.
I totally thought
he'd died somewhere.
I don't remember anyone
like him.
Well, no wonder.
This was during the last Great War.
He killed everyone in his unit
and went into hiding.
Damn it, I can't stand
the sight of him.
So, like, what's he doing here,
acting so high and mighty?
Well, we'll have to ask him
that directly.
Wh-Who are you guys?!
You can't run away anymore,
Minoichi.
I-I don't know that name!
Don't play dumb with me!
Shadow Paralysis Jutsu!
Clearly, you remember it...
If you're from Hidden Leaf Village.
you know just what this jutsu
can do, don't you?!
S-Stop!
You've moved up in the world,
considering you killed
all your comrades.
Don't think you can get away
from shinobi law!
I-I'm not a shinobi anymore!
I'm a revolutionary!
A revolutionary?
All of you living your idle lives
in the stagnant world of shinobi
couldn't possibly understand
our noble intentions!
Enough of your stupid arguments!
Or do you want me to
kill you right here?
S-Stop!
Now answer me!
Tell me all you know
about this guy, Gengo!
Start talking!
Shikamaru!
Revolutionaries... earn that title when
they have had their eyes opened by
Lord Gengo's divine will.
That's pretty lofty talk.
This land does not need lowly men
like Feudal Lords.
We will create the ideal society
for the shinobi.
That's the true revolution
envisioned by Lord Gengo.
Lord Sai of the Hidden Leaf is supposedly
being held captive here.
Will you tell us where he is?
You're Ro, aren't you?
Who cares about shinobi law?!
I've had enough of dying for
the sake of Feudal Lords!
I'll do anything to protect myself!
Tsk...
At last, you revealed your true self.
A coward like you would
understand how I feel, right, Ro?
D-Don't!
What are you talking about?!
Don't you know what he did?
That pressure point paralyzes
the whole body.
He'll be out for a while.
Ro!
Are you okay, Ro?!
You're up.
Like, you had me worried.
I was... dreaming.
It's okay if you don't want to
talk about it.
It's funny how the memories
one wishes to forget most
tend to stick like glue.
It was back when
I was still a Genin.
My unit was ambushed by
the enemy and... annihilated.
I was the lone survivor,
so I buried myself under
the corpses of my comrades...
and I suppressed my chakra for days,
pretending to be dead.
Thanks to the jutsu I mastered
during that time,
I was picked up by the ANBU.
But this jutsu is a cursed power...
acquired from the slaughter
of my comrades.
The same thing happened to me...
The revolutionaries are like,
gathering in the square.
They're planning something.
Let's go.
But we can't go looking like this.
We need like, two more.
Ro, is the chakra disguise ready?
I've already traced
the clothing's owner.
Soku, we're counting on you
if anything happens.
Soku, are you listening?
Hey, you!
Fix that collar!
Lord Gengo is going
to address us!
Shape up!
I'm sorry.
If you're not doing anything,
help with the preparations!
Understood?
Perfect timing, wasn't it?
It almost seems too perfect...
But we can't pass up this opportunity
if Gengo's going to appear.
From this spot, we can get Gengo,
no matter where he tries to hide.
Soku, stay alert.
You've been spacing out.
What Minoichi was saying...
Huh?
Kick out the Feudal Lords and
create the ideal world for shinobi.
It's not a bad idea.
What are you saying?
I like, just can't accept this system
with useless Feudal Lords
at the top.
Don't deny ever thinking that too, Ro!
I get where you're coming from.
But focus on the mission right now.
Distraction leads to mistakes.
Like I need to be reminded.
The stage is undefended...
Either this Gengo is
really confident,
or really stupid.
He's finally going to appear.
Let's expose this guy
for what he really is!
First, I thank everyone who
has come together here.
Everyone...
The day is near for true revolution!
We'll have a better chance of catching
Gengo with Shadow Stitching
if we move up closer.
Follow me.
Tonight, I've planned
something special.
Allow me to introduce someone who tried
to obstruct our true revolution!
Sai!
Everyone... What fate awaits this man?
Death!
A sacrifice for our revolution!
Your wishes have been heard.
With the red blood of this man,
the true revolution for justice
will take another leap forward!
Are you going to ignore Lord Sai?!
We're helpless against that crowd.
I'm going to use this.
A diversion?
Ten years have passed quickly
since I rose up in this land.
Many comrades have joined me
and this land has started to flourish.
However...!
Not a single one of
our hopes has yet been realized.
I want to ask the citizens
of the Land of Silence!
This land under the rule
of the Feudal Lord...
and this land now—
Which world is better to live in?
Feudal Lords who have
nowhere near
our strength or intelligence
have ruled over the shinobi.
But that dark age is a thing of the past.
We, the revolutionaries,
will protect this land!
The wish of the revolutionaries
is to push forward
to make this land rich
and prosperous!
Damn it!
The ones who should rule this land
are not the Feudal Lords...
but we who possess
the power of shinobi!
Hey, Ro!
– This is no time to daydream!
– The shinobi is the key...
– Snap out of it!
– to make this land safe and just.
Shikamaru!
– I was...
– It's been ten years since
I'm going to rescue Sai.
When you see me go around
the back, lay it on real thick.
Got it?!
Understood!
Why must shinobi
be treated differently?
Why must we
be discriminated against?
Damn it!
He's using some weird trick!
Shinobi locked in the old ways,
content with their lot
content with discrimination,
content to be controlled, destroyed us!
Now hear me!
People of the Land of Silence
awaiting the dawn...
The sunlight of a new era shines
on the Land of Silence!
So, you've shown yourself, rat.
Your performance is over!
Protect Lord Gengo!
Lord Gengo, please take cover!
Sai, I've come to get you.
You'd better not be dead.
Cut it out, Sai!
I'm here to save you.
I've woken up.
You will soon
understand too, Shikamaru.
Sai, you!
Gengo, is this your doing?
How a shinobi of your stature would
be bound by old-fashioned laws,
is beyond my comprehension.
Shut up! Shut up!
Why do you suppress
your memories?
Are you afraid to face them?
You're not fooling me with
your pretentious talk!
Soku, do it!
Too bad.
Don't you dare do anything
to my comrades!
Do anything to them?
Of course, not.
I happen to like shinobi
with abilities.
And of course, you happen
to be one of them,
genius of the Hidden Leaf,
Shikamaru Nara.
It's no use.
Shikamaru, you must wake up too.
Stop messing around!
I just hate getting woken up
when I'm fast asleep!
Farewell...
Silver-4c, pawn-3f, rook-4b, rook-4h,
bishop-3f, pawn-1f, pawn-1d,
pawn-2f, king-6b...
King-6h, king-7b, king-7h, silver-6b...
You're really hanging in there.
The average shinobi would
have given up long ago.
I'm busy playing shogi
with past masters.
I don't have time to get bored.
I like your stubbornness.
You can learn a lot from shogi.
No matter what position you're in,
there's always a way out.
Are you planning on
getting out of this situation?
I look forward to seeing that.
Hey, can you at least
give me back my lighter?
I just can't calm down
without it.
Sure, when you decide to
accept Lord Gengo's beliefs.
Why would you follow
a guy like that?
Let's just say I found
the place where I belong.
And that wasn't
the Hidden Leaf Village.
Weren't you a member of Team 7?
Then why didn't Naruto come?
You and I aren't close,
so why did you come?
Naruto knows nothing
about this situation.
This was all my decision.
Even still, if this had been
Sasuke or Sakura,
surely Naruto would have come...
I bet Gengo put those ideas
in your head, right?
There's no doubt that
Gengo controls people with words.
So why don't you snap out
of it and wake up?
I woke up a long time ago.
When Lord Gengo gave me a will.
Wait.
Do you still have more to say?
I promise I'm going to undo
Gengo's jutsu and save you.
I'd resign myself if I were you.
Otherwise, things will get much worse.
You're a member of the Hidden Leaf.
Don't forget that!
Pawn-4e, bishop-3c...
Knight-3g...
Nope...
I don't have enough pieces right now.
The king's going to get away.
Ro! Is that you?!
That voice... Is it you, Lord Shikamaru?
Hey Gengo!
These guys were just
obeying my orders!
If you're going to kill someone,
kill me!
Remember, as long as you live,
there's a chance.
Don't give up!
I won't let you give up and die!
Worry not.
This is nothing...
What happened to Soku?
Wasn't she with you?
She's okay, isn't she?!
Why do you insist on
serving Feudal Lords
and incompetent people
who oppress you?
Like, that's none of
your business!
Remember...
The way that those people
looked at you.
What did you see deep
inside their eyes?
Like, I don't remember!
Sure, you do.
The truth is, it's stuck to your mind
and won't go away. Isn't that so?
Remember!
The eyes that looked at you.
The suspicious eyes
that feared me,
and tried to discriminate against me...
Why must you give your proud and
mighty life for people like that?
Why pledge loyalty to those
who hold you in bondage?
They are using me.
Everyone is an enemy.
There is nothing to fear.
Now, turn.
And accept everything.
A purpose has been granted.
I've brought him, Lord Gengo...
My apologies for
the inhospitable treatment.
As you know,
I can't let down my guard.
I have no intention
of speaking to you.
It's obvious you're trying
to control me with your words.
You're starting to look
like your father.
Forgive me, but I looked
into your background.
Your family and friends...
And the fact that
you came here to kill me.
Why do you people
keep oppressing us?
When did we do that?
This land is feeble.
We barely have natural resources
and the soil is barren,
yet we are trying
our hardest to survive. That is all.
Yeah right, all the while
you're gathering up rogue ninja...
What's your motive?
Are you planning on starting a war?
I'm not gathering them.
They come to me,
seeking salvation.
Salvation?!
Have you never questioned
the current existence of shinobi?
Without war,
they are no more than hunting dogs
for Feudal Lords and the rich.
Is that truly a fitting life
for a shinobi?
What is it that
you're trying to say?
They come here because
they want to be real shinobi.
The alliance of nations
to maintain a dark peace...
and bind shinobi with
meaningless laws.
But there will always
be those who reject it.
This land is merely
the gathering place for them.
Various rules are necessary
to preserve peace.
The peace you speak of
is nothing but a theory,
forced upon us
by the Great Nations.
The Tailed Beasts that
you keep are proof of that.
Had you used one,
this land would be
completely helpless.
Isn't that so?
We have no intention of ever using
a Tailed Beast for war again.
You keep the Tailed Beast
for yourselves,
and you expect us to believe that?
Isn't that the biggest excuse
by the Great Nations?
Quit jumping to conclusions.
Then how about this?
Give this land a Tailed Beast too.
I'm sure the Hidden Cloud
has an extra one, correct?
Then we wouldn't worry,
and we would believe you.
You know we can't do that.
Of course not.
You espouse peace openly...
but deep down, you don't trust
small countries like ours.
But you can't make the argument
for war because of that.
There's got to be another solution.
You need another solution?
Come with me.
I'd like to show you something...
What is this?
Agricultural crops can't grow
at our elevation.
The people live in poverty
with little to eat.
If we just had some kind of product,
something to enrich their lives...
This flower is the result
of selective breeding.
You've seen it here and there,
haven't you?
But it was all for nothing...
This flower wilts the moment
it's taken out of this village,
due to its unique environment.
Why did you choose
the way of the shinobi?
Was it to be chained to a desk
for the rest of your life?
Who knows.
Most likely not.
You train daily to hone
your skills.
And with your skills,
you defeat the enemy,
to protect what is precious.
That is the way a shinobi
should live.
That is the way your father
and mentor lived.
How would you know?!
You probably hope that you can
measure up to them someday.
But in a world of peace,
can you really accomplish that?
It is because of war,
that shinobi abilities developed remarkably.
If there had been continual peace,
even you would never have spent
such worthwhile moments with your friends.
Am I wrong?
If that's the price for peace,
I'll gladly throw down my weapons.
You're not speaking
from your heart.
You feel your own abilities
weakening, don't you?
Shikamaru...
Shut up!
Stay out of this.
Do not fear, Shikamaru.
Put your hand down.
Yes, that's it.
First, why don't you calm down?
Take a deep breath.
Do you like it?
The scent of my precious flowers?
Come on.
I get it...
So, that's it.
The scent of certain flowers has
the effect of stirring up memories.
So, that's what you've been
using to brainwash people.
What inconceivable will...
But that discovery won't
get you anywhere.
You cannot defy me.
Where are my comrades?!
Where are Ro and Soku?!
Bring them here!
We are right here.
Huh?! You two?!
Like, Lord Gengo has
given us the will...
Find him! Don't let him escape
from this castle!
Shikamaru, it's useless to hide.
I'm still numb...
Damn it, Soku!
I can't use my Shadows.
My rook and bishop
handicap is gone, too.
The situation is bleak.
It's unlike you...
I can't believe you'd go
with the Climbing Silver.
It's using an advance unit
to break through enemy lines.
You have to be ready to use tactics
like this once in a while...
If I escape now, the risk for
the Hidden Leaf will increase.
That's what you told me back then.
So, I guess that time
has come for me.
Calm down.
There's still a chance
an opportunity will present itself.
Shikamaru, presently,
you are the knight.
Breaking through the enemy camp
with a Climbing Silver or...
perhaps a knight that jumps high...
Guess I have no choice
but to jump back into
the den of the king.
Lord Gengo, are you sure it's all right
to leave the search for Shikamaru to Sai?
Like, it will be bad if
he gets out of the castle.
Don't panic.
If he gets cornered,
he's the type
to throw himself into an even
more difficult situation.
Isn't that right, Shikamaru?
You knew I was here?
That's no fun.
You wouldn't leave this behind.
You came back just for that?
You're something.
Resign yourself and be captured!
If the floor won't work,
there's always the ceiling.
Below.
My body...
Whoa...
Shikamaru, release me!
To break a genjutsu,
the theory is to bring down
the one who placed it.
What do you say, Gengo?
Impossible.
No one can resist my words.
Ro...
Sorry, but you'll have to
be my shield for a while.
Shoot.
Don't worry about hitting Ro.
Go ahead and shoot.
Just make sure you aim straight.
Stop, Shikamaru.
You cannot resist my words.
Don't tell me you—?!
You purposely let Soku
hit you in the ear
to dull your sense of hearing?!
This is the knight's jump!
I'm disappointed, Shikamaru.
So disappointed.
Please stay back, Lord Gengo.
Leave this to me.
Well done!
Gengo!
You won't get away!
Damn it!
Damn it, you keep
getting beaten up by girls.
Weren't you going to become a better
leader for the sake of your comrades?
Dad... I...
I'm just not cut out to
be a shinobi.
Is he dead?
I didn't like, kill him yet.
Well, he had no chance
at the end.
How pitiful...
I'm physically at my limit.
The air feels so heavy.
Man, this is such a drag.
Are you okay, Shikamaru?
Don't you dare die on us!
You guys?!
But what are you doing here?
Oh, I get it. I'm still dreaming...
Shikamaru!
T-Temari?!
I expect a lot more from you!
Why are you just sitting around
dazed like that?!
Shikamaru?!
Stop it, Temari!
He'll really die.
Shut up!
That's for lying to me at
the Shinobi Alliance meeting.
Sorry, Temari.
Thanks to you,
I've come to my senses.
Shikamaru!
Sorry, but can you take over here?
I have one more guy
to take down.
Is that Gengo?!
How did you know?
Lord Hokage told me.
I had a hell of a time trying
to get it out of him.
I don't want to
even imagine what you did.
So, Shikamaru, it's okay
to crush these guys?
They're brainwashed,
but they're comrades.
Please wake them up as well!
Like, shut up.
Wait!
You're forgetting one thing.
He probably knows you're coming
and has laid traps.
I hope the odds of your winning
in that condition are good.
I have no intention of being
a sacrificial pawn.
All right then!
Okay, let's get on with our final moves...
Gengo!
I won't let you get away... Gengo!
To think, Shikamaru had this many
reinforcements waiting in the wings.
As expected of a coward like him.
I think you're misunderstanding something,
so I'm going to set you right.
We barged in on our own.
Shikamaru is hiding something.
Yes.
It must be serious,
for him to act alone.
Will you look into it, Temari?
Use as much manpower as necessary.
Are you sure?
Shikamaru is a Leaf shinobi.
Sand or Leaf... The age of
drawing lines is over.
A man who is essential to
the Alliance is worth it.
Besides...
I doubt the Hokage would
willingly give us intel.
I'll drag it out of him.
I know you understand,
but do it as peacefully as possible.
Sure, I'll do it as peacefully...
as I can.
And...?
Is there something else
you needed to ask me?
Shikamaru is now...
Anyway, we rushed over after
hearing that Shikamaru was in trouble.
Out of friendship, right?
That brings a tear to my eye.
Well, wait.
I'll make you cry so hard,
you'll hate it.
Leave Sai to me.
He's strong, you know.
Yeah, I know.
Sorry, Ino,
but you're no match for me.
Let me take the old man!
Oh?
Wind Scythe Jutsu!
Wow, that was a surprise.
But you won't get me
a second time!
I shall show no mercy,
even if you are just a brat!
Expansion Jutsu!
What?!
Who did you just call a brat?
Your name is Soku, right?
You should be supporting Shikamaru.
So, what the hell are you doing?!
Like, I simply chose my master
in order to realize my full potential.
What?
Like, staying under
a weakling like Shikamaru
is too tedious and futile!
Damn!
Aim more carefully next time.
If you miss again...
you'll lose.
You will definitely
accept my will, Shikamaru.
Your head's nothing
but a flower garden!
Resign yourself...
It's all too late.
Too late?
What the hell do you mean?!
Not bad!
But if you're already out of breath
against one opponent,
you don't have a chance.
Sai, wake up!
Why don't you worry
about yourself instead of me?
"I don't even know myself anymore..."
That's what you supposedly wrote
in the last message you sent.
I have the will that Lord Gengo
bestowed upon me.
So... I'm not lost anymore!
Oh...
Did I overdo it?
His chakra's not reacting...
No way... Did he die?
You could say that making my target
misread chakra is my specialty.
I have no idea what you're saying...
Shikamaru should be kneeling
before Lord Gengo about now.
Shikamaru would never...
What brute strength!
... bow down to anyone!
Partial Expansion Jutsu!
Why you—!
Take this!
Cyclone Scythe Jutsu!
I'll never give up...
on a precious friend!
Around now, your precious friend
should be receiving Lord Gengo's will.
Even as you lay your life on the line.
You don't understand, do you?
The precious friend I'm talking about...
is you!
You belong to the Hidden Leaf.
Don't ever forget that!
Being friends is useless!
Then...
Then what's that on your cheek?
Mind Tranfer Jutsu!
Let me take over your mind
for a little while.
I didn't lure you in here
just to prevent you from
using your shadows.
When a human loses
the ability to see and smell,
his sense of hearing
becomes much sharper.
Giving you an even
greater advantage, huh?
In the shinobi world,
you're either the user or the used.
What are you talking about?
Words from a shinobi that
I once believed in...
Surely, even you've heard
the name Zabuza Momochi.
Zabuza...
Wasn't he the instigator of
the Mizukage assassination incident?
After the failed coup d'état,
we deserted the village.
We had faith in Zabuza's promise to return
some day to create the ideal society.
But the hardships of wandering
took its toll and changed him.
And so, I used Zabuza instead.
Just as he had taught.
To put it bluntly,
you sold out your friend.
And I settled here with
my comrades.
In order to create the ideal society
that Zabuza could not.
And now, it's finally becoming a reality.
Don't you want to usher
in that moment with me?
No thanks!
The only society I'll sacrifice my
life to protect is the Hidden Leaf!
The same way that your father
and mentor did?
You have no right to talk about
my dad or Asuma!
I'll tear down your ideals!
What has happened... to me?
You are...?
Like, my head is throbbing...
That guy's...
the only one left.
Sai... answer me!
Sai!
Who are you?
I'm your friend.
No...
They are my only friends.
That's just what that guy Gengo
made you believe!
Don't come any closer! Go away!
Let's go back together, Sai.
Everyone is waiting for you.
Sai... Sai!
Ino?
You're back!
Where is Shikamaru?!
Shikamaru went after that Gengo guy.
That's not good!
I have to let Shikamaru
know right away!
No matter what happens...
He can't turn around!
Is the Hidden Leaf
that important to you?
Damned right it is!
Then I'll let you in on something good...
Do you think that I only isolated
myself in this region and did nothing else?
What would you say
if I've sent my initiates with
the will I bestowed upon them,
into all the Hidden Villages?
The people of the Five Great Nations
aren't blind.
Your people may have
infiltrated the core,
but they'll get caught in time.
I'm talking about the citizens...
The safety of those
who are most dear to you...
What did you say?
One signal from me,
and they will create an incident.
You don't have the means to stop it.
You're bluffing!
In time, you'll see if I'm lying or not.
Stop!
Don't you dare touch Mirai!
Big Brother Shika!
Mirai!
Y-You can't fool me...
I've already figured out that
you infuse chakra into your voice
to manipulate people.
The more you resist with your mind,
the more the heart seeks it.
Big Brother Shika!
Mirai!
You'll pay if you lay
a hand on Mirai...
I'll make sure your breath
is completely snuffed out.
Kill... Kill...
– Gengo, you're dangerous.
– Kill... Kill...
I can't let you go on living.
This is to protect the Hidden Leaf!
– It's for that reason that...
– Kill... Kill...
I've come to carry out
a mission that's not like me!
– In order to make Naruto the Hokage!
– Kill... Kill...
Naruto...
Ramen!
Huh?
What the hell was that?
What's the matter, Shikamaru?
Now, confront the darkness
that consumes your heart!
I-I have to get it right
the next time.
Look, you're just a brat,
so it's okay if you ease up a little.
But it's my fault that my friends...
Thinking about your friends
is important.
But you don't have to take on
all that responsibility.
'Cuz it's a drag.
Why?
Why doesn't my jutsu work on you?
Your heart is full of cracks!
Yeah... My heart is full of cracks...
In fact, it's nothing but one big crack.
I-Impossible!
Your words don't have
any effect on me anymore.
I finally understand.
Earlier, you said you came to
this land with your comrades.
But why isn't there a single comrade
standing beside you?
You probably killed them all,
and hid them in this castle, right?
You're all alone, because you only
believe in using others or being used.
This place is like peering deep
into your heart!
You and I are alike!
We're smart, we can't trust anyone!
Don't lump me in with you!
You—!
Looks like you're still conscious!
Yeah, but it was touch and
go for a little while.
Ro, Soku!
Let's go.
Okay, let's clean this up quickly!
Why don't we leave it
to them this time?
Yeah, you're right...
Shikamaru did just call
on those two.
A clone?!
That's right. With his chakra—!
Enveloping his shadow
with chakra?!
Which one is real?
I can't... move!
If you stop me,
the world of the shinobi will decline!
Don't you care if you're consigned to a
life of servitude under the Feudal Lords?
A place where even the easygoing
can live in their own way...
That's the kind of world
I want to protect!
How stupid!
I will not let you interfere
with my vision!
Like, the chakra flowing to
your tongue's been cut off...
Mission... complete!
Good work.
We'll be taking Gengo
and his revolutionaries
back to the Hidden Leaf Village now.
Will you be joining us?
We...
You came to the rescue again.
Sheesh...
You really are something, Naruto.
You guys!
What? Did you forget something?
Like, we were told we're on a
mission until we get back to the village.
We shall accompany you, Shikamaru.
Huh? Oh, yeah?
Senpai!
Yurito?!
You came too?
I finally got to handle
a big assignment!
O-Oh...
Huh? Senpai, aren't you being
too stiff and formal again?
Clouds! The clouds!
Remember, the clouds!
Oh, yeah...
Anyway, I'm busy, so 'scuse me!
Shikamaru?
You can reach out to try and grab
the cloud but you can never grasp it.
If there's wind, it'll blow away.
Such a strange thing with no core.
Temari...
Huh? What is it?
Well... It's nothing important, but...
Um...
What is it?
Spit it out.
Go a bit easier
when you slap people, will you?
If you space out again,
I'll slap you as much as I want to!
Okay... I'm counting on you for that.
Thanks... for what you did this time.
Is this an awkward conversation
or what?!
Just hurry and ask her out!
There, there...
Ino...
Sai?
Thanks, beautiful.
I really felt... your kindness.
Beautiful? Oh... uh!
I want to thank you...
That's if you'd let me.
Oh... Well then...
Maybe a d-date...?
Ino, now you're being awkward.
Maybe... next time... we can...
go get a bite to eat.
You mean, a date?
Huh?
Are you asking me out on a date?
Well, yeah.
I see. A date, huh.
You don't want to?
That's not it.
Huh? Uh?
Be prepared.
A date with me
can be quite a drag.
Do you have a plan?
Huh?
Like, a date strategy.
Like I'd have one!
Going on a first date
without a strategy
is like fighting
a Tailed Beast unarmed.
You have zero chance of winning.
What would you two know?!
What are you saying?!
I do know a thing or two
about relationships.
You must first find out everything you
can about Lady Temari's likes and dislikes...
and come up with a careful plan.
And you need at least
three contingency plans:
one for a sunny day,
a cloudy day and a rainy day!
Prepare small talk
that won't bore her.
Have at least a hundred stories
in your arsenal.
Hey, hey!
That's even more of a drag
than taking Gengo down!