So, what are you doing here?
Sakura said she was coming
to see you, so I tagged along.
What is it, Sakura?
There have been incidents of
Hidden Leaf shinobi going missing.
Going missing?
So you noticed it too, Sakura.
You were already aware of it,
Kakashi-sensei?
Yes. But why were you investigating
something like that?
Well, there's a regular
at Ino's family's flower shop...
It's coming from the Aun Gate.
I'll go check it out!
Oh...
Wait, Naruto!
Hey, you two!
I'm counting on you.
Run! Get away from here!
It's the Security Unit...
Why are they only using defense?
I'm going to help 'em!
Wait!
Ino? Shikamaru... Choji?
What happened?
It can't be...
Tadaichi...
That's Tadaichi!
Tadaichi?
You mean your regular
from the flower shop?
Are you sure that's him, Ino?
There's no mistake!
But he'd never turn against
the Hidden Leaf!
So why?
So does that mean...
there's a possibility
he's under a genjutsu?
And the others could be
the ones who went missing!
What?!
Then... these are Hidden Leaf shinobi?
That's why we can't do
anything other than defend!
He didn't even dodge.
Doesn't he feel any pain?
This is bad!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Naruto?!
We're going to jump away.
He's an exploding human!
Tadaichi...
It's okay.
Let's go tend to the wounded.
Hey!
They're getting in!
Not... them too!
It's too big!
Damn!
Choji...
Can you make wings
with your expansion?
G-Got it!
I'll help!
Let's go, Kurama!
Right!
Did... it help at all?
Good job!
Looks like it ain't over yet.
There are more of them.
Naruto!
Getting wounded is probably
what causes them to explode.
I saw strange chakra being
released from the wound,
and the body began
to change shape.
Which means,
we have to be careful
how we engage them.
Naruto!
Hinata!
What's happening?
It seems everyone's under
a genjutsu.
Can you see if
someone's controlling them?
All right, I'll check.
Byakugan!
I don't see anyone.
No one?!
Then how are they being manipulated?
There's a strange chakra
moving around in their bodies.
Maybe that's what's controlling them.
So we just have to take
that chakra away?
The chakra is circulating like
it's part of their body.
The chakra could be fused internally.
So you're saying
we can't just extract it easily.
First things first.
We have to start
by capturing them.
But Shikamaru,
it'll be hard to capture them
without inflicting any wounds.
I just had a great idea!
Okay, let's go!
First, I'll have my clones
stop the exploding humans.
Shadow Possession Jutsu!
Then Shikamaru will capture them
with his Shadow Possession Jutsu.
Hinata!
Right!
And lastly, Hinata will pierce
their critical chakra points
so that they can't move.
They won't be able to move
for a day.
You okay, Hinata?
Yes.
I'll fight with you.
It's no good.
My genjutsu reversal has
no effect against
the special kind of chakra
circulating in the body.
Don't get so depressed.
Whoever did it,
that's a genjutsu unknown to us.
It has to be the work of someone
with extraordinary skill.
So it will require someone
with exceptional visual jutsu powers.
Visual jutsu?
Good observation!
I-I didn't say anything!
Didn't say what?
Don't ask!
Naruto!
We may not be able to see anything.
But the one who possesses both
the Sharingan and Rinnegan just might.
Huh?! You mean...?
I'll call Sasuke back.
Can I ask you to do it?
Yes.
Sasuke's going to come back!
Return to the Hidden Leaf Village. huh?
A human exploded!
D-Damn you!
Stop!
Don't tell me that's the exploding
human that attacked the Hidden Leaf?!
Why? A village like this?
Old Man Iou!
Chino, stall them.
You got it, Nowaki!
Water Style: Water Formation Wall!
Shinobi?
What's going on?
Wh-What?!
Are you one of them?
You've got it all wrong.
Silence!
They asked you to come
and get even, didn't they?
Get even?
Young ones!
What are you doing?
Damn it!
Sorry, I don't have anything
against you, but...
Water Style:
Rain Hail!
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
What?!
I didn't know Fire Style
could beat Water Style!
Get back.
A Change in Nature of Wind, huh?
Oh, come on!
Hurry up and kill him!
No one told me he was so strong!
You spineless—!
You can tell me later why
you mistook me for someone else.
That eye...
The Sharingan?!
Uchiha...
Why did the villagers end up like this?
How should I know?!
The one you mistook me for
is involved in some way, right?
I've got nothing to say!
I-I'm sorry.
We don't know
what's going on either.
From the looks of it,
you're not from this village, are you?
We're former shinobi
who are now traveling performers.
We finished a gig at a resort
in the Village Hidden
in the Hot Springs.
It's pretty profitable there
for entertainers like us.
Anyway...
We decided to head somewhere else,
so we came through the Bamboo Village
to stock up on supplies.
And Old Man Iou's daughter
is such a great person!
She made us really good food!
By the way, is my daughter...
Is Amino okay?
Amino!
We had all the women and
children take shelter...
Hey!
We have no choice
but to ask these guys directly.
Amino?!
An exploding human?!
Iou, don't get close.
It's too dangerous.
Who cares if it's dangerous?!
That's my daughter!
Let go... Let me go!
Amino!
I'll never forgive you.
Never... Fuushin...
I'll never forgive you, Fuushin!
Who is Fuushin?
The leader of the Lightning Gang.
The Lightning Gang?
They take money from bad people
and distribute it
to poor people like us.
They're honorable thieves.
So why would their leader
try to get even?
This is just what I heard...
The Lightning Gang was betrayed
by the Hidden Mist...
It seems they barely escaped
with their lives
and found their way to this village.
Just for a little while...
Let us rest here.
Please go somewhere else.
What?
If we harbor you,
we'll end up paying dearly for it!
We have no intentions of
troubling the village!
We'll leave right away!
Just because you take money
from others and give it away,
don't think you can do
whatever you want!
The village rejected
the Lightning Gang.
What are you going to do?
I'm going to look inside memories
of the exploding humans.
Huh?
Are you okay?
That red eye...
There's no doubt about it...
It's a Kekkei Genkai.
"Encountered Exploding Humans."
"Will investigate independently.
Please approve."
Just how long will
your journey continue?
Sasuke, where are you going?
You're Sasuke Uchiha, right?
The lone survivor of
the exalted Uchiha Clan.
I knew it the moment I saw
your Sharingan last night.
Where are you going now?
That has nothing to do with you.
It does involve us!
Amino...
... made us yummy meals.
She was kind.
You're going to look for
that Fuushin guy, right?
But isn't he the one who changed
Amino and the others
into those exploding humans
or whatever, right?
We're going with you.
I think we may be able to help.
And don't give us that look that says
"I don't need you guys!"
That will only make us more determined!
Sasuke, are you listening?!
I don't care what you do.
Just stop calling me that.
I figure I'm older than you, Sasuke.
So I can treat you like a kid.
Older? You?
Ahem!
By that much?
What do you mean by "that much"?
Sasuke, it's not good
to judge people by their looks
or by your impression of them.
You shouldn't judge people
by their looks or
by your impression of them.
Are you going to join too, Big Brother?
I wonder...
You should! When I'm older...
I'm going to join
the Leaf Police Force too!
Forgive me, Sasuke...
This is the last time.
No matter what becomes of you,
I will always love you.
Sasuke!
By the way... Have you been back to
the Hidden Leaf Village. Sasuke?
What? Ignoring me again?
What about reviving the Uchiha Clan?
You're the lone survivor, right?
Hello! Are you there, Sasuke?!
Chino, stop it.
Whose side are you on anyway?
You know, you...
Hey, where are we going?
Ignoring me again!
I mean...
Hey.
My name isn't "hey"!
You asked if I'm going to
look for Fuushin.
The answer is yes.
Huh?
That's what I should do right now.
A-Any ideas on where to look?
The only thing that can create
an Exploding Human
is a Kekkei Genkai.
H-Hey, Sasuke...
Hold on a minute...
You think you'll find him inside
that really scary-looking cave?
Ignoring me again!
You're Sasuke, right?
You can call me Yamato.
Since you're watching over this place,
it must mean that Orochimaru is here.
O-Orochimaru? You mean that—?!
What's the purpose of your visit?
I can't allow just anyone through
to see Orochimaru.
Regarding the Exploding Humans
that attacked the Hidden Leaf...
It's possible Orochimaru may have
information about the perpetrator.
Did you send word about this
to Lord Sixth?
I intend to, if I get results.
It would be much easier for us
to coordinate things,
if you'd send us progress reports...
However...
You're doing this all for the sake
of the Hidden Leaf, right?
Yeah...
Then there's nothing else to say.
I'll send Lord Sixth a report.
Remember, we're comrades.
I'm sure Kakashi also taught you
the importance of trust and teamwork.
Thank you...
It's been a long time, Sasuke.
You've brought some
interesting-looking friends with you.
Do you know Fuushin
of the Lightning Gang?
What? Not even a greeting?
You're as blunt as ever.
Tell me everything you know.
Is that any way to ask
a person something?
Hurry up.
Fuushin possesses a Kekkei Genkai...
I believe he originally was a member
of En Oyashiro's guard unit.
En Oyashiro?
He's not affiliated with any group.
Even though he's a shinobi,
he's an arms trader.
He'll sell weapons to anyone
for the right price,
so he's known as
the "Merchant of Death."
He's amassed a huge fortune
during his lifetime.
Where is he?
Who knows...
He has a hideout
even better hidden than mine.
I think finding him
will be very difficult.
For you, even the difficult is easy.
Does that mean you trust me?
Well, I don't know where to find him,
but I can lure him out.
However...
that may cause a few problems.
Why do you think I came here?
How unlike you...
I'm just doing what I have to.
I sense the wind.
Wait here.
It will take some time to prepare.
Sasuke!
I didn't know that
you knew Orochimaru.
I don't recall ever telling you.
Sasuke!
Hey! Why didn't you
let me know you're coming?
Sasuke...
"Sasuke"?!
What? Is she your girlfriend, Sasuke?
You mean, that ugly hag?
Hey! Who are you calling ugly?!
Sasuke, say it's not true!
It's not true.
You should've seen
the look of panic on your face.
Shut up!
If it weren't for that
big mouth of yours!
That's no excuse for looking like...
- It's been awhile.
- It's the end of the world!
You've been continuing your travels?
Yeah.
You haven't gone back to
Hidden Leaf Village.
See, you're worried sick
about Sasuke.
You're really getting on my nerves!
Quiet, you guys.
I'm ready. Shall we go?
Lord Orochimaru, are you going out?
Sasuke and I are going to the sea.
Huh?!
The ocean? With Sasuke?
You all will stay and mind the fort.
The sea with Lord Orochimaru?
I can't quite picture it.
Wait, that's news to me too.
To be more precise,
a solitary island in the sea.
There's a paradise for the wealthy there.
And that's where En Oyashiro is?
If he takes the bait.
- Nowaki.
- Yeah.
Sasuke...
Bleh!
What's with that girl?
Want to fight?
Oh, what a drag.
Sasuke working for
the sake of strangers...
The Hidden Leaf was attacked...
They're not strangers...
But he didn't return to the village.
I wonder if it's hard
for him to go back?
Don't you guys get it?
The big war might be over,
but there are still lots of
dangerous characters lurking around.
As long as Sasuke has those eyes...
shinobi will continue
to attack the village.
So by showing that Sasuke Uchiha
isn't in Hidden Leaf Village
and he's still traveling
around the world,
it lessens the possibility that
the village will be harmed.
So then,
Sasuke has to continue traveling?
That might be it.
Still...
The fact that you, the one who instigated
the destruction of the Hidden Leaf,
the assassination of the Fourth Kazekage
and countless other horrific crimes,
can still move around freely
is quite astonishing.
I'm not free.
And who are you to talk, Sasuke?
By all rights, you should be locked up.
But even Kabuto,
one of the war criminals from
the Fourth Ninja World War
is now the director of an orphanage...
Kabuto is?
Of course, compared to me,
the likelihood that Kabuto will
resort to evil is lower.
How can you be so sure?
Don't you trust the power
of Itachi Uchiha?
You and I, and Kabuto
could just be insurance...
in case something happens that cannot
be countered with common sense.
Insurance?
In every era, a maverick appears.
When that happens, there may be
a need for people like us
who possess powers
considered to be inhuman.
There are things that cannot be
protected by righteousness alone.
If that's the case, keeping us around
like pets might be mutually beneficial.
But...
your friend would never even
think of such a tactic.
Probably not.
There...
You can see it in the distance.
Where are we?
This is an island that
you can't find on any map.
Oh...
Let's go.
What is this place?
It's called the Coliseum.
Coliseum?
Is everyone enjoying themselves so far?
Honors to the victor!
Despair to the vanquished!
As you know, the rules are simple!
The one with your ID tag goes up against
one with another person's ID tag.
And the winner is whoever manages
to take his opponent's ID tag...
Simply put, it's a survival match!
What's going on, Orochimaru?
You heard the explanation.
The wealthy patrons here pit their shinobi
against shinobi employed by others.
The losing shinobi becomes theirs.
And now, today's semi-final match!
Now entering the ring...
Wearing the ID tag of President Makibi
of the Makibi Corporation...
Raimei, the Black Lightning Flash!
His opponent...
Wearing the ID tag of President Himeyuri
of the Himeyuri Company...
Suzuran, the Eerie Flame
of the White Moon!
This place is like a casino.
All right, let's begin!
It's now or never, no foul play,
no grudges afterward...
A single-bout challenge!
Ready?
Fight!
I don't have time to waste
on sick hobbies.
Where is En Oyashiro?
I wonder...
But this is about the only place
that he'll show up.
Although, he won't come
if there's no shinobi he wants.
Whoa! Suzuran is down!
The winner is Raimei!
President Makibi is overjoyed!
You're useless!
Why do you think
I kept you all this time?!
You ingrate...
This place is worthless.
Then why don't you help?
To a victim, the assailant and
a third party are no different.
People are no better than the assailant
if they don't try to help.
If you only pity the loser and do nothing
to stop the decadence of the rich...
you're just as guilty, Sasuke.
Chino, stop.
Chino!
Was this sight too shocking
for a child?
No, she's older than me.
What?
The wait is finally over!
Now, for the main event!
Wearing En Oyashiro's ID tag is Futsu!
It seems he took the bait.
And his opponent will be wearing
Lord Orochimaru's ID tag...
The legendary shinobi who attacked
the Five Kage Summit...
The last Uchiha...
Sasuke Uchiha!
What is the meaning of this?!
I told you. Oyashiro will only
appear for something he wants.
He is... a collector of Kekkei Genkai.
A collector of Kekkei Genkai?
Yes...
As for you with
your Sharingan, Sasuke...
He probably wants you so bad,
he can taste it.
Couldn't he have just searched
for me if he knew I was here?
Oyashiro is a careful man.
He can easily camouflage his scent,
let alone his appearance and form.
Who knows where he is?
However, he will definitely appear
after the match for the ID tag transfer.
That's the custom here.
Wait a minute,
could this be a default?
Now go...
He's here! He arrives, ready to go!
Sasuke Uchiha has appeared!
So that's Sasuke Uchiha.
Let me see your Sharingan.
All right, let us begin!
It's now or never, no foul play,
no grudges afterward...
A single-bout challenge!
Ready...
Fight!
Vapor Style: Solid Fog Jutsu, eh?
P-President Makibi?
Is he all right?!
A-Ambulance!
Call an ambulance!
An Exploding Human?
What is that?!
Get away from him!
So that's the Sharingan.
What a surprise.
Sasuke using his Sharingan
to save someone's life...
Huh?
W-Watch out!
What happened?!
Lady Himeyuri!
Just what is going on?
Leave one of them to me!
We can't save them...
but we can lessen the damage!
How bothersome.
Chino!
What is it?
I didn't expect you to save me...
Sasuke.
Thank you.
Chino!
Are you okay?
I'm fine, I'm fine... Ow!
You need to get that taken care of.
These are the Exploding Humans that
attacked the Hidden Leaf Village.
They're quite troublesome.
I can't make contact with him,
so I'm going to get going.
Looks like you won't get
to meet Oyashiro.
What?
I told you, didn't I?
He's a very cautious man.
I can't imagine he'd stick around
after all this uproar.
And since the match
ended midway,
there won't be an ID tag
transfer ceremony either.
Besides, we won't be able
to get any intel on Fuushin,
who belonged to
Oyashiro's former guard unit,
who's making all
these Exploding Humans.
This has been
a total waste of time.
Lord Orochimaru.
What did you say?
Sasuke...
Oyashiro is asking for you.
Go on ahead.
What about you?
I'm going to get
this wound looked at.
I'll stick with Chino.
All right.
Oh, hello!
I am En Oyashiro.
Nice to meet you!
Is he really En Oyashiro?
There's no mistake.
It's been a long time,
Orochimaru!
When was the last time
we were face to face like this?
It's been so long,
I don't remember.
What's going on?
I don't recall you being someone
who'd reveal himself so casually
before others like this.
It's only because I witnessed
something very interesting.
Though it was quite a shock to
see humans explode like that.
They're just like
the Exploding Humans
that attacked
the Hidden Leaf, right?
You know about that?
You can't be in
my line of business
if you're not on top of the news.
They appeared because
they were after you, right?
Perhaps, this time.
This time?
Are you saying that they attacked
the Hidden Leaf Village
for a different purpose?
I mean, doesn't it seem like it?
They attacked the Hidden Leaf Village.
with me as their target?
The man creating
the Exploding Humans
seems to be a former member
of your guard unit.
What? No way!
His name is Fuushin.
You know him, don't you?
Hmm... That kid?
He initially belonged to someone else.
Someone else?
I won him at the Coliseum and
assigned him to my guard unit.
I believe he was born on
a small island in the Land of Water.
When he was young,
he was sold off by the islanders
because they were scared of him.
Sold off?
Isn't that how it is with
the Kekkei Genkai?
Weak humans who
consider themselves "normal"
always fear unusual power.
It's a disadvantage from
the moment you manifest it.
Though personally,
I like Kekkei Genkai.
I mean, they're powerful and rare!
That's why I've collected
all different kinds for my guard unit.
I've even slaughtered the rest
and left only one to
increase the rarity...
The only thing is,
because of the difficult situations
surrounding their upbringing,
many of the kids were rebellious.
If I didn't know medical ninjutsu,
I probably couldn't
have tamed them.
Fuushin was a relatively good kid,
but one day, all of a sudden,
he took the other kids and ran away.
I wonder why he ran away?
I fed them every day and
even gave them an allowance.
I've heard enough!
Did Fuushin have red eyes?
Red eyes?
Oh, now that you mention it...
One of the kids who ran away with
Fuushin had eyes like that.
Ran away with Fuushin?
So Fuushin has a partner?
Was that genjutsu trap
his doing?
What was his name?
I've forgotten.
Then remember.
You're so harsh!
Oh, I know!
That kid was from the Chinoike Clan.
The Chinoike Clan?
What is that?
It's a tragic story.
I don't care, tell me.
It goes way back...
Even before the time Hashirama Senju
and Madara Uchiha competed for power.
Bloodshot eyes...
The Chinoike Clan with
their Ketsuryugan.
They lived in
the Land of Lightning.
They were especially proficient
with genjutsu
and once you were caught
in their visual Jutsu,
it was said
you could never escape.
Anyway, one of the Chinoike Clan
women was sent
to become the concubine of
the feudal lord of the Land of Lightning.
She was personable and beautiful...
and that made the lord's consort
terribly jealous.
Unfortunately, shortly after taking
the girl as his concubine,
the feudal lord became ill and died.
"It's her fault he died!"
The lord's consort put all
the blame on the concubine.
And those who knew about
the Chinoike Clan's unusual genetics,
supported the consort's claim.
As a result, the girl and
her entire clan
were exiled to a place known
as Hell Valley.
And for that, the consort hired...
What's the matter?
The Uchiha Clan.
What did you say?
The Uchiha Clan with their Sharingan
were the only ones
who could go up against
the Chinoike Clan
and their unique visual Jutsu.
The Chinoike asked the Uchiha to set up
a meeting place to negotiate,
but were rejected.
Seems the Uchiha Clan who suffered
long through persecution
were also complicit in
the persecution of others.
What about Itachi?
Was Itachi aware of this?
I wonder...
However...
you may learn something
if you go to Hell Valley.
Where is Hell Valley located?
It's in the Land of Steam.
Are you going?
I don't know.
I guess not.
You don't know if Fuushin
is actually there.
But I'm rooting for you.
Good luck!
We need to get rid of nuisances like
Exploding Humans as soon as possible.
That's unusual.
I didn't expect to hear that from
a weapons trader like yourself.
If a convenient explosive like
that became commonplace,
I'd be forced to shut down
my business.
Just as guilty...
That's what you said.
Huh?
To a victim, the assailant and
a third party are no different.
People are no better than the assailant
if they didn't try to help.
If you only pity the loser
and do nothing to stop
the decadence of the rich...
you're just as guilty, Sasuke.
It's just as you said.
But...
"But"?
No, never mind.
Hey, you probably won't tell me...
But I'll ask anyway.
Where are you headed this time?
Hell Valley.
See? You didn't tell me...
What? Hell Valley?!
The one making Exploding Humans
is there?
Probably not.
Then why are you going?
I want to see this Hell Valley
with my own eyes.
As the last survivor
of the Uchiha Clan.
Huh?!
We came all the way here
to the Land of Steam,
and we're not going to soak
in the hot springs?
You two can do
whatever you want.
This is where we go
our separate ways.
But why?
The one making
the Exploding Humans is after me.
It's better if
you're not around me.
We came all the way here together.
As if we'd desert you now,
Sasuke.
We're going with you
to Hell Valley!
Exploding Humans!
Sasuke!
Stay away!
Nowaki, let go!
He's...
not cloaked in chakra.
Hot! So hot...!
Hot! So hot!
You're not Fuushin, are you?
Wh-What are you saying?
I'm the Lightning Gang's...
I possess the Sharingan.
I can look into
your memories with this.
If you're lying, I can't guarantee
that I'll spare you.
Fine.
Won't guarantee my life?
Well, I'll say it right back at you!
Whoa... I won't let you.
Earth Style: Mud Wall!
Lava Style: Rubber Wall!
Rubber is strong against
the Lightning Style!
Lava Style: Rubber Sphere!
All right...
Let's do this!
It starts now!
What?!
Then I'll just increase the amount!
Amaterasu.
Wh-What the hell is this?!
I-It won't go out!
Hot! Hot!
I-I'll tell you anything you want!
I'll talk! Please let me talk!
So please put out the flames!
Hot! Hot!
Kagutsuchi...
You don't have to talk.
"I need your help... Fuushin."
Just hold on, Boss!
So you want me to make
this Sasuke guy think
that I'm after him?
I figured as much.
That's right.
That chakra sword was
the same as the chakra sword
you threw at me at Bamboo Village.
Show me what you really look like...
"Really look like"?
That's not your real appearance.
Otherwise,
you wouldn't have shown yourself
before Old Man Iou in the Bamboo Village.
Still, were you that scared
to see En Oyashiro?
Indeed... This is how I really look.
Fuushin!
You're going to tell me
everything I want to know.
I wonder if you can make me?
Severe Wind Destruction!
This isn't over yet!
There's no wind.
So this is the eye of the storm!
Now, tell me everything.
No way.
Damn it!
What's that?
Don't think I'll fall for
the same trick twice!
So this is Hell Valley...
The Chinoike Clan really lived here?
Yes, we did.
Take a good, long look.
That's proof people lived here.
False suspicion was cast on them
and the Uchiha Clan forced them
all the way here.
The clan had no choice
but to settle here.
They drank this scalding water,
hunted down whatever birds
they could that flew past...
ate the meager grass that grew
in the soil in order to survive.
Weary of fighting,
the clan never ventured out
into the outside world,
and scraped out a living,
so I've heard.
"So I've heard"?
By the time I was old enough
to understand,
I was already living
in Oyashiro's mansion.
I was told Oyashiro kidnapped me
from Hell Valley... just me.
You were all alone?
You were all by yourself?
What? You're actually interested?
How unlike you.
Then let me show you.
I was the only one from
the Chinoike Clan.
But there were lots of kids like me
at Oyashiro's mansion
and we were all forced to train
to become shinobi.
What's the matter?
If you don't win, you'll go hungry.
You did well, Chino.
And on that day,
Oyashiro brought me to...
the Coliseum.
Representing President Kusabi
of Kusabi Real Estate Company
and currently on
a record-setting run of no losses!
The Hurricane Kid
who has no mercy...
Fuushin!
And going up against him...
representing En Oyashiro,
who returns after a long absence...
The Beauty of the Ketsuryugan...
Chino!
I've never heard of
the Ketsuryugan.
Just what kind of power is it?!
It seems like our audience
is very curious too!
And now, let's begin!
Ready...
Fight!
If you're so eager,
I'll show you my Ketsuryugan.
I'll blow you away before
you have the chance.
Typhoon Style:
High Wind Destruction!
Whoa... What's this?!
Fuushin's just been standing there!
What's wrong, Fuushin?!
Did I... just lose?
Yeah, you lost.
Can you believe this?!
The one and only Fuushin has lost to
a young girl in her debut match!
There we go.
You're really strong!
Are you being sarcastic?
N-No way!
My eyes are...
S-See... They're special, so...
Special, huh?
Anyone who possesses
a Kekkei Genkai is special.
Because of this power,
people feared me
and kept their distance.
At times, I was shunned
and treated cruelly.
Even having a past like that
was better than what I had.
What do you mean?
For as long as I can remember,
I've been here.
I have no memory about
anything before I came here.
I see.
You're fortunate.
Me? Fortunate?!
Having memories you don't want
to remember is pointless.
I was born in the Land of Water.
But it wasn't on the mainland
where the Hidden Mist Village is.
I was born on
a poverty-stricken island nearby.
And...
Because of this power,
I was blamed for a typhoon
that struck the island.
They wanted to get rid of me,
so I was sold off to a rich man
named Kusabi.
All I remember about Kusabi's place...
was the constant torture
even when I was obedient.
But I wasn't averse to fighting
in the Coliseum.
Because I was able to
demonstrate my strength there.
And still, I lost to a brat like you.
I'm sorry I won.
You better be!
Still, I envy you.
I don't know what
my mom or dad look like.
I don't know why I was born...
or even why I'm alive.
I don't have anything!
I don't care how terrible
any past might be.
It's better than being
empty like me!
I...
I just said some terrible things.
But that's how I feel.
Sorry.
I don't know why, but...
This is first time I've spoken
about myself to anyone else...
and the first time someone's tears
have actually moved me.
In the end, we were both assigned
to Oyashiro's guard unit...
and we started working.
And one day, we found it
at the Oyashiro mansion.
Look, Chino!
An old historical document
about the Chinoike Clan.
Let's go, Chino.
Huh?!
If we go to Hell Valley,
we may find some of your kin
from the Chinoike Clan.
And we might find something
regarding your past!
If you go to Hell Valley,
you won't feel so empty anymore.
But there's no way
Oyashiro will allow it.
We don't need his permission!
Fuushin and I gathered others
who wanted to get out of
Oyashiro's mansion and escaped.
We're all free now!
And we ran towards Hell Valley.
But...
Hey...
You get to live by selling
these crude bamboo knick-knacks.
Who do you owe that all to?
Why, we owe it all to you, my lord.
Silence!
Father!
This is hardly enough!
– So... I'll take your daughter in exchange.
– Are you okay, Father?!
Amino!
Wh-Who are you?!
If you don't want to get hurt,
get lost.
Y-Yes...
Hurry, grab him!
S-Sir...
Th-Thank you for saving me.
Think nothing of it.
We just happened to see
what was going on.
Where are you
chivalrous thieves from?
Chivalrous thieves?
P-Please! Please continue
to protect us!
We were hailed
as chivalrous thieves.
So we adopted the name,
the Lightning Gang
and worked for
the sake of nearby villages.
We were treated like heroes.
Every time we appeared,
the villagers welcomed us.
They gave us food and shelter.
Everyone was kind.
Sorry that we haven't been
able to go to Hell Valley.
That's okay.
I can go to Hell Valley anytime.
For now, let's work hard
for these people.
We owed allegiance to no one,
others were at our mercy.
Seeing this, some shinobi villages
tried to use us.
During the reign of
the previous Mizukage,
the Hidden Mist were
our valued clients.
That same thing happened then.
We went after a Feudal Lord
who was taking money
from the unfortunate.
Oh come on. What's the matter?
You mustn't, my lord.
A-Are you the infamous—?!
Yeah, we're the Lightning Gang.
Get him.
W-Wait... please.
As long as you pay up,
we won't hurt you.
That's as far as you'll go.
Shinobi...?!
The Hidden Mist?!
I see... You want to get rid of us.
And not only that,
you intend to create a direct relationship
with the Feudal Lord.
Th-Thank you for saving me.
You're correct.
It's horrible, isn't it?
But, what's worse was...
Just for a while...
Let us rest here.
Please go somewhere else.
What?
If we harbor you,
we'll end up paying dearly for it!
We have no intentions
of troubling the village!
We'll leave right away!
Just because you take money
from others and give it away,
don't think you can do
whatever you want!
Every village was the same.
They wouldn't even give us water.
One by one,
our wounded comrades died.
Eventually, it was just
Fuushin and me.
There's nowhere else we can go.
Yes, there is.
Huh?
So we... finally made it
to Hell Valley.
I'm empty, after all.
Chino?!
I can't remember anything!
My father, my mother...
I can't remember anyone's faces!
Coming here didn't solve anything,
after all.
I still don't know why
I was born or why I'm alive!
Pursuers from the Hidden Mist!
Chino!
Let go, you damn—!
Owww!
Chino...!
Wh-What the hell is this?!
What's wrong?
Chino!
Chino, are you all right?
I... didn't know I could do this.
So... that was the true power
of the Chinoike Clan?
I'll get my revenge!
You were going to use that to
get revenge against the Uchiha
who forced the Chinoike Clan
to Hell Valley?
So I was your target
from the very start.
If I sent Exploding Humans
to the Hidden Leaf Village,
then you were sure to return.
I planned to kill you and
the entire Leaf Village, but...
You happened to meet me
at Bamboo Village, is that it?
Coincidence is a scary thing,
don't you think?
We attacked that village just to
get back at them for the last time...
Meeting you there was
the last thing we expected.
But thanks to
the head of the Bamboo Village's
interesting parting words,
we changed our plans.
I'll never forgive you...
Fuushin!
I happened to be looking for Fuushin,
so you joined up with me and
used your Exploding Humans whenever
something happened as a diversion.
And Nowaki, rather Fuushin, would come
after me with his chakra sword.
And just in case
you couldn't kill me,
you went so far as to ask an old partner
to stand by and pretend to be Fuushin.
So what now?
Are you going to kill me?
You and me... We're the last ones from
the Chinoike and Uchiha Clans.
Let's put it all on the line
and fight to the death!
Unfortunately,
I'm not interested in that.
You're the same as usual...
But don't think
you can go around
with that aloof expression
on your face forever.
The Chinoike Clan uses blood
to handle all kinds of jutsu.
And here in this location...
this red lake with
its high iron content...
will make the power of
the Chinoike even stronger!
What?!
Take this!
Go!
Do you still want to continue?
Chakra is entering
from my wound?!
What?!
My chakra seals the wound
and waits.
Waits for what?
Isn't it obvious?
Goodbye, Sasuke Uchiha.
So that's how you made
the Exploding Humans?
The Sharingan?!
I envied you, Sasuke.
You were born in
the Hidden Leaf Village
and bore the Uchiha name...
and you had a family
that loved you.
When you deserted your village,
you and your reputation were notorious.
But even now,
you're allowed to travel freely.
That's because you have people
who love and protect you.
I know...
You've always, always had someone
who kept loving you, no matter what.
You're not like me...
I've been alone from the beginning!
You've been alone
from the beginning!
How the hell do you think
you understand?
It's because I have these ties,
that I feel this agony.
How could you
possibly understand
what it feels like to lose all that?!
So...
So why do you fight for
the Hidden Leaf?!
The leaves of the Hidden Leaf
are brilliant,
but its roots are black!
There is light and darkness
in the Hidden Leaf!
Your clan was used up and absorbed
by the Leaf's roots as nourishment!
So why do you go so far for them?!
Because I'm alive.
What do you mean?
I have a friend who saved me.
A friend with whom I can share
my pain, and him, with me.
His wish is that one day
the world will be like us.
A world like that is impossible.
That's just wishful thinking!
That's why he wants to
make it real!
And it's that hopeful heart that
connects me to the Hidden Leaf!
To be like my older brother...
and support this world from
the shadows, and...
And?
And look beyond this world...
to the light!
I don't want to see such a world!
Enough already! Kill me!
Hurry and kill me!
Chino!
Fuushin!
Fuushin?!
What are you doing here?
Fuushin?
Now, you should be able to understand
the meaning of my words.
I have a friend who saved me.
A friend with whom I can share
my pain, and him, with me.
If you're going to kill someone,
kill me.
Fuushin, it's okay.
It's okay.
I'd be in pain... if you died.
Chino...
Sasuke, I wish I didn't meet you
at Bamboo Village.
Then I could have kept
on hating you.
Also, I want to see
this world that you speak of...
This is the last one...
It's penetrated the brachial artery.
We're good now.
There's no more unusual chakra
flowing inside of him now.
Thank you.
What would I have done
without you?
I think it's all because of
your exceptional skill, Sakura!
The ringleader was turned over to
the authorities last night, right?
Yes.
Was Sasuke there?
I thought he would be.
But they asked the Leaf shinobi to go over
to the Land of Steam to take custody.
The one who captured
the ringleader didn't return...
Hello.
I'm the perpetrator.
I take all responsibility.
So please go easy on the other two.
Chino, that's not what we want.
That's right, Miss Chino!
I–!
Now calm down...
Actually, the Mizukage of
the Hidden Mist
wants to take custody of you.
Wh-Why?
Now's the only time to stop
the chain of negativity.
Please come in.
Let's skip the greetings.
I'd once heard about your past connection
to the Hidden Mist.
Huh?
If it's okay with you...
I'd like you to help
the Hidden Mist.
Wh-Why?
You must atone for what you did
for the rest of your lives.
But every shinobi, great and small,
must bear the same burden.
I'm no different.
Would you like to fight again...
with your own life?
And, there's another thing
I need to let you know.
Around now, he's...
Wh-What is this...!
The last Uchiha...
a.k.a. Sasuke Uchiha has
returned to the Coliseum!
To a victim,
the assailant and a third party
are no different.
People are no better than
the assailant
if they didn't try to help.
If you only pity the loser
and do nothing
to stop the decadence of the rich...
you're just as guilty, Sasuke.
I will welcome all challenges!
And I will free all shinobi!
If you desire the Uchiha's eye,
come and get it!
Sasuke is—?!
But there are many shinobi
with Kekkei Genkai there!
Even someone like Sasuke...
Don't underestimate Sasuke!
Sasuke's probably doing this
for your sake.
So he will never, ever lose!
So you're Sasuke's?
Yeah, I'm his friend.
I'm Naruto Uzumaki.
Your friend saved me.
I'm very grateful.
I see!
Th-This is something
no one's ever imagined!
Sasuke Uchiha has beaten
each and every shinobi!
Which means, he has acquired
every single shinobi!
What's going to happen to us?
The Hidden Cloud will take you in.
The Hidden Cloud?
Indeed!
We, the Hidden Cloud, will
safeguard all shinobi!
At the same time, everyone who took part
in the illegal gambling here
will be taken into custody.
This is so dull.
This isn't looking good.
I'm here, kid.
I'm grateful.
Be grateful to your Lord Sixth.
– He came and insisted...
– Hurry and come here!
That this island
was close to my village,
and that it was the Cloud's business
to deal with it.
That's why we're here...
So dull...
Long ago,
Naruto put his hands together
and passionately argued for you.
It was the time you kidnapped
my kid brother, Bee,
and Danzo agreed to our request
to mark you a rogue ninja
and assassinate you.
I want you to cancel
the disposal of Sasuke Uchiha!
I'm begging you!
I don't want us killing each other
for revenge anymore!
I'm glad we didn't kill you
back then.
Know yourself and know others,
and never alter your path again.
Feel the significance of why
you can walk this world freely.
And create a reason to
convince others around you.
Perhaps with this incident,
you just created one.
But just one won't be enough.
You weren't caught?
I'm here, aren't I?
Did things work out as planned?
Thanks to you, it did.
Conflict breaks out easily
in small communities.
Even though they've lived shoulder
to shoulder for many years,
even the smallest incident
festers hatred
and in the end, they end up
killing each other off.
That sounds like the Uchiha Clan.
They were definitely like that, however...
This is the truth of
the Chinoike Clan.
When my wife got wrapped up
in everything and died...
lots of things didn't matter anymore.
That's why you killed
your entire clan?
Even still, my daughter
is quite endearing.
And you saw with your own eyes
the foolish thing
that your dear daughter of yours
was doing in the Coliseum.
I wonder if that's why
you gave up on acquiring Sasuke,
and used him instead
to stop your daughter?
You're such a doting parent...
I consider myself more
of a foolish parent...
Still it feels strange.
Sasuke's not back in the village,
yet he's protecting it.
You're right.
There are so many things
we can't do
without a skilled shinobi like Sasuke.
There are guys who do
terrible things like this time,
but I guess everything works out
as long as there are guys
like Sasuke to counter it.
You seem kinda happy, Sakura.
Huh?
Sasuke said to me before
he left on his journey...
This is a trip to atone for my sins.
With this recent incident,
I know that Sasuke is
definitely making inroads.
Just...
I just wish I was there next to him...
F-Forget what I just said!
Huh?
It's probably from Kakashi.
It's so messy. It's Naruto's handwriting...
Sasuke...
You're not back in the village,
but you're still protecting it.
You're just like the Leaf Police Force!
Are you going to join too?
Well... I wonder about that...
Why not?
When I grow up, I'm going to join
the Leaf Police Force too!
It's been a while...
Maybe I'll go home.