If only Lady Tsunade would
come out of her coma,
I know she would resolve
the situation with Sasuke.
Excuse me.
Sai?
I need to speak to you.
Naruto did what?!
Yes.
In order to protect Sasuke.
He was bruised and battered all over.
Still, he refused to sell out Sasuke.
Not only that...
In order to prevent you from worrying,
he asked me to keep it quiet.
He's on his way to see the Raikage
and ask him to forgive Sasuke.
Why would he be so reckless?!
Wasn't Kakashi with him?!
It probably wouldn't have
made any difference.
Kakashi Sensei has faith in Naruto.
Even if it's a long shot,
he probably wants to create
an opportunity for him.
If Lady Tsunade were there,
she'd have done the same thing.
Sakura...
I was only recently assigned to
Team Kakashi to take Sasuke's place.
So I still don't know
all of you that well.
And I'm not good at understanding
a person's feelings.
But...
Even I can tell that
Naruto loves you!
I swear I'll bring Sasuke back!
I promise that on my life!
Sakura! I'll keep my promise to you.
I swear I'll keep it because I said so.
I said so...
Sakura...
It's as though Naruto has been shouldering
the burden of his promise to you.
As though he intends to bear
that burden for the rest of his life.
I don't know what you told Naruto.
But it's no different from
what was done to me.
It's like a Curse Mark.
Sasuke is the source of
Naruto's agony.
But aren't you a part of it too?
Ino...
Don't cry, Ino!
Kiba, don't be so harsh.
You know how Ino has felt
about Sasuke all these...
It can't be helped!
Things have changed since then.
Will they be okay?
Look at Ino.
How will Naruto and Sakura take it?
Let's leave it to Shikamaru.
He'll find the right words.
Plus, there was that first mission of his
as a squad leader that failed,
and he still feels somewhat
responsible for it.
If only we had been able to take
Sasuke back that time.
That's why he volunteered
to be the persuader.
Wait! Naruto genuinely wants
to rescue Sasuke,
not just because he promised
Sakura! Isn't that so?
I totally agree with you.
But...both Sakura and I...
and everyone else rely on
Naruto too much.
I've watched how Naruto
has been acting lately
and I figured out what he's feeling.
It's sadness.
Then my thoughts turn to Sasuke...
and it starts to get warm inside my gut.
I realize now that it's anger.
Whether it's for Naruto's sake
or for the village,
we can't just rely on Naruto.
We have to take action ourselves.
Sasuke is...
Sai is absolutely right.
Shikamaru...
We're not kids anymore.
We must stop the Akatsuki.
And we must stop Sasuke.
I came here for Team 7's consent.
Consent? Don't tell me...
Yes...exactly that.
We can't allow war to break out
between the Hidden Leaf
and the Hidden Cloud
because of Sasuke.
According to the messenger
from the Cloud,
Sasuke is already being treated
as a criminal on a national level.
If Sasuke continues to align himself
with the Akatsuki
and intensify the hatred throughout
the country,
the Hidden Leaf must deal
with Sasuke.
That is my belief.
You understand where
I'm coming from, don't you?
Sakura...
That's why I need your consent.
Sakura, will you...
Shikamaru!
Please don't...
say anything more.
Sorry, Sakura...
But whatever your answer is,
I must act for the sake of
the Leaf's future.
I intend to tell Naruto this too.
Where is he?
Naruto has gone to the Land of Iron.
To meet with the Raikage.
He's willing to go that far?
I guess this isn't gonna be easy.
I'll talk to Naruto.
Sakura!
He's foolish enough to like
someone like me.
So let me handle this.
Well then, what do we do now?
We have to form
an Allied Shinobi Force.
It's the only way we can counter
the power of the seven Tailed Beasts.
You were opposed to this,
weren't you, Lord Raikage?
It seems my younger brother is alive.
We cannot allow ourselves to be
manipulated by the Akatsuki any longer.
Form the alliance and
settle this once and for all!
What about the Hidden Leaf?
The Hokage ran off.
There is too much suspicion
surrounding Danzo.
He lost our trust at this summit.
When the Hidden Leaf ninja
learn about him,
his position in the village will
become insecure.
He will be removed in no time!
I will speak to someone I trust among
the Hidden Leaf
regarding the Allied Shinobi Force.
Who would that be?
Kakashi Hatake of the Sharingan.
You mean the White Fang's son?
Fine. He seems more trustworthy
than Danzo.
Agreed.
Lord Raikage, we must take measures
to find Killer Bee immediately!
If the Akatsuki want
the Eight-Tails and Nine-Tails,
they are probably still pursuing Bee.
Yes. Shee, send word to
the village to put together
a Tracking Unit to begin the search
for Bee immediately!
Yes sir!
We must notify Samui's team too.
Omoi and Karui have been
feeling quite distraught.
If we are to stop
Madara's Project Tsuki no Me,
we cannot let the Eight-Tails and
Nine-Tails fall into his hands.
I think it is imperative that our
Allied Shinobi Forces find the two first
and place them into hiding.
Y-You're absolutely right!
If the day comes when
this Ten-Tails is revived…
However, we cannot even imagine
the power Madara wields
with the seven Tailed Beasts
he already has.
Furthermore, he may possess
certain jutsu or a trump card
for using the Tailed Beasts.
Otherwise, he wouldn't have
come on so strong.
Perhaps it would be wise for
the Allied shinobi Forces to plan
on using the Eight-Tails and Nine-Tails
as military weapons too.
That cannot happen.
This is also a war to protect those two.
There is a reason why Madara
is waging war
with just the seven Tailed Beasts
he has collected thus far.
It is too difficult for Madara,
in his weakened state,
and the Akatsuki members to capture
the Eight-Tails and Nine-Tails.
And even if they had succeeded,
he felt the risk was too great.
That is why he may be hoping to
lure the two to his side through war.
In any case, using the Eight-Tails
and Nine-Tails for battle
is not a wise strategy.
I agree.
I also concur with the Kazekage.
If we consider
the worst-case scenario,
it will be like offering the Eight-Tails
or Nine-Tails on a silver platter!
And besides, the Eight-Tails is
my younger brother and
"military strategy" is
a foreign concept to him.
I can't predict what he'd do.
He may just create more chaos
on the battlefield!
Naruto the Nine-Tails,
would do the same.
– That's for sure.
– I'll say.
I understand.
Well then, Lord Tsuchikage,
our aim will be to protect and
confine the Eight-Tails and Nine-Tails.
Fine.
Intel about Killer Bee
will be provided to
the Stone, Mist, Sand and Leaf Villages.
Use it to form Tracking Units
and get moving!
Send word the instant
you find the Eight-Tails.
My younger brother will
only heed orders from me!
By the way, Kazekage, we will leave
the matter with Kakashi to you.
Yes.
On my way here,
I met Kakashi Hatake and
the boy who is the Nine-Tails' Jinchuriki.
They might still be here
in the Land of Iron.
You should start your search
for them here.
Understood.
U-Um...May I say something?
What is it?
Uh...Yes...Umm…
Spit it out!
I-In the Akatsuki, there's someone who,
like me, is a member of
the Seven Ninja Swordsmen of the Mist.
Kisame Hoshigaki.
He has chakra equal to that
of a Jinchuriki
as well as a sword known
as Samehada, Shark Skin,
which is the most evil, even among
the Seven Ninja Swordsmen of the Mist.
When his chakra and sword merge,
even though he is human,
he releases power close to
that of a Jinchuriki.
He is like a Tailed Beast
without the tail.
That's what I've been told by my seniors.
He is extraordinary and
must not be underestimated.
We already know that!
But are you all sure about this plan?
We do not know what kind of power
the seven Tailed Beasts possess
under Madara.
If we confine the Eight-Tails
and Nine-Tails,
and our Allied Shinobi Force is destroyed
while protecting these Tailed Beasts,
our entire effort would
have been meaningless.
If that is the case, I think it is better
to use the two right from the beginning
in a combined effort with
the Allied Shinobi Forces.
I wonder about that.
At this moment, the world's first
Allied Shinobi Force is being formed.
Its power is also unknown.
Madara will also be taking a great risk
in pitting the power of
the seven Tailed Beasts against it.
Otherwise, why would he have come
to this summit to try to negotiate?
He must also be dealing with
unfavorable conditions.
Furthermore, we Samurai
will also participate in this war!
Lord Tsuchikage…
Do you still have doubts even now?
After what we learned about Danzo,
who was your initial choice?
The question of who will lead the
Allied Shinobi Forces is still an issue.
Is there any among the current Kage
you consider competent enough?
Mifune, you criticized every Kage
including me.
I believe appointing Lord Ei
would be the wisest move.
Didn't you say that Ei
was unsuitable
because he gives in to his emotions
and relies on power?
There is no longer any doubt
that the Eight-Tails is alive.
Furthermore, he skillfully built
a consensus earlier
and was quick to come up with
a counter strategy.
And Lord Ei is the only one capable
of controlling the Eight-Tails,
which is key to this battle.
Mizukage, Kazekage…
Are you in agreement?
This is not the time to argue.
I trust Lord Raikage.
We'll leave it to you, Raikage.
Understood. I will lead the Allied Forces.
Ohnoki the Fence Sitter,
since you are the only one
who has battled Madara Uchiha,
we'll need any intel you can give us.
I expect your cooperation.
He certainly enjoys barking orders
at everyone.
If you don't trust me, fine.
But if we don't do something,
the ninja world as we know it
will disappear.
Now is the time to put
personal differences aside and cooperate!
Well, it's certainly better than
losing this war.
Our arguments are nothing compared
to a world without ninja.
So I shall cooperate.
The Allied Shinobi Forces
are hereby formed.
First, we must notify the Feudal Lords.
Looks like the Raikage and
Kazekage went upstairs.
Sasuke and Karin must
have gone ahead.
We should go up too.
But it's guarded.
We'll be spotted right away.
Well, I have a good way.
What the hell was he?
So gross!
Shinobi...We shinobi we endure…
Shinobi suppressing our sobs!
You don't just sing enka.
Enka requires a passion-filled soul!
Now you try singing.
Yeah!
Shinobi, by being so stealthy…
We extend our life expectancy.
You lack passion.
Passion!
You're just mouthing the lyrics
and not taking it seriously!
Passion?
That's right! Passion!
As the characters in “enka” imply,
it's important to act out the world
in the song with passion!
Also, the tremolo,
you have to clench your belly
and bring the note into your nose,
all right?
What's the matter, Ponta?
He's one of the Akatsuki, Master Kin.
This personal biz will take a second,
what a miff,
but no worries I'll erase him in a jiff!
I searched high and low for you,
Eight-Tails.
My great blade Samehada
loves powerful chakra.
And it seems to have finally caught scent
of some delicious chakra.
I'm sorry, but you're going to
be food for my Samehada.
Not to worry though, I won't kill you.
But I'll kill you.
I'll show you that
we're worlds apart in power.
So prepare ya-self, fool, ya fool!
My rhymes are…
Ponta!
You sure are chatty for a Jinchuriki.
There's a peculiar bear upstaging you!
If we keep doing what we've
always done, we'll never find Sasuke.
I've got to use Sage Mode.
But first, I need to be able
to sustain it longer.
Naruto, come inside soon.
Finally found you!
Sakura…
Sai, Kiba, and even Bushy Brows?
Why did you all come here?
Naruto…
I need to talk to you.
W-What did you just say, Sakura?
I think I heard wrong.
Could you say it again?
I said…
I…
Love you, Naruto.
I said Sasuke doesn't mean
anything to me anymore.
I must have been crazy to carry
a torch for him for so long.
Listen carefully when
someone confesses her feelings for you!
But why? What for?!
This isn't the place to be joking around.
It's not funny, Sakura.
What's going on?
Nothing really!
I just woke up.
Why should I love a rogue ninja
who's a criminal?
I'm not a child anymore.
I can face reality.
So Naruto, you can forget about
that promise you made to me.
You can stop chasing
after Sasuke, all right?
What's going on?
Do you think Naruto will calmly
accept our decision?
But this is something we all decided.
We have to make him understand.
I'll talk to Naruto about everything.
You, Sakura?
Do you have a plan that'll work?
Just leave everything to me.
So don't say anything to Naruto.
Please promise me this, everyone.
And…
Damn it…
Is this what she had in mind?
Sakura, did something happen?
This is all so sudden.
Nothing happened!
It's obvious why I fell in love with you.
All I really want, is for you
to accept me, Sasuke.
That's all...I'm desperate.
Sasuke! Sasuke! Sasuke!
Naruto, this is
a once in a lifetime request.
Please, bring Sasuke back!
Next time I'm coming with you.
Sasuke…
Sasuke keeps getting
farther and farther away from me.
But Naruto, you've always
stuck by my side
and cheered me up.
Naruto, I finally realized…
Your true self.
You used to be a prank-loving loser.
But now you've become
a wonderful person.
And I've witnessed it all, first-hand.
Meanwhile, Sasuke keeps adding
to his crimes,
and breaking my heart.
Always becoming more of a stranger.
But you Naruto,
I'm able to be close to you like this.
You comfort me.
I care about you,
from the bottom of my heart—
Cut it out, Sakura.
This joke isn't funny at all!
Why are you so upset?
I'm just telling you that I like you now
instead of Sasuke.
You know the saying, “women are
as fickle as the autumn weather.”
I hate people who lie to themselves!
I'm lying to myself?
I'm the one who decides how I feel!
If you hate me,
just come out and say so!
Don't just make up a convenient excuse.
But it doesn't make sense!
You came all the way out here
just to tell me that?
"Just" to tell you?
"Just"?
You don't think it's a big deal for
a girl to profess her love?!
I came “all the way out here”?
Of course,
I'd come all the way out here!
Sasuke, Sasuke, Sasuke!
That's all you think about!
Going after Sasuke and
putting yourself in danger!
You're the Nine-Tails' Jinchuriki
and the Akatsuki are after you!
Worry about yourself for a change.
I'm saying that it's not necessary
to endanger yourself
just to chase after Sasuke!
I want you to come back to the village now,
that's why I'm here.
That's all!
I think it just sounds
like a painful excuse.
I know you pretty well, Sakura.
Then why don't you understand?
I don't care about Sasuke
now that he's a criminal.
So the promise between us
doesn't matter anymore.
It's not just about the promise.
I kind of understand more now,
about why Sasuke has become
obsessed with revenge
and is causing so much damage.
Sasuke loved his family and his clan.
Because his love was so deep,
it's hard for him to forgive.
If he were so devoted,
why would he join the Akatsuki after
defeating the unforgivable Itachi?
That's not how it went down.
Naruto!
It doesn't matter, even if
there's no promise between us anymore.
I personally want to save Sasuke.
What now, Sakura?
Maybe you should just
tell him the truth.
Oww!
Forget it! I'm going back.
Let's go, Kiba, Lee, Sai!
Sakura…
Let's go.
Naruto…I'm sorry!
Are you okay with this, Sakura?
Kiba, I need a favor.
What is it?
I'm going to start looking
for Sasuke right now!
Will you help me?
If we just got rid of the Eight-Tails'
and Nine-Tails' hosts,
we could stop Madara's plan and
weaken the military power of
the Cloud and the Leaf.
We could kill two bird
with one stone!
It was agreed that this time,
we will do no such thing.
Why not?! That's not like you,
Stubborn Geezer!
Then let me ask you this.
Sure. I will answer anything, kid.
When did you all forsake yourselves?
It's because I remembered.
Remembered what?
I remembered who I was
before I became so stubborn!
He may be big,
but he's not a bear worth shredding!
Ponta is a raccoon!
You will feel the passion of my wrath!
Passion? So you can use it
in this sort of situation.
Okay, got it!
I'd better add that Ponta is a raccoon.
So you mean…
You're going to get in my way!
Yosaku Chop!
He's watching my moves and using
Lightning Style enhanced ninja tools
from mid-range distances.
But it's also a diversionary tactic
to try to confine me.
Now twice you shall be perfo-rated.
Don't let that make me hated.
What's going on?!
Bee's Super Vibrato Lightning Blade
didn't pierce through?
Well then…
Eight-Tails' Cloak!
Head butt!
You...My chakra…
Bee! I saw it!
It's that sword!
It's sucking away your chakra!
It probably absorbed the chakra out
of your Super Vibrato Lightning Blade
before it even made contact!
That's why it didn't pierce through.
Your octopus-flavored chakra
must be very appealing.
It's rare that Samehada
gets this worked up.
You are worthy of shredding.
Your eyes are cute, it's so surprising.
But making them into dead fish eyes…
is what I'm devising.
You...Umm…
Kisame Hoshigaki,
pleased to meet you after the fact.
It appears to be a jutsu
where a seed-like clone
parasitizes a life form with chakra
and feeds on its host's chakra.
So that's why you didn't notice it.
Most likely a ninjutsu of the Akatsuki
we saw at the meeting.
And what about the other one
who has been following us all along?
He continues to tail us.
Probably the Byakugan user
from the Hidden Mist.
Him?
There.
It would be a stroke of luck
if he falls for this.
Your traps are special.
It'll work.
Dead or alive, make sure
you gouge out his right eye.
Yes, sir!
Judging from the markings,
Ao went this way.
Let us hurry.
Yes, ma'am!
Take care of my body, Torune.
A booby trap. It must be Danzo's.
Why am I seeing my own body?!
Gotcha.
What's going on?
You are under my Mind Transfer
Puppet Curse Jutsu.
Damn it! Was this
a curse-type Mind Transfer Jutsu
that activates itself when
the object is attacked?!
Your mind is now sealed inside
that puppet.
And I am in possession…
Of your body.
Damn it. It's useless.
Forget it.
That is a barrier ninjutsu that
only us Hidden Mist Black Ops,
the shinobi tracking unit, can undo.
My Byakugan is precious,
the only one that the Mist possesses.
Do not think that you'll be able
to reclaim it easily.
So it self-activates
when the eye is at risk, eh?
A fitting jutsu coming from you guys,
also known as the Undertaker Squad.
I don't expect it to be easy.
Taking your eye means that I,
as the jutsu caster, will lose my own eye.
You know that.
So it's Danzo's orders?
Just what does he think of
his subordinates?
If the Mist's military power becomes
greatly diminished because of it,
losing one of my eyes is
a cheap price to pay.
Though, thanks to your barrier,
it's not going to happen at this rate.
But there are plenty of other options.
What do you plan to do?
I'm simply going to jump down
and behead you.
If I can't remove your eye,
then I'll just have to take
your entire head back to the Leaf with me.
You're going to kill yourself?
No. I'll undo this Mind Transfer Jutsu
just before the blade cuts your neck.
Either way, you'll die.
And I, back in my body, can retrace
my steps here to grab your head.
Fine. Just make sure you're careful.
Or else you'll fail.
What do you mean?
Because if you get nervous and
release that jutsu an instant too soon,
I'll defend myself from your sickle!
If I'm not dead,
the tables will be turned
when you come to get my head.
Remember that.
Saved.
What happened?
I was caught in the enemy's jutsu
and couldn't move my body.
If you hadn't come, I would be dead.
That was a very close call.
I'm sorry I made you worry.
Couldn't move?
It must have been a genjutsu
or something.
It was a type of Mind Transfer Jutsu.
Your right eye…
The enemy was after the Byakugan,
weren't they?
They almost succeeded in smashing it.
I'm sorry, but can you untie me?
Of course.
I'll also undo that jutsu protecting
your right eye.
Thank you, that will help.
What is that?
No!
He hasn't undone
the Mind Transfer Jutsu yet!
She fell for it.
If the Mizukage can undo the jutsu
protecting this right eye,
I couldn't ask for anything better.
I can destroy the Byakugan and
then undo the Mind Transfer Jutsu.
This should do.
Lady Mizukage?
Lend me your Hiramekarei, Chojuro.
Huh?
You are not Ao.
I cannot undo the jutsu
on that right eye.
Ao knows that well.
Besides, Ao would never apologize
to Chojuro.
You played me…
you sly old vixen—
Ow!
I-I wasn't the one who said that…ma'am.
Oh, you're back to normal.
I'll kill him!
That Sensory-Type Hidden Leaf ninja!
It's a good thing she didn't use
the Hiramekarei on you, sir.
Foo.
Well?
Forgive me, sir. I have failed.
It cannot be helped.
Kisame Hoshigaki, eh?
Ink in your mouth…
The rumors are true.
You really are an octopus brat.
I'm gonna make you weep!
You sharky creep!
A Tailed Beast Cloak with
only seven chakra tails…
Does this mean
you're going to get serious?
Did you know?
Know what?
Octopi eat sharks!
Bee!
This time, the shark shall
devour the octopus.
That sword Samehada's got
a big appetite and it's a speed-eater,
but it looks like it can only devour
six tails' worth of chakra at one time.
If that's the situation with this version,
then my next version
should do the trick.
Samehada has never grown
this big before.
Its delight is not trivial either.
What'll we do, Bee?
Enter Tailed Beast State, Bee!
No way, fool, ya fool!
An attack with you would
be way too huge
and would destroy the area.
Master Kin and Ponta are
here with us, don't forget!
Besides, I finally managed to
sneak off under the radar.
If I let you out, it'll be like
announcing that Killer Bee is here!
It's not like you to make excuses, Bee!
So what'll you do?
Fight in Version 2 State?
Oh yeah.
'Cept most of my chakra got taken away
during those last few exchanges,
so lend me yours.
If it weren't for me,
you'd have lost a long time ago.
Ya sure got a cheeky personality,
but I'm still grateful for
your hospitality, yeah!
Huh?
Going into a Tailed Beast State, eh?
No, this is a Tailed Beast's power
trapped in a humanoid form.
It's Version 2 State!
Lariat!
Samehada is so excited
it's tripping out.
The chakra earlier is nothing compared
to this volume and quality.
I'm amazed he can control this
much chakra without losing his mind.
You did it!
I can't believe I was reduced back
to Version 1 State.
He's still alive! Hurry and finish him!
You've sure done it.
What is that?!
The stronger my opponent,
the stronger I become.
I do not tire.
I do not fall.
So his blade steals his enemy's chakra
and transfers it to its master
in the form of stamina?
And that's why
I'm called the Tailless Tailed Beast.
Water Style:
Super Exploding Water Shock Wave!
The longer this battle drags on,
the more chakra will be shaved from you
and the greater you will weaken.
And I'll grow proportionately stronger.
Bee! You must take his sword away!
That sword is the key to his strength!
That's if you can pull it off my body.
At this rate,
both Master Kin and Ponta will drown.
First, we have to get out of the water!
You cannot escape this Water Style Jutsu.
I have the advantage in
this location right now.
I can't see the boundary!
So much water! So crazy!
These circumstances are hunky-dory!
I won't be taken down, sorry!
This isn't the time for
your lame rapping!
The water bubble is in motion
and that half-fish guy
is at the center!
Pay attention!
And he's faster under water
than we are!
Plus he's half fish,
so he probably breathes through gills!
Just running away
is gonna get us killed.
So what'll we do?
Akatsuki's target is you, Bee!
Leave that enka geezer
and the raccoon
and run in a different direction!
He's definitely gonna come after you.
I see. That way, those two can…
Right! While he's pursuing you,
the water will move with him.
Then those two can
get out of the water.
All right! Now come this way!
What?!
I must capture the Eight-Tails alive,
but there's no rule against
killing these two!
I ain't letting that happen, ya fool!
Wha—?!
I got you!
Suction pads?!
Gotcha!
No way will you keep
taking my chakra.
Fool, ya fool!
You really are worthy of being
called the perfect Jinchuriki.
To be able to change just one part of
yourself into your Tailed Beast is impressive.
All right, they're out.
You seem to be
having trouble breathing.
It was a good idea,
but as long as you're touching me,
you'll continue losing chakra.
I can see why Samehada
can't contain his excitement.
He has discovered
his favorite kind of chakra.
No one in the Akatsuki is as good as
I am at taking prey alive.
This Water Prison Shark Dance Jutsu
is so much fun
because I can probe
the amount of chakra to shave
until you're just on the verge of death.
I must admit to failing once in a while.
I guess I have to use Lariat again.
I just have to time it right.
Don't!
You can't beat him underwater!
That last attempt with
the octopus leg put him on guard.
Just make a run for it!
Use that!
Ink...A smokescreen.
You are an octopus, after all.
However…
With my body merged with Samehada,
I can detect chakra through my skin.
It seems you'll run
out of chakra soon.
Bee…
I'm coming…Bee!
The Eight-Tails turned out to
be rather disappointing too.
I can't chance you squirming around
and going into
a Tailed Beast State again.
So I'm going to cut off your legs
as a precaution.
Though, my blade doesn't cut cleanly!
What's the matter?
Don't tell me you've become
attached to the Eight-Tails.
You like his chakra that much, Samehada?
That was chakra you took from me!
Very well.
Shall we exchange weapons then?
This sword…
It looks like it has a nice, sharp edge!
A pencil?!
Too bad.
Definitely too bad.
So that was your plan, eh?
Sorry we're late, Bee.
Brother…
Raikage? How did you find us?
That mass of water you created
was quite visible.
And I perceived Bee and
the Eight-Tails' chakra mixed inside it.
You really went to town sucking up
someone else's chakra
and using it for yourself.
It was so obvious.
Guess you found us, after all.
That Samehada...It's giving
the Eight-Tails more chakra!
Let's do it.
Okay, Brother.
Water Style:
Super Shark Bomb—
— Double Lariat!
I must say, you two are too fast.
Brother…
No!
Wandering around by yourself!
Even ya non-dominant arm does me
a lot o' harm! Sound da alarm!
How was the lower level?
Everyone was annihilated except for us.
It seems like two of Sasuke's subordinates
are still around here.
Did you see them?
We haven't seen them.
They probably died too.
Everything is a mess down there.
No. A Sensory-Type ninja
from the Hidden Cloud
confirmed that they survived.
They asked us to capture them
and then they left.
Oh, is that so?
You two…
Remove your armor.
Oh my, it seems we've been found out.
Just as I thought,
that wasn't a very good plan.
Sakura, why did you do
something like that?
Sai! What are you doing here?
It's a clone.
I'm going to tell you
what Sakura really wanted to say earlier,
but couldn't.
What do you mean, Sai?
Sakura didn't come to
confess her love for you.
The Hidden Leaf ninja have
come to a consensus
and I'm here to inform you.
I thought it was strange.
So she was hiding something after all.
The Hidden Leaf will deal with Sasuke.
Every one of your comrades is committed
to that and will act accordingly.
Did Sakura…
Did Sakura really agree to that?!
Sakura loves Sasuke so much!
And yet…
How could she?!
After Akatsuki's attack on our village,
the Hidden Leaf ninja can no longer
recognize Sasuke as one of their own,
not after he supported the Akatsuki.
Sakura is not a fool.
She's not a child who wouldn't understand
the difficulty of the situation.
That's why we came here in person
to try to explain it to you.
Then why didn't she just come out
and tell me the truth?
It wasn't that simple.
You know that.
She understood how hurt
you would feel.
But still…
To be honest, Sakura made us promise
not to tell you the truth.
She said she would tell you somehow.
She said it was her duty to do so.
This is just an assumption on my part.
But I believe Sakura…
She intends to kill Sasuke herself.
Is that true, Sai?!
Probably.
Please don't take it all on yourself.
I feel the same way as you.
So does everyone else.
Oh…yeah.
Thank you, Sai.
I know.
Sakura smiled and told everyone
she would cooperate.
But this time,
I saw through her fake smile.
No way.
Sakura wouldn't do such a thing.
She's crazy about Sasuke—
It's because she loves him so much
that she can't bear to watch
Sasuke turn more and more evil.
It's because she loves him so much
that she wants to save Sasuke
from this path of evil.
Even if that means killing the one
she loves with her own hands.
That is how committed she is
to her love for Sasuke.
And in doing so, Naruto…
She's prepared to accept your hatred.
It's her way of atoning for
the lifelong burden she placed on you.
Until now, Sakura relied on you too much.
This time, she intends to resolve
everything alone.
Sai…
Why are you telling me all this?
I couldn't ignore what Sakura's doing.
And besides, I belong to Team 7.
I see.
There is something
you must hear immediately.
We will tell you everything that happened
at the Five Kage Summit.
I see.
Who would have thought the meeting
would become so intense.
I guess with Danzo…
I'm not too eager about
becoming the Hokage.
And even if the situation
requires me to accept…
I'll have to return to
Hidden Leaf Village first
and hear what the others say.
Madara has declared war on us!
There's no time to deliberate.
I'm sure everyone will approve.
We should have them proceed
on the premise
that you are the Hokage, Kakashi.
If our response is delayed and the
Akatsuki and Madara take the advantage,
that would be even worse.
I guess you're right. Thanks.
And Sasuke…
For him to attack the summit…
Naruto, this is a battle to protect
the Eight-Tails and the Nine-Tails.
Namely you.
And it's also for the ninja world.
As the Kazekage,
I would give my life to protect you.
If Sasuke Uchiha confronts
the Allied Shinobi Forces
as a member of the Akatsuki,
I will show no mercy.
Sasuke doesn't care about you.
All he wants is darkness.
Naruto, you told me,
"I am going to be the Hokage."
I have become the Kazekage.
If you are prepared to bear
the burden of being a Kage,
then do what is right
as Sasuke's friend.
We've said everything we needed to say.
Let's go, Gaara.
We will return to our village.
Kakashi Hatake…
With the understanding that
you will be Hokage,
the Sand will take action.
As allied nations,
I pray that there will be
no conflicting intel between us.
Understood.
I consider you my friend.
In the past,
"friend" was merely a word to me.
Nothing more, nothing less.
But after meeting you,
you made me realize that…
The meaning of that word
is what's important.
What does it mean?
What can you do for Sasuke?
Think hard about that.
Let's go.
Naruto…
Let him find the answer himself.
So? What do we do now?
In any case, I think we should
return to the Hidden Leaf
and report what happened
at the summit.
And also about Sakura.
The real me is accompanying Sakura.
She won't be allowed
to get near Sasuke!
You can count on that.
But it would be better to go
in person and talk her out of it.
All right.
Yamato, take Naruto and
head back to the village.
I'll bring Sakura back.
Sakura is no match for Sasuke.
It would be like
she's going there to die.
I'll dispatch the ninja Hounds with a
report about the summit since it's urgent.
Understood.
Sai...Take me to Sakura.
Yes.
Itachi Uchiha…
His life was one of
personal sacrifice.
For the village and more importantly,
for his younger brother.
Sasuke lost everything,
and he was left all alone,
in exchange for peace
in Hidden Leaf Village.
Can you still blame Sasuke?
Sasuke said that he couldn't forgive
the Hidden Leaf
for sacrificing Itachi's life
to secure peace.
He is doing everything out
of a desire for revenge.
He is the real thing.
A true avenger.
Hatred...It is Sasuke's ninja way!
The Hidden Leaf will deal
with Sasuke.
Every one of your comrades
is committed to that
and will act accordingly.
Sakura intends to
kill Sasuke herself.
If you are prepared to bear
the burden of being a Kage,
then do what is right as Sasuke's friend.
Calm down, Naruto!
He's hyperventilating.
Breathe slowly.
Naruto!
Naruto…Can you hear me? Naruto?
You're finally awake?
Where am I?
You lost consciousness.
You really had us worried.
Where are Kakashi Sensei and Sai?
You're going back to
the village with me.
They're Kakashi's orders.
I'm sorry, but you just have to
let Kakashi handle Sasuke.
Got it?
Fine.
Let me rest some more,
then we can head back to the village.
You should eat a little
to restore your strength.
I don't have an appetite.
It's been a long time, Danzo.
We haven't met since
the Uchiha incident.
Foo, Torune, assist me.
I'm going to break the seal
on my right arm.
Keep him occupied.
So you're going for it, Danzo?
Madara...His abilities are limitless.
Be careful.
– Yes, sir.
Torune, we'll back each other up
and attack.
I know.
Mind Transfer…
A Sensory-Type with Mind Transfer skills.
A member of the Yamanaka Clan, huh?
In order to protect himself,
he de-materializes his body
at the moment of an attack
and passes right through it.
But he solidifies his body to make
physical contact when he attacks.
We have to aim for the counterattack.
That was a well thought out analysis.
The counterattack must
be timed perfectly.
We'll attack one after the other
and get him on the second stage.
The first stage will be a diversion.
I'll be the decoy.
He's already seen through
my Mind Transfer Jutsu.
We'll go with your jutsu.
Got it.
Now!
This guy…
He just pretended to attack.
Damn it. We fell for it!
Hmm…
A jutsu to flush in chakra
and destroy cells?
How troublesome.
Forgive me, Foo.
I'll extract them right away.
This isn't chakra.
These are nano-sized venom beetles.
They are almost like bacteria.
Insects that devour cells on contact.
I've heard of them.
You are a ninja from the Aburame Clan
who knows Hidden ninjutsu.
I see. You're the son
of Shikuro Aburame,
the one with immunity to those insects.
To think you were in the Foundation.
Danzo!
You have yourself a good subordinate.
Forgive me, Torune.
Don't blame yourself, Foo.
Use your sensors to
locate him quickly.
I'll get him the next time.
Damn it!
He sucked in Torune!
My right arm has been injected
with the venom beetles.
You're next.
Let me out of here.
Don't be so hasty.
I'll let you go.
I have something for you outside.
Sasuke Uchiha.
You stay back.
If you get involved, you'll die.
Perfect.
Sasuke...Madara…
I'll take both your Sharingan.
W-What? That right arm…
It has many Sharingan!
It's disgusting!
How did you get those eyes
in your right arm?
Through various means.
It would take too long to describe.
Any explanation would upset me more.
Forget it. I've decided to kill you.
Before that, let me ask one thing.
Is it true that Itachi Uchiha eliminated
my clan by order of the Elders?
So that's Sasuke's…
So this is the Susano'o.
I'm asking if it's true!
Answer me!
I...I didn't think Itachi was the kind
of man who would reveal secrets.
Does that mean it's true?
Self-sacrifice…
That's what epitomizes a shinobi.
Never seeing the light of day.
Toiling in the shadows.
It is as it was in the past.
That is what a true shinobi is.
It describes not only Itachi.
Countless other ninja have
died the same way.
Niceties alone will not make
the world go round.
Peace was attained all
because of people like him.
People like you who misunderstood
Itachi's intentions
couldn't possibly understand.
Still…for Itachi to reveal such
a secret to you makes him
a traitor to the Leaf…
Don't say anymore about Itachi!
You're right.
Then let us proceed
to a battle of the eyes.
What's going on?!
He should've died earlier!
I can only sense chakra
from one Danzo.
I'm certain it's not a clone!
As expected…Susano'o.
Just the thing to protect yourself.
The power in its attack is as expected.
Again? So if that wasn't
a clone either…
Is it genjutsu?!
Sasuke's inner chakra isn't disturbed.
And my chakra is calm.
What kind of jutsu is this?
Amaterasu!
Susano'o and even Amaterasu…
That's too much just to
test Danzo's power.
He'll tire himself out.
Sasuke! Behind you!
Wind Style: Vacuum Bullets!
Sasuke!
Summoning Jutsu!
A new summoning jutsu?
When did he get that?
Amaterasu. It's been a while
since I last saw that.
You are Itachi's younger brother after all.
You've taken over Itachi's jutsu.
I told you never to
speak of Itachi again!
Brothers with the same ability.
Yet, what your eyes perceive
is so different.
The truth about Itachi
isn't important to you.
You direct your hatred at whomever
you can lay your hands on.
You make the sacrifice of
the Uchiha Clan meaningless.
You have no right to talk
about the Uchiha!
Wind Style: Vacuum Blast!
Sasuke!
This is…
No way!
It's useless.
Th-This is…
Itachi?
Die…
Amaterasu!
I commend you for placing me
under genjutsu.
However…
I was aware of your genjutsu
long ago.
It is a far cry from
Itachi's masterful Tsukuyomi
in which he freely manipulated time.
A Curse Mark that paralyzes the body.
He must have placed it back then.
Sasuke...You can't move?
Taijutsu, huh?
It seems he wants to
preserve his chakra.
Release!
The flow of Danzo's chakra
has changed.
What's he up to?
If Sasuke knows the truth
about Itachi,
then the Akatsuki must know as well.
It's impossible to try to conceal
the information any longer.
Why was it necessary to save
the life of such trash, Itachi?
He's your…ultimate mistake.
But he could not kill…
his little brother.
He cried tears of blood and killed
every shred of feeling he had inside him,
then he killed his brethren
for the sake of his village.
But he just couldn't kill you.
Do you understand what
that means?
To him,
your life was more precious…
Than the village.
He broke free from the Curse Mark.
Is that Susano'o?
It's completely different from before!
All right.
His hatred has matured
and gained in power.
And his body is responding to it.
This is going well.
He doesn't need my help at all.
He's aiming for my landing.
I can't weave the signs in time!
It can't be helped!
I managed to alter its path.
Danzo's chakra level
plummeted with that jutsu!
Why did he go to that extent
just to dodge Susano'o's attack?
The jutsu this guy's been using
is supposed to make him immortal.
So the jutsu he released
earlier was his own.
That was Wood Style.
I see. So that's why…
With that many Sharingan,
I knew there had to be a secret
for someone not from the Uchiha
to be able to use them.
Damn Orochimaru…
It seems he and Danzo
have been in close contact.
He had the cells of
the First Hokage, Hashirama,
implanted in him to enhance
his physical energy.
That's how he was able
to control so many Sharingan.
No, he can die!
If he hadn't countered that
earlier attack, he would have died.
That's why he exhausted
so much chakra!
Sasuke!
That's the real Danzo!
The jutsu that makes him invincible
is broken right now!
He's vulnerable!
So that woman's a Sensory-Type ninja!
She figured me out.
But it's too late.
He activated the jutsu!
I'm probably the only one
who can see that.
Susano'o's attack just then
was probably too late.
Damn it!
As far as I can tell,
he has ten Sharingan in his arm,
as well as the First Hokage's cells.
The power of the Uchiha
and Hashirama.
Looks like he intends
to control the Nine-Tails.
So he's after Naruto too.
Danzo's chakra level has
decreased some more.
This jutsu carries a lot of risk
after all.
There's no mistake.
This is the Visual jutsu that was forbidden
even among the Uchiha.
Izanagi…
I didn't expect to see it here,
of all places.
Sasuke!
Stay calm!
The only thing I can do right now
is analyze Danzo's jutsu!
Izanagi…
Where in a brief moment in time,
anything disadvantageous
to the user of the jutsu,
like damage or death,
can be rewritten as a dream.
And…
Anything advantageous,
such as the user's attacks,
is kept as part of reality.
The ability to control the space
between fantasy and reality.
An ultimate genjutsu cast upon oneself.
And the eye that uses
Izanagi loses its light,
never to open again.
But…
The number of eyes
he possesses…
The duration of Izanagi varies
with each user.
He wanted to extend the time
by whatever means
so he agreed to become
a test subject for Orochimaru.
Damn that Madara…
It doesn't seem like
he plans to join the battle,
but I cannot take any chances.
I must reserve enough power
to take him on.
It will take some time
for the right eye I used
at the summit to recover.
However, this Susano'o
is not easy to deal with.
That arrow attack is difficult to dodge.
And I can't undo Izanagi yet.
I'll have to bet on this next minute.
Summoning Jutsu!
With this, Susano'o won't
be able to move.
Wind Style: Vacuum Blast Barrage!
Fire Style:
Fire Ball Jutsu!
53…54…55…
56…57…58…59…60.
Those eyes…
One closes every 60 seconds or so.
And during that time,
his chakra continues to drop drastically.
Which means…
That right arm shows how much time
that weird jutsu has left.
Four more left!
Sasuke! I figured out
a little bit of that guy's jutsu!
Listen! All right?
When all ten of your eyes
have closed on your right arm,
your jutsu will be undone,
isn't that so?
You knew about Izanagi?
As I suspected!
You tricked me?
What a crafty brat.
Y-You fool!
Why are you engaging him?
Sasuke! Get away from him now!
Prolong the battle!
How many Uchiha did you kill
to get that right arm?!
It was Itachi who enabled me to get it.
You made him do it!
I guess this is the extent
of Sasuke's power.
You were too hasty.
My eye is still open.
Go to Itachi so he can lecture you.
I win.
Why won't Izanagi activate?
You're the one who's going
to see Itachi.
It's a far cry from Itachi's Tsukuyomi,
in which he freely manipulated time
within a genjutsu.
But the trick lies in how you use
even a short, weak genjutsu.
In an instant,
before you were even aware,
Sasuke placed a genjutsu on you
and made you believe
that the last eye on your right arm
was still open.
You yourself were concerned about
the instability of the Izanagi's duration
and kept checking the Sharingan
on your right arm.
Sasuke did not miss that.
Very subtly, he wanted
to make you think
the Izanagi would last a little longer.
He had already confirmed that
he could place you under genjutsu,
even if it was just for an instant.
And Sasuke seized that opportunity.
Because you also possess the Sharingan,
you underestimated how
to use it in battle.
Your arrogance led to your defeat.
Now that's battling with your eyes.
Don't underestimate the Uchiha.
Danzo didn't get to use Shisui's eye,
but you pressed him
into a corner, Sasuke.
Looks like I'll be able to take
Shisui's eye soon.
The Foundation should have
stayed hidden underground.
Sasuke!
Are you all right?
Hurry up and bite!
Bringing that woman was
a wise decision.
She's useful.
I see why Sasuke chose her.
How could I…of all people…
lose to this brat?!
I can't die here yet!
No, at this rate, I'll be taken over
by the First Hokage's cells!
He's near death and he's losing
the ability to control chakra.
Hashirama's power is
not easy to control.
What a persistent guy!
Not yet…
This is where we battle with our eyes.
The visual prowess in
his right eye has returned.
I see. He intended to use Izanagi
until Shisui's eye recuperated.
You used your visual prowess
too much, didn't you?
Sasuke…
Sasuke is no longer useful.
As I thought, Madara's the one
I need to place
under genjutsu and manipulate.
I can't waste time, my wound is deep.
Isn't it ironic that you,
who glorified self-sacrifice,
would take a hostage?
It's not that I consider my life precious.
But for the sake of Hidden Leaf Village…
for the ninja world…
I cannot afford to die here.
No matter what the means,
I must survive.
For I will be the one reformer
who will change this ninja world.
This woman will be sacrificed
for that cause.
Sasuke help!
Don't move…Karin.
That's what I wanted to see.
Brother...One down.
You didn't have time to cast Izanagi,
did you, Danzo?
Karin…
Since you managed to
get taken hostage,
you're nothing but a burden to me.
Danzo…
I'm taking Shisui's eye.
He took Shisui's eye?
Are you all right, Danzo?
Why'd you interfere, Hiruzen?!
Don't say that.
We don't want to lose comrades
in a situation like this.
You're alive!
Kagami! Torifu!
Yeah, I managed somehow.
There are too many of them.
What'll we do, Hiruzen?
Yeah, you're right.
We should meet up with
the Second Hokage.
We're surrounded.
There are…
20 of them.
Judging from their tracking skills,
I'd say they're from the Hidden Cloud.
The highly skilled Kinkaku Unit.
There are seven of us including you,
Lord Hokage.
We're completely outnumbered.
Homura! Don't be such a coward.
The enemy hasn't pinpointed
our position yet.
We should lie in wait until we can find
an opportunity to break through.
It's no use, Koharu.
One of us will have to
divert their attention.
A decoy?
It means certain death.
So who?
I am a shinobi.
I've made up my mind to die on
the battlefield like a proper shinobi.
Sarutobi…
What are you thinking now?
Are you prepared to make
that sacrifice?
Go ahead! Say it! That I'll…
What's the matter?
Why can't I say it?
I will go!
Sarutobi…
Hiruzen, you…
Don't worry!
I may not look it, but I know
I'm better than any of you.
I won't die.
My trembling…stopped.
Damn it! I'm such a coward.
Look after the others, Danzo.
I know you'll—
Shut up! I was planning on volunteering!
Don't try to steal the spotlight!
I'll be the decoy!
Danzo…
My father and grandfather both died
on the battlefield as shinobi.
Self-sacrifice is a shinobi's duty!
No, I will go and be the decoy, of course.
You all are the young Wills of Fire that
will be defending our village
in the future.
No! You are the Hokage!
There is no greater shinobi in
the village than you!
Danzo, you are always competing
with Saru over one thing or another,
but what's necessary here
is for you to unite and work together
as comrades.
Do not make this a personal fight.
The fact is, you took too long
to reach a decision.
You must first look at yourself rationally
and know yourself.
Otherwise, at this rate,
you will place your comrades in danger.
In any case, Danzo and Saru…
You two are still young,
so don't be hasty.
Your time will come.
Until that time, stay alive.
Saru…
Protect those who love the village
and those who believe in you.
And nurture those to whom
you can entrust the next generation.
Starting tomorrow, you are the Hokage!
Saru...Take care of the Hidden Leaf!
Yes, sir!
You always get ahead of me!
For the sake of the ninja world…
for sake of the Hidden Leaf…
I will not let you both live!
This is the Reverse Tetragram
Sealing Jutsu.
Sasuke!
Get away from Danzo!
Hiruzen, it's my turn next.
Just as you gave your life to
protect the Hidden Leaf.
This time, I will.
I cannot allow these men…
But in the end,
I could not become the Hokage.
No matter how far I ran,
I could never catch up to you.
You were a tree leaf
upon which light shone.
I was nothing but a foundation
hidden in darkness.
What do you think of someone like me?
Hiruzen…
What was I to you?
That was the Collateral Damage
Sealing Jutsu.
He would've dragged you into
his corpse and sealed you inside.
He probably set it up to activate
at the moment of his death.
That was close.
We'll head for Hidden Leaf Village next.
The Hidden Leaf, huh?
I'm taking his eye.
Sasuke, don't be hasty.
Go back to the hideout and rest.
You used up too much of
your visual prowess.
Eventually you won't be
able to keep it up.
Your eye is losing its light.
What can you do by yourself now?
Patience is necessary
to reach one's goal.
Sakura…
What is it?
Perhaps it would have been
better to tell Naruto the truth.
There's no way
I could have told him.
Absolutely no way.
Sakura…
You're underestimating Naruto.
I found Sasuke.
That Tobi guy is next to him.
Stop, everyone!
What's wrong? Why did you stop?
We already went over our formation.
Kiba...What is Sasuke's precise location?
Facing directly north,
he's at 2 o'clock.
Up one kilometer.
Okay.
Forgive me, everyone!
I knew it.
You were going to use this to make
everyone fall asleep, weren't you?
Sai!
Huh?!
Sakura was going to take care
of Sasuke herself.
Why would you go alone?
Yes, why?
We promised to do it together!
No, you can't.
I won't let anyone proceed.
The four of us alone are no match
against Sasuke or this Tobi.
I promised Kakashi Sensei that
I wouldn't let any of you go.
What?
Is that the reason?
Sai…
I'll say this only once.
Move aside.
We must hurry.
It's becoming
a rather dire situation.
Ninja Art: Super Beast Scroll!
You're going to bind us
with those snakes?
I understand where
Kakashi Sensei's coming from,
but we just can't keep
letting Sasuke go.
I'll take care of him!
Why not, Akamaru?!
Don't be so scared!
The dog is smarter.
It seems he understands
what I'm saying.
Shut up!
Let's go, Lee.
Sure thing! Yeah!
I'll take care of this
with Tunneling Fang!
Good diversion, Kiba!
Here!
Damn it!
I'm sorry…everyone.
She got us. Please hurry!
I'm impressed, Sakura.
Naruto, let's go soon.
Are you still not ready?
I don't feel like going outside yet.
Can you wait a bit longer?
All right. He still hasn't caught on
that I'm a Shadow Clone.
Sasuke…
I'm going to give you a bit of advice.
That woman…
If you don't need her,
make sure you finish her off.
She knows too much about us.
"Us"? When did I join you?
Well, nevermind.
We'll meet again.
No!
Karin…
You said you didn't feel well.
Hurry up!
We have to help out.
It's the requirement for us
being allowed to stay here.
But!
I'll be right back.
No!
Be a good girl.
Mom!
Mom…
Stand up.
Where are we?
We took huge losses
from a surprise attack.
The village is overflowing
with the wounded.
We won't make it with
just your mother.
Mom?!
Let me go!
My mom…!
My mom is—!
There was no other choice
in order to protect the village!
What—?!
It's unfortunate that
you lost your mother,
but we still have more wounded.
You're late!
Where's that woman?
She's dead.
She's going to take over
from today.
Huh?!
This child? Can she handle it?
She is that woman's daughter.
She has the same ability.
No!
Let me go!
We're letting you stay because
you have nowhere else to go.
Work enough to earn your stay!
It hurts!
Damn it! It hurts!
Don't worry!
We'll heal you in no time.
No!
Now go on, bite!
Please…stop.
We took your mother
to your house.
From tomorrow,
go to the hospital even
if no one comes to get you.
Over there! Send more chakra!
Forget him! It's too late.
Check the one next to him.
Don't dawdle! Come with me!
That one can be treated
with medicine.
Continue just like that.
Now this one!
Hurry and come with me!
Hey, you have work to do!
Don't stop here!
But I've never been
on a battlefield…
Shut up!
If you can't run, I'll kill you.
Stand!
Go.
Come on!
Mom…
The higher-ups have decided
to let you take part
in the next Chunin Exams.
Me?
This exam displays the strength
of each ninja Village through
their genin's abilities.
It's considered a war by proxy.
We cannot afford to lose.
Your duty is to keep the other two
completely replenished.
We took in an outsider like you…
Keep that in mind and make sure
you get us good results.
Yes.
Oh yeah.
I have to keep hiding.
Lions Barrage!
The Earth Scroll…same as us.
M-My glasses!
– Later.
I wish I could've seen your face
from back then,
just one more time.
Sasuke!
It's you, Sakura.
He feels totally different.
Is this really Sasuke?
What are you doing here?
Who is she?
I'm coming with you!
I'm deserting the Hidden Leaf!
That Danzo…
He destroyed Shisui's eye
before he died.
What's in it for me if
you come along?
What are you plotting?
I'm not plotting anything!
Ever since you left
the Hidden Leaf Village,
I've regretted not going with you!
Is she an old teammate?
And she's also in love
with Sasuke? But…
I'll do whatever you want.
I don't want to have any more regrets.
And do you know what I want?
I don't care!
I'll do whatever you ask.
I'm going to destroy the Hidden Leaf!
That's what I want!
Will you really be able betray
the Hidden Leaf for me?
Yes. If you asked me to.
Then prove it.
Finish her off.
Then I'll believe you.
Who is she?
A member of the group,
Taka, which I founded.
As you can see, she's useless.
Sakura, you're a medical ninja, right?
You can replace her.
This will work out just fine.
How could he?
He's definitely not the old Sasuke.
He's completely changed.
Well, Sakura? You can't do it?
She has nothing to do with this.
If I...If I stab Sasuke now…
It will all be over.
Stop, Sasuke.
He really meant to kill her.
How you've fallen, Sasuke.
One after another.
Sakura, you tried to kill Sasuke
by yourself, didn't you?
You don't have to shoulder
such a heavy burden by yourself.
I was the leader of Team 7.
It was my cowardice that
split all of you up.
Sakura…
I said something irresponsible to you
in an effort to put you at ease.
Kakashi Sensei…
Don't worry.
It will be like it was before!
I must have been trying to
convince myself of that too.
I'm sorry I'm such
a careless Sensei.
But you're…
Sasuke…
I don't like to repeat myself.
But I'll say this once more.
I've seen so many guys
like you, I've lost count.
Those who follow the path
of revenge end up nowhere.
Do not become possessed
by vengeance!
Itachi...My father...My mother…
My entire clan!
Bring them all here!
Do that and I'll quit right now!
I don't want to kill you.
You talk like you could kill me
at any time!
Stop acting like
you're still my Sensei.
I'm itching to kill you…
Kakashi.
He's been completely twisted
by Madara.
Sakura...Heal that girl to the point
that she can speak.
We still have time right now.
She knows a lot of intel
about the enemy.
What about you, Sensei?
I will take on what would
have been your burden.
I guess you could say
it's my responsibility.
All right?
Hurry and go, Sakura.
No matter how far he had fallen,
he was still dear to you, wasn't he?
Third Hokage…
Even though you had nurtured
many other fine pupils…
A cherished student
abandons the village.
The agony of having to face
that dear student in battle.
No one can begin to imagine
the resolve it took.
Now I finally understand how
the Third Hokage must have felt.
You will go the same way
as the Third Hokage!
You…
Don't talk yet! Just a little longer.
You're the enemy,
I don't want to know how you feel.
So…stop crying in front of me…
With such a sad face!
The Sharingan is proof of
being an Uchiha.
A lowlife ninja who isn't an Uchiha…
Has no right showing off that eye!
Earth Style: Mud Wall!
For someone whose Sharingan is
borrowed, you're quite skilled in using it.
However, can your Sharingan do this?
I will show you…
That my Sharingan is in
a completely different class than yours!
This is…
So fast.
If I hadn't blown it away with the
Mangekyo, I'd be dead right now.
To think that someone who's not an
Uchiha could awaken the Mangekyo.
So it seems that eye's power
saved you.
You should be grateful to
the power of the Uchiha.
Sasuke…
You are more than just your clan.
More than just hatred.
Look deep inside your heart.
One more time.
Are you still going on about that?
Deep down, you know.
They're all laughing.
You're laughing at
the cost of Itachi's life!
Laughing together,
completely ignorant of everything!
Your laughing voices sound like
contempt and mocking to me now!
I will change those laughs
to screams and wails!
Damn it!
My sight!
What is she going to do?
Sakura! Why are you here?
Don't!
I won't let Kakashi Sensei
bear the burden!
Sakura…
Thank you.
I was sure…I was prepared.
Sakura!
Damn it!
This always happens right after
I use the Mangekyo!
Stop, Sasuke!
Your timing is better
than mine, Naruto.
I never imagined you coming here.
You're a lifesaver!
Th-Thank you, Naruto.
Sasuke…
Sakura is a fellow ninja
from Team 7.
"Was" a fellow ninja.
I no longer belong.
Now do you understand,
Naruto, Sakura?
His intent to kill is real.
Sasuke is no longer
the same person as before.
Sasuke…
What?
I heard the truth about Itachi
from a guy named Tobi.
The truth about Itachi?
I don't know for sure
if what he said is really true or not.
But it doesn't matter.
What you've been doing is…
Understandable.
Naruto...I told you before.
You don't have parents or siblings,
so you couldn't possibly understand me.
So outsiders can keep
their mouths shut!
Do you know what Naruto
has gone through for you?
No matter what rumors
we hear about you,
he never stops thinking
of you as a friend.
While everyone targeted you,
Naruto alone tried to rescue you!
Even now…
Rescue me? From what?
Well, from…
From revenge.
I swear I'll save you from
the chaos of vengeance.
There's no need for that.
The stage has already been set
for my vengeance to happen!
I killed a high-ranking elder
of the Hidden Leaf.
Someone named Danzo.
Sasuke killed Danzo all by himself?
I've never felt like this before.
I feel the tainted Uchiha name
becoming cleansed.
I feel the Uchiha getting free
from this rotting ninja world.
You guys couldn't begin
to understand.
And isn't what I'm doing exactly
what you Leaf ninja wanted all along?
You've always snubbed and
put down the Uchiha.
So I'll help erase the Uchiha
from your memories.
I'm going to kill all of you,
and destroy the Hidden Leaf!
Severing all bonds to the Hidden
Leaf is the ultimate purification!
And that shall lead to
the Uchiha's true restoration!
Sasuke…
Hatred. The history of repeated
accumulating hatred.
That is what created
the Sasuke in front of us.
Though they may not realize it,
Naruto and Sakura are
seeing with their own eyes
that Sasuke is a victim
of the times we live in.
And that is why…
This is my task.
But Kakashi Sensei…
If you stay, you'll see things
you do not want to see.
Now go!
I…
Sakura, the poison-laced kunai
Shizune taught you how to use
won't kill Sasuke.
Orochimaru gave him
resistance to poisons.
What's more...You've come to terms
with your feelings, right?
Sasuke...I healed you.
But your body cannot…
withstand another battle.
No...I don't care about
Sasuke anymore.
Kakashi Sensei,
this "something" I don't want to see…
Are you going to kill Sasuke?
Go! Both of you!
Now's my chance!
I'm not holding back!
Wait, Naruto!
There's a chance, Sasuke…
That our roles…
Could have been reversed.
– Chidori!
– Rasengan!
Sasuke...You remember, right?
The entire village used
to despise me.
It's because I have
the Nine-Tails inside me.
At one time, I hated the village too.
I even thought about revenge.
One step in the wrong direction
and I might have conjured up
some terrible plan just like you.
I almost gave in to despair.
But you and Iruka Sensei saved me.
I knew that you were always alone.
Watching you, I felt reassured
that I wasn't the only one.
We were both kids,
and looking back…
I had to live with the Nine-Tails
and you, the fate of the Uchiha.
It's ironic that
we had similar burdens.
To be honest,
every time I saw you,
I wanted to walk over
and start talking.
I'd get sort of giddy.
Because I felt like you
understood me.
But I stopped.
The reason is because
I was jealous because
you were good at everything.
So I made you my rival.
You've been…
My goal.
I had nothing,
but I built bonds with Team 7.
With you and Sakura.
I wanted to be strong
and cool like you.
That's why I kept chasing
after you.
I'm really glad I met you.
Naruto…
You can't change me,
no matter what you say to me now.
I'm going to kill
each and every person in the Leaf,
including you!
And I'll get revenge for
the Uchiha Clan!
Is that really the only way?
Yes.
So your only choices are
to kill me and
become the hero who
saved the village,
or to be killed by me and
become known as just a loser!
Sasuke…
I don't believe that.
I'm not going to be the loser,
or the hero who killed you!
Neither one's gonna happen!
I…
Whoa!
You!
When did you—?
I've been tagging along
for quite a while.
Tobi told me to make sure
you didn't notice me.
But, since you were in a crisis…
I should summon him soon.
It doesn't seem like
he's going to retreat quietly.
Naruto…
I told you to go back
to the village.
Now…
It's all clear.
I'd better collect the Rinnegan
before the war begins.
Sasuke's in a bind.
What do you want to do?
What's going on, Sasuke?
I told you to go home and rest.
Madara…
The Nine-Tails, huh?
It seems you cannot suppress the
urge to fight when you two get together.
I'll arrange a proper place
for you to hunt the Nine-Tails.
For now, we retreat.
I'll fight in your stead.
Since we need the Nine-Tails
Jinchuriki anyway.
Madara as well as Zetsu?
They're sticking close to Sasuke.
This is going to be tough
all by myself.
What should I do?
Zetsu...You can't capture Naruto.
The Nine-Tails will be too much
for a non-combat type like you.
I'm going to let Sasuke
get the Nine-Tails.
It's for my enjoyment as well.
Oh, is that so?
But I'm concerned about Kisame.
So go to him.
And rendezvous with Black Zetsu.
Okay, okay, I understand.
Naruto!
I'm all right.
But I need to make sure
I say something to Sasuke.
Let's go, Sasuke.
Wait.
Sasuke...Do you remember?
Do you remember what you said
to me long ago in the Final Valley?
The thing about high-level shinobi.
When two shinobi are
of a high enough level,
they can read each other's thoughts
through no more than
a trade of blows.
They don't need to say a word.
You're naïve, Naruto.
So tell me…
Were you able to read what
was inside of my heart?
Clashing face-to-face.
Just now, we learned things from
just trading blows with each other.
It means we've become
high-level shinobi.
You and me.
Sasuke…
Were you able to read…
What was inside of my heart?
And you saw it, didn't you?
That if you and I fight…
We will both die.
Sasuke…
If you attack the Hidden Leaf,
I will have to fight you.
Save your hatred until then.
At that time, throw all of
your hatred at me.
The only one who can
handle all that hatred…
Is me.
Only I can fulfill that duty!
And on that day,
I'll bear the burden of
your hate and die with you!
What is it with you, Naruto?
Just what the hell do you want?!
Why are you so fixated on me?!
Because you're my friend!
Sasuke…
I knew from the moment we first met
that it was going to take more
than just ordinary means
to understand you.
Exchanging fists is how
we understand each other.
That's for sure.
Like I said just now…
It means we've become
high-level shinobi.
Once we understand each other,
your hatred will go away.
The same way that I changed
after meeting Iruka Sensei.
I'm not giving up yet.
I'm taking you back
to Hidden Leaf Village!
That's something I'll never give up on!
Naruto…you…
Well, I've rambled on enough.
Damn it.
A poor talker like me lecturing you,
it's not my style.
If we both end up dying…
You won't be an Uchiha and
I won't be the Nine-Tail's Jinchuriki.
We'll be free of all our burdens.
And we'll finally be able to understand
each other in the next world!
I don't plan on changing.
Nor am I interested
in understanding you.
And I don't plan on dying!
You're the one who's going to die.
If I die, we both die, Sasuke.
Fine then! I'll kill you first.
It's clear you still haven't
acknowledged me yet.
Enough, Naruto.
I'll take Sasuke on.
You have your precious dream
of becoming the Hokage.
I can't let Sasuke take
you down with him.
How can I become the Hokage
if I can't even save one friend?!
I'll fight Sasuke!
All right, Naruto.
I'll leave Sasuke to you.
However, Sakura…
Watch over my body.
I'll get rid of Madara
once and for all.
Kamui!
Forget it, Kakashi.
A jutsu like that won't work on me.
Let's go, Sasuke.
Madara, I'll talk to you later.
I'll be ready anytime, Sasuke.
Naruto...Thank you, as always!
Because of you,
I can still hope for the day
that we'll laugh together again
as Team 7.
– What?!
– Wha—?!
Naruto!
A scratch on his cheek.
This must be the cause.
Then it's…
It's from the poison-dipped
kunai knife I used earlier.
Seems like it.
You need to administer
the antidote right away, Sakura!
What did you want
to talk to me about?
I want Itachi's eyes.
So you finally made up your mind.
You've overused the Susano'o.
I'm aware that you can barely see.
It's perfect timing.
Transplant them right away.
You're in a hurry.
What's going on?
I'm going use every ounce of
my strength to crush Naruto!
I'll eradicate him completely!
That's all.
I'm taking you to Hidden Leaf Village.
So please behave yourself.
I wouldn't try anything at this point.
I still feel sick.
A-Are you all right?
You're gonna throw up!
So that's…
Naruto Uzumaki, huh?
Are you ready?
Do it.
Brother…
I will crush the Hidden Leaf!