I-Is that...?!
That's the...!
There's no mistaking it.
Yeah…
That's…
The Ten-Tails!
But I thought the Statue's evil chakra
had disappeared!
Damn it! They got us!
That thing doesn't have
that kind of emotion of feeling!
It can't be sensed.
It's Natural Energy itself.
It's the same as that which
circulates around the world,
that you can feel in
the soil, water, and the air.
It would be a different story
if you tried it
while engaged in Sage Mode though.
Got it!
So if you say he's all Nature Energy,
then I can check him out!
Forget it, Naruto…
Even if you tried something like that…
All you'll see is just
how immeasurable it is.
You're not kidding.
I had planned to capture them
before the Ten-Tails revived, but...
They're pretty good.
I want to start the Infinite Tsukuyomi
ritual immediately.
That great genjutsu requires time
to summon the moon.
They will interfere with the jutsu.
Things will go more smoothly
if we use the Statue's power
to get rid of them first.
Don't you agree?
Madara…
You just want to test
the Ten-Tails' power, don't you?
You're like a child.
No.
Brats are impatient, touchy fools.
Hey...Here comes a big one.
You think we can really do this?
Don't think you can hide
under your tentacles
'cuz you're scared!
But first, hand me Guy over there.
I'll heal him later.
And that Naruto and Kakashi too!
Yeah!
Here you go!
Listen up.
First, we keep our distance
and see what move he makes!
Then we'll counter the attack
and hit him with a big blow
as close as we can get.
Just like I said earlier!
Nine-Tails,
you're acting like a captain.
Huh? You got a problem with that?!
Nope…
In fact, I feel kind of happy!
That line...
Save it for after we've won!
Let's go!
It's surprisingly fast…
There wasn't any time to
observe its moves!
Damn it!
Now! Eight-O!
Tailed Beast...
Bomb Barrage!
There's no need to dodge.
I want to preserve Ten-Tails' power
as much as possible.
This is…
…not good!
It's all on you now!
Persistent lot!
Hey, Naruto, don't tell me...
Don't worry Bushier Brow Sensei.
Nice control, Naruto!
You got them in nice and close!
We focused too much on Ten-Tails.
Sorry about the one leg.
But here we go!
Kamui!
I'm gonna smash this
into his eyeball!
Huh?!
There are two flies above us as well…
Kakashi!
Naruto, you really are
a lot like me.
That's right,
you're just younger than me.
Eventually…
Forgive me, Eight-O and Octopops!
Another Shadow Clone, huh?
Kurama!
How can you fall apart
at a time like this?!
That was about eight minutes.
It's longer than before,
but that's the limit.
I'm going to have to infuse
and build up my chakra.
Guess we have no choice.
That hurts, fool. Ya fool!
Bee!
I'm going to rest a bit too.
I'm also at my limit.
I can't get healed yet?
Pulling something as massive
as Eight-Tails in and out
sure comes with
a correspondingly large cost.
I'm drained already.
Seems Eight-Tails and Nine-Tails
have run out of chakra for now.
You favorite Shadow Clone Jutsu?
It may be forbidden high-level ninjutsu,
but just increasing
the number of losers won't--
I'm not a loser!
Stop, Naruto!
It's meaningless to
create Shadow Clones
that will divide your chakra
even more.
They might be useful as diversions,
but not for decisive hits.
And if you go down...
we lose this war.
You were always just
a motley crew anyway.
Huh?!
M-M-Motley crew?
Like I said, you're incompetent.
He's saying that it's pointless to
merely increase the number of heads...
if they're all empty.
You and I are both powerless shinobi.
You...
no, I should say everyone…
will eventually end up like me.
I'll never end up like you!
How many times
do I have to tell you?!
My dream is to become the Hokage!
Don't worry.
Everything will go as planned.
There is no shinobi jutsu mightier
than the Infinite Tsukuyomi.
I'll make you Hokage inside this jutsu.
So…
Just disappear along
with the rest of this world!
What the…?
Did it miss? On purpose?
About time!
Kakashi! Guy!
Sorry to keep you waiting!
I can't believe he shook off
my Byakugan-aided, spot-on Mind Transfer
in just two seconds!
But you still succeeded in shifting
that large thing's aim off target.
Good work!
Are you all right, Naruto?
Yeah!
You don't have to act tough
in front of Hinata, Naruto!
Beetle Jamming Jutsu!
Hidden Mist Jutsu!
We're here, Naruto!
All right, we won't be
so easily detectable now!
Lord Bee! You're in better shape
than I expected!
Lord Bee! You look seriously wounded!
Omoi, you worry too much!
Guy Sensei, don't tell me
you used Hirudora?!
Lee!
I'm sorry we're late, Captain Kakashi.
Sakura, first off...!
I know!
The Sensory Water Sphere won't
maintain its original shape...
Inoichi! Ao! Confirm the situation!
- Roger!
- Okay!
First Company has arrived!
Second Company has also arrived!
Third Company has arrived!
Fourth Company has arrived!
Fifth Company has also arrived!
The Medical Unit's here too!
Sensory Unit has arrived!
Nice try hiding, but...
Wind Style:
Art of the Gust Blade!
We're not a motley crew anymore!
Here is the Allied Shinobi Forces Jutsu!
The world's greatest, most invincible,
super-duper ninjutsu, you know!
A jutsu that trumps
the Infinite Tsukuyomi. Remember that!
The Allied Shinobi Forces Jutsu, eh?
Don't you think that's a bit of stretch?
We're going to stop you two
with this jutsu!
You're wrong.
Why won't you realize that
it's meaningless for you to stop us here?
After this war,
even that jutsu will disintegrate…
Then someone from your side
will attempt to do
exactly what we're doing now.
There is no victory,
no matter how much you struggle.
Get it through your head.
There's no such thing as hope
anywhere in this world.
This world…
- will end!
- Will not end!
Let's go, everyone!
This is the final deciding battle!
Scatter!
Thanks for buying us
some time, Naruto.
Did you have enough time
to come up with a strategy?
Thanks to you, I was able to
relay it to everyone!
Kakashi told us the masked man
is Obito Uchiha.
But there's no time to be shocked.
For this fight, we need to take
and maintain the upper hand
and not give them
any opportunity to counter!
According to the intel we received,
our enemy has impressive eyes.
First, we'll impede their movement
by destroying their vision.
The Hidden Cloud!
Lightning Style:
Flash Pillar!
Gale Style: Laser Circus!
I see…
Their true aim is to blind Ten-Tails!
With the two jutsu from earlier,
the Hidden Mist's Mist
and the Beetle Jamming...
Along with the large volume
of airborne dust
stirred up by the Gale Style right now...
The Hidden Sand, now!
Wind Style: Air Current Dance!
We'll not just destroy
their vision completely,
but thwart them from
even sensing us at all.
And since their sheer bulk
prevents them from hiding...
we'll be able to take
full advantage of the situation.
We only revealed our jutsu
to him a short while ago,
and he's already incorporating them
into the battle plan!
Leave it to Shikamaru's dad,
like father like son!
This makes it impossible to sense them.
We'll wipe them all out with
a Ten-Tails' attack!
The Hidden Stone,
proceed immediately!
We know!
Earth Style: Vast Mobile Core!
After shutting down their senses,
we'll immobilize them!
As soon as we bring down
the Ten-Tails, pour in quicklime!
- Lava Style: Quicklime Jutsu!
Hidden Mist! You're up next!
- Water Style: Water Bomb Jutsu!
We'll add water to the mix,
and rapidly stir up the quicklime!
Hidden Leaf! Let's finish this!
Sarutobi Clan members!
Let's go!
Fire Style: Majestic Flame Jutsu!
And we'll dry it with the heat
from the Fire Style…
Let it set and immobilize it!
Unbelievable.
Who would've thought,
that the ninja from the five villages
could work so cooperatively.
Unless we stop the Ten-Tails,
we don't have a chance
to go after Obito or Madara.
The Ten-Tails is merely a tool
for them to aid in activating their jutsu.
If we cut off the head from the body,
namely those two…
Infinite Tsukuyomi cannot
be activated!
But keep in mind that
we won't be able to suppress
the Ten-Tails' power for too long.
Only physical attacks work
on Madara.
So shinobi who are skilled
in taijutsu will go after Madara!
Obito can slip through
all moves and jutsu,
but according to our intel,
that only lasts for five minutes.
Coordinate with the Medical Unit and
keep attacking him
for more than five minutes!
Do not let up!
That's right, Naruto...
It's now time for your...
Allied Shinobi Forces Jutsu!
How pitiful.
Yeah.
This hope that they're clinging to
doesn't exist.
Just like their very lives,
at this point.
It seems Ten-Tails is ready.
Fifth Gate of Closing! Open!
So this time, they're coming
after us, not Ten-Tails...
Well...
Taking the enemy's brains
is a fundamental strategy...
For that to work...
they would need to
stop the Ten-Tails first!
What?! I thought we had immobilized
the Ten-Tails!
Are you okay?! Damn it...
My shoulder's dislocated...
Look at the Sensing Water Sphere...
It's practically like a small planet.
But that's...impossible!
So we didn't immobilize
Ten-Tails, after all?
It merely stopped moving on its own
in order to amass power
and undergo transformation?
How are we going to be able to stop it?
And now we can't target those two either!
Even with the jutsu of my clan
who specialize in immobilizing...
the effect would be miniscule compared
to the amount of chakra expended.
Inoichi!
Link me to Kakashi!
Roger!
Kakashi, it's me!
There's something
I want to confirm
regarding the intel from
the last battle sequence...
It's going to start getting more difficult
to control Ten-Tails soon...
Reinforce your bond with it
using Hashirama's cells.
Don't you want to check out
Ten-Tails' power in its current state?
First, let's...
Yes, let's show them...
...despair!
Shikaku, I'm going to
let you go for now!
What's the matter?!
This is...
No way!
Lord Shikaku! Lord Inoichi!
My Kamui won't make it in time!
Displace it upwards using
an Earth Style technique.
Right!
That far away?
It's so much greater than
all the previous Tailed Beasts!
What power!
It's wobbly from just
that little counter...
Its control isn't perfect yet.
Next!
Unbelievable! Such a far-off city
destroyed in an instant!
It's been acting strange for a while,
it seems to be aiming far away!
So all the cities,
and people are within its range of fire?
Then that means
the evacuated Feudal Lords,
everyone protecting the villages...
plus all the citizens of
each nation aren't safe?
That's the direction of--!
Please listen to me calmly.
Here, eh?
Well, Shikaku...What do we do?
Just keep doing what we must do.
It will be our last act.
Put me through to
everyone on the battlefield.
I have a plan to stop the Ten-Tails!
Finally got them.
We've now smashed
the brains of the Allied Forces.
Like I said before,
it's fundamental strategy.
Shikamaru...
We're in the middle of a war.
Don't waste any words on me.
Or on Ino.
Like Dad said, we just have
to do what we have to do.
Wait...What exactly just happened?!
You are the key to our plan.
Not about that!
I'm asking what happened to
Shikaku and Inoichi?!
Neji! Rotate clockwise!
Got it!
- Eight Trigrams Palm Rotation!
A-Amazing...
Don't just stand there
spacing out, Naruto!
This is a battlefield
and we're in a war.
People will die!
But if we are defeated
and lose this war...
everyone will die!
Of course I know that!
Shikamaru and Ino's father
would likely say, that as shinobi,
they're glad to have died
before their children.
Just as my father did.
Naruto, your power is critical
to the plan.
So until we execute it...
We must protect you, Naruto!
Know this!
The Hyuga are the mightiest
among the Hidden Leaf!
There he goes...
I was hoping to take them down
before they started
with the speeches, but...
It's hard to control Ten-Tails well.
This ought to do until
the next transformation, but...
Afterwards...
I suspect only a Jinchuriki will
be able to control it.
Though for me to become
the Ten-Tails' Jinchuriki...
I'll need to be fully alive,
not hosted within a corpse
as a Reanimation.
They will know despair...thoroughly.
Wood Style:
Cutting Sprigs!
There's so many of them!
Just try to evade them.
My Mountain Jutsu should
at least slow it down
until Nine-Tails' strength returns.
Except I need some time
to build up enough chakra!
Hold on, everybody!
Cha!
So many!
My Rotation can't keep up!
Thanks, Neji!
I can activate Sage Mode now!
I can't keep relying on you geniuses!
Now it's my turn!
Rasen Shuriken!
Here's a few more!
Eight Trigrams: Air Wall Palm!
Damn it! A focused attack!
There's too many!
Hinata and Neji's Air Palms
won't be sufficient...
Earth Style: Mountain Jutsu!
Medical Team!
Where are you?!
There's a critical injury here!
Hurry!
I'm no longer...
Naruto...
Lady Hinata...
is willing to die for you.
So...you hold more...
than one...life in your hands...
And it seems...that my life too...
may have been...
one of them...
Why? Why did you do this here?
You were going to change
the Hyuga!
Long ago, those words of yours,
freed me from the shackles of fate.
Father...
I finally understand...
the freedom you felt...
choosing to die in order
to protect your comrades.
Didn't you say you wouldn't
let your friends die...?
Naruto!
Those words...
"I'll never let my comrades die."
Now look around you...
and say it again!
As the bodies of your comrades
grow cold in your arms...
take in their deaths!
Neji's...dead?!
Hizashi, forgive me...
I let Neji--!
This will continue...
And your flippant words and
ideology shall become lies.
This is the end result of
hope and ideals.
This is reality!
Naruto...
What is there for you in this reality?
Your mother and father are gone,
as well as your master, Jiraiya.
And if you keep standing against us,
you'll continue to lose
your friends one by one.
This shall become a world
where no one who
acknowledges you will exist.
Obito...
The only thing that awaits you...
is your worst nightmare,
which you know quite well!
Solitude!
You've become exactly
like the old me, Obito.
Naruto will give up shortly...
Which will break the will
of the Allied Forces.
Why must you cling to reality?
Enough of this...
Now come join us, Naruto!
Brother Neji just said,
that you hold more than
one life in your hands.
Do you know what he meant?
"I'll never let my comrades die."
Neither those words nor
the conviction behind them are lies!
Because he was able to successfully
store them in his heart,
and live them out to until the end!
Brother Neji did!
It's not just you, Naruto...
We all hold those words
and feelings in our hearts.
They're what bind our lives together...
and make us comrades.
If we all give up and
discard those words and feelings,
Neji's final act will have been
for nothing.
And that is when...
your comrades truly die!
For you are then
no longer comrades.
That's...how I feel.
So, stand with me, Naruto.
Because never going back
on one's word...
is my ninja way too!
Naruto...
Lady Hinata...
is willing to die for you.
So...you hold more...
...than one life!
Don't forget about me!
I know.
I take my bonds seriously!
I'd never abandon my comrades!
But in reality, Neji is...
Stop your rambling!
I'll beat you up and take over
your body for good this time!
And did you also forget?
Your mother and father did
the same thing Neji did
just after you were born.
They sealed me,
their archenemy inside you,
and entrusted the future
to you and died.
Your life was already linked to
two others from the time you were born!
Will he just stand back and
see how Naruto responds...?
It seems Naruto makes him uneasy.
Enough!
Don't be hasty!
You're going to harm yourself
as well as Ten-Tails!
I don't care!
Ten-Tails hide is tough!
They're going to hit us!
Recharging completed!
Be careful, Lord Bee!
Go get 'em!
Take this!
Lord Bee!
Don't go overboard!
There's no need to worry...
Protecting the Alliance is my territory!
That's right.
It wasn't just Mom and Dad.
Yeah...
It hasn't just been my life...
up until now.
Thanks, Hinata!
It's all thanks to you
standing by my side.
And Neji...
Thank you.
Naruto's hand is so big...
and strong, but most of all...
Let's do this, Hinata!
Yeah!
It's comforting!
That's Nine-Tails'—
I mean, Naruto's chakra!
Nice work transforming and
transferring my chakra, Naruto!
I've gotten the hang of it.
Work with me, Kurama!
That shinobi Nara,
he sure analyzed my chakra
exchange capabilities extensively.
We've kept them waiting a while.
A few shadow clones should be okay.
Got it!
A-Amazing...Naruto is able
to use this chakra...
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
You're late, Naruto!
Sorry!
Choji! Ino!
O-Okay!
What...is this?
Are these calories?
Hey! Choji!
You're gaining weight again!
That brat Naruto...Is he giving
them the Nine-Tails' chakra?
8 Trigrams Air Palm!
I feel...my power surging!
She did that with just an Air Palm?!
That girl...
She's gotten quite strong after
getting power from Naruto...
Expansion Jutsu!
Shikamaru! Ino!
Are you ready?!
- Yeah!
- Okay!
Don't mock me!
What?!
- Shadow Possession...
- Mind Transfer...
- Jutsu!
I'm in!
Tsk...They did it again!
Damn you!
They just keep on coming...
Now it's the Nara's Paralysis jutsu...
- Don't mess with the Nara Clan!
All right! We stopped him
in his tracks!
You can stop now, Ino!
Are you all right?!
Y-Yeah...
Neji!
Lee, stop crying!
Lee...
So long as we don't abandon
Neji's convictions,
he will continue to live on,
connected inside all of us.
Let me share a little something
with you.
It's those connections that
made me what I am today!
You ought to know that bonds
can be powerful curses too!
Naruto...
I was the one who once told you,
"I will never let my comrades die..."
Those words are also
an admonition aimed at myself.
I haven't been able to save
many comrades.
Which is why I keep telling
myself this time, I will protect them.
But then, I end up having to face
the fact that I couldn't once more.
I'll be confronting those wounds...
for the rest of my life.
But that's why we're ninja.
We are those who endure.
They'll never let you forget.
But it's those wounds that prove
your comrades live on inside here.
Your friends are still alive
in here...
Friends that you create
inside a dream,
so you can't get hurt,
aren't real.
That means you're just erasing
your real friends!
Curse or not, I want to keep
the real Neji right here.
The real Neji...right here...
Gentle Fist!
It's no use, Lee.
No matter how hard you try,
you'll never defeat me.
That's just how things are.
Look for a different rival.
So you saw me lose.
Hey, Lee, I used to think that
you couldn't change the fate
that was handed to you...
One day, I'll fight you for real,
so we can see which is greater,
your Ferocious Fist
or my Gentle Fist.
But...I shall not lose so long
as my eyes are black.
In your case, Neji, isn't it
the white of your eyes?
Oh...Yeah...But anyway...
You have me as your rival.
It's a lot stronger than before,
and more of it than last time.
There's something I want to confirm
regarding the intel from
the last battle sequence...
Kakashi, you said that
the reason why
you were able to travel
through space time using Kamui,
plus pull Eight-Tails
in and out almost whole,
was thanks to receiving
Nine-Tails' chakra from Naruto, right?
Yes...
To be more precise,
I received that chakra
directly from Nine-Tails...
In reference to your choice
of words, "Thanks to..."
How different was it
compared to using Kamui
without Nine-Tails' chakra?
Explain it to me in simple terms.
I would say more than
three times the power.
I couldn't really hurl things
that were very large
or do it very often before that.
Almost done?
Humph...Looks like things
have gone your way, Fourth Hokage!
Until now, the only one who was
able to link their chakra to mine
was Naruto because
he possesses Kushina's
and because he has been
my Jinchuriki for many years...
And Naruto has matured
to the point
where he's skillful enough to sense
and transmute my chakra
to be compatible with other shinobi
and then hand it over to them.
Though I can also help
or use Naruto
as an intermediary
to give my chakra to anyone...
The same exact way
you handed over
and inserted your own chakra
into Naruto, Minato.
He's already...
Surpassed you both
a while ago now.
The amount of chakra
he's linking and delivering
is on a completely
different scale!
Kushina, Minato...
You're pathetic!
You both pale in comparison
to your brat Naruto!
But this is probably...
the power you wanted
to give to Naruto.
Heh...I should probably lend
a little more power too.
Damn it!
He's pushing me back hard!
Naruto, now's your chance!
Do it now!
Tailed Beast Bomb!
Beam of Light.
- Eight Trigrams: Wall of Air Palm!
- Wind Style: Giant Casting Net!
I won't let Neji's death
be in vain!
A curse mark that doesn't
go away until you die...
A shinobi curse that Hyuga's main
and branch families gave rise to...
An existence where one can
only await one's death inside a cage.
It's a nice analogy for
our current situation.
You're all exactly like that brat
who just died a pointless death.
Neji...
Neji's will...
isn't...
dead yet!
I'll take the right!
Gotcha!
Damn it! My shoulder's dislocated again!
Gentle Fist!
Go, Lee!
All right!
Unlike you guys, I don't want...
to sever any of my bonds...
or get them cut off!
We shouldn't have cut them.
Fire Style: Majestic Flower Flame!
Fire Style: Bomb Blast Dance!
We're safe!
If we didn't have
Naruto's Chakra Cloak,
we'd be crisper than a roast pig!
The next round is coming!
Naruto's chakra has been protecting
everyone this whole time.
Naruto, are you sure
you're okay to keep this going?
Naruto, you're only fighting
defensively now,
trying to protect everyone.
Is there any meaning to all of this?
Are you all right, Naruto?
It's too much for you to control
the chakra that I gave you, all at once.
You'll wear yourself out
in no time.
Also, it looks like Ten-Tails
is charging chakra,
so you'd better watch out!
You're only growing weaker.
I don't think you'd understand,
since you want to be alone...
But having everyone by my side
makes me really, really happy!
That alone gives me strength!
Did he run away?
If the pain of your comrades' deaths
is part of your bond...
then there's no need
to protect them, right?
What the hell,
you quibbling bastard?!
That's what I hate about you!
That's not what I‘m talking
about you, quibbling idiot!
I'm saying I can endure any pain
if it involves my comrades.
It means I don't want
to give them up!
It might seem selfish of me...
But it's more painful for me to not
have any comrades in here!
There's no mistake!
This chakra is...
Hashirama!
Dad! It's collapsing!
I can't hold it back any longer!
Damn it, it's repelling
this Mountain Jutsu
enhanced with Naruto's chakra!
There's no other jutsu
that can stop it, Dad!
Bad news, Naruto!
The Ten-Tails is planning to
do the Cataclysm!
It can't be controlled anymore,
because you cut the link
between Ten-Tails and me.
Although I guess it's about time
I became its Jinchuriki.
The real fun...
is just beginning!
This time, I'll make
the Ten-Tails disappear!
Kamui!
Looks like you were waiting
for your chance.
But so was I, Kakashi.
Naruto, you take care
of things here!
Kakashi Sensei!
Here it comes! The Cataclysm!
That should have cleaned
most of them out.
Naruto protected us again.
Naruto...
Is that all you've got?
It's disappearing!
Nice try pretending to be tough, but
it seems you've reached your limit.
You've given me something
to look forward to...
but I think it's time
you made your exit.
Everyone! Let's join together
and fight as one!
- Right!
Hinata!
Time for you to recover!
You guys...
Such a futile demonstration.
Lightning Blade!
So there's still doubt
in your heart.
You've had several chances to
kill me if you really wanted to.
One more blow!
It's pathetic that
you feel compassion
towards an enemy
in the midst of fighting.
Is it guilt?
Are you feeling remorse
over the fact that
you couldn't protect Rin and
keep your promise to me?
Are you hoping that
I'll have a change of heart?
Obito...Let's stop this already!
Your dream long ago was
to become the Hokage...
Naruto has the same dream.
Naruto's words are exactly
what you used to say in the past.
You haven't realized it...
But you've been trying to merge
your past self with the current Naruto...
Hearing the old you
in Naruto's words.
Is it because you secretly want
to be repudiated by your old self?
I can't see you not understanding
Naruto's feelings!
You can still go back...
to the person you once were!
It's because I understand
Naruto's mind...
That I want to hear it all...
And negate everything
that he does!
Obito...
By the way, let me tell you
one more thing.
This guilt you feel towards me
is really presumptuous.
If you believe that I started
this war simply over you and Rin...
To call you misdirected,
would be an understatement!
I know everything.
I know that Rin deliberately ran
into your Lightning Blade.
That she chose to die.
Back then, Rin had been kidnapped
by the Hidden Mist
and forced to become
the Three Tails' Jinchuriki.
You succeeded in rescuing Rin
and got her out...
But that was part of
the Hidden Mist's plan.
They even pretended
to pursue you
to get you home
to the Leaf quicker.
Once Rin made it back
to the Leaf,
the Hidden Mist intended to make
the Three Tails rampage
and attack the village.
Rin realized this...
And took advantage of the Lightning Blade
you aimed at the enemy...
to commit suicide.
She made up her mind to die
at the hands of the one she loved.
In order to protect
the Hidden Leaf.
No matter what you say,
to me, you're still an impostor
who couldn't protect Rin.
To me, Rin is someone
who wasn't supposed to die.
So Rin dead is also an impostor.
Rin is Rin because she is alive!
The things that created
all these circumstances...
The system of shinobi, village,
and the shinobi themselves...
What caused me to despair,
is this world itself.
This counterfeit world!
Remember Naruto's words?
That it's most painful
not to have real comrades
inside one's heart?
I quoted exactly what
you said long ago to him...
I know the old you would have
resonated with that.
And I still believe
the current you, can as well-!
Look!
There's nothing in my heart!
I don't even feel pain anymore.
Don't feel so guilty, Kakashi.
This hole was opened
by this hellish world.
In the past,
all I felt was pain here.
What's the meaning in that?
So I abandoned everything.
You've been suffering all this time,
haven't you?
As you stood at Rin's grave...
and at my grave.
Kakashi...
Enough already.
You don't have to
suffer anymore.
Rin is here.
I love you, Kakashi.
Along with your ideal version of me.
I'm gonna be Hokage!
You can wish for
whatever you want...
You can have anything you
desire in this genjutsu World.
The hole in your heart
can be filled immediately.
Rin is gone.
You are still alive!
Do you really think
that something like this
can fill that hole in your heart?
Don't erase the memories
of the real Rin!
Rin sacrificed herself to protect
and save the village!
You can try and fill that hole
with delusions all by yourself...
But that hole will never be filled!
What's your issue with
a genjutsu World?
Reality is cruel.
This hole is only going to get bigger.
Things don't always
go the way want them.
Nor does help always
get there in time.
Just like how it was with me!
Just like how I couldn't
get there in time!
Wouldn't you agree, Kakashi?
How are you going to seal
this hole by staying in this world?!
It's transforming again!
No, it's only reverting
to its original form.
That was only its attack form.
However...
It's just one stage away
from its final transformation.
Naruto's still recovering,
and Nine-Tails is
infusing chakra right now.
Right now, it's up to us, Bee!
Right. We'll show everyone the way!
Listen to me, Bee...
If we let it undergo
its final transformation, we've lost.
We must stop it now!
Ten-Tails isn't holding back...
It probably got impatient
after seeing the same Tailed Beasts
inside Naruto!
It's getting bigger and bigger.
I-Is it after Naruto?
Honestly, how're we going
to stop that thing
without Naruto's chakra?
We can't waver after
coming this far!
Naruto is putting everything
into doing what has to be done.
Yeah. He's been going
out of his way
even to protect shinobi like us...
That's not what
I was talking about!
He's told us that
he considers all of us his comrades
from the bottom of his heart.
I'll fully heal Naruto!
We have to do
what we have to do!
If we're going to die anyway,
we might as well go down...
fighting to the best of our abilities!
Ino!
I want you to link me
with someone!
You've got a plan, haven't you?
I knew you would
come through, Shikamaru!
Isn't there anything
we can do, Dad?
I don't have enough chakra.
Kitsuchi! Please hear me out!
You're Shikaku's child...
Teach me the signs to
an easy Earth Style Barrier
that even non-Stone ninja
can perform!
One that anyone could perform
would be too weak!
It would be better to...
No, it's crucial that
everyone be able to produce it.
If the enemy has quality,
we've got quantity.
But these walls will
be blown away quickly.
Even if they are
if we keep creating more,
they'll act like a shield.
We're going to slow
that thing's momentum
with many weak walls rather than
try to stop it with one powerful one!
Of course, I intend to have
all of you from the Hidden Stone
build me a super wall as well...
I see...Your idea might be
worth a try.
All right,
these are the hand signs!
Before we start...
Master Bee!
While everyone is
building barriers,
I want you to bombard that thing
with Tailed Beast Bombs
to shift its trajectory upwards.
Ino...
Next, I want you to link me
with every shinobi here
on the battlefield.
Can you do it?
Doesn't matter, I will do it!
I may be trash as a shinobi,
but I've learned a few things.
The hole in one's heart gets filled
by others around you.
Friends won't flock to
someone who abandons
the memory of his friends
and gives up on the world...
Just because things don't go
the way he wants them to.
That won't help fill
the hole in your heart.
And people don't help those
who run away and do nothing.
As long as you don't give up,
there will always be salvation.
No matter what you do...
It's over.
- Earth Style Barrier!
Here it comes, Bee!
Let's go!
Its power is off the charts!
It's more powerful than I thought.
At this rate...
The last barrier...!
Lord Bee!
All your tedious whitewashing!
One can only achieve true happiness
by abandoning reality
and ridding yourself of
the memories of your comrades!
In the ninja world, those who
break the rules are scum.
But...those who abandon
their friends are worse than scum.
And...those who don't care
about their friends' feelings...
are even worse scum!
I won't abandon my memory
of the old you.
Even if it's the current you
who's repudiating it.
Am I late?
Nope.
Right on time, Dad!
Who...?
My name's Minato Namikaze.
Brace for an impending explosion.
What is that?
What?
I sent Ten-Tails' attack
back toward the sea.
- What's that?!
- Is it an attack?!
Watch out!
What the hell's going on?!
What just happened?!
That shock wave came
out of nowhere!
What's with that?!
Stop complaining!
We're lucky that
we got off that easily!
He has Reanimation eyes!
Relax. I'm an ally.
Thanks for healing Naruto!
Are you...
Naruto's girlfriend?
Huh?
Hmm...
Uh-huh...Yeah!
I suppose you could say that.
You keep quiet!
Don't waste your energy talking!
You're supposed to be healing me,
but I just suffered more damage...
I'll heal the extra damage too!
She reminds me a little of Kushina...
Please go easy on my son.
So, why did this happen so suddenly?
It seems like you knew.
I sensed his chakra when
I was in Nine-Tails Mode.
The others should be arriving soon...
Something's coming!
Minato, you're as fast as ever!
Lord Third Hokage?!
And also...
That's the...!
Fourth...
You're better
at teleporting than I am!
All right, let's do this!
No way!
I don't believe it...
I've been waiting for you, Hashirama!
I'll deal with you later!
I have to stop
the Ten-Tails first!
He hasn't changed a bit.
We're never on the same page.
After all...
It's charging towards us...
My fellow Hokage, let's go!
Second and Third,
stand in front of me.
That's exactly like Naruto's...
I never imagined
Minato would too!
See! You see!
Isn't my dad awesome?!
I know that better than you!
After all, he's the one who
split me up before sealing me away!
Have you already placed
your markers?
Yes.
You're quick at striking too!
He vanished!
Let's go!
Ninja Art:
- Four Crimson Ray Formation!
And...I'll just add on...
Sage Art: Gracious Deity Gates!
Ten Seals!
A red barrier?!
It's said to be dozens of times
more powerful
than the Four Purple
Flames Formation!
It's a barrier that requires
four Hokage-class shinobi
together to create!
It won't be able to move
so easily now.
You sure took your time
getting here, Sasuke.
Sasu...ke?
Is that you, Sakura?
S-Sasuke! Why?!
S-Sasuke!
Hey, Ino! Stop!
He's an enemy!
Ino...You better keep your distance!
You're all still as noisy as ever!
Why the hell are you here, bastard?!
Why are you here, Sasuke?
A lot of things have happened.
I've decided to protect Leaf Village.
And then, I'll...
become Hokage.
What?!
You can't just come back
all of a sudden
and crack a lame joke like that,
you rogue ninja!
Do you even know
what it means to be Hokage?
I don't know what happened to you,
but that's not possible.
Do you even realize
what you're saying?
Do you think we can just forget
all the things you've done?
Yeah, I realize you probably can't.
But...
it doesn't matter
what you guys think of me.
All of the previous Kage created
these current circumstances.
So I will become Hokage
and change the village.
You don't become Hokage
in order to be acknowledged
by the village.
The one who is acknowledged
by everyone,
is the one who becomes Hokage.
I leave Sasuke to you.
Leave it to me.
I'm going to be Hokage!
I'm glad there's so much interest
in becoming Hokage...
But you guys are
taking too much time!
Start infusing chakra right now!
We'll take down Ten-Tails
with an all-out attack!
Thanks for healing me, Sakura!
Now it's your turn to get some rest.
Let's go, Sasuke!
Sakura?
So do you see me as
some sort of weak woman
who can't keep up with you two?
Do you think Lady Tsunade
would be the only one
out of the Legendary Sannin
to inadequately train her student?
I'm almost there...
I'll be at full capacity in a little bit.
Then I can output my true power.
Just like you,
I'm a member of Team 7...
and I'm a student of
one of the Legendary Sannin!
Okay then!
Team 7 is finally back!
Let's go, Sakura! Sasuke!
Right!
Yeah!
That sight sure brings
back memories, doesn't it, Shikamaru?
Well, if he's willing to
help us defeat the enemy,
I won't turn him away.
Even tho' I don't want to accept him...
It's been a long time since
our class has been back together.
I haven't felt like this
since the Chunin Exam.
I'm going to become Hokage!
Hey, are you guys even listening?!
Kiba, no one's paying attention
right now...and it's pitiful.
Stop it.
It's because the impact of
Sasuke's sudden appearance
and his declaration to
become Hokage are much too great.
Kiba, I heard you!
We should all aspire
to become Hokage!
Let's show them
what we're made of, ya know!
Wait a minute!
Huh?!
It's that thing again!
It wants to break the barrier!
Fellow previous Hokage!
Please re-focus and
prepare yourselves!
We know that!
Now then...
It held up!
What an amazing barrier…
To be able to keep that thing out…
Where's the Ten-Tails?!
That Ten-Tails, he hit himself!
It's not some simple barrier!
Wow…
The previous Hokage were
truly amazing people!
Looks like they weren't just all talk.
Wood Style: Wood Clone Jutsu!
I'll make entry points
on all four sides of the barrier,
so shinobi can go in and out!
Follow me!
All right! Go!
Right!
It's not over yet!
Sage Arts: Gracious Deity Gates!
Head Seal!
Now then, time to deal with you.
Sorry to keep you waiting, Madara…
No...
A clone is no fun.
I'll wait for the real one
to show up.
Now!
Fission Beings?
It's trying to keep us away
from its real body!
Please take me on as your apprentice!
First and foremost,
you are my disciple.
A kunoichi who will inherit
the power of the Legendary Sannin.
And…Sakura Haruno…
You are also the disciple
of the Fifth Hokage!
And...
I just now reached full capacity.
And I can finally unleash it!
Cha!
What monster strength!
It might just be greater than Tsuna's!
Amassing chakra at a continuous rate
over three years…
requiring extremely
delicate chakra control.
The 100 Healings Mark
that I couldn't even achieve.
And I have no need to keep up
a youthful appearance!
Wind Style…
Inferno Style…
- Rasen Shuriken!
- Flame Control!
Sasuke!
Um…
I'm here too…Sakura!
Don't drag us down, Naruto.
He's right! Keep complaining and
I'll just grab the title
of Hokage away from you!
Huh?
Not you too, Sakura?!
This time, we fight with
our backs to each other!
So this is how Nine-Tails
chakra looks under control...
A new Sharingan…
with black flames…
That Naruto…
He's even mastered changing
the Rasengan's nature...
Hey, Team 8! Let's go too!
We can't let Team 7 show us up!
Right!
I've worked out
a new jutsu too, Naruto!
Don't think you're the only one
with this jutsu!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Did you just say Shadow Clone Jutsu?
All you did was make one clone!
Back in the day,
I could make a lot more...
Just watch!
There may be just one,
but he's three times stronger!
Come on, Akamaru!
We're gonna attack the enemy!
Inuzuka Style:
Man-Beast Team
Transformation Combo!
Three-Headed Wolf!
Sasuke's joke was disgusting.
But it's revving me up!
Tail Chasing…
Rotating Fang!
Parasitic Gigantic Beetle...
Infestation!
Gross! What are those?!
Parasitic Gigantic Beetles…
If you mistake the amount
of chakra to give them,
they'll devour your flesh
and undergo rapid growth.
They are beetles
that are difficult to nurture.
Two Palms! Four Palms! Eight Palms!
Sixteen Palms!
Thirty-Two Palms!
I guess this is still my limit...
No such thing.
But I'm not like you, Neji…
If you set limits on yourself,
you'll never be able
to catch up to him…
Overcome your limits,
fearlessly take a giant leap forward.
That's the…
Sixty-Four Palms!
...trick to achieve the Sixty-Four Palms.
Naruto is always striving
to get ahead.
And I…
...want to keep standing
by Naruto forever!
This time, I'll proceed to
Eight Trigrams
Sixty-Four Palms like this!
So I'll continuously
move forward as well!
Come on, Team 10!
Let's attack with
the Ino-Shika-Cho Combination!
Formation E!
This isn't the Chunin Exam.
We're not competing against
the other teams.
This is war…
But we want to show them
what we're made of, right?
Expansion Jutsu!
Shadow Grasping Jutsu!
Twenty-five enemy signatures
picked up and locked on!
Sensory Relay!
Human Boulder Yo-Yo!
I'm going to expand even more.
Can you handle more weight?
Yeah...You're still light.
And besides, this isn't quite flashy
enough to impress.
What? Who's being
super competitive now?
Actually, I'm technically on
Team 7 too, you know...
I'll quickly attack
the main body from the air!
Sai!
Are you all right?!
Yes…
It's no good!
The enemy keeps
increasing in numbers.
Not only that…
Some are huge!
These big ones...sure are heavy!
Naruto…
Can you share your chakra
with everyone again?
I can't right now!
Kurama hasn't finished
amassing chakra yet!
In order to take down
the main body,
we need to mow down
the big ones and slip past them.
The distance is too great to
make a single leap for it.
We also need time to weave signs
and repel the enemy's attacks.
Without your chakra, Naruto,
it's very likely
we'll suffer heavy casualties.
And the Medical Corps
can't come up to the front.
Mow down and slip past?
Easy.
This guy has the power to
clear the distance in a single leap
and repel enemy attacks.
I can now stay nearby and
heal anyone who suffers
serious injuries at all times.
- Summoning Jutsu!
Huh?
Wait…
This color…
You're…
Gamakichi!
Pop was tied up with
some negotiations,
so I came in his place.
You surprised?!
No! No!
But man, you sure got big
all of a sudden!
I'm more shocked than
I was about Akamaru!
You humans grow too slow, that's all.
Anyway, what's up?
Right!
See the gigantic guy way
in the back?
Could you get me closer to it
with a big leap?
You mean the biggest one
over there?
Yeah.
Lord Sasuke, your desire?
I need you to just keep
advancing forward.
I'll get the real body in the back!
Sakura dear!
You've finally able to invoke
the 100 Healings Mark!
Lady Tsunade would be so proud…
Lady Katsuyu, we don't have time…
Please divide and attend to each person
in the Allied Shinobi Forces.
Our role will be to heal everyone.
I never expected
to see the Three-Way Deadlock
Summoning again!
Go!
Go! Aoda!
Lady Katsuyu, please proceed!
Jump, Gamakichi!
This is the original Team 7…
Nice, Gamakichi!
Your size isn't just for show, eh!
Nevermind that, just hurry up
and weave your jutsu signs!
Get with it,
or I'll shake you off my head.
Even his attitude has gotten bigger!
I know!
What's going on?
It's all right.
These slugs are part
of the Fifth Hokage's Healing Jutsu.
Please do not worry.
My strength is being restored!
My wounds are…
It's healing me…
Her 100 Healings Mark was
only just activated!
And yet she can already perform
Lady Katsuyu's long-distance healing!
Sakura...You are simply amazing!
Lord Sasuke?
Keep moving forward.
Sasuke!
Wind Style: Massive Rasen Shuriken!
Inferno Style: Susano'o Flame Control!
Sasuke and I must've been
compatible, after all…
Yes…
Only "Wind" can beat "Lightning."
No…
That's not what I meant.
Only "Wind" can assist
and magnify "Fire"…
It's hit!
It really hit!
I don't recall ever seeing
a Flame Control of that magnitude.
And they combined jutsu
with matching chakra ratios!
That's difficult even for
a seasoned duo!
A windmill-like shuriken,
and an arrow blacker than lacquer…
Let's name it
the Scorch Style Nimbus Gale
Jet Black Arrow Formation Zero!
Nah, never mind.
Burn away…
You heard what
Sasuke said earlier, didn't you?
What are his true intentions?
I have no idea.
Look at the sorry state
you're in, Tsunade.
Gross...A gigantic slug…
How much salt would
you need to take it down?
That's just one part of Katsuyu
that was summoned from
Shikkotsu Woods.
I'd say it's pretty small, actually.
You don't say.
I thought we were here
for the Five Kage, not the slugs.
Lord Orochimaru,
stop paying attention to Suigetsu
and get to the task at hand.
Are you that upset because
you couldn't stay with Sasuke?
That's totally…not the case!
Let's just do this.
Damn you, Suigetsu!
Why are you picking on me?
Doesn't everyone who sees
a slug want to sprinkle salt on it?
Tsunade first!
Let's go.
Lady Tsunade!
Wait, was the Hokage
always a granny?
Ugh…
It's not like she had a really
long torso either, right?
It seems you were reckless, Tsunade.
Orochimaru?
Katsuyu…
I came here to aid the Five Kage.
I'm not an enemy.
I have no reason to believe you.
Besides, you were dead!
If I do anything that
strikes you as suspect,
you're welcome to kill me
once and for all with your acid.
All right.
I'll believe you.
You're quite sensible, unlike Manda.
Now then…
First of all…
Where are the other Kage?
They're recovering inside
my fragments.
They sustained serious injuries,
and it's very…
But Katsuyu…
With you here, why is it taking
so long for them to heal?
I can only use my power
in response
to the strength of
Lady Tsunade's 100 Healings.
But Lady Tsunade is
extremely weak right now,
so I'm not able to activate
my strength fully.
Is that how the system worked?
Anyway, whatever I remember,
I've never seen Tsunade so weak.
So it must be true.
I am trying to persevere
and focus on healing,
despite the Summoning
starting to unravel.
That's why I haven't been able
to properly reattach her body.
Suigetsu, bring Tsunade's lower half
and join it to her upper half.
Huh?!
I'm better at cutting things up.
Ugh…
The slugs are all slimy
and wriggly. Gross!
Well, so are you, Suigetsu!
In fact, you're grosser and weirder
because you have a human form!
Karin…
Let her bite you
so that she can heal.
What? I don't want anyone
but Sasuke biting me…
Hah! You just admitted
you're in love with Sasuke!
Huh?
You're wrong!
How could I hate,
I mean, like that damn Sasuke?
What are you saying?
He tried to kill me…
And it was irresistible…
No, it wasn't!
You were covered in bite marks
long before Sasuke bit you!
Shut up!
Right now, I'm exclusively for Sasuke.
Don't be so defiant,
you denture mold model.
Besides, how does
your body work anyway?
You're the weird one.
What? Say that again!
You two…
Make it snappy.
You're both weird.
So stop fighting.
Or else…
I'll have my snakes ties you up
and crawl into your mouth
and possess you.
You're the weirdest one
among us all!
She's taking so much,
I might end up aging into a hag.
Lady Tsunade,
you're going to be all right!
Tsunade, be a little grateful to me.
You betrayed the village…
So why all of this now?
The range of things that
interest me has expanded.
In the past, I wanted to become
the wind and turn the windmill myself.
But now, I know the pleasure
of waiting around for
someone else's wind.
One that is unpredictable.
And I don't want that wind to
get sealed away before I can enjoy it.
You still don't make any sense.
But…I suppose you've changed a little.
Orochimaru…
If you were like this sooner,
Jiraiya might not have had to die…
And if I had…
Jiraiya might have changed too.
Like how it was for us,
the Legendary Sannin,
things don't always go
the way you want them to.
We're not made of stone.
Distortions will appear somewhere.
Perhaps that's why I want
to observe Sasuke's future.
While patiently waiting
for his wind to blow.
Fine. I thank you for helping me heal.
So...Do you know about the war?
Of course. That's why
I'm helping you out like this.
How long have I been like this?
I can report on the battle situation.
How did you end up on the front?
I see…
Sakura summoned Katsuyu!
Around now,
a new Three-Way Deadlock
is probably making their debut.
What?
Well, we're heading back.
You should work on healing
the other Kage.
Then why do you work with Sasuke?
Because I exist to protect him.
Sasuke! There are other Tailed Beasts
inside that huge one!
Once it's weakened,
shut off your Black Flames!
Then Kurama and I will
pull them out of it!
No.
They all burn.
Hey! Don't you get it?
If we don't save them now,
we'll end up facing
a lot of trouble later on!
I'm going to put an end to
this failing system currently in place!
And then, a new...
It detached the piece of itself
that was on fire!
Sakura...Can I ask you something?
Since I don't know him very well,
I can look at this objectively.
Sasuke cannot be trusted
as a true comrade.
What are your true feelings
on the matter, Sakura?
Don't worry,
Sasuke has come back to us.
I'm happy about that.
And I do trust him.
Your words may not be lies...
But...
I can already tell that
your smile is fake.
What's up, Shikamaru?
It's nothing...
Obito...
Enough of these tricks...
I'm over it.
No more genjutsu.
Looks like I can't find anything
that will change you.
Right now, all I can give you...
...is death.
Then I shall do the same.
Come!
All right!
Shinobi Hand-to-Hand Combat!
Begin!
I'm going to borrow this.
Fire Style:
Fireball Jutsu!
Earth Style:
Mud Wall!
The real one is here!
Hand-to-hand combat is over.
Kakashi wins.
Now perform the Unison Sign.
Obito...
Your once strong will is
still alive today, right next to me!
What the current me can do
is protect the current Naruto!
You will...
Actually, everyone will
eventually end up just like me.
Sasuke is a rogue ninja.
Standard procedure is to erase him.
I'll bring back Sasuke!
Someone who can't even save
one of their friends
could never become Hokage!
I'm going to surpass every Hokage
who came before me!
- I'd never kill any of my friends!
Naruto...You never waver.
You're stronger than me and
you have many things
that are solely yours.
This is all I can do right now.
And that is...
to protect this world, my comrades...
and the Obito of the past...
by killing...
the current Obito!
It's over, Obito.
I'll let you win...
this battle.
But I'm not conceding the war!
I thought I told you.
I have no intention of fighting a clone.
You can come at me with them,
but they offer no resistance at all.
You're concentrating too much power
in your actual body.
Madara...All the time, you kept
holding something back...
That's...
Looks like that's of no use
to me anymore.
I wanted to fight Hashirama
before I became a Jinchuriki...
I guess I have no choice.
M-My body!
It's time to make him bring me back
with Rinne Rebirth!
That's...!
Obito...
You're just a backup that
I had cultivated for my rebirth.
You saved me, Gramps?
Thank you.
It's too early to thank me.
I intend to have you...
...repay your debt.
That time is now.
He's being controlled by
Madara's chakra!
The Six Paths Forbidden...
Rinne Rebirth Jutsu?
Madara...He must not be allowed
to fully return to life!
Lads!
You're all closer!
Stop the jutsu of the one
on top of the Ten-Tails right now!
Okay! Got—
Sasuke!
I see...
So that's how it is.
Is this the maximum amount
I can make inside this barrier?
Tobirama!
Okay!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Only two.
Is this also the best I can do?
We'll just have to make do with this!
They can't get to Obito in time,
so they're going to attack me...
They should know by now
that I can't be stopped with clones.
That's enough, Aoda!
You can get out of here!
Yes, Lord Sasuke!
You won't always be
like this either, right?
Don't give up.
You love Rin, don't you?
We'll both become Hokage.
Right, Obito?
Sensei...
Obito!
That...was you?
Which one is he?
What a failure!
But...oh well!
Did they succeed?!
That's Lord Fourth Hokage!
He teleported a Shadow Clone.
Had he marked him already?
A Flying Raijin marking
never disappears.
I didn't teach you that, did I, Obito?
If you were alive,
I would have wanted you
to become Hokage...
Why did you...?
That was disappointing...
All that's left to do is to seal
the un-reborn Madara...
and this war will be over.
As well as this giant thing.
What makes you think
the war is over...
my fellow traitor?
Dad! Sasuke!
Gamakichi!
Okay!
What? What's happening?!
Is the Ten-Tails changing
form again?
No, that's not what's happening!
He shook off Madara's manipulation and
was weaving the signs
to do this from the beginning!
That's...
...the Ten-Tails' Jinchuriki!