What is a clan?
What is a village?
What is…a shinobi?
What am I?
Found you!
You guys…?
What're you doing here?
Stopping the Reanimation.
Huh?
This is Kabuto?
He's kind of gross, huh?
This one coming out of
his gut looks like a huge—
Just leave him be.
She's alive.
What do you want with me
at this point?
Why'd you go out of your way
to look for me?
Oh yeah! That's right. See…
We found something incredible
in one of the hideouts.
Now let's see…
Earlier, you said that you and Itachi
stopped the Reanimation, right?
But I don't think it worked
on the reanimated Madara.
I see.
So it hasn't been stopped.
I'm talking to Sasuke!
Don't interrupt me.
Anyway, never mind that.
Look!
Look, look!
See! Amazing, right?!
With this, we Taka can rule
the shinobi world!
This is it…
I have to meet up with someone.
I'm leaving.
Huh? Who?
Orochimaru.
Huh?!
What are you talking about?
You killed Orochimaru!
Are you really surprised someone as
tenacious as Orochimaru
might not be killed so easily?
And even if I do find him vile…
I need him to do something for me.
It's time to see the all-knowing.
What do you mean,
“see” Orochimaru?
Who is this all-knowing person?
You don't need to know.
What? I don't get it.
In any case,
Orochimaru must never be resurrected!
You probably want to ask
Orochimaru for help
in using the power of the scroll, right?
Just give it time and
you'll figure it out.
That's why we looked for you and…
There are still things only
Orochimaru can do.
Sasuke, tell me…
You were Orochimaru's
favorite pupil, right?
So why can't you…?
Suigetsu!
Listen.
Huh? What?
Don't underestimate Orochimaru.
Idiot!
I don't underestimate him!
It's the exact opposite!
You were able to bring
down Orochimaru
only because both his arms
were useless from
the Reaper Death Seal, that's all.
You're the one
who's underestimating him!
Even if he is revived,
his arms will probably still be useless.
But he'll still be dangerous.
He's going to come after
your body again!
If he finds out about this war,
he's going to want to be a part of it.
He wants to destroy the Leaf too!
And that means that Team Taka
will get mixed up in this war!
Are you okay with that?
We succeeded in beating
our superiors.
It's our time now!
Who'd want to see Orochimaru now?
Hasn't he caused us
enough trouble?
Shut up, Suigetsu.
Cut out and bring me
a piece of Kabuto's flesh.
Huh?
You don't listen to me,
but you expect me to listen to you?
I'll do it.
It's always like this…
Jugo, are you okay with this?
Orochimaru's going to
be resurrected, you know…
I don't care.
Sasuke's will is Kimimaro's will.
I will abide by it.
You're just the same.
What is going on with all of this?
In my village,
we call it Sage Transformation.
My transformation originally
was the same thing.
But in all of my clones, it's called
the Curse Mark Transformation.
I'm going to seal your Curse Mark.
Curse Sealing!
So the reverse of it is:
Curse Unsealing!
Who could have imagined…
that it would be you who
would facilitate my return!
H-Hello there! Long time no see.
Orochimaru, there's something
I want you to do for me.
Don't bother explaining.
I've been watching from
inside Anko this whole time.
I secured My Sage jutsu chakra
into those Curse Marks.
They are like pieces of
my consciousness.
Then you know about the war too?
Of course.
I just have one thing to say
about that, Suigetsu.
Huh?
I have absolutely no interest
in this war.
Huh?!
It's someone else's war.
The only thing I'm interested
in right now…
Sasuke…
is your young body!
I told you!
Having said that, I don't currently
have the power to steal it.
I wouldn't be so sure…
What is your intent
in meeting with them?
There's too much that I don't know.
So I plan to ask them everything.
Everything?
There's no need to know it all.
You're still a child.
You're wrong.
If I had been open
with you from the start…
and looked you straight in the eyes
and told you the truth.
I'm not a child anymore.
I can't stay a child.
And no matter what you do
from here on out…
I want to know what started it all.
What I'm supposed to be,
what I'm supposed to do.
Are you questioning
your vengeance?
No…
Not my quest for
vengeance itself.
Reuniting with Itachi
made my hatred
towards the Hidden Leaf
grow even stronger.
It's just…
I want to understand
how even in death,
Itachi could still consider
himself a Leaf shinobi,
and care about and
try to protect the village
that dishonored his name.
Who was Itachi? What is a clan?
What is a village?
And so…
I want to know everything,
so I can finally have the answer.
I need to see with my own eyes and
decide with my own mind
what I must do.
He's no longer the Sasuke
who was manipulated by Itachi…
or me…or Tobi.
What a strange sensation.
He's going to absorb all of
Kabuto's power, and then kill him!
You better stay alert.
He might try and catch you
off guard too!
The current you…isn't half bad.
Didn't I tell you?
He did absorb his power!
No, you're wrong.
He undid the Sage Transformation.
He's taken back his own chakra
that was inside Kabuto.
He didn't touch Kabuto's chakra.
Fine, I'll help you.
Come along.
Where are we going?
Someplace you're very familiar with.
Let's be on our way.
I-Is that...?!
That's the...!
There's no mistaking it.
What is this chakra?
They all sense the chakra,
even though none of them
are sensory types.
This chakra is...
Let's go.
Hurry and
lead the way, Orochimaru.
It looks like he's a bit concerned...
about Naruto.
This place sure has changed a lot too.
What's up with Sasuke?
He's just like how I was before
I wanted to destroy Leaf.
How so?
Even if both he and the village
have changed,
this place is still his homeland.
He needs some time to reaffirm
his decision and resolve,
through immersing himself in sentimentality
and by retracing the past.
Hmm...
So you're over it already?
The whole immerse yourself
in sentimentality
to affirm your resolve
to destroy the Leaf thing.
Hey, come to think of it,
we were all your cream of
the crop subordinates, right?
And now...
we're inside of the Leaf...
All the strong ones are gone
because they're away fighting.
Isn't this a perfect opportunity for you?
Perhaps, indeed...
Except for one thing...
You're no longer Hebi.
So this is it...
This place seems to be untouched.
It's in shambles.
Well, I suppose it is way outside
the village.
Which one is it?
Let's see, it should be
around here somewhere.
There it is.
This place gives me the creeps...
If we've found what we were
looking for, let's get out of here!
Yes, let's go...
to where all the secrets sleep.
Oh, you use a jutsu to remove
the entry stone...
There's not even a trace of
the Uchiha's Nakano Shrine...
The exterior doesn't matter.
What's important is what's beneath.
Let's go.
Well then, I'm going to get started.
It's best if you stand back.
In order to perform
what is written in the scroll,
first, the Death God's Mask
is necessary.
That is located in
the Uzumaki Clan's Noh Mask Hall
on the outskirts of the Leaf Village.
Then one must allow the Death God
of the Reaper Death Seal
to possess oneself and
guide it forth.
Slice open the Death God's abdomen
and the seal will come undone.
Though I shall then end up
a human sacrifice.
However, it will also allow me
to get back
both of my arms from inside
the Death God's belly.
They're mine again!
And if I can regain the power
that lies in those arms,
I can perform the Reanimation.
That's right...
I can revive those four.
Of course in that case,
you're well aware of what will
then become necessary...
You're planning on using us as sacrifices
for the Reanimation, aren't you?!
That's not such a bad idea,
but we've actually got something
even better than you guys.
Though it's still invisible
to you yet.
Jugo, Sasuke, Suigetsu...
Get ready!
Got it.
Jugo, bestow upon Sasuke some
of your Curse Mark Sage Power.
And when you do, the Zetsu that
Tobi stuck onto Sasuke to watch him
should respond and
rise to the surface.
Damn it! How did you--?!
I know your Hashirama cells inside
and out from my experiments.
Including how to detect you,
of course.
Six of you, huh? Tobi sure
wasn't taking any chances!
When I reclaimed and
reabsorbed my chakra from Kabuto,
all his intel was transferred
inside me.
And he'd thoroughly
investigated the six Zetsu
that had been attached to Sasuke.
I possess those four's DNA as well,
since I love collecting and
storing knowledge too.
Suigetsu, Jugo...
Take care of the remaining two.
Okay, Lord Orochimaru!
Reanimation Jutsu!
Now, here I come!
They, who are all-knowing...
The previous Hokage!
That's the First Hokage?
The real Hashirama who's been
touted as a God of shinobi?
Don't tell me it's that
shinobi Orochimaru again!
What do you mean?
I suspect he undid
the Reaper Deal
that has been keeping us
sealed away.
And then performed
the Reanimation Jutsu.
No way...
You found out how to undo
that Sealing Jutsu?
How did you do
that Mr. Orochimaru?
You underestimate me, Minato.
Originally a Sealing Jutsu
of the Uzumaki Clan...
I've been researching the ruins
and scattered documents
of the now extinct clan
ever since I lost my jutsu.
Lord First...
It appears we've been recalled
into the world of the living.
Who the hell are you?!
Oh, uh...
The Fourth Hokage, sir.
Oh? The Fourth Hokage,
you say?
I see!
So the village has
remained stable!
Well, I'm not actually sure
if it has or not.
Because I died and was sealed away
much earlier than Lord Third.
Huh? Is that so...
In a separate incident than when
I was sealed away with Sarutobi?
Yes...
a completely separate incident.
So who's the Fifth Hokage?
Your granddaughter,
Princess Tsunade.
Tsuna, huh?
Is the village okay?
Is there something to be
worried about?
She was my first grandchild,
so I spoiled her rotten!
In the end, she even picked up
my gambling habit...
He's not what I expected
of someone considered to be
the God of shinobi!
How do I put it?
The Reanimation Jutsu again...
I can't believe the jutsu I devised
would be used so casually.
It's not a complex jutsu.
However, you should not have
created it in the first place.
Lord Second...
Many of your policies and jutsu
that you developed
ended up causing problems
later on down the line.
Even now...
Why you!
Are you planning on attacking
the Leaf again?!
I took away your jutsu
in exchange for my own life.
Yet you still--!
And this time you revived me,
your former master,
to pit me against the Leaf!
Conflict, no matter what the era.
It certainly cannot be called
that great a jutsu.
Tobirama, that's why I told you
that time to...
Will you be quiet, big brother?
I am trying to talk to
this stripling right now.
But I...
Shut up!
So not dignified for
the God of shinobi!
Please do not misunderstand.
I don't have any more leanings
in that direction.
Haven't you noticed that I'm not
suppressing your personalities?
There are certain circumstances
at play this time.
I'm merely creating a stage for
discourse per his strong desire.
I'm Sasuke Uchiha and I want to
ask you Hokage some things.
Is that you Sasuke?
You belong to the Uchiha?
Of course you'd stick with
a scoundrel.
Tobirama! I told you to stop
saying such things!
You're too soft, big brother!
Never mind me.
Lord Third...
Why did you make Itachi
do what he did?
So, you've learned of
what happened.
I...killed Itachi to avenge
the Uchiha Clan.
Afterwards, I learned the truth
from Tobi and Danzo.
And I leaned towards swearing
vengeance against the Leaf.
However, I want to hear it
straight from your mouth.
Everything regarding Itachi.
So it came to that...
Not only did I have him
kill his brethren...
I also had him bear
the false charge of traitor...
and keep tabs on the Akatsuki
all by himself.
From the time he was
a small child,
Itachi paid attention
to the teachings and signs
of our predecessors that
no one else gave heed to.
He was a sensitive child who understood
our village's past and our shinobi.
And perhaps due to that,
the trappings of a clan
never bound Itachi.
He was able to think ahead about
the future of shinobi and of the village.
And constantly had misgivings
regarding those futures.
Even at the age of seven,
he thought like a Hokage.
We left everything to Itachi
in his hands alone...
and he executed
his missions perfectly.
He killed his entire clan
and stopped a revolt.
Prevented a coming war
all by himself.
He even infiltrated the Akatsuki as
a spy to protect the village.
On the condition that I protect you
within the village.
So it's all true.
This is part of
the Uchiha's cursed fate.
I can't believe they're on
the brink of extinction.
So they even plotted a coup...
I'd envisioned that it might come
to something like that.
The rebellious elements bearing
Madara's will had been smoldering.
But you're the one who drove
the Uchiha to it, Lord Second...
It could be said that
the seeds got sown
with the Uchiha Police Force
that you created.
What did you say?
Those who crack down on crime
tend to be easily disliked.
The more authority
such a group has,
the more conceited it can get.
By building the Police Station
next to the prison
under the pretext of facilitating
the monitoring of criminals,
you conspicuously shoved the
Uchiha Clan to the margins of the village.
That's what fostered
the adherents to Madara.
Tobirama!
Did I not emphasize to you
over and over again
not to slight the Uchiha?
But I gave them positions that
they were eminently qualified for.
And I believed that even if
another Madara were to emerge,
he could be dealt with right away.
As you well know, older brother,
the Uchiha are...
...a clan possessed by evil!
It's like Madara left
a psychological scar upon you.
To cause such fear of the Uchiha.
You stripling.
You do not know Madara.
Second Hokage,
a question for you...
What is it about the Uchiha Clan?
What do you know?
The Senju and Uchiha Clans
share a long history
of battling each other.
We were once bitter enemies.
I know that already...
What did you mean about
the Uchiha being possessed by evil?
There used to be a thought that
in contrast to the Senju Clan,
who based their strength in love
as opposed to jutsu...
The basis of the Uchiha Clan's
strength was the power of their jutsu.
However, the truth
is actually different.
There is no clan that feels
deeper love than the Uchiha.
And that is why the Uchiha have
suppressed and sealed it away.
What do you mean?!
Once a member of the Uchiha
knows love, it's almost as if
all of his or her previously
checked emotions are released.
They awaken a profound love and
power that exceeds even the Senju's.
But why is that a problem?
It should help things go smoothly
with the Senju too...
This super-strong
power of love, right?
Except it is quite problematic.
This great power hides within it
the possibility of going out of control.
When an Uchiha who has known
love loses that deep love,
it is replaced by an even
stronger hate that changes them.
I've seen it happen
quite a few times.
And that's when
a special condition emerges.
Condition?
When an Uchiha writhes
in agony over the loss
of a great love or disappointment
in themselves,
a unique chakra is released
inside their brain and
reacts with the optic nerves and
changes appear that person's eyes.
The eyes that reflect the heart.
This is what we call the Sharingan.
The Sharingan taps into
the power of that person's heart,
rapidly increasing their strength,
along with the power of their hate.
There were many sensitive
individuals among the Uchiha,
and nearly all who were
exposed to strong emotions
were taken over by darkness
and fell to evil.
The deeper the darkness gets the
greater the visual prowess becomes,
until the person can
no longer be stopped.
Just like Madara.
Madara cared deeply
for his younger brother...
His love was, perhaps, greater
than your brother's love for you.
I thought I had arranged
and guided things as such
that the Uchiha's power could
be harnessed to serve the village.
Although if they self-destructed
for the sake of the village,
then so be it.
Either way, in the end, they were
of use to the Leaf Village.
Tobirama! Stop talking like that!
You are speaking to
an innocent Uchiha child!
What is all-important
is the village.
The village is the keystone.
I know that you know
that too older brother.
It doesn't bother me.
I am neither innocent nor a child.
It's not the standard pattern...
It's the Mangekyo Sharingan...
First Hokage...I ask you this...
What does it mean to be a village?
And what does it mean
to be a shinobi?
What is a village,
and what are shinobi?
My older brother Itachi, despite
having been used by the Leaf,
defended the village with his life.
He died a proud Leaf shinobi.
So what exactly is this village,
that one strives to protect
even if it means killing one's kin?
Even if it means their own death?
And what are shinobi who've
created such circumstances
and consider them acceptable?
I'll listen to your response
and find out the truth,
and then I'll make my decision...
Whether or not to declare
vengeance against the Leaf.
Or...
You brat possessed
with the Uchiha evil!
In that case I shall...
Lord Second!
Tobirama!
Now we're talking presence!
Lower your finger.
All right...
Don't get your chakra
so riled up, brother.
Sorry about that!
Wow, that's incredible!
You haven't changed a bit,
Lord Hashirama...
Well then, Sasuke,
you had a good older brother.
He was a greater shinobi
than I ever was!
I don't mind telling you more
about the village,
but it will take a while.
If possible, could you
please tell the child
everything he wants
to know quickly?
We don't have much time.
No time?
We're in the middle of a war.
Madara Uchiha has been revived
and apparently intends to erase
all the shinobi of this world.
Always conflict,
no matter what the era.
I definitely feel
some powerful chakra
in the direction of 2 o'clock.
This is Naruto and
Nine-Tails' chakra.
I see
So you did it, Naruto!
And you're fighting together...
even now!
It seems to be true.
I'm definitely sensing
Madara's chakra.
Then we ought to head
to the battlefield.
As all of you are under the control
of my Reanimation Jutsu,
your movements can be restricted.
If you insist,
you may head to the battlefield
after we finish talking.
Talk later!
Do you truly understand
the gravity of Madara
having been revived?
I'm sticking with this child.
If Sasuke isn't satisfied
with your explanation,
I may use all of you to destroy
the Leaf now.
The timing couldn't be better.
This jutsu--!
Orochimaru, was it?
You seem to be
misunderstanding something.
The fact that you've upped
the precision of the Reanimation
since the last time shall
be your downfall.
Now that we've been revived
at close to our original power...
I am not someone who can be bound
by the Reanimation of
one such as you.
Do not forget,
I am the one who devised
this jutsu in the first place.
Older brother, you must agree
that we have no choice.
I will take action!
Sarutobi, you sure raised
quite a shinobi.
It is an honor to be praised
by the God of shinobi himself.
He's acquired my cells and
enhanced his power to bind us!
Tobirama...
Your instincts have dulled a bit.
Damn him...
Taking a closer look,
most of his body is composed
of my older brother's cells...
First Hokage Hashirama...
He's different.
He could undo my binding
at any time...
I have to be careful not
to let down my guard.
Orochimaru...Do not fret.
My priority is to undo the ill
feelings that are binding this child.
I don't know what he will decide
after he is done listening to me...
But if we ignore him now,
he will definitely become
the next Madara.
If that happens, ending the war
and winning will be meaningless.
Do as you please, older brother.
Now then...
Where should I start?
Yes...
This time, I'll reach
the other side for sure.
Just aim it a little higher
than you'd expect.
That's the trick.
I don't need you to tell me that.
It will reach the other side
if I put my all into it!
Who the hell are you anyway?
Right now, I'm just your rival
at stone skipping.
Though mine has already
reached the other side.
That was the first time
I encountered Madara Uchiha.
I asked you who you are!
It's Hashirama.
I can't tell you my last name
due to reasons...
Hashirama, eh?
Well, just watch.
I'm gonna make it this time.
The way he throws…
I'm sure…
It's the shuriken jutsu!
Hey! You stood behind me
on purpose to distract me!
I'm the type that can't even pee
when someone's standing behind me!
S-Sorry!
Hey...Don't take it so seriously…
Sorry, I was just making excuses…
I…I didn't know…
That you had such an obnoxious
self-diagnosed neurosis...
I can't tell if you're a nice guy
or a nasty guy!
One thing for sure! I'm better
than you at stone skipping!
Want me to skip you instead?
S-Sorry...I didn't mean to upset you.
To make amends,
I'll let you throw me into the river.
Go ahead, throw me.
Do you even notice
your own obnoxious neurosis?
I just...hope I reach
the opposite shore...
You're a real eyesore!
Get lost!
Well then...
Wait a second!
Which is it?
Why don't you be more clear?
Th-That's…
That's…!
Are you…a shinobi?
This location will become
a battlefield soon. Go home.
This is a Hagoromo Clan crest…
Sorry, but I've got to go…
So long…
Uh…
It's Madara.
Madara…
Not proffering one's family name
to a stranger...
is shinobi law.
I knew it…
You're a shinobi too.
Our personalities differed,
and yet I sensed
a mysterious kinship with him.
I felt I knew why he'd come down
to the river too.
Kawarama...
Shinobi do not cry!
Shinobi are born into this world
to fight and die in battle.
Be grateful that we have
even a piece of his corpse!
For our enemy this time includes the Uchiha
Clan in addition to the Hagoromo Clan!
They are particularly merciless!
Kawarama was just seven years old!
How long…will this kind
of fighting continue?!
Until the very last foe
has been vanquished.
The path to a battle-free world
is not easily made!
And children must be sacrificed?
I will not allow Kawarama
to be disrespected!
He fought and died as
a full-fledged shinobi!
He was not a child!
Older brother Hashirama, are you okay?
You know what happens
when we defy Father.
I…don't want…
either of you, Itama or Tobirama…
to die in vain!
The Senju, the clan of love? As if!
A full-fledged shinobi, my butt!
All of this is just grown-ups
driving kids to their deaths!
We're doing exactly
the same thing as the Uchiha!
That's how we honor our opponents.
Even an infant wielding a weapon
is deemed an enemy.
And to raise one's child to become
full-fledged is a parent's love!
So in order to become full-fledged,
you have to die?!
We kill and are killed so much,
you can't even keep track
of all the grudges!
And it's too risky to even divulge
our family names!
There's something totally wrong
about a ninja world like this!
Children like you are called brats!
Father…
Older Brother's feeling depressed today…
So please forgive him.
Hashirama, go and cool your head.
Grown-ups are stupid.
If they want to stop the fighting,
they should make a pact…
But…what about avenging
our parents and brothers…
and all our friends who were killed?
Keeping saying stuff like that
and you'll end up dead too.
You and the adults are both hotheaded.
Sorry…
Forthcoming shinobi must suppress
their emotions,
create suitable rules that they then
follow and avoid extraneous conflict.
Can't a true pact...
an alliance be achieved?
What's a true pact?
During the Era of Warring States,
the average life expectance
of both shinobi and citizens
was around 30 years old.
And the reason
the average was so low was...
Itama!
The deaths of many young children.
Hey, long time no see!
Umm…
It's Hashirama.
So, Hashirama…
You seem awfully down.
What happened?
What's with you!
I'm fine!
Liar...You can talk to me, you know.
It's nothing…
Come on, tell me.
I said it's nothing.
Hey, stop dragging this out!
I promise I'll listen!
It's really nothing…
Nothing at all.
Out with it!
What's the matter?
My little brother…died.
I come to the river
because I feel like
all the haziness in my heart
gets washed away as
I stare at the water.
So that's what happened...
Your name's Madara, right…?
I wonder if you're like me…
Do you have siblings?
I'm one of five.
Well, there used to be five of us.
Used to?
We're shinobi.
We never know when
we're going to die.
If there were a way where
neither side had to die...
It would be where both sides revealed their
insides, and hid nothing from each other...
And poured each other drinks
and drank together like brothers.
But that's impossible...
Because one can't look deep
into another's insides down to their guts.
In reality, they could be as mad as hell.
Isn't it possible…
to really show how you feel
without showing your guts?
I don't know…
But every time I come here,
I pray for some way
to make it happen.
I finally got it to go
in the right direction.
You're not the only one…
Me too…
It reached.
In all honesty, I was shocked…
That one person understood
how I felt
despite all the people
that didn't.
So there was another foolish kid,
who thought as I did,
to try to change this war-torn era.
Maybe shocked isn't the right word…
To me, Madara was a gift
from the divine.
In your case…I can tell without
looking into your insides that...
What?
That your hairdo and outfit
are totally lame!
Not that we thought alike
in every respect...
After that, we started
meeting up every now and then,
still without knowing
each other's family names...
We'd spar and
compare our shinobi moves
or talk about the future…
Taijutsu and kumite.
Nice job pulling a draw against me!
It's not a draw...
I'm still standing.
Huh?
Ouch!
What were you saying?
How's this not a draw?
When did you…?
I threw it the instant
you blew me away.
I'm not gonna be
beaten that easily.
But the question is, how do
we change things concretely?
We've got to have
a vision for the future.
The first steps are for us to
not give up on our ideals
and to get a lot stronger.
Weak pups barking
won't change a thing.
Right. If we master all sorts
of jutsu and get stronger,
the adults won't be able
to ignore our words anymore.
We gotta master many jutsu
and cover any weaknesses.
Well...I am stronger than most adults
around me already.
No kidding? I'm impressed.
You really can't, eh…?
Stop standing behind me!
I found your weakness…
I'm gonna throw you into
the exact spot I pissed in!
Take this! It's my Water Style!
Disgusting! Don't whip it around!
Each time we met,
we became closer friends.
Madara…
I came up with an amazing jutsu!
Let's master it together!
Really? Show me.
A secret taijutsu technique,
a Super Fire Style Genjutsu Slice
Giant Shuriken Two-Step Drop Jutsu!
Nope...I can't visualize it at all.
I mean, which is it?
Taijutsu or genjutsu?
In the first place,
the name is too long!
Who can remember such
a long name?
Well, let me explain it...
Never mind!
Today, I'm challenging you
to cliff climbing!
Quit getting depressed
all the time!
That's your weakness.
And your weakness is
to judge too quickly…
I'm just psyching you out…
before cliff climbing!
Huh? Hey you!
See you later!
You were just pretending, huh?!
I win…
That's to be expected…
You started before me!
What a sweeping view of the forest!
Yeah, you can see really far!
I know my eyesight's just
as good as yours.
Want to challenge me?
What makes you say
that all of a sudden?
You sound really proud
of your eyes.
Well sure! I have Sha…
What's the matter?
No…never mind.
I guess it's not all that.
What is it? You're being awful
candid for once.
If I were better,
my siblings wouldn't be dead.
I couldn't even protect them.
So I shouldn't...shouldn't...
Madara…
Sorry…
I brought back some memories
for you too, huh.
So…you don't have
any more siblings?
No...I have
one younger brother left.
And I'll protect him,
no matter what!
What about you?
I have one brother left too.
And I intend to protect him too,
no matter what.
I've decided!
Let's build our settlement here!
Huh?
And make it so kids won't
have to kill each other!
We'll create a school where kids
can train and grow up stronger!
Assign missions that fit an
individual's abilities and strengths!
Have superiors who can properly
assign ranks to commissions!
It will be a place where kids
don't have to be sent
into harsh battlefronts.
You're pretty much
the only one spouting nonsense.
Well then, what about you?
It doesn't sound bad at all.
Then it's decided!
Yeah...If that settlement
gets built here,
then I could watch over
my little brother,
and protect him in this place
where you can see to no end!
That was where the Leaf Village
would eventually stand.
I made a resolution that day.
To endure for
the sake of my vision.
We both made it.
That stone…
is perfect for rock skipping.
Hang on to it until
we meet next time!
What is it, Tobirama?
Older Brother...Come with me.
Hashirama, this boy you've been
meeting up with...
How did you…?
Father ordered me to tail you…
You?
I have better sensory skills
than you.
You've been going out
quite often lately,
so I knew something was up.
I checked up on that boy.
He belongs to the Uchiha Clan.
He has killed adults from our clan.
It seems he was born
with inherent shinobi talent.
So I was right…
Given your lack of surprise...
Don't tell me
the two of you already
knew each other's clan names.
No...I didn't know.
He probably
doesn't know mine either.
Hashirama.
Do you know what this means?
The Senju and Uchiha Clans
are bitter enemies.
I haven't told anyone
in our clan yet…
If we're not careful,
you could be branded a traitor.
If you don't want to be accused
of being an enemy spy…
after you see that boy next time,
follow him.
And bring back intel
about the Uchiha Clan.
This is a mission.
If he should notice you...
kill him!
W-Wait...
A-Are you sure he's an Uchiha?
Yes...
If he's found out that you're Senju,
he'll pretend to let his guard down
to steal intel on us.
Do not trust him.
No, he's not like that...
You'd trust the clan who killed
your younger brother?
You have no idea what
he's thinking inside his gut!
If he tricks you, you'll be putting
the entire Senju Clan at risk.
That's not...
Just in case, Tobirama and I
will come along. Understood?
Answer me!
Yes.
I know it's right off the bat,
but how about we just skip stones
instead of exchanging greetings?
Yeah...
Hashirama...
Sorry. I can't stay today...
I just remembered something
I have to do.
O-Oh yeah?
I'm going to head home then.
That speed!
He's planning to run for it!
Damn Hashirama!
He warned him!
Let's go, Tobirama!
Yes!
Seems like we're both
on the same page.
Butsuma Senju.
And Tobirama, I believe.
Indeed, Tajima Uchiha.
And Izuna, right?
It seemed the Uchiha coincidentally
had the same idea.
Exactly the same circumstances.
Butsuma Senju and Tajima Uchiha
both knew from numerous prior clashes
that they possessed
practically equal strength.
- Stop!
Shinobi are trained to keep
their hearts in check on the battlefield,
no matter what happens.
A single flash of emotional display
can lead to vulnerability
and mean the difference
between life and death.
However...
The two adults were well aware...
that if their own child were killed
right before their eyes,
it would likely, no matter how slight,
unbalance their heart.
Meaning...
whoever could land the first strike
would determine the outcome.
I'll never forgive anyone who tries
to hurt my little brother,
no matter who they are!
Same here!
Hey, Hashirama...
What is it?
Maybe it just isn't possible for us...
to reach that...
pipe dream of ours...
Madara...What are you...?
It may have been brief,
but it was fun...Hashirama.
Three against three...
Can we take them, Madara?
No...
Hashirama is stronger than me.
If we fight, we'll lose.
There's a kid stronger than you, Brother?
I see, quite impressive.
Let's retreat!
So long.
Madara!
You...really haven't given up, have you?
You've gotten to the same point I...
You are Senju.
I truly wish it wasn't so.
My brothers were killed
by the Senju.
And your brothers, by the Uchiha...
So there's no need to show
our guts to each other.
Our next meeting will likely be
on the battlefield...
Hashirama Senju.
I'm...Madara Uchiha.
Father! Look at Big Brother's eyes!
We may not have obtained
any intel on the Senju...
but it seems we gained something
valuable from this, after all.
He awakened his Sharingan...just now?
In that moment,
I felt like I understood what awakening
the Sharingan truly signified.
He decided to completely
erase his friend.
To erase me from his life.
After that, we battled.
We fought each other day after day.
And before we knew it,
we'd each become
our respective clan's leaders.
We were at the furthest place possible...
from the dream that
we wanted to fulfill.
Fire Style:
Fire Ball Jutsu!
Water Style:
Water Dragon Missile!
A blind attack...
I curse the misfortune of the ones
who do not have the Sharingan.
Flying Raijin Slice!
Izuna!
Hang in there!
I swear I'll save you!
Hashirama...
Madara...You cannot defeat me.
But I had never abandoned our dream.
Why don't we end this?
If the two strongest shinobi clans,
the Uchiha and Senju, join forces,
nations will not be able to find other
shinobi clans that can stand against us...
The conflict will eventually
start to die down.
Come on.
No...Big Brother...
Izuna!
Do not be deceived by them...
Have you forgotten that these bastards
killed everyone...killed the Uchiha?
It was clear to all that the Uchiha Clan
was in an unfavorable position.
In fact, defectors to the Senju
soon began showing up.
And that's about when
Madara changed as well.
He had obtained
the Eternal Mangekyo Sharingan.
Those eyes...
What happened to Izuna?
My little brother ended up dying
from that day's wounds...
Leaving me powers that
will help protect the Uchiha!
I sent you a cease-fire agreement!
If you truly want to protect the Uchiha,
let's stop fighting!
Hashirama!
Wood Style: Deep Forest Bloom!
Poison Pollen eh?
Enough, Madara!
Fighting is meaningless!
Meaningless?
Then why did Izuna die?
It's because...
because you bastards killed him!
Wood Golem Jutsu!
Hashirama!
Madara, we were friends!
And we shared the same dream!
Hashirama!
How long will you keep saying
such juvenile things?
It's just not possible to show
our guts to each other!
Don't you get it?
Hashirama!
Madara!
At the end of a battle
that lasted a whole day...
Madara's back touched
the ground for the very first time.
Madara...
You're finished.
Wait, Tobirama.
Why, Elder Brother?!
This is our chance!
No one touches him!
Just get it over with, Hashirama.
It would be an honor to die
by your hand.
Stop posturing.
If I kill the clan leader of the Uchiha,
it will only incite the young ones
who follow you.
There isn't anyone left with such pluck
among the Uchiha anymore.
Sure there are.
Perhaps not right now, but in time.
Come on...
Why don't we end this war?
We made a promise, remember?
To create the ideal village someday.
Can't we go back to those days...
and skip rocks together?
That's just impossible.
You and I are no longer the same.
Let's build our settlement here!
Heh...You're pretty much the only one
spouting such nonsense.
Well then, what about you?
Yeah...If that settlement gets built here,
then I could watch over
my little brother,
and protect him in this place
where you can see to no end!
I don't have a single brother left.
I have nothing to protect.
And...I just can't trust you.
Is there any way I can
convince you to trust us?
Well, there is a way to
show each other our guts...
Either kill your brother...
or kill yourself right now.
And then we'll be even.
I'd be willing to trust your clan.
Kill your little brother or kill yourself?
How dare you say
something so ridicu-
I agree.
This is crazy!
So what are you going
to do, Elder Brother?
Are you going to kill me now?
Or are you going to die on account
of this guy's nonsense?
It's idiotic. Don't listen to him!
Thank you, Madara.
You really are kindhearted.
Madara had given me a choice,
an option where I wouldn't have
to kill my little brother.
He knew all too well...
how an older brother feels
towards his younger siblings.
Listen, Tobirama...
Etch these words into your heart,
for these are my final words...
Brother...
Words that I shall be exchanging
with my life.
You too, my fellow clan members.
After my death, do not kill Madara.
I forbid any fighting between
the Uchiha and Senju.
Swear this right now...
upon the lives of your fathers,
and your grandchildren yet unborn.
Farewell...
Enough...
I have now seen your guts.
It was like a dream...
The Uchiha and the Senju
formed an alliance.
There would no longer
be any casualties,
nor would any more children
have to die.
And so, we began building our village.
Later, we would ally
with the Land of Fire,
and the creation of
a peaceful state
where nation and village stood
on equal footing also commenced.
In any case, it was like a dream.
I thought we were just talking
about our dream.
They say where there's a will,
there's a way...
And yet, I...
That dream is now becoming reality.
The leader of shinobi who protects
the Land of Fire from the shadows.
The Fire Shadow, or Hokage. Well?
What's that supposed to be?
The Land of Fire requests that we select
someone who will represent the Village.
I'm considering naming you
to be our leader...the Hokage.
You no longer have any siblings left...
But I'd like you to think of all of
the village shinobi as your siblings.
I want you to protect them
with all your might.
Even though I couldn't protect
my own Uchiha brethren?
There's no time to
get weak right now!
In addition to the Uchiha and Senju,
it seems the Sarutobi and
the Shimura Clans also want to join.
Are you kidding? Are you serious?!
And there are many others!
This village is going to
keep on expanding!
We're going to need to come up
with a name for the village too...
Any thoughts?
How about...
The Village...Hidden in the Leaves?
It's too simple...
It's not imaginative.
You called it exactly as you saw it.
How's it different from "Hokage"?!
And you still have that habit
of getting depressed easily!
It took a long time, but it felt like
we were back to being
the friends we once were.
So you're saying
the role of the Hokage
is to stay in the village
and protect everyone?
There's that...
But he'll be even more significant.
As village-building picks up speed,
the Hokage will get busier too.
That's why I want to
have your likeness
carved into this cliff at our feet.
As a symbol of
our village's protector!
You've got to be kidding!
Although...your face is a bit too stern...
so it will have to be softened
here and there.
Well, it beats that sad mug of yours!
Is it that sad?
Yeah...It's beyond sad.
Is that so?
There you are!
What are you dawdling here for?
The Feudal Lords from the Land of Fire
will be here soon for the conference!
It's Tobirama...
For Hokage?!
That's not your choice!
To propose Madara as
a candidate for leader is fine...
But the final decision will be made
with the top officials,
after consulting with the Land of Fire
and the people of the village!
Things are different from Father's era!
But...
Besides, Madara Uchiha being chosen
as the leader won't happen.
Everyone knows...
You are the one who founded
this settlement, Big Brother.
Even those from
the Uchiha say as much.
Furthermore, haven't you heard
the rumors about them?
The stronger their hate,
the stronger their visual prowess
manifests itself.
The Sharingan is such a power.
They're unpredictable.
For the future of the village...
Stop talking like that, Tobirama!
I just felt someone's presence.
Tobirama, you would know.
No...I'm not infusing chakra right now.
Don't change the subject, Big Brother!
From now on,
things will be run democratically.
Any objections?
No...That's fine.
And so...
I became the First Hokage.
This is the stone tablet that has been
passed down the Uchiha for generations.
It's never been shown
to an outsider before.
The special text requires
visual prowess to decipher.
This is what I'm able
to decipher so far...
"One god seeking stability
split into light and shadow.
"And it is these opposites together
that give rise
"to all things in this universe."
This is a universal truth.
In short, it states that
true happiness can be found
when two contrary powers
cooperate together.
However, it could be
interpreted differently.
Hashirama...
Do you think I don't know
what's going on?
Leave Tobirama to me.
I can't do this without you.
Help me as the Hokage's right hand...
and as a brother!
The people will eventually
recognize your merits!
And then,
I'll name you Second Hokage.
After you, I suspect Tobirama
will probably become the Hokage.
When he does, the Uchiha
will be eventually eliminated.
Knowing this, I've reached out to
other Uchiha about leaving the village.
But it seems no one is willing
to follow me.
Madara...
I couldn't protect
my younger brother...
And it seems I won't be able
to keep the promise I made him...
that I would protect the clan.
I'm not even trusted
by the clan I want to protect.
That's not true!
Everyone is...
Perhaps that time, the ultimatum
I should have given you was
"to kill your younger brother."
You call me your brother.
But which of us would you kill
for the sake of the village?
I'd like to think that
I know you pretty well.
I've had enough.
I'm going to leave the village.
I've found a different path to take.
It became clear to me because
we showed each other our guts...
Cooperation is merely
a quiet form of conflict.
You're wrong!
I won't let it be like that.
Hashirama, it's what
you make of reality.
Let's stop being slaves to it.
It's healthier to view this world
as merely a sideshow...
Have you been listening
to me, Madara?!
You are the only one
who's an even match for me.
I'm looking forward
to the battles we'll fight...
up until the time
I achieve my true dream.
What is your true dream?
I thought everything we've aimed for
is here in this village!
You just can't see it...
What's beyond this...
The dreams of the far future.
Then tell me about your dreams
of the far future.
If it's connected to
this village's dreams,
I need your strength as a leader,
as a senior member.
And...as a friend.
There is no connection.
And you'll never reach it.
Chasing after me is useless.
You, of all people, should know.
No one is capable of
catching me from behind.
Upon saying those words,
Madara left the village.
We had come this far together.
And now, Madara was gone from
the village we had created together.
But in the world,
everyone respected and copied
our village system of Allied Ninja Clans
which had been created
by the former warring rivals,
the Uchiha and Senju, joining forces.
Villages like the Village Hidden
in the Leaves
which began in the Land of Fire,
and its one leader system,
spread like wildfire across
the Great Nations.
In the Land of Lightning,
Hidden Cloud Village was formed
with its leader named Raikage.
In the Land of Earth,
Hidden Stone Village was formed
with its leader named Tsuchikage.
The Land of Water had the Hidden Mist
with their Mizukage.
And in the Land of Wind,
the Hidden Sand was formed and
they named their leader, Kazekage.
Not only the Great Nations,
but even the smaller nations
adopted this system.
Madara's and my dream had come true.
Shinobi children learned
and played instead of battling.
And they started living long enough
to even know the taste of alcohol.
But, as if he wanted to destroy
his previous dream...
Madara came back to
attack the Leaf Village.
Wood Style:
Wood Golem jutsu!
The Wood Style Wood
Expulsion Jutsu, was it?
Perfect for taking on
difficult beasts...
He clad his Susano'o around
the Tailed Beast like armor!
Madara, you crafty fox!
I can read your sword swings!
Wood Style:
Laughing Buddha Jutsu!
At this rate, this land
will be completely obliterated.
It's best to move this
to the seashore!
You're not getting away!
There, try grabbing that!
What will you do now?!
Summoning...
Five-Layer Rashomon!
This...
will change the trajectory!
All the way to the other shore?
Hashirama...
It's been a while since we've
fought each other earnestly!
You can see that I have changed!
Will you destroy everything that
we've accomplished until now, Madara?
Nothing will come of us
battling each other.
This fight will only...
hurt the village and shinobi!
It is disrespect toward
our siblings and our comrades!
You know nothing...
I don't want to kill you!
Are you implying that
you could kill me at any moment?
No! I'm saying we are friends...
I've already...reached it!
Then so be it!
Sage Art!
Wood Style:
Shinsu Senju
Veritable 1000-Armed Kan'on!
Here I come, Madara!
Come, Hashirama!
Chojo Kebutsu!
Artifacts of the Buddha!
He stripped off the Susano'o!
Here I come!
10th Edict on Enlightenment!
Madara!
Hashirama!
This time...
you're not going to
reach the other side!
I'm the one still standing.
Opposite from the last time.
I just want to protect...
the dream I finally realized.
I don't want anymore...
You look pretty depressed, Hashirama.
Can't perk back up this time, eh?
Can't we show each other
our guts?
The first steps are for us to
not give up on our ideals
and to get a lot stronger.
Let's build our settlement here!
They say where there's a will,
there's a way...
And yet, I...
That dream is now becoming reality.
A Wood Style Clone...
I can't believe my back was taken...
I will protect our...no, my village.
No matter what.
I still believe to this day
that protecting the village
will lead to the protection of
the people, shinobi, and children!
I will not forgive anyone
who threatens the village.
Be they a friend...sibling...
or even my own child...
You've changed...Hashirama.
I made up my mind right then...
to endure in order to watch
over the present.
You've got your priorities backwards.
Ultimately...It shall someday
lead the village to darkness.
And thus...my battle with Madara
came to an end.
I don't know how Madara
returned to life now.
I definitely killed my friend...
For the sake of the village.
The village...
that Madara and I first envisioned...
is something that joined
one clan to another.
It was an invaluable cornerstone
that created order out of chaos,
then maintained it.
It protected the children and
averted pointless conflict.
It made peace a reality.
However...it gave rise to despair,
the kind that your brother Itachi
was forced to bear.
Perhaps what Madara said
was correct, after all.
Perhaps he foresaw
this state of affairs.
I am the shinobi who created
these circumstances.
Furthermore, I am also the one
who considered them acceptable.
I believe that shinobi are those
who endure for a purpose.
But depending on what that purpose is,
a shinobi can change.
Just as Madara...and I did.
Shinobi...
Shinobi are those who endure...
in order to achieve their goals.
For me, it was building a village.
But it seems Madara
found something else.
This plan of Madara's that
Orochimaru mentioned earlier...
To erase all the shinobi in this world...
I don't know what
that means in literal terms, but...
It's the Infinite Tsukuyomi
where village, shinobi,
and citizen are all irrelevant.
He intends to put everyone
under genjutsu
and manipulate them as he sees fit.
To negate everything that my older
brother, Madara's younger brother...
and all of you...
have tried to protect.
My older brother inherited your will
without even talking to you.
My older brother endured longer
and harder than you.
And died stating he was proud
to be Leaf shinobi.
Isn't it ironic that the shinobi who
understood you more than anyone else...
was from the Uchiha Clan?
Your brother was not the only one.
I had a subordinate
named Kagami Uchiha
who was much like your brother.
Second Hokage...I thought
you despised the Uchiha.
That's not entirely true.
I treated anyone who posed
a danger to the village,
no matter what clan they belonged to,
with extreme caution.
And there's no doubt that
the Uchiha Clan warranted my suspicions...
The Uchiha just happened
to be a clan
particularly disposed
to be considered as such.
But, it is also because
they could feel such deep love
that there were quite
a few Uchiha over the years
like your brother and Kagami...
who could transcend
the boundaries of the clan
and devote themselves to the village.
My elder brother believed the village
was something that could
eliminate the framework of clans.
Well, the reality is...
This wasn't so simple.
The idealism of
my elder brother Hashirama...
And the danger that Madara posed...
Mediating between these two things,
and protecting and
strengthening the village
were my duties as
the Second Hokage.
Shisui Uchiha was
a descendant of Kagami Uchiha.
He was a friend of
your older brother Itachi.
Many, including myself, embraced
the First Hokage's Will of Fire.
But perhaps, I was more naïve
than any other shinobi.
I wasn't able to continue
the Second Hokage's task
of village-building skillfully enough.
Which is how I ended up burdening Danzo
with the village's darkness.
I killed Danzo in vengeance.
Until the end, he spoke that
he would protect the village,
no matter how dirty the means.
It seems I've failed miserably
time after time as the Hokage.
I guess I'm responsible for creating
the situation that exists now.
No...You're not to blame, Lord Third.
You did everything you could
for the sake of the village respectably.
I'm the one who died during
the Nine-Tails' attack on the village!
You had such high hopes for me
as the Hokage...
And I couldn't live up to them.
I'll say...After he passed over me
and picked you.
Everyone was so disappointed.
Lord Orochimaru...
You sound like you're pouting.
A little...since the Third Hokage
is right here.
Had I lived, perhaps I could
have helped to foil
the Uchiha's plans for
a coup d'état much sooner...
Now then...Sasuke...
What will you do?
Will you destroy the village?
Or...
Sorry, Sasuke...
Let's do it some other time.
Sorry, Sasuke. Let's do it next time...
You probably hate me, huh?
But, we only have each other
as siblings.
I'm always going to
be there for you,
even if it's only as an obstacle
for you to overcome.
Even if you do hate me...
That's what big brothers are for.
You all suspect me?
There is no value in killing you now...
my foolish little brother.
If you wish to kill me,
resent me, hate me,
and survive...in obscurity.
I did what you said...
I resented you and hated you...
and I survived just so I...
so I could kill you!
I have no interest
in someone like you...
You're weak,
because you don't have enough...
hate.
I always lied to you and
asked you to forgive me.
Deliberately keeping you at
a distance by my own hand.
All because I didn't want you
to get caught up in any of this.
But now, I believe...
That perhaps you could have changed
Father, Mother,
and the rest of the Uchiha.
If I had been open with you
from the start...
And looked you straight in the eyes
and told you the truth,
then I wouldn't have had
to stand before you,
from above, as a failure,
telling you all of this.
So this time...I want to impart
this truth to you...
You don't ever have to forgive me.
And no matter what you do
from here on out, know this...
I will love you always.
I'm going to the battlefield!
I won't let the village,
and Itachi become nothing!
It's been decided then!
Tobirama!
Prepare to fly us outside!
Even if I wanted to use Flying Raijin,
I'm bound right now.
Orochimaru, was it?
What will you do?
You said earlier that
you'd follow Sasuke.
Of course...We will accompany him.
What?!
J-Jugo, what about you?
I'm going too.
It's my job to protect Sasuke.
Four super-strong zombies...
Three monsters...
If I tag along, I'm dead for sure!
I'm making a break for it
when I see a chance!
This view brings back memories!
It's now or never!
What the hell?!
It's you after all, Sasuke!
I sensed your chakra
and I couldn't believe it,
so I backtracked and look what I find!
Karin...
Oh my...So many of my best experiments
gathered here in one place!
You bastard...!
I'll never forgive you!
I'm sorry, Karin.
You bastard! As if a simple apology
will get you off the hook...
you good for nothing...
I see you still have
a weakness for Sasuke, Karin...
Listen, Lord Orochimaru!
Sasuke...had the gall...
to stab me and...
What a coincidence. Me too.
But I'm helping Sasuke now.
This is perfect timing. You help too.
What?!
I guess I have no choice...
Who is she?
Judging from the chakra
and that red hair...
She's from the Uzumaki Clan.
One more idiot joins the pack.
I bet Madara will be surprised.
Orochimaru...
Why did you decide to help Sasuke?
You were trying to destroy the village.
After being inside Kabuto,
I realized something...
He imitated the way I lived and
tried to possess everything,
and failed.
So now, I'm just curious about
the different path Sasuke has chosen.
Unlike Kabuto, Sasuke didn't copy me.
Fellow Hokage!
As we stand atop the Great Stone Faces
that have watched over
the Hidden Leaf...
Let us burn this sight of
the village into our memory!
I'm finally going to see my son.
Naruto, I wasn't able to do
anything for you as a father...
I'll make it up to you by
bringing you a huge present.
All right! It's been a while
since my last war!
I'd better be on my toes!
Madara...We'll defeat you
this time for sure!
This may sound foolish,
but I'm kind of looking forward
to seeing my old friend!
Just you wait, Madara!
There's always conflict,
no matter what the era.
But this shall be the end of wars!
Let's go!