The Ten-Tails disappeared?
What's going on?
Did they defeat it?
No...
Hinata! Did you see it?
Yeah!
Can you explain what happened?
Ten-Tails was completely
absorbed into that man.
Based on looking at its chakra.
Don't tell me...
That's the Ten-Tails'...
Jinchuriki?
He looks even creepier
than before!
Obito...
Naruto...
How can you tell
he's a Jinchuriki?
I've become friends
with the Tailed Beasts.
They gave me some
of their chakra earlier,
so it's obvious to me.
I could sense the Tailed Beasts' chakra
getting sucked into Obito
one after the other.
Plus, I've seen Nagato do that
Six Paths Rebirth Jutsu before.
But the signs he was weaving
were completely different!
Anyway, he was performing
the jutsu
to become a Jinchuriki
all this time.
I see...
Eight-o! Is that the final form?
No, it's not.
It's hard to explain,
but that isn't it.
Looks like Ten-Tails was
used to create a Jinchuriki
before it reached its final form.
Even if you have become
a Jinchuriki,
the Gracious Deity Gates
are still in play.
Whoa! Amazing!
The Sage Art Seal that
suppressed the Ten-Tails was...
Such power...
What?!
Impossible!
The Four Crimson Rays Formation!
Is it just me,
or is he stronger than
when he was gigantic?
Before, it was just throwing
its power around.
But now, it's learned to focus it.
Everyone, keep your guard up!
We don't know what that man,
who made the Ten-Tails' power
his own, might do!
He's broken the barrier!
Enough! Obito, stop this!
O...bi...to?
I'll be blunt.
This guy is stronger than me!
No offense, but it appears so.
Even if you reabsorb
your remaining clones,
you're no match, Elder Brother!
I know.
However...
It would be fun to watch
all the Hokage beg for mercy,
but I cannot wait any longer.
Obito is now just like
the Sage of Six Paths.
I can't let him take the lead
before I use my trump card.
What's happened?
He's so fast!
Saru! Fourth! Scram!
This is Lord Second's attack plan!
– Elder Brother!
– Mm-hmm!
Minato, get away!
Lord Second, you sure work fast!
Flying Raijin Jutsu!
I suspected that might
not be enough to kill you...
I created the Reanimation Jutsu,
as well as ancillary jutsu
to go with it.
Though this is the first time
I'm using it on myself.
There it is!
The Lord Second's special...
Tandem Explosive Tags!
This is how it's done!
Each tag summons more tags,
resulting in continuous explosions.
Concentrated and focused
consecutive explosions!
This is too much!
What's going on? I can't keep up!
Don't freak out!
Always keep one eye on
what's happening around you!
I don't care if that is
the Jinchuriki of the Ten-Tails!
The Lords Hokage are
engaged in battle!
We have to join them!
Don't be hasty! We need to—!
All of you!
You must not approach heedlessly!
What is he?
He's solid and swift.
And he has an attack that
turns all to dust in an instant!
Shuriken Shadow Clones!
It's similar to Ohnoki's Particle Style,
but its shape is fluid.
It can shift to be either
offensive or defensive.
And can be continuously maintained.
I suspect it's a combination of more
than four changes in chakra nature!
This is more than a kekkei genkai
or even a kekkei touta...
But there seems to be
a time limit to how long
he can use each
change in chakra form.
Gramps!
Dad! You couldn't teleport
Grandpa Third with your jutsu too?
It's impossible. I can't teleport
anything that I myself,
or my chakra isn't touching directly.
Calm down, Naruto.
The Hokage are Reanimations.
They intentionally attacked head-on
knowing that they won't die,
in order to check out
the enemy's moves and abilities.
Stop worrying and analyze
the battle instead.
So that's Sasuke...
He's extremely smart.
Although it still takes a while
for a Reanimation to regenerate.
I'll go first and create an opening!
At this point, I feel the need to...
I'm done waiting, Hashirama!
W-What's going on?
I get it...
Ten-Tails hasn't completely
synched with its Jinchuriki yet.
This is our chance to take it down!
I'll summon my original here then!
It's been a while, but it's time
for my Rasen-Flash Super-Circle
Dance Howl Stage Three!
Gamakichi! Below you!
He passed underground!
It's just his upper body!
Damn it!
You're not the one...
...who's going to sever the past. I am!
I hope this makes it in time!
Flying Raijin Jutsu!
My markings on Obito disappeared?
Damn it!
Owww...
I thought we were going to die!
Looks like my boy is
as accomplished as Sasuke.
Now then...
What is that?
We have to take him down
while he's still unable
to use his body well.
Was he after your clone
just now, Dad?
No, I don't think that was it...
What? What happened?!
He hit himself with his own attack.
His attack missed.
Seems Obito's consciousness is
merely clinging to Ten Tail's great power.
He barely has any control over it.
This time, I'll get
the Rasen-Flash Super-Circle
Dance Howl Stage Three in for sure!
I'll create an opening,
so you two hit him immediately
with your strongest combo!
Rin...
Of course,
I'm going to be the Hokage!
And then...
I won't have any time for girls!
Right, Sensei?
Here I come, Obito!
Who...are...you?
Finally, Sensei...
Damn it!
Dad!
Naruto, focus!
He got me, but I'm okay!
Are you sure about that?
When did he...?!
I'll have to teleport it away
with me!
You can have this back.
Don't worry.
I only teleported a clone.
I marked him that last time
we were in contact.
Amazing! You can copy
my dad's move!
Impressive,
Second Great Stone Face-guy!
Lord Fourth is using my move!
And just call me "Lord Second"!
Get out of my way, Madara!
I don't have much time,
but there's something
I've got to do now!
Wood Style: Wood Golem Jutsu!
A-Amazing!
They're on a completely
different level!
So this is the battle capacity
of our predecessors!
If we went out there...
we would just get
in their way for sure.
Did he get him?
He blocked it, huh? He's fast.
We won't be able to hit him
with ordinary jutsu.
I guess I'll have to make an opening
with my Rasen-Flash Super-Circle
Dance Howl Stage Three...
Amaterasu!
Sasuke! Naruto! I said
I would create an opening for you!
I'll do it!
No, we will!
We'll let Dad and the others
be the main act!
I could tell you were
amassing chakra in your left eye.
Hardly a surprise attack.
Let's go, Fourth.
A clone's Flying Raijin
is much slower.
Let's combine and
reciprocate our Flying Raijin.
Go ahead and put your mark on me.
Yes, sir.
Plus with these bodies,
we can still move after being hit!
Naruto, this time, I'll match
your chakra level using my Sharingan.
No need to turn it into a competition!
– Wind Style: Rasen Shuriken!
– Inferno Style: Flame Control!
You two are the main act!
Distracted by what's going on
in front of you?
Now!
– Reciprocal Round-Robin Jutsu!
– Flying Raijin Jutsu!
I name it the Scorch Style
Nimbus Tempest!
Just keep on going as planned!
Hinata! What's going on with
Naruto and Sasuke?
They're both...
smiling...
I got in a direct hit before
those black things could protect him.
He should have felt that one.
No effect at all.
We can't touch those black,
transforming spheres...
Our attacks have
no effect on him...
He's quick on both offense
and defense...
What a pain.
He's even more perfect than
how I imagine myself in my dreams!
It's like he's truly obtained
dreamlike power.
That's odd.
What is?
Your arm was ripped off...
There should be dust swirling
around to restore it by now.
Our reanimated bodies
aren't regenerating...
I have come to possess the same power
as the Founder of Shinobi.
You can no longer measure me
by the standards you are used to.
Don't tell me, your jutsu...!
What does he mean by the same power
as the Founder of Shinobi?
Fourth...
Try not to get seriously injured again,
even with our reanimated bodies...
He's probably using
a jutsu based
on Shadow and Light Styles
that nullify all ninjutsu.
In other words, if he destroys
our reanimated bodies...
we'll be unable to regenerate,
and we'll die!
Also...assume that right arm
of yours is permanently gone.
If that's the case, we'll need
to fight him even more carefully...
But since ninjutsu won't work on him,
this will be tricky.
How about physical attacks?
Let's try it out.
Sasuke...
What?
We're going to have to take the lead.
Think you can keep up?
Don't underestimate the Uchiha.
All right!
I'll up my Kurama Mode and
go into Tailed Beast State!
Huh?
Kurama! Lend me
a little more chakra!
Hold off on going into
Nine-Tails State for just a bit!
But he's not someone
we can beat without it.
If you want to enter into
Perfect Tailed Beast State,
you're going to have to fight
in normal mode for a bit.
Syrup Gun!
A toad from Mount Myoboku?
What was that about Gamakichi?
If you're going make a move,
do something diversionary or a combo...
Sorry, but we're approaching
the time limit for the summoning.
I just wanted to repay him
with a parting shot!
Thanks for the effort!
Go get some rest!
Sorry about this.
This is...
Obito, I thought you wanted
to become Hokage.
Why are you doing this?
You want to know why?
This is my chance!
Lecturing me now?
Isn't it a bit late for that...Sensei?
You're always too late
when it matters most.
I'm glad my teacher was a Hokage.
It made it easy to give up
on becoming Hokage.
He got past Lord Third's
personal ANBU Black Ops,
infiltrated a top-secret barrier,
and knew that the seal
on the Nine-Tails would be
at its weakest during childbirth...
Are you Madara Uchiha?
Even though you were my teacher,
you didn't realize it was me.
That's just who
you are fundamentally.
How pathetic...
You died a heroic Hokage,
but now you're being exposed
as a disgrace in front of your son.
That's right...
A Hokage is a pitiable existence...
compared to what I am now.
Apparently the kid's not a goofball.
He's caught on!
You have no right to
make fun of a Hokage
when you couldn't even
become one yourself.
Naruto, you—!
Especially my dad...
who actually became Hokage.
How dare you put him down!
That worked?!
Why? How?
It's effective! I knew it!
Even if ninjutsu is ineffective,
Sage Jutsu still works!
The toad from Mount Myoboku
used Sage Jutsu
and his attack wasn't nullified.
You bastard!
That's amazing, Naruto...
What's going on?
His Sage Jutsu is working!
He's even mastered the same
Sage Jutsu as Jiraiya Sensei...
He's grown into quite a son, eh, Minato?
It's no wonder he managed
to sweet talk my other half.
Minato...You intended for your brat to
clean up after your mess, right?
That's why you sealed
my other half inside him…
as if you were confident they would
be able to work together.
Nine-Tails…
Then don't regret it now.
It's not your fault
that Kushina died.
And making your brat into
a Jinchuriki wasn't a bad thing either.
Because your brat is trying
to change...
what this world has
become right now.
He's not that
newborn babe anymore.
In fact, tomorrow is...
Naruto…
Listen up...I need to
tell you something...
I can't believe the Ten-Tails'
Jinchuriki has such a weakness!
And with Ten-Tails inside me,
I can't pass through things either!
How frustrating!
Sage moves will work!
Sage Power?
The toad attacks are Sage Jutsu…
They use Nature Energy.
Come to think of it, when I tried
to sense Ten-Tails' power,
it was Nature Energy itself.
So you can maybe counter
Nature Energy with Nature Energy.
Not that I really understand it.
I'm just glad I learned
Sage Jutsu! All right!
Next up is Frog Kumite!
He instantly grasped how to use
the Flying Raijin with me...
and has even mastered
Sage Power.
I feel like I'm fighting
alongside Elder Brother!
It clearly worked.
But he's recovered already,
and now he's guarding his back.
If we teleport behind him carelessly,
we might get erased.
I should start preparing for
the Tsukuyomi.
Let's tidy things up.
There is nothing worth saving
in this reality.
This world is already dead.
Hey...This is super bad!
Four of them…all at once?
Even if we were to create
an Earth Style Wall,
it wouldn't be enough!
There are too many of them!
What do we do? Think!
It would take one person
per each of those
to teleport away using
the Flying Raijin.
The Fourth and I can get
to two of them,
but that leaves two others!
Impossible!
Where's Elder Brother?
Madara! Could you wait a moment?
Your comrade is acting up...!
We are all Reanimations!
There's no need to worry!
Keep fighting!
Do not give up everyone!
I am with you!
My clones are with you!
We only need to change
the spheres' trajectories!
The other Hokage will
also take measures
and repel them across the ocean!
I ask that you all work on putting up
an Earth Style Wall!
I'll use the Deep Forest
Emergence to launch
and guide them to
toward the ocean!
I won't let you!
Six Crimson Ray Formation!
A barrier!
Hey! Don't tell me we're...
Endgame.
Our only choice now is
to teleport those spheres
outside the barrier using
the Flying Raijin.
Fourth, can you handle two of them?
Since we can't mark them,
I can only take one.
There's only one way.
We could...
You intend to teleport
the stalk itself outside?
You think I'd let you do that?
You can't save anyone!
Dad!
I don't know if it will work,
but I've got an idea.
Will you bump fists with me?
Hey, other half. How ya been?
Do you mind sharing some
of your chakra with me?
Naruto…
Minato's useless,
he can't do anything.
He couldn't even
protect your mom...
Nor his own subordinates.
You know what tomorrow is,
don't you?
It's the anniversary of
Minato and Kushina's deaths.
In this world, it's over
when you die.
You see...
Oh, right, which means...
it's also the day I was born!
So you see...
It's not over...
'Cuz I exist in this world!
Let's go, Dad!
Yeah!
Thank goodness for
the chakra of you two!
It's just as I thought!
Yeah well, the both of us
used to be one, after all.
Plus...those two are
father and son.
Naruto...
Huh?
I wish there was more time
to talk to the grown-up you!
Guys don't need to talk!
I already know!
I...already met Mom's chakra...
What you want to say is the same
as my nagging mom, right?!
I already know!
What's your plan, Naruto?
Just...give me some time to focus...
Let me explain what
Kurama and I came up with.
You tell me if
it will work or not, okay?
All right, go ahead!
I'm so sorry, Naruto...
I'm sure you must have had it
real tough up until now!
The real tough part
is about to start, Dad!
This is Naruto's…!
So…it wasn't depleted?!
I noticed it when
I was healing everyone, but…
It seems it had merely shrunk down.
It's bigger and more powerful
than before!
Have ya noticed Eight-o?
I sense two Nine-Tails,
one light and one dark, yo!
This isn't just Nine-Tails.
You're thinking about
protecting us from that attack
with this chakra, Naruto?
Jugo.
Sasuke, this is looking bad.
Let's get outside of this barrier.
Use the Snake Reverse Summoning.
That was my plan already.
I'll take you and Naruto
with me.
I haven't given you
any of my chakra yet.
Get over here, will ya?
What's your chakra
going to accomplish?
There's no time! Just hurry!
I can't believe he shared
his chakra with every shinobi!
He's got almost as
much chakra as us!
No!
Actually, this has
Nine-Tails' chakra mixed in!
That won't help you
withstand the shock wave of
four Ten-Tails' Tailed Beast
Bombs exploding together!
Begone...
What?
What happened?
This chakra protected us again!
Not quite, check it out!
We're...
outside the barrier?
It was the Teleportation Jutsu.
Damn that Naruto!
He's even mastered that too?
This isn't just Naruto's chakra.
He moved everyone using
the Fourth Hokage's Flying Raijin Jutsu!
Fourth…
This is the second time
you've saved all of shinobi-kind.
I've still failed...
more times than that,
so I must continue making up for it.
What did you do?
Dad teleported everyone
outside the barrier.
Everyone? With that jutsu?
I'd shared Kurama's and
my chakra with everyone earlier.
So if Dad, and our chakra
and everybody were to uh...um...
Indirectly…
Right! If we were all
in indirect contact with each other,
it would work.
So, I connected Dad's chakra
with Kurama's and mine.
That's all!
He used the principle
of Shadow Clones.
Even if you split up and
disperse your chakra...
as long as you keep even a little
bit there without putting it out...
when the original body infuses
chakra again to regain control,
all the individual chakra bits
begin resonating and link together.
In short, by joining his chakra
with the Fourth's,
Naruto linked the Fourth
to the rest of his chakra
residing in everyone else.
Right, Naruto?
Huh? Is that what I did?
Never mind…
Old Man Second, you sure know
a lot about my Shadow Clones too!
I created that jutsu!
It's my Shadow Clone Jutsu!
This feeling is so familiar...
Even though we're out of options,
it feels like we can
accomplish anything...
That's right! It's just like
when I was with Kushina!
I feel power welling up inside me!
Let's go!
Naruto's got this much chakra?
Naruto! Letting out a shout
and showing off
is all well and good...
but don't tell me
you've already forgotten...
that nothing other than
Sage Jutsu works against him?
I know you're not an idiot!
That's right!
You're a bigger idiot
than my elder brother!
It looks like you've surpassed
all the previous Hokage, in stupidity!
Shut up! Stupid, stupid Kurama!
Fools are easily liked
and trusted by others.
It'll be all right.
Don't worry about it.
I-I'm not worried that I'm an idiot!
I'm not talking about that.
Huh?
I'm saying that you might
be able to go into Sage Mode
while you're in that state.
Listen up...You've probably
already forgotten,
but during your final battle
with Pain, Nagato...
I got so mad by what he was saying
that my chakra leaked out,
even though you were
in Sage Mode at that time.
My power and your Sage Power
actually managed to synchronize.
You say that, but back when
I was undergoing Sage Training,
you interfered with Gramps Sage's
Sage Jutsu, remember?
That's because I had no interest
in sharing the same space with toads!
Besides, it really pissed me off
that you would rely on Sage Jutsu
when you had my chakra.
You stubborn bastard!
You're the stubborn one!
Anyway, what I'm trying to say is,
that I'm willing to let you use
both my power and
Sage Power right now.
What's stubborn about that,
damn it?!
You just can't be up front about
your feelings, can you?
You bastard! You've been
making fun of me a lot lately!
It's not like that...
It's out of familiarity...
Using Tailed Beast State with
Sage Jutsu at the same time, huh...
You've got the same me
inside you as your son.
You should be able to provide him
with powerful support.
Yeah...
I already know that!
I'll have some jutsu prepared too!
I'm absorbing Nature Energy
a lot faster in this state.
All right!
Naruto, add Sage Jutsu
to the Rasengan!
Okay!
Old Man Second!
Let's do it!
Just forge ahead!
We'll ward off his attacks
with our chakra!
– Rasengan!
That black thing sure is solid!
Damn it...
He blocked us this time!
He predicted our attack...
Using only the Flying Raijin
in our strategy isn't enough.
Our only option is to destroy
that black thing!
But how?
All right, next up...
Let's try adding Sage Jutsu
to a Tailed Beast Bomb!
All right, excellent idea!
You might just surpass
my Elder Brother as Hokage...
Hey, other Kurama! You help too!
I like the sound of that!
This is what Naruto is
capable of now?
He's able to control this much
chakra perfectly...
How far will you...
There's no harm
in taking measures early.
W-What's that?!
He's starting
the Infinite Tsukuyomi already?!
I'll suspend the barrier for now.
Th-This is—!
What?!
Run! It will absorb all your chakra
in one swoop!
It's coming after us one by one!
But why...?!
Why...?! Why do I get so many
coming at me, huh?
Fool...Ya fool!
This is the tree of God.
It's called the Divine Tree!
It's the Ten-Tails' final form!
It knows that you have
more chakra than everyone else!
At this rate, the chakra that Naruto gave
to everyone is meaningless.
W-What is this?!
Chakra first originated with...
this Divine Tree!
All the chakra here...
Even the enormous amounts
of chakra you possess.
What?
Humans stole chakra from
the Divine Tree long ago.
It's just trying to take back
what belongs to it.
What are you talking about?!
The endless passing of time
has cast a fog over the truth.
Do you know how shinobi
came to be, Hashirama?
Long ago, when people didn't
even have a concept of chakra...
...even then, people still battled
each other.
The Divine Tree was never involved
in their battles
and was worshipped as
a sacred pillar.
But one day...
The Divine Tree bore a fruit
that was said to be produced
only once in a millennium.
I don't know what it signified,
but legend dictated
that no one was to ever
lay hands on the fruit.
But one princess, in her desire
to reap the power of
the Divine Tree to win a war,
took and consumed the forbidden fruit.
Afterwards, she gained
the power of a god,
and it was said she quashed
the war by herself.
Her name was Kaguya Otsutsuki.
She was the first human
to have chakra.
Eventually, Kaguya would bear a child
who was born with chakra
already within him.
However, the Divine Tree
came alive
and went on a rampage
in order to reclaim its stolen chakra.
That is the Ten-Tails.
And the one who stopped it
was Kaguya's child.
His name was Hagoromo Otsutsuki.
He was the one who preached
the teachings of chakra,
and was the founder of Ninshu.
He was the forefather of the shinobi—
The man known as
the Sage of Six Paths.
How do you know all of this?!
It was inscribed on
the Uchiha Stone Tablet.
Do I need to explain what happened
to those who tasted of
the forbidden fruit...
for the purpose of ending all conflict?
That's right...
It didn't change anything.
In fact, subsequent wars
become more gruesome!
Upon learning this,
I fell into despair.
There are no such things as true dreams
in this world, Hashirama!
Ever since people tasted that fruit,
humans have been cursed...
And destined to hate
each other even more!
And it is we shinobi
whose very existence
symbolizes that foolishness,
don't you think?
In which case I'd rather...
So relying on the power
of the Divine Tree again
by using a great genjutsu...
Naruto!
Water Style: Severing Wave!
Damn it! There are too many of them!
I might be able to sense Naruto,
but it's useless!
Fourth! Can you teleport directly
to Naruto?!
I can't! That last Flying Raijin
and these vines have drained my chakra!
In that case...
Let go...of me...
Gramps...
Sorry it took so long!
Oh!
Saru!
All right!
We're teleporting out of here!
Have things finally settled down?
Is this what you meant by
"dreams of the far future"?!
Yes...
But it will be a little different.
"A little different"?
When the Divine Tree's bud
finally blooms...
The moon will reflect the eye
at the flower's center, up above...
and the Infinite Tsukuyomi
will be fully activated...
And I...will be the one
to accomplish it.
We're doomed!
This is crazy...
Miss Sakura!
Are you all right, Miss Sakura?
That was a close call, fool! Ya fool!
That was too close!
Is it over?
Now, be still...
You have all...
endured plenty already.
W-What is that?
Katsuyu!
Yes, ma'am!
I shall explain everything!
Are you all right, Sakura...?
Yeah...
The Five Kage will
be here shortly.
Shikamaru!
Hey!
Hey, he looks real bad!
Lady Katsuyu!
Let's begin Distance Healing
immediately!
That's not possible.
Why?!
Even my mini fragments attached
to everyone have been drained...
They have lost their chakra
and died.
That's...
In other words...
Everyone is in the same state
as my fragments.
Sorry, Dad...
Looks like I'll be right
on your heels...
Shikamaru!
Sorry...Mom...
Sakura!
Shinobi are done for.
There's no need to keep going.
If you don't resist, I won't kill you.
Unless you want to
be filled with regret,
stop and do nothing
from here on out.
If we don't do anything,
we'll be saved...?
Yes...
You don't have to fear death
or keep enduring anymore.
You'll be entering a dream.
Do not give up!
If you succumb to a genjutsu,
you're no different from being dead!
This giant tree is closely
connected to Obito...
They're like limbs
that suck out chakra.
We can't approach carelessly.
Such words of weakness.
So very unlike you.
Sarutobi Sensei...
Orochimaru...
You're late...
What of the Five Kage?
I had them healed.
So as long as they don't chicken out,
they should be coming.
As sarcastic as ever, I see.
Sorry I'm late, Jugo! Sasuke!
You're here...
This tree is huge
now that I see it up close.
I wonder how long
it'll take to cut down?
What's going on?
When that bud blooms,
Infinite Tsukuyomi will be complete.
That's what Madara said.
And yet, after depleting
the chakra of this many shinobi...
the bud shows no signs of blooming.
So when is it going to bloom?
The Eight and Nine-Tails still live.
However, if it contains even a small
amount of each of their chakra,
it's fine.
In other words,
it's not like it can't bloom.
All that is affected is how
long it will take to bloom.
There's about 15 minutes to go.
In that time, I shall stop Obito
and switch places with him.
Using your Sage Power.
This is bad.
Everything my original just heard
must be relayed to the Allied Force.
Anyone here belong to
the Yamanaka Clan?!
Here!
Can you do
the Mind Transmission Jutsu?!
Yes, I can, sir!
Good! Please link me
to everyone here!
There are things I'd like to explain
about that giant tree,
and the Infinite Tsukuyomi!
This sensation...
Grandfather!
Ah! Is that you, Tsuna?
This voice is unmistakably
Lord Hashirama's!
This means the Five Kage
are close enough
to be within range of my jutsu!
Oops! We'll have to
reminisce later!
I have things I must relay
to you five and everyone else!
Listen to me carefully!
I'll retrieve a little more chakra.
It's taking too long for it to bloom.
So we're just nourishment
for that tree?
That's what shinobi are?!
Then...how are we supposed to fight it?
If there's only 15 minutes left,
it's crazy!
We can't even get close to it!
And yet, doing nothing will
yield the same result.
We must either cut down that tree or
defeat the caster within
the remaining time.
But...
I told you not to give up hope!
That's what you say...
But you're a reanimated person
from the past!
Brought back to life!
We're still alive!
It's all...over...
If it's going to end like this,
we shouldn't have gotten
started at all...
That's right. Just stay like that.
I'll take you to a world where
there are no regrets.
Naruto, are you done?
Because I'm not.
Let's go, Jugo.
Yeah...
These are...
I can feel them,
these are Naruto's feelings...
coming through my jutsu.
I...
I don't want to regret anything.
I never want to think,
"I should have..."!
Naruto...
And...
I just can't make
everything we've done...
up to this point meaningless!
Sasuke!
I'm coming too!
Naruto Uzumaki...
Time and time again...
Sorry to have to borrow
more chakra.
No worries!
Naruto, we're counting on you!
Hey, Sasuke...
You realize that only Sage Jutsu
works on him, right?!
Don't compare me to you.
Look, Karin...
Isn't that...Sasuke's
Curse Mark patterning?
The Curse Mark is supposed
to have lost its power...
Sage Power is the source
of Jugo's Curse Mark.
And with Sasuke,
back when I experimented with
injecting Jugo's chakra into him,
he immediately unleashed
the Curse Mark.
So it's not surprising
for Sasuke's Susano'o
to adapt to Jugo's chakra
in similar fashion.
In other words, you could call it
a Sage Jutsu Susano'o.
Sasuke Uchiha, huh?
He shows the same potential
that Madara once did...
You Uchiha...
Aim!
Gotcha!
It'll be too late for regrets,
you know.
Not that there's going to be
a future for either of you.
I'm looking forward to
the battles we'll fight...
...up until the time I achieve
my true dream.
What is your true dream?
I thought everything we've aimed for
is here in this village!
You just can't see it.
What's even further ahead...
dreams of the far future.
Then tell me about your dreams
of the far future.
These are Lord First's memories?
Dreams of the future...
The fact that we were able
to convene this Five Kage Summit
with the first Kage of each
of the Five Nations...
truly fills me...
...with gratitude!
Elder Brother!
You are the Hokage, representing
the Hidden Leaf of the Land of Fire!
A person like you, need not bow
to the other Kage!
But...I'm so happy!
Lord Hokage, raise your head...
That's not becoming of
a village leader...
I did indeed come here to endorse
the gist of Lord Hokage's pact,
but I'm not just signing
anything for free.
If you behave too humbly,
you'll make us suspicious.
Distributing the Tailed Beasts that
Lord Hokage has collected
to the other villages
is the condition of signing the treaty.
This is a transaction,
not something to get emotional over.
Exactly, and we'll allocate
the Tailed Beasts based on power,
but you will be acquiring them
for a price.
Not for free?
Shut up!
This was the very first summit!
Yes, and it was what would lead
to the end of minor conflicts.
In our village,
a certain temple's disciples
have long been sealing away
a Tailed Beast.
Since we already have one,
we do not need another.
Instead, we would like
an alternative compensation
for our collaboration in this pact.
Would that be acceptable?
What do you desire?
Our nation is completely
covered in sand.
Thus, we'd like the adjoining Leaf
to share arable land with us
instead of a Tailed Beast.
And the other nations to hand
over 30%
of your Tailed Beast
purchase price as well.
Don't mess around, Kazekage!
What—?!
You overstep your bounds,
Lord Kazekage!
I won't sign on unless
all of you accept these terms!
Mine is a desert-locked nation
with zero fertility!
It's only natural to use my village's
Tailed Beast to full advantage
in dealings with
the four other Great Nations!
We four nations could join up...
and defeat the Land of Wind...
It's true that we've never
gotten along in the past...
But we each did what we did
to protect our brethren and clans.
There were, perhaps,
times when we had no other choice.
And now, today, even if
our Five Nation Treaty comes to be...
I can't say how long it will last...
or if we can even hold to it.
But I have this dream,
That sometime in the future...
There will come a day when
shinobi will collaborate,
and help each other, with one heart,
regardless of their affiliation.
That is my...
My dream of the future.
I ask you to take the first step
toward that dream today!
So please, please, please, please...
I beg you!
All of my, our beloved children!
Now is the time to
take all the pain,
the suffering, and frustration
we shinobi have endured...
and weave it into
Our true dream!
Seems like our generation no longer
needs to talk about that dream.
Am I wrong?
Indeed.
That goes without saying.
But if we don't win here,
it won't come to be!
Tsuchikage is right.
Defeat is not an option.
All right!
We'll spread out and take command...
and draw out the ultimate power
from the Allied Forces!
That is our primary duty
as the Five Kage!
– Scatter!
Sasuke!
I'll keep in sync with you!
You better be prepared...
This is...!
Damn it, Naruto...
You never change.
You're always going overboard...
Sticking your neck out for us...
How far will you go...?
All this time, you've never held back
or compromised when it came to us.
In front of you, I can't complain about
what a drag things are...
Sorry, Dad...
Naruto doesn't want me...
to join you just yet.
Shikamaru, stop talking!
I‘m not letting you die!
Naruto...rather, everybody needs you!
Unlike Lord First, that dumb Naruto
doesn't have an adept brother...
like Lord Second, to be his advisor.
That's why...even more so...
I need to stick around so that
when he becomes the Hokage,
I can stand next to that idiot.
So I'm sorry, Dad...
I can't join you just yet.
There's no one more qualified than me
to be Naruto's advisor.
Naruto, thank you...
Your chakra and the power
of your heart saved him!
Yes! He's rallied!
Thank you, Sakura.
Thank you, Naruto.
Don't overdo it, Shikamaru.
You just might become
my advisor instead!
Don't worry, Akamaru.
It's because a Kage can have
up to three advisors.
I want to stay by Naruto too.
I'll have to work hard!
Shikamaru!
Lady Tsunade!
You did well!
Forgive me, Grandfather.
Tsuna, don't apologize.
I dragged this mess into
my grandchildren's era.
My cowardice is to blame...
But your heart and dreams have
also been passed down
even beyond your grandchildren's era...
Yes, your...
Will of Fire!
Hey!
Why you...!
All right!
Let's cut down this giant tree while
he is distracted by his battle!
No matter how large it may be,
that tree is nothing compared
to this very earth!
And the great earth,
this land is on our side!
– Right!
I'm begging you!
I don't want us killing each other
out of vengeance anymore!
A ninja does not bow
his head so easily!
A ninja values action and strength!
It seems those who become Hokage
like prostrating themselves, but...
As an act that relays one's heart,
perhaps it can lead to strength
and be meritorious too.
Let's go, everyone!
Okay! Double lariat time, bro! Yeah!
– Here we go!
As a woman, I mustn't get
a late start on battle...
All right, everyone. Let's go!
– Right!
Damn it!
Naruto...
You have truly become a necessary
existence to this world...
What the two of us had
always wanted to be.
And you will now save
the entire world, Naruto!
– Everyone, follow me!
– Let's go!
All right, I think I should
get going now.
The springtime of my youth…
hasn't ended yet!
Let's go, Lee! Tenten!
– Yes!
– Right!
Your past is filtering into me
through the others.
Naruto Uzumaki, you are uniting
everyone right now.
Your tempestuous life made you
into who you are.
And your way of life has given
everyone's hearts hope!
Let us pursue hope! Onward!
Let's do it!
Let's go!
Let's cut down that giant tree!
We samurai must not waver either!
Go forth!
Fourth, I'm going to use the link
between your chakra and Naruto's.
I can't move simultaneously like you,
but I'll still help protect them
all with my Teleportation Jutsu.
Orochimaru...
Are you just going to spectate?
I have no interest in this war.
However, this dream of Obito's would
lead to the elimination of this,
my precious laboratory...
So I suppose I cannot support it.
Then lend me a hand.
Fine then.
I'll partake in a bit of nostalgia...
and participate in some
student and teacher teamwork!
I'll shift to a more offensive form!
What is it?!
Do not panic!
It's coming!
Huh?!
What?
I'll use my Teleportation Jutsu
to whisk anyone in danger away.
So go forth without fear!
It's the voice of Lord Second!
We can give it our all.
It's because...
Still, don't get careless!
With two 100 Healings adepts,
we can likely summon
one-tenth of Katsuyu's actual body here
from Shikkotsu Woods!
We'll mold Katsuyu into
the Allied Force's entire footing,
into a Healing Area where one can
be restored just by standing on her.
Ready, Sakura?
Yes!
– Summoning Jutsu!
Ino! Have you relayed that to everyone?
Yes!
Huh? What's that going to do?
Is this it?!
This way, we can fight without
our chakra being stolen!
Oh, this is great!
So this is the Healing Area?!
If you understand,
quit playing around and get going!
Damn it!
He really is fast...!
But...
I'm starting to sense him
better and better!
– Right there!
It's about time that you go to sleep.
Why do you get up?!
And what are you fighting for?
Is it for your comrades?
Or is it for this world?
Listen, friends will eventually betray you.
And this world transforms love
into hatred.
You should know!
In the past, the people of the village
and Sasuke betrayed you.
And your love for Jiraiya
made you hate.
You and I are the same.
The cumulative weight of all
your suffering will change you in time.
And now, even more pain
shall assault you.
And you still insist that
you will not change?!
You don't know when your friends
will betray you again...
Or if the Allied Forces might
go back to fighting each other.
And you don't even know
if you can defeat me!
There is no reason to keep on
fighting for a world like this.
In a few minutes,
this world will be gone anyway.
Why do you still fight?
Because it's my ninja way.
I never go back on my word.
That's my ninja way.
I thought I told you to go to sleep!
Let's settle this with
our next move, Naruto!
Right!
We'll sleep tomorrow,
dreaming our own dreams!
The Susano'o is...
That's...
I believe this is what
Madara did once before.
This is...Naruto and Sasuke?
Nothing you try now
will change anything.
Look above you...
What can you see through
that hole at the top?
I can see what Obito sees...
and hear his voice.
It's resonating.
The moon.
The time to enter
the moonlit dream world nears.
The gaping hole of hell that has opened
will be filled by the moon's dreams...
That time is finally here!
This sword is the divine blade
of the Sage of the Six Paths...
the Nunoboko.
You can no longer defeat me.
Strong emotions dwell within the blade.
It's a sword of the soul.
The Sage created the world
with this blade.
Hey...did you feel that...just now?
Yeah...
Tenten, isn't this...?
Yeah. Let's go, Lee!
He's calling us.
Let's focus everything on
a single blow.
I think we're only gonna have
a tiny window to strike.
Don't miss it.
And I will use this sword
to obliterate this world!
Obito...
Even if it's someone
they used to make fun of...
when people see someone
trying twice as hard as others,
they instinctively start wanting
to lend a hand.
That's because...
people eventually learn
that they only have each other
to fill the holes in their hearts.
I'm giving a Rasengan
to each of you!
Use it to blast through his shield!
This, right?
Can I really do this?
You can!
And he who possesses
a heart filled with comrades...
is truly powerful!
Go get him, everyone!
Why am I...
seeing such images...?
Just like we thought!
The chakra you received
from the Tailed Beasts earlier
reacted to the Tailed Beast chakra
inside him and
you were able to pull it all out
in one shot!
Yeah!
This wouldn't have worked
if the Tailed Beasts hadn't taken a liking
to you back then
and shared their chakra with you.
Now!
You know what to do next, right, Naruto?
It's a tug-of-war!
Just pull the Tailed Beasts' chakra
right out of him!
Yeah!
Damn!
I guess it won't work with One Tail
and Eight-Tails
because we never got their chakra.
One Tail used to be linked to me.
I'll get him.
Gaara!
Come here, Shukaku!
We finally found a weakness,
that's the key!
You can leave Eight-o's chakra to me!
Octopops!
Let's do this, Bee! Don't lose!
Extract them!
Then the only power he'll have left
is the Ten-Tails' shell!
And the Divine Tree's bud
will not bloom!
They've stopped...
Which means...
he's lost control of the Divine Tree!
In other words...
It's because your chakra
is connected to his!
His feelings will flow into you,
but don't let them distract you!
Don't underestimate
the power of the Ten-Tails' Jinchuriki.
I'm equivalent to
the Sage of the Six Paths!
Just keep pulling, Naruto.
Naruto! You're the one
who asked us to lend a hand!
So we're helping out until the very end!
Guys!
And that's not all...
Everyone! Grab onto my chakra!
This one?
All right!
Everyone, we'll do it together
on my mark!
Pull!
Are you saying…
That I…
I've got regrets...?!
You once told me...
"I'm nobody..
"I don't want to be anybody..."
Stop! Don't come into my thoughts!
But the truth is...
You wanted to become the Hokage,
just like me.
It could have even ended up where
I was chasing after your shadow...
since I've always wanted
to become the Hokage.
I threw away the past
and my naïve self!
So don't tell me I'm—
Then why am I able to see this?
You can't hide behind a mask.
You were Kakashi Sensei's friend...
my dad's subordinate...
an Uchiha like Sasuke...
and a shinobi of the Hidden Leaf
who had the same dream as me.
What...What exactly...
do you want with me?!
To remind you that
you are Obito Uchiha.
I told you, didn't I?
I swore I'd tear that mask
right off your face!
Obito Uchiha?
What meaning is there
in that name...
in that existence, now?
I have merged with Ten-Tails.
I have transcended and
attained enlightenment.
I am no longer human.
I will guide mankind to
the next stage.
I possess the same will and body
as the Sage of Six Paths.
I am the Second Sage
of the Six Paths!
Wrong! You are Obito Uchiha!
When our chakra touched earlier,
I saw your past.
Our personal histories and
our dream of becoming Hokage
are the same.
Almost exactly alike.
Neither of us knew our parents.
And we both lost people
precious to us.
Which is why you tried
to scare me
by saying solitude is
my worst nightmare.
In the beginning,
you too wanted to be acknowledged
and praised by others!
That's why you wanted
to be Hokage...
If you're the same as me, that is!
But look at you now!
You've turned all shinobi
into enemies
and you go spouting
some nonsense
that you're doing it for
the sake of the world...
when you're only doing it
for yourself!
No one...
not even those precious to you
would ever acknowledge
this current dream of yours.
You used to have
the same dream as me.
But now you've become
the exact opposite of a Hokage!
It's because you're just
like me that...
No, it's because of that...
That I wanted to see you despair
about this world.
Or...I suppose I wanted
to feel again for myself,
that the path I have chosen
for myself is not a mistake.
When I was fighting you,
you made me recall my youth.
That's why I started wanting
to test you.
To see when you,
someone who's just like me,
would fall to despair...
and abandon your feelings, your past.
It's because we were so alike
that I'm pissed off!
You're just...abandoning everything
and running away!
No...
What I'm doing is no different
from a Hokage's actions.
In fact, I'm doing even more...
I can make peace a reality.
Are you really serious?
Do you really believe that?
You know, Rin, you saving me...
is really the same as
you saving the world.
Hmm?
I mean...
It's because I'm gonna become
the Hokage and end this war!
For me to do that,
I have to stay strong and
healthy in this world.
You get what I'm saying?
Yeah! Though you're not
making much sense...
So...how do I put it...?
If you don't stay close
and keep an eye on me...
I mean...
Well...
Yes...That's how I feel.
There's no need to voluntarily tread
a steep and rugged path,
not knowing what's ahead.
You'll have to step over
the corpses of your comrades.
Anyone would choose a shortcut
with a fixed outcome.
Yes.
The goal a Hokage should
seek is world peace.
What the hell are you talking about?
What I want to know about
isn't a shortcut...
but how to navigate
the steep and rugged path!
Would you still say that
if the final destination...
were the same?
Who can tell in the beginning
which one is the dangerous one?
You never know until
someone starts walking.
The Hokage is someone
who endures the pain
and takes the lead in front
of everyone...
So a Hokage never walks
over his comrades' corpses.
There is no shortcut to
becoming the Hokage!
And there are no ways out for
the one who becomes Hokage!
Isn't that right?
I messed up...
I got some sand in my eyes and...
A scar or two on a man
is a badge of courage!
I was just thinking how
I needed that.
So this wound's...
Ouch!
Don't act tough and
hide your wounds.
I'm always watching you.
You promised me that you would
become Hokage, Obito.
Listen, I want to stop this war too.
I really want to save the world.
So I decided to stick by your side
and watch over you.
You told me saving you
was the same as saving
the world, remember?
Yeah...
Since I'm keeping an eye on you,
you can't hide anything
from me anymore.
Okay! Okay!
Go for it, Obito!
Become Hokage and show me
how you'll save the world.
That's another promise!
Let's go!
You...
You told Kakashi Sensei
you would throw away
all your memories and feelings
about your comrades.
But when you became
the Ten-Tails' Jinchuriki
and were about to
be taken over by it...
Didn't you try to suppress the
Ten-Tails because you didn't want that?
The reason why you beat
the Ten-Tails and could control it
was because you stood firm
on not throwing away the past
and stayed yourself, right?
You just couldn't throw out
the memories of
my dad, Kakashi Sensei or
this Rin person, could you?
That's how you could stay Obito
even after you became
the Ten-Tails' Jinchuriki.
Am I wrong?
But dragging everyone with you
onto your path
and continuing on it
won't be allowed!
I'm bringing you back
as Obito Uchiha...
as a shinobi of the Hidden Leaf...
and you're going to atone
for your sins.
You tried to run away
from every single thing.
I bet this Rin person would say this
if she were still alive...
Don't act tough and
hide your wounds.
I'm always watching.
You're no one else but you,
damn it!
Don't run away!
Come join us...
Obito!
I will never go over
to your side!
I have no regrets with
my path up until now.
I told you I saw everything.
So…
don't…
keep imagining yourself as Hokage!
The person Rin wanted to watch over
isn't the current you…
It was Obito Uchiha.
We're late again because
of you…Obito.
Let's go, Obito.
Sorry! We'll be right there.
Rin…
That's right…
You ought to fill in that hole
in your heart yourself…
Others will be of no help.
So…come over here.
I won't ignore you.
Come…
Obito…
Hold on, Rin!
That's right...Rin won't even turn
to look at the current you.
The one Rin wanted to watch over
is Obito Uchiha.
Enough already…
I am…
Obito Uchiha!
Now just come over, you bastard!
Everyone's power…
Don't you dare underestimate it!
They're out!
– All right!
– We did it!
Yes!
Did I…lose?
Let's go.
Rin…
You kept your promise,
Naruto Uzumaki!
We were lucky.
He did it.
For real.
You're right.
I'm so glad!
Isn't he…?
H-Hey!
Wait, Sasuke!
Where is he?!
Where'd he go?!
Over there! He's still alive!
Right…I've lost…
Kakashi!
Sasuke, we'll talk later.
I apologize for appearing
so suddenly…
But I was once
his classmate and friend…
So please let me
take responsibility for him.
Kakashi Sensei!
He's now—!
Dad!
He's weak now!
Now's the time to finish him!
Let's go!
– Right!
Hold it!
Obito…
When we had that
chakra tug-of-war just now,
I got to see inside your heart.
It seems like my son nagged
and lectured you quite a bit.
I think he might have gotten that
from his mother.
Dad…
But that duty actually falls…
on you.
I think the one who truly
understands Obito
and should talk to him…
is you, his friend…Kakashi.
Isn't that right, Naruto?
Naruto, you two and
the Allied Forces should go
and help Lord First,
and seal Madara away.
Oh, right! We still need
to deal with him!
Let's go, Sasuke!
I think you were younger
than Naruto is now.
Do you remember?
All the missions that
the four of us went on?
As a medic ninja, Rin did
her utmost to protect you two.
She would never have wished
for a situation like this.
But what caused this
is my responsibility.
It's no coincidence that I, who should be
dead, am standing before you two like this.
Perhaps it was Rin
who made it happen…
Her way of scolding me
for failing as your teacher.
I'm sorry I couldn't protect Rin.
Rin…
Rin was my only light and hope.
After I lost Rin…
The world as I saw it, changed.
It became a pitch black hell.
There's no hope in this world.
I took Madara's identity
and walked the world.
But all it did was confirm my belief.
Even with my Sharingan,
I couldn't see anything…
There was nothing to see.
I don't know anything
for sure either…
Then…my new path is—!
Without a doubt,
your path is just one of many.
And it may not actually
be wrong either.
I've thought this world was hell too.
I thought that you had died…
And right after that, I lost Rin…
And I lost Minato Sensei as well.
But…
Even though I don't know
anything for sure…
I tried my best to see
the world with this eye.
I felt that as long as I had
your Sharingan and words…
I could see it.
And what you saw is Naruto?
How can you be sure
his path won't fail?
No…
He may very well fail too.
Of course.
How is Naruto different from me?
Why do you go so far for him?
Because I can say
without hesitation
that he is less likely to fail
than the current you.
Why is that?!
Because if he trips and stumbles
on his path…
I'll help him.
Why would you help him?
He would never give up
on his dreams…or on reality.
That's the kind of guy he is.
Found him!
And the way he forges ahead
draws others towards him.
He makes you want to reach out
when he's about to stumble.
And the greater
the support behind you,
the closer you can get to your goal.
That's the difference.
Massive Rasen Shuriken!
Bigger! We'll go with something
even bigger!
– Right!
Do you really believe
such a thing is possible
in this pitch-black hell?
I'm sure you could've seen it too,
if you had tried.
After all,
you and I have the same eyes.
If comrades that you trust,
gather around you…
hope can take physical form
and become visible.
That's what I believe…
Obito.
Naruto's path…
Take this!
Massive Rasen Shuriken!
That Wood Dragon will absorb
your chakra!
Your chakra-stealing ninjutsu
has now been nullified!
In other words, you can't move
nor will you be able to extract chakra
with your next ninjutsu!
Good timing, son of the Fourth!
Let's get him with this
and seal him away!
Naruto aimed his attack over there,
so that's where Madara is!
Naruto, this way!
Let's go!
Thanks, Sai!
Don't waste any time!
Now's our chance to seal him!
We won't let Naruto's attack
go to waste!
Right!
Without any orders…
without a single word…
Everyone is galvanized into action…
Naruto…
Shukaku…
I'd like to borrow the power of
your Sand to seal Madara.
You mean,
the Grand Sand Mausoleum?
That's right...A giant one too.
I'm not bound to a Jinchuriki anymore.
What makes you think I'd listen
to you after all this time?
I'm not ordering you.
I'm asking you.
If you refuse, fine.
I'll just ask one of the others.
Naruto Uzumaki, huh?
Seems you've become friends
with that Fox Demon's brat, Gaara…
If you're not going to help,
let's talk later.
I'm going.
That tone you're using ticks me off!
As they say, if a fox has
seven tricks, a tanuki has eight!
And I, the Demon Tanuki,
will not lose to a stupid fox!
I'm not doing this
because you asked!
I'm doing this because I want to!
Lead the way.
It's this way.
Now then…
Wait up.
Huh?
We'll help too.
I'm grateful.
Sage Art: Gracious Deity Gates!
Naruto's jutsu didn't bring him down,
but with this,
he won't be able to move at all!
All that's left is to wait for
the sealing shinobi.
Having the Tailed Beasts
extracted from him
means that Obito's...
The Ten-Tails' Jinchuriki aren't
like all the others.
They won't die if
the Tailed Beast is extracted.
It's because the Ten-Tails' husk,
the Gedo Statue remains.
It contains a lot of life force.
Is that true?
How do you know?
Hey, now.
Who do you think scattered us
all across the world
after splitting Ten-Tails' chakra
into nine pieces?
The Sage of Six Paths...
But with nine bodies extracted out
of him all at once,
he'll be so weak it will
be like he's dead.
He won't be able to move
for a few months.
Just as it was for
the old man back then.
So that's how it goes.
Kakashi...
the Tailed Beast inside me
just explained to me...
I was hoping he would atone
for all his past deeds, but...
It can't be helped if you can't move.
Just stay put.
Sensei, please keep an eye
on Obito.
All right.
What are you trying to do?
The same thing the man
I once tried to use...
did to betray me.
It's the Gedo...
Art of Rinne Rebirth.
I feel like I finally understand
why Nagato…
betrayed me back then.
A string of hearts linked together
like prayer beads...
That can be a strong power
as well, huh...
Nagato and Naruto were
both Jiraiya's students.
So you could say
Jiraiya defeated me.
Sensei...
He was also your master,
the one who groomed you
to become the Hokage...
And I...was your student.
A shinobi who gave up
on becoming Hokage...
and cut all his ties.
I won't have much to say
to Rin on the other side.
I'll help you out this time!
Time to switch places!
It's now my turn to attack!
Stop acting tough!
This war is over!
– Sai!
– I know!
Sealing Jutsu!
Crouched Tiger Bullet!
Naruto...
I'm grateful to you.
You even extracted
the Tailed Beasts from Obito...
Saving me the trouble
of weakening him.
Sorry, Obito...
This is the reason
why I was stuck onto you.
Black Zetsu!
W-What the—?!
Okay! Just a little bit longer!
– Art of Rinne Rebirth!
Finally, I can fight for real!