All that's left…is them.
So it really didn't
let the light through…
Finally…
Looks like it didn't affect
that black one.
Sasuke!
What do we do to release everyone
from the genjutsu?!
Rinnegan genjutsu can be dealt with
using Rinnegan, probably.
Which means we need
Sasuke's left eye.
I won't let that happen.
All that's left to do is to
get rid of you guys…
Which I, the savior
of the world will do.
That eye on his forehead!
Be careful.
We're surrounded in all directions
by four of his Shadows.
I know that!
I won't allow you to
do anything further.
I just severed the Karmic Cycle
of this world.
I have freed humankind from
their suffering, pain and their futility.
But all this…is just a lie!
Naruto, you're the one who's
interfering with everyone's happiness.
Just look at this world now. All
fighting between shinobi has ceased.
I've transformed hell into heaven.
I've finally corrected
Hashirama's mistake.
What do you mean by
the First Hokage's "mistake"?
You Hidden Leaf may not
want to acknowledge it,
but Hashirama ultimately failed
in reforming the shinobi world.
In the beginning, both Hashirama
and I had the same goals.
And we worked together.
We tried to change
the shinobi world
that sent out barely grown
children out to war.
The two of us created
the shinobi village.
However, that does not result
in true peace.
People cannot show
each other their true feelings.
Fear, suspicion, and resentment…
…never subside.
My opinions were pushed aside
and the shinobi world moved forward
in accordance with Hashirama's vision.
And what happened because of it?
The fighting between shinobi
hasn't stopped.
Rather than ceasing,
establishing ninja villages led to
an increase in
their military build-up,
which resulted in battles
that turned into great wars…
with countless lives lost.
The battling in what became
the First Great Ninja War…
The Second Great Ninja War…
The Third Great Ninja War…
The fighting never stopped.
That is Hashirama's legacy
to the shinobi world.
Although I admit that I triggered
this Fourth Great Ninja War…
That's right! Because of you,
so many people died!
I did make a proposition to
peacefully hand over the Tailed Beasts.
Right now, everyone is
inside the Divine Tree.
Each one of them,
dreaming their own idyllic dreams.
They are in their own ideal worlds.
Is this your idea of
a perfect world?
You're just deceiving people.
I just want to be the savior
that ends the long history of
fighting amongst shinobi.
Just know this…
It's all over.
You're wrong, Madara.
You are not the savior…
Nor is this the end of things…
I can't…move…
What's going on?
How can you say that you,
unlike Obito,
are able to completely
take advantage of others?
Isn't that presumptuous to think
that you alone are different?
My dear Madara…
You have also been inside
a phantom dream…
Inside a dream that I concocted.
Black Zetsu…
What are you saying?
I created you.
You are my will incarnate!
Wrong again…
My will is…
Kaguya's!
What the hell is going on?
They're having a falling out,
at this stage in the game?
No, that's not it.
He just mentioned Kaguya.
Huh? Kaguya?
What is that?
The one the Sage of
the Six Paths mentioned.
What's up with this guy?
This chakra is ridiculous!
All of Madara's shadows that were
surrounding us have disappeared!
Something's about to happen!
Is he absorbing all the chakra
that's erupting from the ground?
Where is all this thick potent
chakra coming from?
It's probably from everyone trapped
in the Infinite Tsukuyomi!
This is really bad, Sasuke!
This chakra is much stronger
than Ten-Tails'!
Stop them before they move!
Go, Naruto!
You mean while they're
still swelling up, right?
Like two moths flying
into the flame…
I'm going to absorb all the chakra
out of the two of you right now.
Damn it!
Don't, Sakura!
But!
Action without a plan
is meaningless.
Damn it!
I can't move!
Sasuke! If we don't stop him now…
He'll drain everyone else's chakra
before ours and they'll all die!
Don't worry,
no one is going to die.
Even when Kaguya previously cast
the Infinite Tsukuyomi
upon the populace,
she kept them alive and preserved…
…in order to form them
into her soldiers.
"Form"? What do you mean?!
You seem to be denser than Itachi.
How can one use
ordinary people in combat?
You're not saying that—!
She converted them
into White Zetsu.
What's left of those who were under
the previous Infinite Tsukuyomi…
That's what White Zetsu are.
They've been transformed
ever so slowly over time.
Are you saying everyone's gonna
turn into those white things?!
Hey!
Look at how big he swelled up!
He's bloated because his body can't
tolerate the amount of chakra he absorbed!
At this rate,
he's going to explode!
Why?
Why did this happen—?
Hashirama…
Where…did I go wrong?
He's shrinking?!
Obito!
Isn't she the one
Super Gramps talked about?
Otsutsuki…
Kaguya!
Sasuke! Naruto!
The way they are currently,
those two can manage…
But Sakura…
Don't make any careless
moves right now!
These two…
are Hagoromo and Hamura's…
No, rather they're…
Indra and Ashura's…
So it was Hagoromo
who gave them the jutsu…
Sasuke! Naruto!
Thank goodness!
Who is she?
And why did Madara
suddenly become her?
This chakra is far greater
than Madara's…
I can't believe such
a person ever existed.
Hagoromo knew she would appear,
that's why he entrusted us with—
Obito…
What are your intentions?
It's futile to speak to you about that,
when all you do is just tamper
with chakra,
without knowing its true meaning.
This place, this land…
is my precious nursery.
I cannot let it be damaged further.
Let us stop fighting…
Here that is…
I shall erase…
You all here…
No way!
Is that lava below?
Is this a genjutsu?
No…
This feels…
different!
Summoning Jutsu!
Sasuke! Over there!
What're you doing?
Help them, not me!
How did you…?
Kakashi tied one end of a scroll onto
a kunai and used it like a rope.
For Obito, he just pinned him
to the wall with a kunai, however…
way to go, Kakashi Sensei!
Obito…
Sorry for being rough with you…
Oh!
It wasn't a genjutsu, after all…
Don't tell me…
She summoned a different dimension?
Eyes forward, Naruto.
Naruto…
I'm going to be frank with you…
This world will come to an end
if either one of us dies.
Only your Six Paths Power
of the Light Style
and my Six Paths Power
of the Shadow Style,
can seal away that being
in front of us.
If we don't succeed,
mankind will perish.
We can't afford to die,
no matter what…
When the Infinite Tsukuyomi
was launched…
Kakashi and Sakura just happened
to be near you…
That's just how it is.
You understand
what that means, right?
I know.
I get what you're saying
and I know that you're right.
But…this is also a situation when
your body just moves on its own…
Like that time on the bridge.
Well, never mind.
I know that you get
what I mean, Sasuke.
Sasuke's right.
Back then…
Maybe Sasuke acted subconsciously…
Even so…
Thank you…Naruto.
Damn it!
Now's our chance!
Byakugan!
Damn it! My hawk's chakra points
have been hit!
This calls for Susano'o!
Madara's rods are…
I can finally move…
Now if…
If I head to the spot where
I sensed that massive chakra…
I might learn something.
But…the chakra
suddenly dissipated.
They've disappeared…
Did they defeat Madara?
I've got to get to Naruto…
just one more time…
Naruto, you—?!
Huh?
You can levitate?
That's right…
Madara, when he was enhanced
by Six Paths' chakra, also levitated…
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Take care of Sakura and Kakashi Sensei.
Six Paths' chakra…
You act triumphantly just because
you have a special accoutrement.
However…
No matter what kind of chakra…
All chakra belongs to me
and me alone.
Once more…
…I shall reunify all chakra!
Sasuke! Now!
Sasuke!
Damn it! I can't stop!
Even Susano'o doesn't work.
Let's get Obito while
we still have the chance.
I forgot that you could use
Teleportation-like jutsu now.
You had me worried there!
It's like this foothold.
We've both benefitted
from Six Paths' power.
But having received it is meaningless
unless we seal her away.
Yeah!
My children, with whom
I shared my chakra…
I can't move…
Now…come to your mother…
She's taking…our chakra, Sasuke!
Kaguya seems to see
her two children…
when she looks at the two of you.
Isn't that sweet?
She, who was sealed away
by her own children.
Such a poor, pitiable mother…
Why'd Six Paths Super Gramps
seal away his own mom?
I thought he sealed away Ten-Tails…
It appears you have the wrong idea…
Just who and what are you,
Black Zetsu?
I am Kaguya's child.
What?!
His aura seems different,
all of a sudden…
I recorded everything that happened
while Mother was gone.
And molded it as well.
The tale of shinobi…
is the tale of restoring Mother.
Huh?! What're you talking about?!
What do you mean?
Since you know Mother's name,
you must have met Hagoromo.
I knew that it was possible, depending on
the power of the reincarnates.
As well as receiving the power
to seal away Mother…
But we're gonna seal away
the Ten-Tails!
It's rare to see the reincarnates of
Indra and Ashura cooperating this closely.
You two know nothing.
Let me tell you her tale while
I suck out all of your chakra.
Like I told you earlier…
Mother was sealed away previously
by her own children.
Apparently, it was an extremely
powerful seal…
The jutsu transformed Ten-Tails into a
Catastrophic Planetary Devastation core…
…and turned it into the moon.
But just before the seal took hold,
she gave birth to me.
In order that she could
one day be restored.
I shall now show you two
all of that…
I don't have any candy,
but the puppet show is about to begin.
The intense fighting between my mother
and the brothers continued for months.
It took a massive toll
on the land.
And at long last,
the decisive moment came to be.
Hagoromo and Hamura's powers
overcame Mother's.
Now, Elder Brother!
Catastrophic Planetary Devastation!
Mother gathered up every ounce
of energy she had left,
and just before the seal took hold,
she gave birth to me.
You…came out of her?
Even Hagoromo did not
know of this truth…
Nor was he aware that
I was working on
her behalf to restore her.
I split the Ten-Tails
into nine souls.
When you look at them like this,
they're very cute.
What will you do with them?
I will take care of
these Tailed Beasts.
I will raise them to trust humans
and to help them.
Elder Brother, I think I'm going
to stay by Mother.
Hamura?
I felt her emotions.
Mother was afraid all
of the time.
In order to protect us,
Mother only did what
she thought she had to do…
It made me feel that she was just
a woman, alone all by herself.
I guess I love Mother, after all.
Hamura…
You are a kind soul.
Elder Brother…
I will always be up there
in the sky…
watching over the world
you create.
Come visit once in a while.
We won't be that far apart.
I will. Take care of yourself.
And so, that's how the battle between
my mother and the brothers ended.
But I was left, with no power at all.
That is why I went deep
into the darkness,
and carefully planned
my mother's revival.
In the meantime, Hagoromo
was ignorant of all of this
and raised Indra and Ashura.
He even created that Ninshu,
Ninja Creed nonsense.
Time passed and Hagoromo died…
And just before passing away,
he scattered the Tailed Beasts
to various parts of this world.
Two things are required
to revive Mother…
The Divine Tree and Infinite Tsukuyomi
by means of Rinnegan.
But the Rinnegan requires
Hagoromo's chakra,
which he passed on
to Indra and Ashura.
And the Tailed Beasts,
which form the Ten-Tails,
were scattered across the world.
In order to bring Mother back,
all of these things had to be collected.
You can't imagine the amount time
that was required to do this.
So first of all,
in order to regain Hagoromo's chakra,
I took advantage of Indra who
lost the fight over succession.
I tempted Indra.
And later,
I selected Indra's descendants,
the Uchiha to be
the cast of my tale.
I revised the stupid script that
Hagoromo wrote just a little bit.
You mean…?!
That's right.
Hagoromo's Stone Tablet…
I rewrote it to say
the Infinite Tsukuyomi
was the path to save the Uchiha.
I must say…
You Uchiha performed
your parts brilliantly.
Why you—!
Indra and the Uchiha.
Ashura and the Senju.
I was able to set up a pattern
of fighting and power seeking.
Furthermore, time after time,
I'd approach the reincarnate of
Indra and Ashura in each clan…
to attempt Rinnegan manifestation.
But it always ended in failure.
Just with that alone,
a thousand years passed.
But when Madara Uchiha and
Hashirama Senju were reincarnated,
I came to believe…
that Madara could achieve it.
That this was the first step
towards Mother's revival.
However…
Madara Uchiha lost
to Hashirama Senju…
I thought I had to go back
to the drawing board.
But Fate did not turn
her back on me…
Madara's corpse is like
a treasure trove to a shinobi.
Tobirama, who had been studying
the mysteries of the Sharingan,
stopped short of disposing his corpse.
And instead, hid Madara deep
within the mountains of the Leaf Village.
But Madara was no fool…
He figured that if he lost
to Senju in battle,
Tobirama would not
get rid of his body.
So he placed a jutsu on himself.
You can invoke a time-delay spell in
one's eye using the Mangekyo Sharingan.
Just like the way Itachi implanted the
Amaterasu with a time delay in you, Sasuke.
Madara had installed
the Izanagi in his right eye.
At the cost of his right eye, Madara
rewrote reality and returned to life.
He then passed off
a shadow clone as his corpse.
He vomited the flesh he bit off of
Hashirama, and grafted it on his wound.
After that, Madara awakened
his Rinnegan…
and summoned the Gedo Statue.
He then cultured Hashirama's flesh
using the Gedo Statue,
in an attempt to prolong
his life further.
Those goblins, the White Zetsu,
seemed to be an incidental
by-product of that.
But they were actually the people
put under the last Infinite Tsukuyomi,
whom I extracted from the statue.
I just made it look that way.
"Two polar opposites operating together
gives rise to all things in this universe."
Just as it was inscribed
in the Stone Tablet,
Madara solidified his attachment
to Hashirama.
I began formulating a plan…
to collect the Tailed Beasts
by making it look like
I was born out of Madara,
and to also manipulate Obito.
I formed the Akatsuki and
steered them towards war.
In order to increase
battle strength,
I deliberately let Kabuto
discover Madara's corpse…
And in addition,
I guided him to use Madara's corpse
as a bargaining chip,
and made Obito cooperate.
This war went exactly as I planned.
The Infinite Tsukuyomi was
launched during this war…
And by amassing a large amount of the
human chakra that had been scattered…
Mother was restored.
I…
Detest you.
Hagoromo…
Hamura…
You…
are mine.
My role has come to an end.
You shall return with me to
the almighty god that is Mother.
You two aren't…
You two alone aren't the entirety
of shinobi history!
Besides…
moms are supposed to be happy
about their kids leaving the nest!
That's what being a mom means!
Your teenage rebellion continues.
Mother is the very progenitor of chakra.
You brats can't hope to
accomplish anything.
Naruto, we need to make an opening,
so we can launch the Sealing Jutsu.
Yeah!
And the only thing that will work…
is that jutsu!
"That" jutsu?
Yeah…
Sasuke, hear me out.
I don't know what you're scheming,
but Mother absorbs all jutsu.
Your actions are meaningless.
How is it going?
Looks like they're just staring
each other down.
I see…
The power to forcefully drag us all
into this dimension, that isn't genjutsu…
This is on a totally different scale.
She's like…
…a god.
How do you plan on fighting
someone like that, Naruto?
This could be the end…
But we gotta give it our best shot.
Just like we've been
doing all along, right?
Are you serious?
We won't know unless we try.
I've been secretly
practicing this jutsu
even more than the Rasengan,
ya know?!
It's worth giving it a shot, right?
If there's a chance
it'll create an opening…
Fine. I'll get my left eye ready.
Let's do it!
Yeah!
Amaterasu!
They're making a move!
Take this!
Sexy Jutsu:
- Reverse Harem Jutsu!
Sexy-type jutsu tend to work better
on stronger opponents, ya know!
That idiot! Using a jutsu like that
in this situation?!
That might work on me,
but there's no way that jutsu
will work on someone so god-like!
It worked?!
You may be the progenitor
of chakra or whatever…
But I'll bet you've never seen
a jutsu like this!
This is the history of shinobi, ya fool!
The number one most unpredictable…
Don't tell me that
Naruto's Pervy ninjutsu
is going to save the world!
Master Jiraiya, are you watching?!
Now, Naruto!
Right!
It's cold! What's going on?!
Ice?
It changed!
This place…
Did we shift dimensions again?
There's no mistake that
this is our enemy's ability.
To be able to rewrite the world
in an instant and make it reality…
This really is just like genjutsu.
An ice world this time?!
On what principle?
She vanished!
This ability…
Can she move across dimensions?
Why that—!
Amaterasu!
Flame Control!
Thanks, Sasuke!
Sorry the Sexy Jutsu didn't work.
I never really expected that
kind of jutsu would work.
This time, we're going
with my strategy…
Help me out.
Mother...These two
are quite annoying.
Why don't you split them
up already…
and take them on separately?
Where am I?
Sasuke!
Damn it!
Now you won't be able to
seal Mother away.
First, I'll suck out all
of your chakra!
You have nice reflexes.
First, I have to find Sasuke!
This child is fast.
So I guess I won't be able to tell
where she's gonna strike from…
What is that?
Is it possible that…
we're the only ones
who were brought to this world?
No. The real me is here too.
But I can't sense Sasuke.
Where am I?
Obito!
Is that you, Kakashi?
I thought I died…
I healed you.
Naruto!
But…
Yeah…
I know.
What happened to Madara?
Did you take him down?
No, things ended up
a little differently.
I'll explain it simply.
Might as well tell you guys
about The Sage of the Six Paths
and Kaguya too, and that seal!
I don't know what happened,
but I assume you didn't defeat
the enemy yet?
Take me to where the fight is.
You can tell me on the way.
Nothing seems to work…
It's hard to believe.
So both your powers and
Sasuke's are necessary
in order to seal away this Kaguya?
Yeah!
But like I said earlier,
I can't sense Sasuke at all!
The ice…is moving.
Over there!
She's merged with Nature!
Naruto!
She's finally showing herself.
What's happening?
That's a form of Time-Space.
Okay...I've made it look
like I'm restrained…
I'll just wait until she gets closer!
You said you suddenly
stopped sensing Sasuke?
Yeah.
I suspect he was taken
to another dimension.
She emerged from
a different Time-Space.
It's similar to
my own visual prowess.
Can you enter it?
If I resonate my Kamui
the next time she connects and opens
a portal to another Time-Space,
I'm positive I can enter it.
If Sasuke is there, I can bring him back
to this dimension.
All right!
Then I'll go and support
the real me.
However…
I'll need an enormous amount
of chakra to do it…
since it's not
my own Time-Space.
If my chakra runs out
while I'm there, I'm done.
Then I'll go with you.
The real me won't go down
that quickly.
Because I'm strong.
Your clone chakra isn't enough.
Would it still be inadequate with
my 100 Healings chakra?
That would give me
the bare minimum.
Both of you, come with me.
All right!
We don't even know if
Sasuke is in that Time-Space.
But we'll start by getting
into close range with her.
I promise to find Sasuke,
and deliver him to the real you.
Obito.
Thanks for rescuing me…
And Sasuke too.
Don't thank someone like me.
Just keep an eye on the enemy.
So no more masks, huh?
I'm…Kakashi's friend,
your father's subordinate,
I'm an Uchiha just like Sasuke…
and…
The Hokage is someone
who endures pain
and takes the lead
in front of everyone…
There is no shortcut to
becoming the Hokage!
There are no ways out for the one
who becomes the Hokage!
The way he forges ahead
draws others towards him.
He makes you want to reach out
when he's about to stumble.
I…
I am your senior who dreamt
the same dream as you.
I'm not going to waste time on a
speech, because I'm almost out of time.
But…I just ask that you
let me walk in front of you…
and die for you.
I'm sorry I'm late.
Have you learned anything yet?
There's no one here.
Just the lower half of Madara's body.
Does finding Madara's lower half mean
that we should
consider him dead?
I have a bad feeling about this…
Either way, it seems he completed
his Infinite Tsukuyomi.
And apparently,
it doesn't affect us dead…
In order to verify Madara's status,
and find out what happened,
we should use his lower half
to revive him with the Reanimation Jutsu.
Then we'll make him talk.
To do that, we'd need
a living sacrifice!
How can you be
so naïve at this point?
There has to be another way!
You truly are a kind soul,
previous reincarnate of Ashura.
Wh-Who are you?
My name is Hagoromo…
As the founder of Ninshu,
the Ninja Creed…
I am also known as
The Sage of the Six Paths.
You're The Sage of
the Six Paths?
Indeed I am.
Right now, Naruto and
Sasuke have taken on
Ashura and Indra's souls and
are battling my mother Kaguya…
Ashura?
You just called me
the "previous reincarnate"?
Yes…
Ashura and Indra are my two sons.
And Kaguya, the one who's
fighting right now, is my mother.
What?!
So Ashura and Indra's souls
are connected to you too.
Their souls have transmigrated
over and over again.
The soul of Ashura was
previously inside you,
and Indra's soul was inside Madara.
Inside of me?!
Mother took advantage
of their souls,
and after an extraordinary
length of time,
she was resurrected.
Right now, I know everything, even
the intentions of the one called Zetsu,
my mother's third son
who possessed Madara.
In order to save
Naruto and Sasuke,
you, too, must know everything
that has occurred.
I see…
Sasuke and Naruto are in
an alternate Time-Space
as well as Sakura and Kakashi.
Naruto and Sasuke are
the core participants in the battle.
I wish we could have gotten
your advice and aid a bit earlier.
This lower body is a part of Madara
after he became the Ten-Tails' Jinchuriki.
In short, it contains Ten-Tails,
Madara and Hashirama…
No, rather Nine-Tails, Madara
and Hashirama.
No, rather Nine-Tails,
Indra and Ashura.
I'm only able to emerge like this now
because their chakra is finally one.
Going back to the jutsu
you mentioned earlier,
just what exactly are you doing to do?
I will weave the signs for the jutsu.
But this jutsu requires
a vast amount of chakra…
which I don't have right now
since I've given it away.
There's very little time.
I ask you to just do as I say.
Keep a hand on me,
so we can teleport to a different
Time-Space at any moment.
Got it.
She knows about us, after all.
We have to keep in mind that even if
we jump into her dimension with Kamui,
she'll perceive us.
So we're not worth her attention, eh?
Yeah, come over here.
What you want…
is my chakra, right?!
Whatever jutsu I use,
she's just going to absorb it.
So what will work best
on her is also…
a feint and taijutsu!
I can't use a pervy move
to distract her anymore.
So I gotta go back to the basics
and corner her!
If she tries to escape through that
weird window again, I'll enter it with her.
This is my Time-Space.
You are powerless here.
Are you ready, Naruto?
Yeah!
I'm going to boost your chakra
to the boiling point!
Vapor Style: Unrivalled Strength!
All right!
A-Amazing…
I infused chakra for you, Naruto!
Thank you, Kurama!
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Right now,
this place is my Time-Space!
U...
zu...
ma...
ki!
Naruto
Uzumaki
Barrage!
It opened!
The real me will go!
He forced his way in?
Impossible!
He disappeared?
Looks like several managed
to get in.
The other two ran out of power
and faded.
Seems your clones didn't
have enough chakra.
Are you the original Naruto?
So what if I am?
Mother, he's made it all the way
into this Root Time-Space.
It's not good that
he's here in this place
that connects directly
to the other five Time-Spaces.
He might be able to get
to where Sasuke is,
using the resonance of
the dual opposite powers.
Take that weird jutsu earlier,
this shinobi Naruto has
always been unpredictable.
We ought to just…
kill him right now!
We can't do that.
I must absorb
those children's chakra.
You use a huge amount of chakra
whenever you change
the Time-Space of the world, Mother.
You need to preserve the chakra
you've got for an emergency.
It's better if you don't keep
engaging him.
If you get sealed away,
all will be for naught.
No doubt,
you'll lose a lot of chakra.
But you don't need his!
It's better than having our long-
cherished plans turn to dust.
You're right.
We can kill him with this!
Murderous Bone Ash!
Die!
Now all of his clones in the
Ice world should be gone as well!
Thanks to Naruto,
we were able to successfully hide
inside my Time-Space.
But he's gone, even as a clone.
You're the only one
I can rely on, Sakura.
I know!
Looks like we succeeded
in getting in, Obito.
We killed the original!
So why aren't they gone?
The real me will go!
Damn it!
Are you okay, Naruto?
How is this okay?!
Never mind. Just be ready
when Kaguya comes back.
The Kamui worked.
They're onto us!
I'll draw their attention,
so you two go hide
in the meantime!
I've marked this spot,
so I can hide in my Time-Space
for the time being.
You too, Sakura!
The other two ran out
of power and faded.
Seems your clones didn't
have enough chakra.
Are you the original Naruto?
So what if I am?!
So they were just
clones back there.
You fooled us.
You got me.
I'm…
the original.
I've gotta fight smart
and keep them busy
so they don't go back over there.
This Time-Space should be
connected to the others.
We'll open them one by one
and look for Sasuke.
Right!
I'll give him all the chakra I've got!
What an incredibly vast Time-Space…
To be able to connect them
in an instant.
Just who is this Kaguya?!
Isn't that where we were before?
I can't sense Sasuke in there!
Are you all right?
On to the next!
Yes!
What is…that?
He's not here either.
You should rest a bit.
What about chakra?
Oh...I still have reserves.
Keep enough to get back.
If worse comes to worst
and we can't find Sasuke…
We'll find him!
Next!
Be careful about making
a gateway, Mother.
Naruto will get closer to Sasuke.
Plus, I've figured out something.
The original Naruto has
Truthseeker Orbs around him!
A sea of acid!
Are you okay?
I'm fine!
This is nothing.
You are a medical ninja,
aren't you?
I'll wait until you heal your wound.
That place wasn't
the right one either.
After we rest a little, we'll…
Don't worry about it!
There's a limit to our chakra, right?
Why don't you tend to
your wound?
Just a little will…
I don't want to waste this chance
that Naruto gave us!
He's here!
Sasuke!
Over here! Hurry!
Damn it!
Sasuke!
Cha!
No way…
How did you do it?
It's one of my abilities.
I can shift myself between spaces,
although only over a finite distance.
But I made it here,
thanks to that.
This man lent me his power.
That's how we were able to get here.
He did?
Oh no…
Damn it...I can't…
Not until I can bring them back…
Hang on!
Will I…
break my promise again?
Rin?
There's still something I must do.
We're going back, you two.
Hang on to me.
All right!
There's no mistake.
Those things…
They cut down
the Shadow Clones earlier.
The Clones are desperately
protecting that one.
There's no mistake, Mother.
The one with the Truthseeker Orbs
behind him is the real one!
There's no end to them!
Am I powerless to do
anything but watch?
What am I doing wallowing,
when Naruto's fighting so hard?
That's why I'm never any good.
There should be something
I can still do!
Obito!
Impossible!
It's Sasuke!
He's here!
Now, there's nothing to worry about.
No way!
Naruto!
Why you!
He passed the Truthseeker Orbs
to a clone?
We fell for something so simple!
Thank you, Sakura and Obito!
What? You're okay?
You scared us there!
Sasuke!
Did you thank
Sakura and Obito properly?
Focus on the enemy!
Well, Naruto was always
unexpectedly cunning.
Mother…
Since they've reunited,
we have no other choice.
We can't afford to be stingy
with our chakra.
I know that.
My body feels so heavy.
This terrain…
is digging into my body!
I can't levitate!
A heavy gravity plane this time!
Except…
She's affected too.
Oh no!
Damn it! The visual prowess
in my left eye hasn't…
Dodge it, Sasuke!
Is the heavy gravity distorting your aim?
I've now adjusted for it.
I won't miss with the next one.
I won't let you!
There's something that I can still do.
I can at least be a shield for them!
– Let me make it in time!
– Rin!
Again, you…
Thank you, Rin.
Obito and I will be joining you soon.
We can catch up then…
together, the three of us.
Rin…
This time, when I get there…
Let's spend some alone time together,
just you and me.
Kakashi would just be in the way.
I'm gonna leave him here.
This is…Kamui!
Obito! You!
Kakashi...You stay here
a little while longer.
Don't you rush to follow us!
Why?
I thought we had both resolved to…
Your power is still needed here!
We need to rebuild chakra again.
Mother, let's teleport to
the Root Time-Space…
You'll recover faster there, too.
Why would you do this
for someone useless like me?
Never mind that.
Kakashi, be wary of the enemy.
Naruto, Sasuke, and Sakura…
This is a crucial time for them.
Kakashi, you must survive
and support the next generation.
It's too soon for you to die.
It's totally useless, Naruto.
He's a goner.
He'll rot away like trash and die.
Enough, Naruto.
He's right.
Don't waste your chakra.
Why do you sympathize with him?
He was originally your enemy, right?
Then again,
he's a traitor to us now.
A loser on both sides.
Hated and resented
by friend and foe alike,
with no one to call
comrade or family…
He's alone, with nothing left.
He's lost everyone precious to him,
and he can't realize his dreams.
And after being used up,
he's helpless at the end…
He's a fool, filled with
nothing but mistakes…
You've done nothing but—!
You're right…
It's an end worthy of
the criminal that I am.
My visual prowess is back!
We've been here before!
Did she change worlds again?!
Naruto!
Naruto, I'll handle
the diversions this time.
He's beyond help.
Come with me.
I'm going on ahead!
Damn it! Damn it!
Damn it!
That's enough.
Thank you, Naruto
After fighting you,
I feel like I've woken up.
Imagining the village, friends,
and me as the Hokage…
Even after all that's happened…
Just the thought of it seems to
fill up the hole in my heart.
Maybe it's because it's the end,
I find myself rambling all of a sudden.
Ouch!
Don't act tough and
hide your wounds.
I'm always watching you.
You promised me that
you would become Hokage, Obito.
Listen, I want to stop this war too.
I really want to save the world.
So I've decided to stick by
your side and watch over you.
You told me saving you
was the same as saving
the world, remember?
Yeah!
Since I'm keeping an eye on you,
you can't hide anything
from me anymore.
Okay! Okay!
Go for it, Obito!
Become Hokage and show me
how you'll save the world.
That's another promise!
Let's go!
A lot more suffering
likely awaits you, Naruto.
But don't ever change
and hang on to your ninja way.
You once told me that
never going back on your word
is your ninja way, right?
Yeah…
Naruto…
You better...
become Hokage!
Yeah!
The vermin traitor has
finally died, eh?
He was vermin and
persistent as a cockroach.
Don't laugh at Obito!
Naruto…
If you keep resisting,
you'll end up pitifully crumbling
to ash just like him!
As someone who tried
to become Hokage,
Obito is nothing but…
awesome to me!
I can't move!
I don't even have
much strength left,
and yet, I was left behind again?
Rin!
I've been waiting.
Really?
Sorry, I made you wait.
Seems you got lost along the way.
Yeah…
A lot of things happened
before I could come here.
Rin, you know...
that promise I made to you…
No, you did your best!
I've been watching you all along!
Let's go!
This is embarrassing…
Screwing up like that in front of you.
It looks like
you've calmed down a bit.
Okay, Obito.
Rin, do you mind waiting
just a bit longer?
Obito?
Only a little bit before
we move on…
I'd like to make one more
detour along the way.
Who do you want to save this time?
Kakashi.
I've finally gotten alone time with you.
It'll be wasted if he ends up
coming here right away.
Besides...He's out there helpless.
Just like his namesake, he's a scarecrow
in the middle of a garden…
And I'm sort of annoyed by it.
Despite all that's happened,
you two are still close, huh?
N-No way!
We're oil and water!
So?
You can go just like that?
Yeah…
Chakra is an energy
that connects two worlds.
I'm gonna go see Kakashi!
I'll be waiting right here.
Sorry, Rin!
I'll be right back!
Obito?!
Before I go to the next world,
I thought I'd emphasize to you…
to not to come
running after me so quickly.
Besides, it's going to
keep bothering me
if this eye I gave you to
celebrate your promotion to jonin,
came back to me.
Obito, you…
Then again, it's not like I'll be
springing back to life anymore.
More importantly,
you know how I told Naruto
to become Hokage?
I meant to say as the Seventh.
You be the Sixth Hokage, Kakashi.
I know you haven't taken office yet,
but I'm giving you your gift now.
It has a fixed time limit,
but it isn't useless.
Do you get what I'm saying?
I mean…you haven't forgotten
your famous nickname
that's known throughout
the lands, have you?
That name, Kakashi of the Sharingan!
Let's do this, guys!
Mmhm.
Yes!
Yup!
All right!
Roger.
Sure thing!
Gotcha!
Yeah!
Here we go!
Sage Art: Super Tailed Beast
Rasen-Shuriken!
Nice, Naruto!
There's no way they can
come out of that unscathed.
Oh no! Don't tell me Mother's—!
What's that?
She turned into
another gigantic thing?
What is that?
A wolf? Tanuki?
Badger? Or a rabbit?
It doesn't matter.
Now it's easier to get close.
And it'll be easier to seal her!
Are the Tailed Beasts
within her resonating
in response to Naruto's attack
and starting to split apart?
They're not stable!
Sasuke, don't get grabbed
by that white hand!
It will absorb you instantly!
And it's fast too!
I know that!
Sasuke!
Protect Sakura with
your visual prowess!
All right, way to go!
A Susano'o?! Whose was it?
W-What? That wasn't you?!
What's going on?!
Kakashi Sensei!
Thank you…Obito.
That's impossible. No way!
Sure it is!
We are talking about the Copy Ninja,
Kakashi of the Sharingan!
But he shouldn't have
the Sharingan anymore…
I don't get it, but he saved me!
You watch along with me.
This time, I'll protect them…
and the world!
Here it comes!
How about this?
Combining the power
of the Kamui into…
shuriken!
Kamui Shuriken!
Just as I thought…
Gaining Six Path's power enhances
one's visual prowess too!
This power…
It's Obito's Sharingan?
But why does
Kakashi Sensei have it?
Wow!
That's more amazing
than yours, Sasuke!
This chakra is—!
This Root Time-Space is
Mother's exclusive domain,
where she can
directly extract chakra
from shinobi trapped in
the Infinite Tsukuyomi!
The Tailed Beasts are now stable,
and Mother has even produced
a Truthseeker Orb…
An Expansive Kekkei Moura
Truthseeker Orb
that contains
each and every nature…
Wind, fire, earth, lightning,
water, shadow, and light.
It is the beginning of
a new Time-Space.
And you all will
become its sacrifice!
That thing!
It's the same sphere
as the one behind me!
The difference in size is too drastic!
And it's growing rapidly!
I definitely can't teleport away such
a gigantic object with the Kamui.
Even if we get out of this Time-Space
and escape temporarily…
If that thing becomes too big,
we won't be able to return here.
In order to stop that…
We need to seal
that Rabbit Granny away right now!
You're right.
Gather 'round. I've got a plan.
This will be our last mission
as the former Squad 7!
We're going to save the world!
Yeah!
Roger!
I am immortal.
If either of you die,
you cannot seal me away.
Now then...
Which shall it be?
You're mine, damn it!
No, we attack her together.
She's scared of being sealed
and her attention will be divided!
Take me part of the way.
Then I'll fly the rest of the way.
Right!
So fast!
Mother just gained more power.
Both her power and speed
are now exponentially greater!
Being able to pass through things,
really is a handy ability, Obito…
And now, I can resurrect this move too!
Kamui Lightning Blade!
Mother!
This is bad!
Her right arm!
There's not enough time to escape
into another Time-Space!
Then!
So they were both
Ashura's reincarnates, after all.
They must have,
switched back then.
So then, the one on the right
is the real one!
Kamui!
Not good.
Don't forget about me!
We're both women,
so don't mock me!
Naruto…Sasuke…Sakura!
You guys make
a nice picture right now.
I really love you guys!
Now!
Cha!
All right!
Six Paths Planetary Devastation!
To think that I,
the originator of chakra…
would be defeated by pieces of
my own chakra, again…
Why?!
Hmm? They've done it!
All that's left is to bring
you all back!
Is the ground being
sucked up towards her?
We finally made it out!
Kurama, your Jinchuriki's pretty good.
Over here!
Sasuke!
What happened to Naruto?
He went off by himself, saying there
was something he had to take care of.
More importantly, we need to
get farther away from here!
At this point, it can't be helped.
I'll just start over and work on
Mother's next resurrection!
That reminds me,
you don't like being separated
from your mom, right?
D-Damn you!
I haven't forgotten about you.
Hiding in the shadows
and creeping around for all this time!
You!
You're just a piece of
the shinobi history I created.
A brat like you could never…!
History?
Shinobi history…
consists of all sorts of ninja's lives,
and deaths!
Many shinobi taught me
what it means to be a shinobi.
The pain and sadness of death…
the tragedy of war.
And not only that!
They taught me the joy of
being accepted and being loved!
The way they lived…
and the way they died…
made me who I am!
They taught me and trusted me!
You're a brat who
can't even leave the nest!
Get over yourself!
It's still growing.
It's like a moon.
Guys!
It's over.
The seal is complete!
We can finally celebrate!
You're right.
The first thing I want is a hot bath
to wash away all
this sweat and grime.
Hold on a sec!
What about us?!
How are we supposed to
get out of this Time-Space?!
Oh no! You're right!
This is bad! This is bad!
He does whatever
needs to get done.
But he's still pretty dumb, isn't he?
Summoning Jutsu!
Welcome home, Naruto.
Dad…
Naruto, who's this?
Six Paths Super Gramps!
Which means…
That's right,
you're back in your world
through a Summoning performed
by all prior Five Kage together.
I called all of
the previous Five Kage
from the afterworld to help.
Naruto, Sasuke…
and the rest of you…
Excellent work saving the world.