Retreat...Retreat!
The chakra threads of world-class
Puppet Masters can control humans
as well as their puppets.
But once the chakra thread is cut,
there's no harm to the human.
I'm indebted to you.
I was about to slay an ally.
There's a special way to fight
between Puppet Users.
And I'm the only one here
who can do this…
Right, Granny Chiyo?!
Your technique is as sharp as ever.
But you don't have any fighting spirit!
I guess Puppet Masters aren't good
at being a puppet, eh?
Inexperienced ones shouldn't act
as if they know…
Don't make light of
the Reanimation Jutsu.
If the user of the jutsu gets serious…
Oh, speak of the devil!
Reverse Secret White Technique:
Esematsu's Ten Puppets!
What?!
Wires?
Wha—?!
So he shares a love and
passion for puppets,
just like Sasori did?
Sasori's soul dwells in
these two puppets!
And his love instilled the souls
of his parents in them too!
Sasori, at least, was able to feel it.
Puppets with souls?!
That's not all, Granny Chiyo…
The love you gave to
his Father and Mother puppets
became a part of their souls.
Huh?
Sasori was aware of that.
And he gave them all to me…
Rather, he entrusted them to me for
future generations of the shinobi world.
Passing it on is our duty too.
Sasori did that…?
Sure, I'm inexperienced and
in your eyes, a stranger.
But my kid brother…
Gaara received your soul
and came back to life.
So I'm not a stranger at all.
And I can sense it through
the chakra threads.
Sasori and his mother and father…
The family's thoughts, their love…
Their souls are saying…
"Please stop Granny Chiyo!"
We can't retreat any further.
We'll have to make our stand here!
I agree.
First, the two of us will launch
long-range offensives.
We'll see how the enemy responds!
They were slowly retreating,
but it seems they've made up
their minds.
Fighting those from other villages
is understandable.
But we are forced to
bring ourselves
to take on shinobi from
our homelands.
Damn that brat Orochimaru
for controlling us!
He will regret this!
I never saw eye to eye
with you before,
but for the first time,
I agree with you.
Do not lament.
I'm certain our children have grown
and surpassed us.
I hope you are right…
Here they come.
First, two of them.
Look at those
amazing waves of sand!
This is Shukaku…
The power of the One Tail…
So they're starting off with
the Playing Possum Jutsu?
Gold Dust?
I see…
You were the shinobi
who manipulated Gold Dust
with the Magnet Style…
It stopped.
Gold Dust is heavier than sand…
If I mix Gold Dust into
the sand, I can slow it down.
I'm impressed that you knew
how to counter it.
When Shukaku the One Tail
would go on a rampage,
I'd stop his sand like this.
It's not Shukaku…but Gaara?!
From above…
You've aged, Ohnoki!
Do you owe your long life
to the Particle Style?
– Particle Style:
– Atomic Dismantling Jutsu!
My predecessor's Particle Style…
is as powerful as ever.
The sand is even more powerful
than before…
Wait for the signal.
Particle Style…
Don't tell me that's
your former pupil, the brat Ohnoki?
Now I really feel like
I traveled through time!
It's been a while…Father.
Gaara...Where's Shukaku?
He's long gone.
I am no longer the Jinchuriki
that you created, Father.
You're no longer a Jinchuriki?!
What do you mean?
The ones that are controlling you
extracted the Shukaku from me.
That killed me once.
But thanks to Chiyo and my friends,
here I am, alive.
Granny Chiyo...She did that?!
You have friends?!
You thought he'd have no friends?
Man, he must've been
some lonely kid, huh?
At that age,
everyone has friends.
Father, you tried to kill me
six times.
And each time,
my fear and hatred of you grew.
But I no longer hate you.
I can understand why you did it.
I am the Kazekage now.
It is a leader's duty to eliminate
threats against one's village.
We must protect it.
You are…the Kazekage?
That's not all.
He is also
the Commander-in-Chief of
the Allied Shinobi Forces'
Main Battle Regiment.
Despite his age,
he not only calls himself Kage,
he has the respect of
all the other Kage as well.
No wonder…
I thought it was odd
I sensed chakra types
from various villages mixed together.
Imagine that, shinobi
forming an alliance.
Not having eyebrows makes
a face more charismatic…
Oh hey,
I don't have eyebrows either.
Then what about that wisp
of a moustache, Mizukage?
Guys, if you're going to kill us,
start with the mummy here!
I'll be more than happy
to root for you.
He's your son, huh.
He's a fine shinobi.
He's small…
So he was premature?
Are you sure he'll be all right?
He's adapting.
At last, with the third child,
we know he's compatible.
This child must be brought up
with great care.
Please let me see…
my child's face.
Are you all right, Karura?!
He's…so tiny.
Lady Karura's heart rate
is dropping.
Do something! Quick!
This child is a failure as well.
The rampages have begun.
If we can't maintain
our defenses further
the Sand will be weakened
beyond repair.
We need to figure out how
we can negotiate with other lands,
and we have to do something
about the Shukaku.
As long as the Jinchuriki is unreliable,
we must rely on Lord Kazekage's
development of new jutsu,
and in our gold dust trade
for village stability.
As for Gaara…
Yashamaru, I need to speak
to you later.
Yes…
But Lord Gaara is still a child…
Over the years, I've had to judge
the value of many things.
And I must test his worth too.
We will assess Gaara tomorrow.
After the village has been evacuated,
corner Gaara.
Tell him about his mother,
and provoke him emotionally.
If he doesn't go berserk,
I won't kill him.
About my sister?!
Are you sure about this?
I know that he loves and
respects Karura with all his heart.
If that is taken away from him,
and if he can still suppress his rage…
then and only then,
will he suffice as a Jinchuriki!
This Reanimation Jutsu may have
some merit, after all.
Let me see what
you may be worth!
Can you defeat me?!
Everyone, go!
Let's go!
– Right!
Sand Hail!
Damn it!
Sand Hail is just a diversion.
He used it to force me to
lift the Gold Dust!
Karura...You still live on
inside this child…
That really is our old man…
You've grown, Gaara.
All a parent needs to do is
to believe in their children.
Just that little bit is
the most valuable treasure.
Isn't that right, Karura?
It seems I didn't possess the ability
to see the true value of things…
What do you mean?
No matter when or what,
the Sand will always protect you.
That's not the Shukaku's power.
But it's your mother's…Karura's.
He's so tiny.
No matter what happens,
I will always protect you, Gaara.
Your mother loved you!
Mother…loved me?
But that day when Yashamaru
came after me, he said…
You were never…loved.
I ordered Yashamaru to lie to you.
In order to provoke you,
and to test the volatility of
the Tailed Beast inside you…
For the sake of the village.
If there was anyone
Yashamaru hated…
it would be me, not you.
I'm the one who sealed
the Shukaku of the Sand
into his pregnant older sister.
But Yashamaru was also a shinobi.
He was my right-hand man and
a member of the Sand Black Ops.
So he did as he was ordered,
for the sake of the village.
I failed.
It seems I failed
in everything I did.
I burdened you unnecessarily,
and arbitrarily decided that
you weren't worth anything.
I took away your future
by turning you into the Jinchuriki
and I took your mother away
from you.
I robbed you of your love
for your mother.
I took away the bonds you had
with people.
And I even tried to take your life.
As a parent…
there is only one thing
that I gave you.
I gave you a broken heart.
Physical wounds will definitely bleed
and may look painful.
But over time,
they heal by themselves.
And if you apply medicine,
they will heal faster.
What's troublesome are
wounds of the heart.
Nothing is harder to heal.
Wounds of the heart?
They're a bit different
from physical injuries.
You can't apply medicine,
for one thing.
And sometimes, they never heal.
There's only one cure for
a wound of the heart.
It's a bit bothersome and
you can only receive it
from someone else.
What is it?
It's love.
– Love?
– Yes.
How do I get it?
You've already received it,
Lord Gaara.
I believe your mother's will
has seeped into the Sand.
My sister…even in death…
wanted to protect you, Lord Gaara.
Karura…
Mothers are powerful.
She's dead, but she believed
in you and still protects you.
She's the one who has
brought you this far.
She gave you life, so that
you would become the Kazekage.
She gave you friends.
She gave you the bonds with
your siblings and community.
All things that I took away from you.
All I did as your father was
to torment you.
I don't deserve to be called
your father.
My mother was wonderful indeed.
Thanks to her, for the first time,
I received medicine from my father.
Gaara...You…
You surpassed me long ago.
I leave the village to you, Gaara!
So they'll use these tags to seal us.
All right!
Well done, young Kazekage!
What?
What's going on?!
I'm totally ready to be sealed!
Our bodies are programmed to
automatically counter an enemy's jutsu!
Here they come!
Surround those two!
Particle Style:
Atomic Dismantling Jutsu!
You've aged, Ohnoki.
Nonsense…
You'd better get the Kazekage here
to use his sensory skills
or you'll die, Ohnoki!
Hey!
Don't underestimate my jutsu!
You really should stand back!
For real!
For real?
Here are my weaknesses!
For real!
For real?
For real.
Now listen! I'm a Shadow Style user,
in other words, I use genjutsu.
And my summoning is…
a Giant Clam!
I'm a Lightning User!
Line up your Earth Style shinobi
and use them as a shield…
and attack with
your Wind Style shinobi!
Thanks for your thoughtfulness!
In fact, I'd like to know more!
I have no control over my body!
I can't waste any more time talking!
Come!
Wind and Earth Style shinobi,
follow me!
Sealing Unit, keep up with us!
That's right. Go away, Raikage.
If you and I stick together,
these guys won't be able to seal us.
So, do you have a strategy…
Fifth Kazekage?
I'm leaving you guys in charge here.
Huh?! Commander!
We have to deal with him
without you?!
Hey, hey! What kind of tactic is that?!
Didn't you hear me?!
I am a Shadow User!
This Giant Clam can cast
a genjutsu over a wide area!
It'll make you see illusions!
A physical attack won't work!
I'm talking about a mirage!
I can tell.
You have no desire to kill.
Of course not!
That's to be expected!
I can't stand being manipulated
by some other jutsu user.
That's why I want you to
seal me quickly, Kazekage! Hey!
Deal with him.
Hey!
You can count on us!
Hey, wispy whiskers!
Wispy whiskers?
Don't call me that!
I don't care about
the Reanimation anymore. I'll kill you!
He means it!
Man, this is awkward.
Let's go, guys!
– Yeah!
– Right!
Let's do it!
– Yeah!
– Right!
I'm counting on you…
Do something.
Good! Now you look like you
mean business!
Listen up, I'll tell you one more time!
Attacking this me is useless!
Your sensory skills are useless
against me.
You shouldn't underestimate me.
Stone Clone Jutsu!
So you'll come at me in numbers…
That might work.
Did we get him?
No way!
I told you attacking
this me is useless!
This me is just a mirage!
Then what do we have to do?!
So, defeat my Giant Clam first!
It's the one creating the mirage.
But its shell is hard.
Use large-scale weapons
or paper bombs!
But…
What?
We just used them
with the last attack…
Just hurry up and
retrieve the weapons!
I'm sorry!
Everyone, quickly!
Hurry!
Hey, that's mine.
Where's my weapon?
Hey! There are a lot of 'em
over that way too!
What are you doing here?
Digging for clams?
Pardon us.
This is awkward…
All right! Let's do it, everyone!
– Right!
Target the Giant Clam!
Take that!
Did we get it?
Huh?
That Giant Clam is also a mirage, idiots!
Aim for the real one!
Yeah, so tell us where the real one is!
Like I said! Look around behind me!
It's camouflaged within
a mirage and hiding!
Aww, damn it!
I told you attacking
this me is useless!
Oh no, I was aiming for
the Giant Clam in the back.
Like I said, that's a mirage, idiot!
Aw man, I don't understand!
I don't get it!
– We don't get it!
Look, you guys…
Wispy whiskers!
I'll kill you!
He means it!
– Who said that?! Apologize!
– Come out and apologize! Hurry!
I'm sorry.
This is awkward…
Where did that come from?!
Behind you, Tsuchikage!
Not now!
Particle Style:
Atomic Dismantling Jutsu.
Is that…?!
Planet Rasengan!
Damn it!
Lord Mu is a Sensory shinobi.
Gaara!
Sand!
Dodge this.
My jutsu is faster than yours!
All right!
This is…
a violently rotating…
Rasengan!
Earth Style: Boulder Jutsu!
Now you're so heavy,
you won't even be able to
raise your arms.
Owww…
You used to hate the other villages,
now you work so well with them.
It's worth living a long life.
You get to enjoy change.
Don't let down your guard. I'm still…
All right! Way to go, Gaara!
Oh yeah…
Nice work too, Shorty Gramps!
I am the Tsuchikage, you know.
By the way—
What are you doing
on the battlefield?!
Why did you come?!
Err…
Well…
Let me explain…
You better have a good enough
explanation to persuade me!
That would be impossible.
So I will do the talking.
This is Shikaku Nara at HQ.
Both you and the Tsuchikage
were in the middle of fighting,
so I thought I'd save
the complicated talk for later.
Let's hear it then.
But the fighting is not over.
We must head out immediately.
You can brief us on the way.
You know,
I'm not trying to win here.
You're too strong for us.
Yeah well…
Still, you must seal me.
Otherwise, I'll remain a puppet…
Okay, everyone, get up! Get up!
So that's how it is, eh?
I can't believe even
the Raikage relented.
All right, I understand.
I'm going to cease transmitting now.
Naruto.
I have nothing against going
from one battlefield to another
to identify the enemy
using transformation.
But as a former Jinchuriki,
I know…
The Nine-Tails' chakra…
Are you sure you can handle
using it so frequently?
I don't plan on dying
until I become the Hokage.
Don't treat me like a kid just
because you're the Kazekage now.
I'll take the right battlefront!
Gaara and Gramps Tsuchikage,
take the left!
Naruto, the Third Raikage is there!
Got it!
And our opponent is
the Second Mizukage, correct?
The genjutsu user…
Yes...Ordinary methods
won't work against him.
Who are you aiming at?
You're too fast for our attacks!
I'll say it again.
I am a Lightning Style User.
When I arm myself with
the Lightning Style,
my speed and defensive power exceed
the normal limits of my body.
Unless you attack with
the Wind Style,
you will never be able
to take me down.
The trouble is,
we can't land a blow even with that!
No, wait…
Wind Style Unit!
Attack Formation C!
Right!
Here we go!
Humph! Instead of doing it quietly,
she announces how
they're going to attack.
Group Wind Style Jutsu!
Wind Style: Casting Net!
A wide-range jutsu
to overtake my speed…
Splendid!
All right! We'll surround him
all at once!
No matter how many times
we attack, there's no effect!
We haven't inflicted any damage!
Our only choice is to batter him
with consecutive top-speed Blade Dance!
Is that you, Dodai?
Yes.
The Third Lord Raikage was a shinobi
blessed not only with
strength and speed,
but also with extraordinary
physical resilience.
Even long-distance Wind Style attacks,
which should reach him,
do not affect him.
We need an even more
powerful Wind Style user.
I'm a pretty good
Wind Style user myself.
So how did he actually die?
In order to save his comrades…
He used himself as a decoy
and faced 10,000 enemy troops alone.
It's said he stood for three days
and three nights
in order to buy enough time to
let his comrades escape.
I need this one to
buy me some time…
while I finish summoning him.
Guess I'll just have to take over.
Honestly, among the Allied Forces,
there isn't a stronger
Wind Style user than me.
There is!
It's me!
What?! Is that Naruto?!
What is he doing here?
No! That's not good enough!
Not with his Cloak of Lightning…
I know! Raikage are
always super fast!
Okay! When it comes back…
At this distance…
It's gonna hit!
That Wind Style is strong!
This will work…
Now, Sealing Corps! Hurry!
Right!
All right!
W-What?!
Third Raikage…
You are so strong,
it's frightening…
I don't believe it.
Rasen Shuriken didn't work?!
The look in Lord Raikage's eyes
has changed…
He's been completely taken over.
That's…?!
Everyone, get away from
the Third Raikage!
Earth Style shinobi,
form a wall immediately!
Everyone, link up!
– Right!
– Earth Style: Great Mud Wall!
Disperse!
Come with me, Naruto!
Lava Style: Rubber Wall!
What the—?!
That was the Third Raikage's
most lethal ninjutsu…
The Piercing Four-Fingered
Thrust of Hell!
He accumulates Lightning chakra
in his fingertip and strikes…
This thrust technique complements
the Lightning Style.
Just like Kakashi Sensei's Lightning Blade
and Sasuke's Chidori.
Everyone, get as far away
as possible, now!
No! If we know where he'll appear,
we should aim for that spot all together!
Everyone, stand by!
It's payback time for all
the times we missed!
Stop! Listen to the Cloud shinobi!
Get him!
Damn it!
Fools!
He's switched to
the Three-Fingered Assault!
What kind of jutsu is it anyway?
It's way too powerful!
He took dozens down in
an instant, all by himself!
The fewer the fingers he uses,
the more focused the energy and
the more powerful the Thrusts of Hell!
It's the Third's Invincible Spear!
And he can handle it with
his impermeable body.
It's his ultimate shield!
Is that old man even human…?
They say he is the only shinobi
to have ever been able
to go head to head with a Tailed Beast,
unarmored and unarmed!
Raikage are amazing!
Huh?
What's the matter?
So what's up with that?
With what?
Look at that…
The scar on his chest!
If his body's the ultimate shield,
how'd he get that?
Oh, that…
Once, the Third Raikage helped everyone
get away from the Eight-Tails
by stopping its rampage
all by himself.
Then the Eight-Tails hurt him?
He called that the most
shameful incident of his life.
One that he never spoke about…
Not even the Fourth Raikage knows.
Okay, I get that ordinary attacks
won't hurt him.
But if he got hurt fighting
the Eight-Tails,
then the Eight-Tails' strongest jutsu is…
Tailed Beast Bomb!
Th-This is the Tailed Beast Bomb…
The same as the Eight-Tails'!
He's holding a mass of chakra
this heavy in his human form?!
Is this even possible?
I figured it was impossible.
What?! What happened?!
Damn it!
It still didn't work!
His cloak of chakra is gone.
He overdid it…
Lady Temari!
The enemy has broken through
our ranks! Many are hurt!
Everyone, hurry and gather the wounded!
Notify the medical team!
Tell all to maintain
a standby position at a distance—!
Are you all right?!
Hey, hang on!
Hey, Bendy Guy!
I need to get a hold of Octopops
and Eight-Tails right away!
How do I reach them?!
You're in luck.
Huh?!
I'm with the Com Corps.
He's withdrawn
his Three-Fingered Assault!
He's aiming for a KO with a punch.
Lava Style: Rubber Sphere!
Lord Dodai of the Hidden Cloud!
What do you need?
Naruto needs to speak to
Bee and Eight-Tails.
Please contact them immediately!
While the Third Raikage is still chasing
after the dummy Rubber Ball!
He made it look like
he had me inside that ball,
but he pulled me out and
hid me behind a boulder!
Bendy Guy thinks fast!
Thanks, Bendy Guy!
Now I'll have time to talk
to Octopops!
He'll probably catch on right away!
Remember, you don't have much time!
Yeah!
Naruto, you want to talk
to Bee and Eight-Tails,
but aren't they nearby?
You're supposed to
be working together.
They're not here now. Besides…
Never mind, hurry and
contact them please!
There's no time!
Naruto's gone on ahead!
Hurry up and finish your business!
How long is it going to take?!
The urge to go pee is
beyond one's control…y'see?
Octopops, it's me, Naruto!
I have to ask Eight-Tails something!
Put him on!
Relieving oneself takes concentration.
So let me focus on urination.
I can't talk now…
I'm here, Naruto! What's going on?
You seem to be in a panic!
Hey, Eight-Tails…
You've fought the Third Raikage
before, right?
Yeah, long ago.
He was solid and
could take the blows.
Once, he used this move called
the One-Fingered Assault
and cut off all my tails.
How did you manage to scar
Gramps Raikage on the chest?
Huh?!
Maybe it was my Tailed Beast Bomb?
No, maybe it wasn't…
We were pushing against
each other with all our might,
and we both fell forward.
I don't quite remember.
Maybe…
Hey thanks, Eight-Tails!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
What? Is this different
from the one earlier?!
Gramps Raikage is headed this way.
When he gets here,
get out of the way, Bendy Guy!
There's something I want to try.
Got it.
Rasengan!
Everyone! Do not assist!
Sealing Corps! Stand by!
Right!
I don't know what he's planning,
but that's just a Rasengan!
Is that going to be enough?
His Invincible Spear will cut
through Naruto's arms and legs.
I'll have him brought back
to me half-dead.
Sage Mode: Frog Kumite!
With this, I can sense danger
over a wider range, and it's faster!
So I'll be able to counter
at the last minute…
And aim straight for his arm!
Just like I thought!
I see...That's how he got
that scar on his chest!
– We did it!
All right! Way to go, Naruto!
Yes!
That was sharp of you!
Eight-Tails told me that they were
pushing as hard as they could,
then fell forward.
I figured that he must've fallen
on his own hand.
He injured himself.
That's why it was so embarrassing.
He was the shinobi with
the ultimate spear and shield…
What a paradox.
Lord Third's spear was stronger,
it seems…
Yeah!
Probably the shinobi with
the greatest shield is Gaara!
– Oh, man…
– Still?
I keep telling you it's a mirage.
Go retrieve them!
I've had it.
Hey, you there!
Huh? You mean me?
You're from the Hidden Mist,
aren't you?
Aren't you familiar with my jutsu?
I know little about you,
Lord Second.
I mean, I only know about
the current Lord Fifth.
The secretiveness of
the Hidden Mist is to blame for this.
If I knew things would be like this,
I would've left behind
a bigger legend!
Not good…
Hey, you there!
Playtime is over!
Come at me seriously now!
We have been serious!
I have no control over my body.
It's casting jutsu on its own.
Damn it! I can't stand this!
It's my Water Balloon Jutsu.
Defend yourselves!
Commander Gaara!
Huh? What took you so long?!
I hope this time you'll seal me!
I intend to.
I'm looking forward to it.
Commander!
This is not the time to be
looking somewhere else!
Hey…
Is that all you got?
I keep telling you my weaknesses,
yet every single one of you…
You tell us, but you're still too strong!
This is closer to oil than water.
Even if I use Sand as a barrier,
it'll just seep in and
make it collapse.
You went to tackle Mu first,
didn't you?
You always want to go for
the stronger one first.
That's what you call battle!
And that's what we did.
Isn't it obvious I'm the stronger one?!
That guy looks like
a half-dead mummy. Am I right?
I realize now
that appearances can deceive.
You certainly are strong.
Finally, you understand.
Huh?! What do you mean
"appearances can be deceiving"?!
But you've got wispy whis—
Cut it out!
I told you…
that this me is a mirage,
created by the Giant Clam's
wide-range genjutsu.
So physical attacks are useless!
Find the Giant Clam quickly
and destroy it!
Otherwise, this will never end…
That's right. Your Sand…
So you were already searching
for it with your Sand.
I wondered why you were just focused
on the defensive.
Well, finally a worthy foe!
Now hurry up and defeat me!
Earth Style: Stone Fist jutsu!
You're not using
the Particle Style…
Have you run out of juice?
I'm not that Lil' Ohnoki
you used to make fun of long ago!
Earth Style:
Super Weighted Boulder Jutsu!
Not bad, Ohnoki!
Uh-oh...I've done it now!
The genjutsu is undone.
Oh, my back!
I always knew
you'd be Tsuchikage.
But you're nothing more than
a geezer with a sore back right now!
I'll admit that was a punch
with some power to it,
but you overdid it and
strained your back!
Anyway! Hurry up and run!
I'm about to use
the Hozuki Clan's Water Gun Jutsu!
I can't stop myself!
What did I tell you, idiot?!
It's because you're way
too old for this!
Oww…
Thanks, Kazekage!
An Eye of Sand…
So he used that to keep
an eye on Ohnoki all this time!
When he got the Giant Clam,
he switched out with
a Sand Clone, eh?
This one's gonna be big…
And he doesn't have eyebrows.
Okay! We got him!
No, it didn't work!
The slime is making the Sand
not stick together!
This is bad!
I'm starting to enjoy this fight!
Grand Sand Mausoleum!
Now! Throw every Sealing Tag
you've got!
There's no way his slime can
keep up with this much Sand.
Attach the Sealing Chains!
Good! We have this one!
Wha—?!
Th-This can't be…!
What the hell is that?!
Is it another genjutsu?
Is it a genjutsu?
No...It's not a genjutsu!
That gave my predecessor
Lord Mu some trouble!
It's the Infinite Explosion Ninjutsu
of the Mizukage!
The Steam Imp!
Hail?
Air forced upwards by
the steam explosion gets cooled
in the upper atmosphere
and turns into hail!
What's this?
He's a clone made from
oil and water
taken from inside
the Mizukage's body.
The exterior surface of
its child-like form is composed of oil,
while its interior is just water.
Its special feature is that it can
both heat up and cool down easily.
When it moves around,
the oil on its surface
heats up precipitously,
causing rapid vaporization
of the water inside,
resulting in an explosion of steam!
And when the hail cools it,
it shrinks back down to its original size
and it is ready to explode again.
It's coming!
He's faster than I expected!
Are you all right?!
Damn it! This clone's a wily one!
The real one should be
around here somewhere!
Don't bother with the clone.
Look for the original!
Another feature of
this jutsu is that
it greatly weakens the caster
while they are using it!
That brat, Ohnoki,
sure knows a lot!
Mu must've told him.
If it's not a Mirage genjutsu,
and he can't make himself disappear…
I should be able to sense him.
The original is behind that rock!
Oh! Found me?
Before the hail stops…
I will seal you!
What's going on with him?
He's getting bigger and bigger!
It's like Lord Tsuchikage said.
We've trapped the original!
Hey!
Damn!
Whoa…
This is a perfect hiding place!
I was once one of
the Five Kage too.
As long as I have my oil,
your Sand is useless.
Unless, of course,
you seal me real fast.
Now!
How are you going to take me down?!
I was hoping you'd tell us.
I'm done doing that.
Sorry.
You were cooperative until just now!
What happened?
Have you decided to side
with the enemy?
You're wrong.
I am a former Kage, after all.
I am helping you out…
just in a different way.
Which is what exactly?
If you can't win against me
using all of your abilities,
that means you're less
than dead old me, you fool!
How are you gonna win against
the enemy boss like that?!
I think he's about to explode!
Retreat!
Just when I thought I'd found
the Golden Child of the Five Kage…
Kazekage! You're just
an ordinary kid, after all!
This is…the Sand Shield?!
Lord Kazekage protected us!
But where's Lord Gaara?!
You protected everyone and
attacked at the same time,
knowing full well
you'd sustain damage!
Unless you stop this guy, the same
thing is going to keep happening!
The hail has stopped…
Let's see what you've got!
You mistimed getting your shield up
because of its sudden expansion!
Another Sand Clone?
That's within expectations…
I knew it.
The real one was hiding below!
What're you going to do?
It's going to explode again!
You'll never catch him with
the speed of your Sand.
What're you...Huh?
What's happening?
Did he increase the speed
of his Sand?
Either way…
Ka-boom!
More smoke!
They've got to be there!
Is that…?
Gold!
Did he mix that Gold Dust
his father left behind
and do something to it?
I hid Gold Dust in
that Sand Clone earlier.
I took advantage of that thing's heat
to melt the gold and bond it to him.
Gold is about 20 times
heavier than water.
Which is why its movements
have slowed down.
Still, why didn't it explode?
Sand mixed with the hail was
more than enough to cool him down.
Gold also has good conductivity,
which helped chill its steam.
Well played. Truly befitting
a current Kage!
I'm impressed that you came up
with such a strategy!
You really are…
the Golden Child, after all!
Are you all right, Gaara?!
What about you?
We sealed the Raikage!
I saw an explosion,
so I rushed here ahead
of Temari and the others.
I see!
I'm almost done here too.
Hey, so you have a friend!
Huh?
W-What is this guy?!
Man, what a weird body!
No, that's my jutsu.
Kazekage…
Unlike you, he seems like an idiot!
You make a good pair.
Really?
It's been a while since
I had this much fun!
Relay our current battle status
to HQ!
Yes, sir!
You fought well against
the former Kage, everyone!
Victory is ours for this battle!
All right!
Extract the injured and transport them
to the Medical Corps!
Those who can still fight will
stand by for orders from HQ!
Lord Tsuchikage, you should go
to the Medical Corps, too.
I'm fine now.
Owww…
Don't overdo it, old man.
Don't treat me like an old man!
I can still take
you young ones on—
Okay, come on.
Let us take you to
the Medical Corps.
Fool! Let me go!
I can walk on my own!
You should just admit
that you're old.
How dare you!
I am the Tsuchikage!
Yes, I heard that yesterday too.
Lord Gaara, please come by later.
Let go, I said!
Didn't you hear me?
We're going this way!
Owww!
Please stop moving around!
We're going.
Naruto, you're a clone, right?
Yeah…
Then where's your original now?
I finally caught up!
You're late!
What were you doing?
A persistent pee, yo.
Sheesh! It sure took long!
Had some other problems too.
Anyway, one of your clones
contacted me.
What happened to
the other clones?
They should be arriving at
the frontlines of every battlefield.
All the fakers we'll seek out
All the bad guys we'll defeat, no doubt
We gotta hurry too!
Damn, I can't tell.
I can't sniff out
the transformed fakes.
You're back, Shino!
Yeah…
Be careful.
There's no telling where
the enemy will come from.
So you were one of them…
Damn it!
Byakugan!
It's no good.
I can't distinguish them
from their chakra.
Are you a fake?
Stop! I'm the real one!
Lava Style:
Dissolving Jutsu!
There's no end to this.
We have to do something
about the real ones though…
Lee, don't get hit!
Why you…!
Do not panic!
Surround them!
I've detected a new enemy!
It's a small unit,
but the chakra is unusual…
It's…
Madara!
What did you say?!
Madara is leading a small unit.
Can you tell who makes up his unit?
This chakra is…
Fourth Mizukage!
The one who was a Jinchuriki?
There's no mistake.
The rest are all Jinchuriki too!
I can't believe he had more pawns
under his control…
Shikamaru…
How long do we have
to stay like this?
If that huge one comes back,
won't we be in trouble?
At least until Naruto gets here.
Until then, do not step inside
anyone else's circle.
If you do, even you will
be considered an enemy.
We just have to verify
what we know about each other!
That won't work either.
Several of our guys fell for that.
Sometimes, a lucky guess
ends up being correct.
You're here!
Finally got here!
Nawaki?!
Is he here?!
Oh, good.
He's gotten real flashy though…
Naruto!
Naruto?
He looks just like Nawaki…
We received word from HQ.
I'm glad you came.
But...I'm surprised that
Lord Raikage gave the okay for this.
Well, Granny Tsunade convinced
Pops Raikage for me.
Tsunade sent that boy?
Just who is he anyway?
The Nine-Tails is sealed inside him.
The adults call him the Jinchuriki.
That boy?!
He's my idiot classmate Naruto,
who's been talking big
about becoming Hokage
ever since we were little…
Don't you think "idiot" is
a bit harsh, Shikamaru?
Well, I'm here and
I'll find every one of 'em!
Naruto, huh…
So guys like Nawaki and me
exist in this period too.
So let's take down the transformed
white ones, everybody!
Hey, stop! Stay away!
Help!
Do not approach!
What's wrong?
He can still be saved
with medical ninjutsu!
Stay away! I told you not to move.
There's no way to prove
that you're allies!
But if we remain like this…
He'll die!
I'm begging you.
Please save him!
Don't let my husband die
in my arms!
Hey! What are you doing?!
If you don't trust me,
I'll kill myself right here!
But please save my husband!
Hey, stop!
Come with me.
You can't. What if…?
What if they're comrades?
I must tend to him.
Thank you.
Looks like you're all right!
Gentle Fist!
It was a fake, after all!
This side is bad. Hinata is…!
Neji!
Sorry I'm late.
Naruto…?
Is that Naruto?
He smells different from before!
It's all right now!
Are you all right, Hinata?
Yes.
Why weren't we notified right away
that Naruto was here?
Naruto just arrived.
I happened to see him first,
but I was in the midst of a battle.
Naruto smells differently
from before.
I wouldn't have noticed.
But you're the one
who sees long distances, so…
He looks different from before.
So is his chakra nature…
Then who are you to talk?!
Are you really Naruto?
I hope you're not
a White Zetsu fake too.
I'm Naruto.
Can you prove it?
It's Naruto.
You can tell by looking in his eyes.
Hinata…
Besides, he came to my rescue.
Naruto saved me too.
When did you get here?!
I'll have you know that your fake
appeared not too long ago!
I'm the real deal.
And I've been here with Naruto since.
I'm sorry, Naruto.
Everyone is so suspicious.
Now that I'm here,
you don't have to fight
a defensive battle anymore.
I'll search out the fakes
one by one.
All right, Naruto!
I've memorized your new scent.
And your chakra.
Well, smell and chakra don't matter
much with their transformation.
They mimic everything, even chakra.
But don't worry!
As you saw, they turn into trees
when I bring them down.
And when I'm in this mode,
I can sense their hatred.
I'll find the fakes,
so let's beat 'em together!
The one we're supposed to protect
is always protecting us.
Don't let it bother you, Hinata.
You protected me twice already. I can't
let you keep doing that. It's not cool!
I-I wasn't worried or anything…
I can see it in your eyes.
Don't be so hard on yourself!
You are strong!
Don't come!
Let's go.
Which one's the fake?!
The one with the axe!
All right!
And him too!
Thank you, Naruto.
Not so fast!
All right!
Do it, Sai!
Sealing Jutsu:
Crouching Tiger Bullet!
All right! Three more left!
Are you all right, Sai?
Yes...I can continue.
No need to worry.
Keep drawing the tigers.
I've got your back.
And here come
the enemy reinforcements.
A whole lot of them too.
They're white…
Are these the ones that can transform
their chakra and everything else?
Things are about to get wild, Kakashi.
Our reinforcements have arrived too.
Or should I say,
reinforcement…in singular?
Naruto has the Shadow Clone Jutsu!
I can't use it now,
not in this situation.
This time, we'll win with quality,
not quantity!
And so…
Things have changed, Kimimaro!
I can tell that time has passed
by looking at you.
It seems you've grown in ways
other than just height.
Here I come!
I put too much force into it…
What happened?
He's just as scatterbrained
and rash as ever.
For sure…
Impossible, is that…?
Oh yes, it is.
Naruto has arrived at
every battlefield!
Good.
Naruto has joined up with
the Fourth Company.
And the Former Kage of
the Wind, Lightning, Earth and Water…
have all been successfully sealed.