So this is…the Great Ninja War.
Water! Water!
Th-Thank you…
Ninja tools?
Father…
Why did this shinobi
try to kill me?
I didn't do anything…
Because this is war.
"War"?
It's not a war between people.
It's a war between nations.
That's why strangers
kill each other meaninglessly.
Is that what it is?
That is what the shinobi world is.
Listen, Itachi…
Never forget this sight…
We managed an armistice,
but the sacrifice was just too great.
Lord Third intends to take
full responsibility and retire.
There are voices in support of installing
you, Captain, as the Fourth Hokage.
- Please…
- Enough talk.
What should we do
about Kakashi Hatake?
He doesn't belong to our clan,
but he possesses the Sharingan.
I understand Obito Uchiha
fought bravely.
Let's respect his wishes.
We should bring the Sharingan
back to the Uchiha…
The war just ended.
Do not sow seeds of discord.
Yes, sir.
We finally have peace.
We will persevere to maintain it.
That is the duty of the Uchiha…
Grieving over the dead
is meaningless.
If there's any meaning in death,
it's to take advantage of it.
What is the meaning of life?
There is none.
There's meaning in life if it's eternal.
There's no meaning…
in life?
No one wants to die, right?
What is life, anyway?
Please take care.
Thank you very much!
Mom…
What is it?
Are you sick?
Oh, it's nothing like that.
You see…
You're going to have
a little brother or sister.
Yes. You're going to
be a big brother.
It's a boy!
He's your little brother.
A life…
A new life.
Have you decided on a name?
Yes.
Sasuke…
Sasuke Uchiha.
Oh...It's a fine name, but that's…
Yes, it's Lord Third's father's name.
I've already asked Lord Third.
I see.
Sasuke…
We shall raise him to never
dishonor his name.
There, there, Itachi!
Itachi!
I'm like that too.
Birth…death…birth…death…
Hey, hey!
Aren't you Itachi?
An Uchiha in my class?
Let's play together.
What do you want to do today?
Kick the can!
Let's play kick the can!
Huh?
We played that yesterday!
Hey! Are you dissing us?
Say something!
I have shuriken training right now.
- Wow...
Well then…
Let's practice shuriken too!
No, don't!
That kid!
Trying to act cool! What a stuck-up!
Hey, you guys. Stop it!
Shut up!
This is between us guys!
Life is born.
Life dies.
Life is…a battle…
Hey! Don't run away!
Wow!
Was it a girl?
It's a boy.
He's so cute!
What's your name?
Hey Mom…
Is Lord Fourth going to
have a baby too?
Yes, I wonder what it'll be.
I'll be going out tonight,
so go ahead and have dinner.
Okay.
Your father's working too,
so please watch Sasuke.
Uh-huh.
There's a full moon out tonight, Sasuke.
What…?
Come on out…
Nine-Tails!
There, there…
Don't cry, Sasuke.
No matter what happens, your big brother
will definitely protect you…
Summoning Jutsu!
No way!
Go, Nine-Tails!
This is an announcement
from the Leaf Police!
All civilians are to evacuate
to the southeast shelter!
The southeast shelter!
Dad! Mom!
Come here!
Itachi!
Hurry!
Okay!
We're going to the shelter.
This way! Hurry!
Mom!
Keep going.
Itachi?
Everyone will be there.
Please stay calm!
You're safe here!
Father!
I knew you would be all right.
Get to the shelter quickly.
Okay.
We drove it out of the village.
Don't let up. Keep attacking!
Just about everyone has
been evacuated.
Captain, we'll go after
the Nine-Tails as well.
The Leaf Police Force is to remain
and protect the civilians.
But Captain!
These are the Village's orders.
What was that just now?!
Looks like they sealed the Nine-Tails…
…somehow.
Many lives were lost including the Fourth
Hokage Minato and his wife, Kushina…
The facts behind the incident
are still unknown…
Life is born…
But for now, let us
mourn our comrades…
And life…dies.
Itachi!
Um...
Thank you for before…
Because of you, I was safe!
I'm glad you didn't die.
Your younger sister?
Younger brother.
Can I hold him?
No.
Why not?
I don't want him to cry.
You're not gonna cry, are you?
There, there!
Aww, come on!
The Nine-Tails' attack caused
devastation throughout the village.
For the reconstruction,
we've decided to revise a number
of the village's boundaries.
We'd like the Aburame Clan
to move into this district.
The clan previously submitted
a request to occupy the forest,
so we took that into consideration.
The Nara Clan's territory was
not part of the stricken area,
so they will remain where they are.
The Leaf Police Force headquarters
which sustained damage,
will be rebuilt here.
And the Uchiha Clan will move along
with the headquarters…
Lord Danzo!
The Uchiha Clan makes up the Leaf
Police Force that protects the Hidden Leaf.
As such, that location is too far
from the village center.
We wouldn't be able to act swiftly
in an emergency.
We have the ANBU Black Ops
for such emergencies.
The Leaf Police has to commute
to the training grounds, does it not?
This location is near an area
that's ideal for training.
You can use that area exclusively
for the Uchiha's training grounds.
Continuing on…
In conjunction with the reconstruction
of the Leaf Police Headquarters,
the Uchiha Clan will also relocate.
Home and buildings that
were spared will be…
During the Nine-Tails Incident,
we Uchiha were not called upon
because they feared that
we would use our Sharingan to
manipulate the Nine-Tails.
Even worse, there are some who say
that the Uchiha
caused the Nine-Tails Incident!
They are sending us to the outskirts of
the village in order to keep an eye on us!
This is just like during
the Second Hokage's era
when the Uchiha were rounded up
and isolated in one part of the village!
This time, it's even farther away!
The village suspects us!
Captain, we can't accept this decision!
We should reject it outright!
Captain!
You are absolutely right.
But the other clans have accepted
their respective relocations as well.
The Uchiha cannot be
the lone voice of dissent.
But Captain!
I'll do what I can to negotiate
the conditions.
But we must accept the move.
Pass the word around. That is all.
Dismissed.
How do you feel?
Let's go and see it, Father.
The new training grounds.
I like it here.
Is that so?
Father, teach me jutsu…
Generational Uchiha jutsu…
All right!
This is a fundamental Uchiha ninjutsu…
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu.
All right, the signs are…
I did it!
What a surprise.
That's my boy.
We'll be moving in no time, huh?
Yeah.
What's the matter?
We're surrounded…
I wish it was my imagination, but…
What is it?
It's nothing…
"In no time," huh? The same could
be said about you, Itachi.
Since you're going to be
six years old soon.
There are too many
unanswered questions
surrounding this recent
Nine-Tails incident.
I thought that Kushina's seal
had been broken.
But that doesn't explain why Biwako
and the ANBU were killed.
Which means someone is behind this.
Like someone from the Uchiha?
Why do you say that?
Even if the Nine-Tails broke free,
it would have just gone wild.
Without someone to control it,
it couldn't have caused this incident.
Hence, the Sharingan...
The Uchiha can control the Nine-Tails
with their visual prowess...
But for what purpose?
To regain their position of power
within the Hidden Leaf Village.
I see...
That's just conjecture.
We must increase our surveillance
of the Uchiha.
We must keep them
under 24-hour watch.
That's bound to
incite them unnecessarily!
Let the ANBU do it secretly.
Better to be safe than sorry.
Wait!
We don't know if the Uchiha
are responsible for this.
That's precisely why
this is necessary.
And if nothing comes out of it...
it will be to the Uchiha's benefit.
Kushina...
Congratulations on your acceptance
into the Academy, everyone!
From this day forth,
do your best to reach your goals
to become a shinobi.
I'm sure some of you have already
been taught ninjutsu in your households…
But here at the Academy,
you will also train
to coordinate and work together as
a team when you are in a group.
The fundamentals are very important,
make sure you learn them well.
All right, Kamano. What's the answer?
I don't know!
Then…Itachi?
The seal is for the Water Style:
Water Bomb Jutsu.
Correct.
Keep that in mind everyone.
It will be on the test.
Itachi…Come at me.
All right!
Begin!
The match is over!
Okay, okay…
Sorry, Sasuke.
Some other time, okay?
Welcome home, Father!
Please teach me jutsu!
Jutsu?
Aren't they teaching you
at the Academy?
It's too easy.
I guess it would be for you.
Wait for me at the training grounds.
Okay!
Make sure you're home by dinner.
Got it!
Look over there! It's Itachi!
Where?
Oh, he's walking. He's so cool!
Oh, he's looking this way!
This is not good.
Don't you think, gentlemen?
For his sake,
if he gets swept up by all of this
and gets the wrong idea…
I agree.
He's stuck up!
It's me! He's looking at me!
No, it's me!
He started walking again!
Itachi's walking!
He's walking!
It's decided then…
- Yeah!
- Right!
Ouch!
Don't jump out at us like that, idiot!
"Idiot"? Who are you calling "idiot"?
You guys must be freshmen!
You…
…run into someone…
and call 'em an "idiot" …?
You ran into us!
What did you say?!
Hold it!
Who the hell are you?
A friend of theirs?
All the freshmen this year are…
…stuck up!
- Wow!
Take him to the infirmary.
O-Okay.
Itachi, you're really strong, my friend!
"My friend"?
Even upperclassmen are
easy targets for you, sir!
"Sir"?
Move it, move it!
Master Itachi is coming through!
"Master"?
Make way!
It's Master Itachi!
- Move it! Make way!
- Stop it…
- Outta the way!
- Please…
Don't…
There is birth…
and death…
Life…
flocks together…
What is a shinobi?
What is a village?
First in every class,
according to your progress report…
That's my boy.
Father…
Hmm?
Teach me jutsu.
I want to know more
about being a shinobi.
In cases like this, always make sure
you have an escape route.
This is important.
If you're in a four-man team…
You're very talented for your age.
I'm no match for you, Shisui.
Oh come on…
What's wrong?
Does the Academy bore you
so much that you're ditching?
I'm not ditching.
You guys! That's unfair!
What's with that look?
Hey! Cut it out!
Hey you, stop!
Itachi!
Take this!
What happened?
He disappeared?!
Yeah, he disappeared!
He disappeared!
That's a clone…
No…
It's a Shadow Clone Jutsu!
What's the matter?
I have to get back.
You do?
Shisui…
Why is there fighting in life?
Who knows?
But…
If the fighting can be stopped,
I'd like to stop it.
Me too!
See you later.
Aside from the clone jutsu
which is a requirement for
graduating the Academy,
Itachi Uchiha has already mastered
the Shadow Clone Jutsu, a forbidden jutsu.
He excels in all other subjects.
There's no purpose in keeping him
at the Academy any longer.
Isn't he just a freshman?
Yes.
That doesn't matter.
This has happened before.
That was a different era.
This is not the age of war.
The boy is a genius, no?
I've never seen a student like him.
So it will be better for Itachi
to let him graduate?
Graduate?
After only a year at the Academy?
Yeah.
The teacher said as long as
both parents agree.
They want to talk to you at school.
I see…
That's my boy.
Graduates!
You will now be assigned missions
from the village.
We'll be forming three-man teams
led by one jonin…
and you will be undertaking
your mission under their guidance.
And now, I will announce the teams!
Father!
We'll discuss this again later.
Returning from a mission, Itachi?
Yeah!
We haven't walked together
like this in a while.
Well, I'm a genin now…
and have I missions.
Oh, I see!
That's right.
Since the Uchiha moved here…
…three years have passed.
We were pushed to
the outskirts of the village,
and the upper echelons
took away our authority…
Many still voice strong dissatisfaction
towards their methods.
You're aware of that too, right?
We want to regain
our power one day…
and step out from
the darkness into the light—
Father, look!
What's so funny?
Sorry, Father…
You're the face of the Uchiha.
I'm proud to be able to
walk alongside you.
Enough flattery…
Should we get your favorite snack
on the way home?
Yeah!
It can't be helped
if they're all sold out…
Itachi?
Izumi…
I'm sorry, Itachi.
Are you sure I didn't interrupt
you and your dad?
Yeah...It's okay.
- It's been a while.
- Yeah.
It's the first time since
you became a genin.
That's right!
I'm sorry I didn't get you
anything for your promotion…
I didn't even congratulate you.
I'm really sorry!
You don't have to apologize
so much…
This doesn't really qualify
as a gift.
But if you don't mind,
won't you have one?
My mom loves the tri-color
dumplings from that shop.
But I guess someone like you
who's brilliant and
who excels in ninjutsu and taijutsu
and whizzed through the Academy…
wouldn't have a sweet tooth.
Sorry for just assuming…
Well, since I opened them…
I guess I'll eat them all myself.
Don't tell me…
Do you want one?
Is it strange?
Oh no, it isn't that.
I've known you for quite
some time,
but I didn't know what
your favorite foods were.
Rank and gender have
nothing to do
with what someone likes to eat.
Yeah, that's true.
Sorry.
I'm sorry…
It's because, Itachi…
You looked so ready
to use your Sharingan.
It was funny.
Okay, I won't laugh anymore.
Sorry, Itachi!
Sorry, sorry!
Let me make it up to you.
Is there anything you want?
"Anything I want"?
Yeah!
That's right. She's…
Yeah...I thought so.
But that's something
I can't give you.
Hey!
We have another mission…
Stop flirting.
We are not flirting!
Itachi…
I can't give them to you…
But I'll pray for you…
I hope that your Sharingan
awakens really soon.
And when it does,
I'll congratulate you!
Thank you for your help.
I did tell him to hurry up
and settle down…
But I never expected him
to fall in love…
This one has good skills,
but no eye for judging females.
I just wanted to find the best bride
for the sake of our clan.
The most important thing
is that you're okay.
You fulfilled the mission just as I
requested…is what I'd like to say…
But what happened
to his whiskers?
To keep the fighting to a minimum,
there was no choice.
So you cut them?
Well, it's my fault for not giving you
a heads up on his skills…
You didn't bring them back?
No...they blew away in the wind.
Well, I guess it can't be helped.
Thank you for your efforts.
Itachi…
Next time you come,
I'll have you take care of the
debts the Uchiha have racked up.
Good thing you got
what you needed, eh?
Well, yeah…
Cheer up, will ya?
The fate of your clan rests on it, right?
It's not that critical!
But…
If this cures my dad,
my clan will be secure.
That ninja cat…
And those grownups…
They're all thinking about their clans…
You'd better not be thinking
that you saved me.
The thought hasn't crossed my mind.
Even if you didn't end up
helping me…
What are you doing?!
Why are you still
saying stuff like that?
He's your friend!
Of course, he's going to help you!
– Huh?! Me? His friend?!
– I was just fulfilling my mission.
You stop being
so difficult as well!
All right! Isn't there something
you want to say to Itachi?!
I swear I'll make it up
to you for this!
Why can't you just
say thank you?!
Shinko, that hurt too much!
Friend, huh?
Big Brother! What is this?
This is…from that time…
Life is born, and life dies…
But life is saved again…
Wait…
When I saved him back then,
I didn't think too deeply about it.
He's your friend!
Of course,
he's going to help you!
A clan grows…
A village is born…
And bonds are made…
If that's what friends are…
We were friends, no doubt about it.
We formed a bond…
That's why that happened…
We had a bond…
That's why he…
I swear I'll make it up
to you for this!
…died.
I didn't understand back then…
What real pain was.
The pain of losing a life…
I felt it for the first time
after losing it…
No, I was made to realize it…
The feeling of not wanting
to lose something precious.
Big Brother!
Your eyes!
Will the day come when
you'll possess these eyes too?
The day when you come
to know what sadness is?
Are you leaving already?
Yes.
I see…
You awakened your Sharingan
at age eight…
I supposed the Village wants
to observe your abilities.
This just shows how much power
and influence the Sharingan holds.
I want you to be aware of that.
It brings joy to the clan when
one of its own excels.
Of course, I'm very proud of you too.
He died…
Father.
But, do not rest on your laurels just
because you have the Sharingan now.
In order to sharpen the power in your
eyes, you must continue to be diligent.
Well, I don't need to lecture you.
You are my son, after all.
My friend died…
But, Father is…
Yes, Father.
I will continue to be diligent.
Good.
I'll be on my way now.
Big Brother!
You said you'd play with me today!
That's right, I did, didn't I?
But I have a mission.
Forgive me, Sasuke. Next time.
Sorry about that, Sasuke.
I'm gonna borrow your brother
for a little bit.
Why did you lie?
Sasuke resents me now.
I know that was wrong of me…
But Sasuke's a smart kid…
I think he'll understand.
"First, have one genin
accompany you,
and secure the scroll in question."
Even if my training exercise required
a genin, it really didn't have to be you.
Don't say that now!
Even if it's not a real mission,
none other than Shisui the jonin
requested me.
I'm not lying when
I say it's a mission, right?
Well, you're half right.
Let's go.
What are the details of
the training exercise?
There are three parts.
The first part is to find traces left
by a fugitive, and then to track him.
Pretty good!
Let's start from here.
A footprint left on moss…
As expected from Shisui…
He doesn't miss the slightest details.
This is…
Our guy stepped on
a piece of a branch…
Very perceptive of you!
But, that's just a decoy.
Dry wood like that would snap
when stepped on…
but this piece still has
a lot of moisture.
Also, see this clean cut?
Obviously, he was in a hurry
to make a decoy…
Sloppy work.
Don't be disappointed…
An animal could have left
that indentation in the moss,
but only humans make decoys.
And if he laid the decoy
over in that direction…
A stone?
Yes.
The underside is dry
and the top is damp.
Could this be a decoy too?
Well…That's very possible.
The moisture on the rock will tell us
how long ago he was here.
I see!
Judging from the dryness,
only a short while has passed.
This scent!
Perfect!
Let's go!
I think a fish left that mark behind.
So it's not a decoy?
No. That's the main purpose
of leaving decoys.
Everything starts to look
like them.
Confusing their pursuers gives
the fugitive many additional options.
At this rate, there's no way
I can find the fugitive by myself.
I need to develop better
tracking skills.
You're half right.
Here.
Drink up.
It's because you're exceptional, Itachi…
That's why…
I bet you've never tried to understand
the feelings of someone who's not.
Having the skills to track
a fugitive is important,
but so is understanding
how he thinks.
If you can understand his mindset,
sometimes you can thwart
a fugitive even without those skills.
I see!
So…
Let's move on to the second part
of the training exercise.
The second part?
Yeah…
To encamp at night.
The textbook said campfires
are prohibited.
So does this mean there's another
reason behind doing this?
Just eat.
You're exceptional, Itachi.
I'm still inexperienced.
Earlier, if I had more skills…
That's true.
Don't laugh!
Sorry, sorry…
It just makes me happy.
"Happy"?
Huh? No!
Just listen…
I thought that there was really nothing
I could teach you.
But…
You taught me a lot today.
Yeah...And that's what
made me happy.
So…
Hmm?
What about this campfire?
Oh…
It's nice to share a meal with
someone you feel at ease with.
Enjoying a hot meal helps
cheer you up.
Eat it while it's hot.
Yeah...It's warm and tasty!
Told you so!
But…
If I'm really exceptional…
He wouldn't have died.
I'm still so inexperienced.
So why would someone like me…
I…
Hmm?
Awakened the Sharingan…
I see…
Is that why…you lied?
"Lied"?
You said the same thing
at the start of practice.
You're good at fooling yourself.
That's why you can't grasp
your true feelings.
You didn't want to stay
at home, right?
That's the look you had
on your face.
That might be true…
Shisui picked up on how
I felt from the very beginning…
I'll be happy to listen any time
you want to talk.
The final part of the training
exercise is about to start.
I'll assist you to the best
of my abilities!
The pursuers are ANBU?!
Is this an exercise?
No…
Put that out of your mind for now.
Why are you attacking
a fellow Leaf shinobi?
Would you consider forgetting that
you saw this and leaving?
If you're going to kill a comrade,
I can't look the other way
without hearing a reason!
The truth is…
We're going after those
who betrayed the village.
Where's the proof that
he betrayed you?
What a waste of time.
Let's just kill them all.
Just wait…
It's not that he's a traitor.
But he has evidence that proves
who the traitor is in that scroll.
If he hands it over, we will disappear.
So she says…
You want the intel…
but for what purpose?
Isn't it obvious?!
Anyone who threatens the village
will be punished…
We maintain the order in Leaf Village
with our code of darkness!
You don't have the right to judge!
I will hand this secret missive
to Lord Hokage…
Lord Hokage will make
a fair and just judgment!
"A fair and just judgment"?
How naïve.
You betray the village, you die.
That's that.
Even a traitor has
a reason behind their actions!
The Hokage's wish is
to investigate that carefully.
That's one way of thinking.
However…
This involves the entire village.
The gravity of one traitor versus
one village is far too great.
What would Shisui…?
He took the opportunity to
substitute himself out
while we were "advising" him…
Don't worry.
My wire is coated with poison.
His body will go numb and
he won't go far.
Without words, they carry out
their purpose with blades…
Leave it to the ANBU…
Or rather, Lord Danzo's Foundation, right?
Nameless individuals who maintain
peace from the shadows…
I believe that is a true shinobi.
Then you share our beliefs.
No, you're wrong!
Order maintained through
the power of the blade…
…is not peace!
I…
Itachi…stay out of this!
I am Itachi Uchiha!
I will fight alongside Shisui!
Itachi!
So this is the how the ANBU fight.
The Uchiha would dare to
push their luck and defy us?
We will not show mercy,
even to children.
At least make it fun for us!
The one your friend is fighting,
is a kunoichi who's unrivaled
within the Foundation.
If you don't stop him quickly,
he will die.
Retreat!
Don't underestimate the Uchiha!
Besides…he's exceptional!
Sharingan!
She keeps mixing it up
with double and triple layers.
But…!
I thought he was just a child,
but he has the Sharingan already?
I can see it!
So this is the power of the Sharingan!
There's no right way or
wrong way to fight in a battle.
But…
I've already seen
through your attacks.
I don't think so…
You have already fallen into my trap.
You're pretty good,
even though you're a child.
What--? How?!
I told you…
I've seen through your attacks.
That threaded ninja tool you threw…
I changed its trajectory
just a little bit.
You…damn Uchiha!
Itachi seems to be doing fine.
So I'll end things on my end!
Teleportation Jutsu!
Shadow Clones…
No, they're just Afterimage Clones.
If they're just afterimages,
I'll sense out the real one…
What…? This is weird.
I can't see the real one!
Get the hell outta here!
He didn't fly off!
Namely…he has no mass.
But his attack is powerful…
What's going on?
My Teleportation Jutsu has no mass.
But you could say everything has mass.
It seems the jonin observing
our training exercise have noticed.
We will be watching you
from the shadows…
Shisui Uchiha...Itachi Uchiha!
This is…!
It's not a fatal wound.
Don't worry about it.
Back then…if I had observed
the enemy more carefully…
Never mind that…
He wants us to forget
this incident ever happened.
His life was threatened! So why?
If this incident becomes known,
it will sow the seeds
for a new conflict.
This is not what Lord Hokage wants.
The ones who aid peace from
the shadows are also…nameless.
So there was fighting, but you assumed
it was part of the training exercise?
I'm sorry.
They were extremely strong,
and I was doing my best to protect
the genin, so I didn't see their faces…
No, we're at fault for not catching
their infiltration too.
I'm glad neither of you are hurt.
I'd like to talk to you more
about this tomorrow.
But this training exercise is over.
Itachi, let's go home.
What's the matter?
Ah...You sprained your ankle.
You're making a big deal
out of nothing.
When you first awaken
the Sharingan,
sometimes there's a "slight gap"
between the image your brain foresees
and your body's reaction time.
And when you try too hard to
compensate for that slight gap…
this happens.
I said you're making
a big deal out of nothing.
Oww!
No matter how exceptional
you are, Itachi…
don't overdo it.
It's not funny!
I'm sorry!
I'm just happy.
You're really like
a kid brother to me.
So being able to take you under
my wing like this makes me happy.
I want you to think of me as your older
brother and depend on me for anything.
Shisui…
Hmm?
About the ANBU…
Oh…
Did I make the right decision?
I won't say yes.
I don't even know if there is such a
thing as justice in the shinobi world.
But that's…!
We fight believing in our own justice.
But if the enemy is doing
the same thing, who's right?
You realized that during
today's exercise, didn't you?
There's more than
one side to an issue.
You must consider things
from various viewpoints.
"Various…viewpoints"?
You must be tired from
using your Sharingan.
Go ahead and sleep.
But there's one thing that's certain…
I will never, ever betray you.
That's the one thing
that's certain.
So it's come to this.
Shisui…
I'm…
I'm Itachi Uchiha.
I'll be part of ANBU from today.
I'm looking forward
to working with you.
I'm going to watch over the Hidden Leaf
from within the shadows.
A new member will be
joining your team.
Is it the one
we previously discussed?
Yes, he's extremely capable.
But he's young.
Danzo recommended that
he gain more experience.
Some of you may be aware,
but my son Itachi has
joined the ANBU.
Being in close vicinity to
the Hokage and the top ranks
means access to more information.
And that is a boon
for the Uchiha Clan.
Itachi, do you have
anything to report?
Well...
I'm still new,
so there's not much to report.
However, I don't think
there's solidarity
in the higher ranks of the Leaf.
It's my belief that how
the Uchiha Clan deals with this
will determine the future
of the Hidden Leaf.
Exactly. By all rights,
the Uchiha Clan must be involved
in the future of the Hidden Leaf.
- That's right!
- Right!
- Yeah!
- Yes, that's right!
That's the...
Time to switch.
Nothing to report.
This is...
This isn't the only
surveillance center around.
Lord Danzo's ANBU are
also watching them.
Now what'll you do?
Notify your clan about this?
What is my job here?
Just keep watching through that.
Okay, Captain. We're going.
Stay alert, Itachi.
This is part of our job as ANBU.
It's not assassination
but it's still dirty work.
A mission is a mission.
You'll be spying on your friends
and family. It's even dirtier.
I can take this shift,
if you want.
No, that's not necessary.
Besides...
Besides?
The Uchiha Clan is aware
that they're under suspicion.
I guess you would be.
Calm down!
A genjutsu!
But when did that happen?
Byakugan!
We're retreating!
But Captain...!
It's Shisui Uchiha,
the Teleporter of the Leaf.
We're no match for him. Retreat!
That should keep the Hidden Mist
quiet for a while.
Team Shisui has returned and
our mission was successfully completed.
That was a long mission.
Thank you for your hard work.
Go and rest.
I have a request, Lord Third.
I'm very troubled by the suspicion
cast upon the Uchiha Clan.
So am I.
I'm hoping that my clan and the Village
will be able to trust each other again.
Will you assign this mission to me?
Do you want to be released
from your regular duties?
Yes. And I'd like to be given
a certain amount of authority.
All right. Let's say I ordered you on
a top-secret investigative mission.
If anyone objects, tell them my name,
and I will take full responsibility.
Thank you.
You remind me so much
of my old friend, Kagami Uchiha.
I am nowhere near his caliber.
Big Brother!
Are you done with your mission?
If you are, help me train!
Sorry, Sasuke.
I have an urgent summons.
We played here a lot.
So you were back.
Yeah. We finally chased
the Hidden Mist away.
Why did you want to see me?
I want to hear
your honest opinion.
How serious do you think Fugaku is?
What do you mean by serious?
A coup d'état.
Dissatisfaction towards the Village
is growing among the Uchiha.
If the Village doesn't change,
the Uchiha won't stand for it anymore.
If the Village changes,
so will the Uchiha.
But if the Uchiha doesn't change,
neither will the Village.
As long as the two sides
distrust each other,
things will only get worse.
I want to clear up that suspicion.
You think you can?
I don't know, but I have to try...
If the Uchiha attempts a coup d'état,
it will bode badly for both sides.
I'm against a coup d'état as well.
But it will take something big
to stop it.
I know.
But you shouldn't do anything.
Why's that?
Some members on the Police Force
are suspicious of you...
and I've been ordered
to spy on you.
What?!
Do you know what day tomorrow is?!
You don't understand
your own position!
I'm setting out on
a mission tomorrow.
What kind of mission?
I can't tell you...
It's top-secret.
Itachi...
You also serve as the Uchiha Clan's
pipeline to the Village nerve center.
You know that, don't you?
Yes...
Bear that in mind.
And come to tomorrow's assembly!
The Uchiha are assembling
again tonight.
I know about it as well.
But we cannot interfere
with their clan rituals.
Rituals indeed!
They're going to fan the flames of distrust
against us, then use it to unite the clan.
They are preparing for a coup d'état.
And the one to nip it
in the bud is...
Shisui!
Shisui Uchiha?
Shisui will attend the assembly.
And if Fugaku Uchiha incites
a rebellion...
I will use my Kotoamatsukami.
Your visual jutsu...
He will have no clue that Shisui
is controlling his actions.
He will believe that
his words are his own.
I'm going to make Fugaku think
about co-existence with the Village.
I don't think that
controlling only Fugaku
will put an end to
the Uchiha's dissatisfaction.
No. If the Uchiha will change,
then we of the Leaf must change too.
Let us improve our relations
with the Uchiha.
That is my hope.
I will assign one ANBU
behind the scenes.
I'm counting on you, Shisui.
Yes, sir!
Itachi isn't coming, is he?
He's late.
What is it, Lord Danzo?
It's almost time for
the assembly to start.
Even if you use your visual jutsu
on Fugaku to get the clan to cooperate,
what if the Village doesn't change?
Lord Hokage has promised
to make it change.
Even if Lord Third is satisfied,
the distrust among
the Leaf will not go away.
I realize that. But in time...
Besides, someone who's always suspicious
like me will never change.
What will you do then?
But Lord Danzo...
When the time comes,
will you use your Kotoamatsukami
on me too?
I'm...
Your Sharingan...
shall be in my safekeeping!
Forgive me.
It's only genjutsu...
You'll snap out of it shortly.
Sharingan?!
I'm going to take it
to replace this eye.
Give me the other one too.
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
Water Style: Raging Waves!
It's a Teleportation Jutsu!
Go after him.
Is that you, Shisui?
Come with me.
It's too late to stop
the coup d'état by the Uchiha.
If civil war breaks out
in the Leaf Village,
other nations are sure
to attack...
which means a full-scale war.
I was going to try to stop
the coup d'état with Kotoamatsukami, but...
Lord Danzo took my right eye...
He doesn't trust me.
He intends to protect
the Village his own way,
no matter what it takes
or how it looks.
I suspect he'll come after
my left eye as well.
So I want to give it to you
before he has a chance.
Shisui.
You're the only person I can count on,
my best friend.
Please protect this Village...
and the honor of the Uchiha name.
I accept it.
What will you do now?
If I die, several circumstances
will change.
I've left behind a note already...
Wait, Shisui!
Don't stop me, Itachi.
If you're my friend...
Shisui!
Shisui...
Shisui Uchiha, who threw himself
into the Nakano River
and killed himself last night…
Why don't you come out and say it?
You suspect me, don't you?
Yeah, we do, you punk.
Listen, Itachi.
Just try and betray the clan.
And you'll pay big time.
The clan, the clan...
You overestimate your own abilities,
and have no idea about
the depth of my own.
That's why you're
groveling there now.
Stop, Itachi!
What is going on?
Just wha—
There's no hope left…
for this pathetic clan.
Brother!
Please stop!
Observe carefully with
those eyes...
Sasuke.
Observe how shallow this clan is.
That's the Lightning Blade!
You're...the Copy Ninja of the Leaf!
Kaka...shi...
You've become quite well known.
Do it long enough and
you're bound to become famous.
Clear the area.
Leave no trace of the Hidden Leaf.
Yeah, yeah. I know.
Dirty work is part of
the ANBU's modus operandi.
You said that a friend gave
your Sharingan to you.
Along with a wish.
Do you need to honor that wish?
Yes, I intend to.
I know about
the Shisui Uchiha incident.
Is it about that?
No, I'm fine.
I see...
Anyway, there's not a lot I can do,
but let me know if there's anything.
Yes.
You're the only person I can count on,
my best friend.
Please protect this Village...
and the honor of the Uchiha name.
Shisui.
Things have gotten much worse
since then.
I don't think
I can protect everyone.
Oww! What are you accusing me of?!
Just be quiet!
Don't be so rough.
Captain...
You are a suspect...
and you're coming to
Headquarters with us.
F-Fine...
Remember to follow
our investigative procedures!
Yes, sir!
C'mon, move.
Shisui Uchiha was a core member
of the Uchiha.
His suicide demoralized and
lessened their fighting power all at once.
So the coup d'état has been foiled.
Are you saying there was no other
way but for Shisui to give his life?
I shouldn't have pushed him...
There are a few among the Uchiha
who believe that you killed Shisui.
The ones who believe that
did not know
that Shisui and I were working
towards the same goal.
Shisui did not appear at
our rendezvous point.
He had secrets,
so he was suspected.
I will notify the ANBU that
it was officially a suicide.
Agreed, Hiruzen?
From today, you are now
an ANBU squad leader.
It's not the Foundation,
but mission orders
will come from me…
There is no need to report this
to Hiruzen and his staff.
Yes.
Without further pause,
I have a mission for you.
It's a simple assassination.
The two behind you will assist you.
We are your subordinates from today.
We're honored to be of service.
Good work…
By the way...
While you were away,
the surveillance team that is
covering the Uchiha reported that
the Leaf Police is strengthening
their armaments.
What does this signify?
Resentment towards the Village has
been increasing among the Uchiha.
So we can't ignore it?
No.
Welcome home, Big Brother!
I'm going to go train.
Come with me.
I'm exhausted from my mission.
You never get tired, Big Brother.
Ouch!
Forgive me, Sasuke.
Maybe some other time.
Man!
You know about the clan meeting
in three days, right?
No.
Come alone to the Nakano Shrine
after the meeting.
Without your ANBU subordinates.
I'll be leaving tomorrow on
a mission away from the Village.
Don't run away.
"Run away"?
From what?
From your Uchiha destiny…
Isn't Itachi coming?
He's on a mission.
The Uchiha Clan…
is intent on revolting against
the Hidden Leaf.
There's no time to waste.
We must strike preemptively
before them.
The Uchiha were our comrades
in arms in past wars…
I would like to use words
before violence.
I will come up with a way.
Despite what Lord Third said…
when push comes to shove…
He will do what whatever it takes
to protect the Hidden Leaf.
I want you to choose.
Align with the Uchiha and
launch the coup d'état,
and be slaughtered
along with your family…
Or side with the Leaf,
and before they attempt a coup
d'état, eliminate every Uchiha?
Eliminate the Uchiha…
In order to protect the Leaf,
every possible step must
be taken to avoid mayhem.
The only one that can
handle this mission is you,
a double agent for both
the Uchiha and the Leaf.
There is no one else, Itachi.
Will you accept this mission?
The Village…the clan…shinobi…
Is fighting…inevitable?
The Village or the clan…
What should I do?
I wasn't serious just now.
Yes, you were, loser.
If I were serious,
I would have beaten you!
This time, I challenge you
to the high jump!
You're no match for me.
What did you say?!
Hey…
There's something I would
like you to help me with.
Who are you?!
Oh...
Such fine eyes.
No way!
Help…Itachi.
Help me!
Over here…
There are no traps.
Come inside.
Father!
I don't want to participate in
a death match…with my son.
I see…
You've aligned with the other side.
Father, Mother…
I…
We already know, Itachi…
Itachi, promise me this.
Take care of Sasuke.
I will.
Do not fear it.
This is the path you've chosen.
Compared to yours,
our pain will end in an instant.
Our philosophies may differ,
but I'm proud of you.
You truly are a kind child.
It's over.
You're…
Never mind. Shall we go?
Go on ahead.
I'm going to confirm things…
with the Leaf higher-ups.
This is horrible!
What the hell?
Rescue anyone who is still alive!
There's a survivor!
Take him to the Medical Unit!
Everyone else is dead.
Take away the corpses.
I mean, every single one.
Check inside the buildings as well.
Who could have done such a thing?
Itachi Uchiha.
Itachi?!
Itachi Uchiha despised his clan.
That is why he killed Shisui
and took his eyes,
and caused in-fighting among
his brethren...and then finally...
He caused this atrocity.
But, why would he...?
Enough talking. Get to work!
This settles everything.
What does this settle?
Don't you see the huge problem
we're left with?!
I consider it very minor.
Danzo, I cannot allow you to act
on your own authority any longer.
As of this moment,
you are relieved of your duties
as second in command.
But Hiruzen, I did it for...
"The good of the Leaf"?
Well then, the Uchiha Clan belonged
to the Hidden Leaf.
Your ANBU and Foundation
will be dissolved!
I will deal with you later.
Until then,
you are confined to your quarters!
Lord Danzo, the body count
doesn't match up.
What did you say?
It's like they just disappeared.
I witnessed everything.
And I will continue to watch.
If you as much as touch Sasuke,
I will pass on classified Village intel
to every enemy nation.
Damn you...
If this is the scope of Itachi's hatred,
it ran very, very deep...
Just one survivor...
Start taking them away.
Yes, sir.
What a mission, even for an ANBU.
First, you have my thanks.
Civil war has been averted
in the Hidden Leaf.
We have maintained peace.
Yes.
However, I regret that there was
no other way to achieve this.
I apologize.
I'm the one who must apologize.
You will now be branded a Rogue
Ninja who massacred his entire clan,
and be listed in the Bingo Book
as a fugitive, wanted dead or alive.
That goes without saying.
What will you do from now?
I've found aid from a group
called the "Akatsuki."
I intend to stay close to them
in order to make sure
a promise is not broken.
What do you want now?
You're a Rogue Ninja listed
in the Bingo Book, Captain.
An S-class, no less.
As Foundation members, we want to
make it appear like we pursued you.
- Please go easy on us.
Your swordsmanship hints at more
than just maintaining "appearances."
The Sharingan won't work.
We won't look into your eyes.
A genjutsu?!
How?!
When you first came to me
as my subordinates…
We are your subordinates from today.
I imbedded a suggestion in case
you turned your sword on me.
You didn't trust us…
from the very beginning?
I was a double agent.
I see through the eyes of
both the Leaf and the Uchiha.
To be frank,
I don't know whose spy I was...
even to this day.
Within the organization,
I'm known as Tobi.
I'm not an official member.
I'm a newbie within the Akatsuki who
doesn't possess any spectacular jutsu.
You should…
treat me the same way.
Why hide your true identity?
If word gets out that Madara Uchiha is
alive things could become complicated.
Only the leader of Akatsuki,
who we're meeting now,
knows my true identity.
The goal of the Akatsuki…
is a world of true peace
among shinobi.
Instead of the Five Great
Shinobi Nations,
the Akatsuki shall rule the world.
That's a big goal.
That's why we're assembling
skilled shinobi
without asking where they're from
or what they've done.
Itachi of the Hidden Leaf,
we welcome you into the Akatsuki.
From this moment on,
reject the Hidden Leaf.
From now…
you are Itachi of the Akatsuki.
Show the world pain…
Juzo...
Huh?
Form a two-man team with Itachi.
Okay.
Follow me, newbie.
Yes.
Do you know a shinobi
named Might Dai?
I know a Might Guy.
Huh, well that’s the kid from that time.
I was one of the Seven Ninja
Swordsmen of the Mist.
Thanks to Might Dai,
the seven of us got cut down to three.
Who could have expected that scuzzy
bearded jerk would use taijutsu like that?
Anyway, I wanna make
something clear...
I could care less why
you joined the Akatsuki.
I don’t even want
to hear your reason.
It doesn’t matter why I joined either.
And it’s okay if
you don’t want to know.
Listen to me!
There’s something
I need to ask you.
And…
It’s about your ninjutsu specialties.
As you see, I use this Executioner’s Blade
and cut up enemies.
So? How about you?
Genjutsu, Fire Style and Shuriken Jutsu.
You’re awfully humble!
Former ANBU Itachi Uchiha, Itachi of
the Sharingan, the Clan-Killer Itachi...
People throw around many nicknames
for you...you’re notorious.
Let’s decide on our formations.
You’ll start with a preemptive attack
with your genjutsu, shuriken or
whatever’s your specialty.
Then I’ll jump in.
And you back me up.
That will be Formation B
What’s A?
We each do things our own way.
Understood.
One word of warning.
Don’t take any opponent for granted.
Understood.
- Who are you?
- Get out of our way!
Shinobi villages only say things
about peace and order,
but they’re really worried
about their roles shrinking.
Behind the scenes,
they’re all trying
to lessen their opponent’s power
while increasing their own.
All the while, preventing other nations
from finding out their schemes.
That’s why the Akatsuki gets jobs.
The more peaceful the world is,
the more work we get...
We accept every request.
We don’t care about the details.
You scoundrels!
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
Why you—!
That’s why…
We don’t know who’s inside
this palanquin…
And we don’t want to know either.
There’s also no need to think about
who the hell would pay us
to do such dirty work.
That’s what the Akatsuki is about.
Pain, the leader, said the Akatsuki
was going to rule the world.
That won’t be for a long time.
We first need to amass money
and power.
Speak of the devil,
he’s summoning us.
So Itachi, have you gotten
used to the Akatsuki?
How would you feel about changing
partners and teaming up with me?
Hey, we’re just getting
our formation down.
Don’t try to steal him.
I second changing partners...
There’s an aspect called compatibility...
I wish our leader would put
a bit more thought into this.
You’re one to talk, you damn snake!
Thanks to your work, Akatsuki’s reputation
is growing in the underworld.
The jobs we’re getting are
becoming bigger in scale,
which means higher compensation
as well.
But that’s only just a step.
And the Akatsuki is ready to
move on to the next step…
which are the Tailed Beasts.
There’re supposed to be nine of ‘em.
Are those the Tailed Beasts?
The Five Great Ninja Nations
harbor most of them.
But the whereabouts are unknown
for a few of them.
Those who aren’t on a job
will try to locate them.
So we just have to locate them?
For now.
What will you do with them eventually?
We’ll hunt down and collect
every Tailed Beast.
And then?
They’ll act as our deterrents in our quest
for world domination.
Tailed Beasts?
Seems to me there are
lots of other ways…
There’s no mistake in
the leader’s reasoning.
Here are the assignments.
Juzo…
You’ll handle the request
from the Land of Water.
Isn’t there another mission I can do?!
You’re familiar with the territory.
This is ridiculous.
I never wanted to go back
to that depressing place.
Is that the village where you’re from?
The job’s easy.
We have to assassinate a member
from the Feudal Lord's clan
in the Land of Water.
I'll explain...
It’s an intra-clan fight
over succession,
a common occurrence in
the Land of Water.
The Hidden Mist cannot interfere
in the Feudal Clan's affairs.
That’s why they’ve come to the Akatsuki.
This river’s the border.
Have you ever been to
the Land of Water?
Never on a mission.
So for an outing then?
You’ve got no sense of humor!
But you do know, don’t you?
What happens to a shinobi
from another village
if he’s discovered in
the Land of Water?
The Hidden Mist doesn’t have
a policy for prisoner exchange...
If captured, the shinobi will be made to
divulge his jutsu and he’ll be disposed of.
You have it good, Itachi.
The Leaf is naïve.
That’s why you and Orochimaru can go
around without a care as rogue ninja...
There is a special unit in the Hidden Mist
that track down rogue ninja.
If I ever get caught in this village…
Oh, I forgot all about Formation C.
If I’m caught by the Mist,
kill me immediately.
If I have a chance.
So what do you want me
to do for Formation D?
Nothing in particular.
Fine, let’s get going!
Are you good at infiltrating?
I'm average.
Okay, show me.
P-Please! Spare me!
I don’t bear a grudge against you.
This is just my job.
W-Wait!
Hey…
Yeah.
Hidden Mist Jutsu!
Wind Style: Supreme Typhoon!
This is—?!
Lord Fourth!
Is that the Mizukage?
Do you remember my warning?
Any way you look at him,
he’s a kid.
He’s the Jinchuriki of
the Three Tails.
And they are the Mist’s
Shinobi Tracking Unit.
I never expected you to reappear
in the Village, Juzo.
I didn’t wanna come back either.
I had no choice.
I have a ton of things to say to you…
At the very least, I’m taking back
the Executioner’s Blade.
Even if your partner
is Itachi of the Sharingan.
So I guess a surprise attack with
your genjutsu is meaningless.
What do you want to do?
This one’s a Formation C.
Formation C? Understood.
Don’t look!
It's a Water Clone!
Itachi!
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
Lord Fourth!
You two…
I’ll show no mercy.
Tailed Beast State?!
The Fourth is a Jinchuriki
who can control his Tailed Beast!
This is not the Hidden Leaf!
Juzo!
It’s the Fourth’s Coral Palm Jutsu.
Juzo?!
Run...Itachi…
W-What?!
What is this?
The power of the Mangekyo Sharingan?
Why you—!
Juzo…?
Did you kill…the Mizukage?
No, he’s not dead yet.
Then…
Hurry! Go!
But…
It's all over for me…
You don’t have to be
a Medic Ninja to know that, right?
I’m sorry.
What a stupid thing to say.
Do you have any last words
for anyone?
Like I'd have anyone, idiot.
I see…But you have someone
like that, huh?
Hurry and go!
I’m just gonna drop dead, right here,
where I'm from…
…this god-forsaken,
Blood Mist Village…
I thought my only partner…
was this guy here, but…
Juzo Biwa is dead.
Oh my, and he was
your teammate, Itachi.
The Jinchuriki of
the Three Tails killed him.
Which means you took on
the Mizukage and came out of it alive.
Another one of us is dead.
Rather than being killed by the enemy,
he was killed by friendly fire.
He was just too slow.
Let everyone here be the judge of that.
Fire Style: Searing Migraine!
Done in bad faith.
Sounds like it was on purpose.
He should have just dodged it.
You ignored your partner, didn't you?
So what?
You wanted to kill him, didn't you?
Oh, nothing. It just seems
to happen a lot.
The Akatsuki works in two-man teams.
What will you do, Kakuzu?
Will you team up with Itachi
who’s also lost his partner?
As long as he doesn’t irritate me.
I wouldn’t know how to cater
to your moods.
What the hell did you say?
Then let's team up and I'll show you.
Wait, I’ll team up with Itachi.
Are you trying to make a fool out of me?!
The Akatsuki needs to
find some new members.
We’ll put this issue on hold until we do.
Do you know what eternal life is, Itachi?
I don’t know yet, either.
That’s why I need a new body.
A magnificent body to link me
to eternal life.
First of all, the problem with you…
is your greed.
Impossible! Have I fallen prey to
the Paralysis Jutsu?
What incredible visual prowess…
Magnificent!
Orochimaru…
Try all of the jutsu you wish...
But, my eyes can see through
all of them.
You're so blunt…
I’m not sure what to do with you.
Whether to kill you right now,
or find a way to use you.
I-Itachi!
You just don’t have enough...
No, you lack it completely...the greed…
for human life!
Lord Orochimaru!
I’ll definitely get you back for this.
Orochimaru betrayed and
deserted our organization.
I knew it, that bastard.
He always put himself
before the organization.
I don’t intend to let Orochimaru
get away with this...
Leave Orochimaru to me.
His subordinate, Kabuto, is my puppet.
I’ll find out where
he’s hiding out in no time.
No need to rush.
I have someone in mind
to be your partner.
It can wait until he joins us.
What about me?
Do I team up with Itachi?
Work alone for a while longer.
I have someone else I’ve prepared
to partner up with Itachi.
I’m going to be your partner
from today.
The "Akatsuki"?
Don't know and don't care.
Now get lost! You're keeping me
from my "art appreciation" time.
And I have to take this brat on
as my partner?
Sure, he's full of energy,
but he seems like
the type to die young.
It's our leader's orders…
His talent will be very useful.
How do you know about my talent?
Just who the hell are you anyway?
We know you're aiding
anti-government factions
of neighboring nations with bombings…
You're a Rogue Ninja,
but what is your purpose?
Purpose? I don't need a purpose!
I take commissions to
cause explosions…using my art.
He's annoying…
Is he done?
Who knows…?
It doesn't matter.
I'll do it.
Let me make it clear,
I won't stop in my pursuit of art!
Do as you please.
But now that you're a part
of the Akatsuki,
I expect you to fulfill your missions.
All right, all right, I got it.
But…
you over there!
I'll never get caught up
in your genjutsu again, hmm!
Now that you're one of us,
I doubt that I'll have to
use my genjutsu on you.
I don't mind giving you
a taste of my art.
Leave it at that.
Sasori!
Partner with Deidara
and go kill Orochimaru.
About time.
Who is this Orochimaru?
I'll tell you on the way.
Orochimaru has escaped
into the Land of Wind.
Beyond that, I don't know.
That's all I need to know.
Let's go.
You Akatsuki sure like
to order guys around…
Hey, hurry up.
I know!
Itachi and Kisame,
go to the Hidden Grass Village.
What about my partner?
Wait just a while longer.
I've ordered Kabuto to keep me
updated through several ways.
If they're headed to
the Land of Wind, this is the spot…
The Great Sand Dune of the East…
I see…
That's one place the guys
from the Village won't go near.
Is that where you're from, my man?
I don't want to talk about it.
Anyway, that location
works out perfectly.
That's his hideout.
I'll blow the whole thing up
with my art, hmm!
We don't even know if
he's there or not.
Sand Snakes!
It's useless…
They know we're here.
Are you serious?
Let's go.
I was expecting Itachi to
be the one who'd come…
So you're the ones the Akatsuki sent?
We're going to kill you
without hesitation, you traitor.
Oh, do you really think you can?
You're the boy from the Hidden Stone…
You used to be in
the Demolitions Unit, right?
Don't treat me like a kid!
Keep watch from above and
make sure he doesn't get away.
What gives, my man?
Are you saying that you want
to capture him yourself?
Yeah, since you have
no grudges against him, right?
If you want back-up,
just call on me at any time, hmm!
I have the geographical
advantage here.
So that's your work, my man?
You're aware of
the Third Kazekage's power, aren't you?
Yes…
My hobby is to collect things that I
find interesting, so I took a little bit.
What the hell?
Huh?
What's that over there?
Is that you, Sasori…?
You bastard, how dare
you do this to me!
What's that, you damn snake?
It‘s the Third Kazekage
that you killed.
I used a Forbidden Jutsu
to resurrect him.
Things won't go the way
they did last time…
Enough of your resentful complaints…
Now then…
With your Human Puppet…
and my Forbidden Jutsu.
Let's see which is superior!
Damn you…
Iron Sand: Scattered Showers!
Unlike the real thing, the puppet stops
working when Iron Sand gets into it, right?
Don't lecture me about puppets!
Unlike the real thing, I've built in
lots of hidden tricks into the puppet.
It's your turn…
Not yet.
What?!
This is one form of immortality…
It doesn't die, even though
it's already dead.
There's no way it can't die!
Heargh!
Well?! How do you like my art?!
Why doesn't it die?
After you two die, I'll resurrect you
both in the same way.
Although, what I really wanted…
was Itachi's body.
My man!
Does that guy have a weakness?!
Resurrection isn't one of
the Third's abilities…
You are both going to become
my pawns forever.
Stop kidding around…
I…am the Third Kazekage…
I am not...
your pawn!
Oh my…
I wonder if my jutsu wasn't complete?
Take this!
Is he dead?!
Don't run away!
Heargh!
Art is…!
…an explosion!
Hey, c'mon now…
We thoroughly searched
the mountain of rubble,
but we didn't find his corpse.
So we can't say for sure
that we killed him.
If he's alive,
I swear I'll kill him myself.
Besides, what was with
that ridiculous jutsu?!
Do you know anything about it?
It's probably the Second Hokage's
Reanimation Jutsu.
You bring the dead back to life,
and control them like a puppet.
You can't kill it even if you tried.
So you must use a Sealing Jutsu
or suppress their movement forcefully.
We just have to kill Orochimaru, right?
Even that won't stop a reanimated being…
What's the supposed to mean?
Be wary of Orochimaru from now on.
If he's alive,
he's bound to make another move.
Ordinarily, no one could
survive that explosion, hmm.
No one who joins us is ordinary.
Another immortal has appeared
out of the woodwork.
We have a request from
the Land of Steam.
A homicidal maniac has appeared
and they want us to eliminate him.
Don't they have
their own Hidden Steam shinobi?
Apparently, they can't kill it.
So this homicidal maniac
is immortal too?
Was he "reani-whatevered"
by Orochimaru too?
I'm dispatching
a different team this time.
You there…
Would you like to join
the Way of Jashin?
This wasn't for money or revenge.
This was out of
a deep desire to kill.
There are other ways
to quench blood thirst…
He had some other purpose.
You really have
a way of irritating me.
And you...Did you come to
make sure I don't kill Itachi?
There are no other
Sensory types besides me.
And…
The others certainly aren't
cut out to be decoys.
Decoys?
All right then…
Hey, you over there.
Do you want to join
the Way of Jashin?
Way of Jashin?
Yeah, the Way of Jashin…
What is that?
You can kill people and
you won't be punished.
In fact, it just pleases
Lord Jashin even more.
I see…
What do you say?
Isn't that a wonderful teaching?
Are you interested in joining?
So you're the homicidal maniac…
Homicidal maniac?
That's not it at all.
I'm just offering up prayers
to Lord Jashin.
Looks like I'll just have to
offer you up to Lord Jashin.
Well?
He doesn't seem to be
a Reanimation.
Fine. I'll test him to see
how immortal he is.
Who are you guys,
dressed up all the same?
You in an orchestra or
band or something?
Let's see...The gloomy one
over there plays bass…
The girl does vocals and keyboards…
No, maybe that guy there
does vocals?
We're nothing like that.
I think Lord Jashin would like
you guys as an offering.
What's wrong?
Is running around all you can do?!
Well, I won't let you get away!
What? Done so soon?
Ouch…
That hurt!
Oh…
I'll punish you in the name of god!
That's not gonna help you!
Looks like the rumors about
your immortality are true.
Okay, let's start the ritual.
Everything is ready!
Die…!
One stab into the heart…
Damn you!
It feels so good…
Glory be to Lord Jashin!
You bastard…You got some nerve…
Hey, hey...Why didn't you die?
I'll beat you to death!
No, you can't!
Did you notice anything?
He licked Kakuzu's blood
and then mentioned something
about a ritual.
That's probably some jutsu too.
He passes on any damage he sustains
to the one whose blood he licks.
However, that doesn't
explain his immortality.
Can you separate them?
Weren't you going to eliminate him?
Yeah.
W-What?!
What's the big idea, Itachi?!
Seems they're recruiting him.
A guy like him?
Are you kidding me? I refuse!
Whatever the Akatsuki is…
I have a mission to spread
the Way of Jashin.
Then you should join the Akatsuki
for the sake of your mission too.
What?
Assassinations, war, you name it,
the Akatsuki will do anything…
since we're a band of killers.
I plan to continue propagating
the Way of Jashin.
Do as you please.
Our two-man teams are in place.
Go and execute your missions.
I didn't expect to be
partnered with you.
You took the words out of my mouth.
Don't irritate me,
or I'll kill you.
Like I said. Just try it!
I don't want your heart.
Art…
…is an explosion!
It's art!
I still don't get what
your art is about.
Soon, you'll understand the aesthetics
of something that's fleeting, hmm.
Hm? It's the leader.
A shinobi village named the Hidden
Sound recently came into existence.
It's possible that
Orochimaru is involved.
That guy!
I want you two to
covertly check them out.
Since you guys specialize in sneaking
around behind the scenes.
I'll find him!
And make him go boom!
The orders were to do it covertly.
There's been an incident
at the Hidden Leaf Village.
Orochimaru's behind it.
Orochimaru used shinobi from
the Hidden Sound and Hidden Sand
to wage war against the Leaf…
But he failed to completely
destroy the Leaf.
Serves him right!
The Third Hokage
was killed in battle.
Orochimaru withdrew,
but his whereabouts are unknown.
I'll send someone out
to investigate, but…
I'll go.
Then I'll leave this to you,
as well as the status
of the Leaf's Jinchuriki.
It seems they
averted total destruction,
but they've sustained
massive damage.
That Village was at
the height of prosperity…
How tragic.
That was out of character.
So even you have feelings
for your birthplace, after all?
No…
Not at all.
Sasuke...Are you safe?
Kakashi.
It's unusual that
you're here first.
Well, it happens once in a while.
What's going on?
Why did you summon us here?
Sasuke!
You've grown up…
It's been a long time, Sasuke.
Itachi Uchiha!
I will…
…kill you!
Ah…the Sharingan.
I see a resemblance…
Just who is he?
He's my younger brother.
So you've awakened your Sharingan.
Otherwise…
It's just as you've said.
I've hated you, and resented you.
I have lived my life…
How strong have you gotten?
…for the sole purpose
of killing you…
Chidori?!
I see…it was Kakashi, huh?
Sasuke!
Damn it!
Ninja Art: Summoning—!
Too slow!
Master Jiraiya!
So your target is Naruto,
after all?
Taking Naruto is the overriding mission
we have been assigned to, by the Akatsuki.
I can't let you have Naruto.
I wonder about that…
Perfect timing. I will get rid of
both of you right here.
Don't interfere…
If anyone is going to kill him…
It will be me.
I have no interest
in you right now.
Not yet, Sasuke.
Sasuke!
Damn it!
Naruto!
I said not to interfere!
This is my fight!
That's right.
Fine by me!
You still don't have enough…
Forgive me, Sasuke.
Forgive me!
You are merciless.
Hate me…
You are weak.
From now, for 24 hours…
Relive that day.
Using Tsukuyomi on
your younger brother?
That's enough…outta…you!
You are weak, because
you don't have enough hatred.
C'mon, Kisame!
Wait! Why you—!
Why did we have to retreat?
You could have—!
Sasuke…
Even though Lord Third is dead,
you still have people
who will protect you…
I'll be waiting, Sasuke.
Why are you so obsessed
with my brother?
He's just a Rogue Ninja.
That's because, unlike you…
He's more of a brother to me
than you are to him…
You've been trying to take Sasuke
back to the village.
But what if it doesn't
go the way you want it to?
I'll do anything to bring him back!
You just said you consider
Sasuke to be like a brother…
What if Sasuke were to attack
the Hidden Leaf Village?
What would you do then?
What? Why would Sasuke—?
There's no way
he'd do something like that!
Sasuke is still a blank canvas.
He can easily be dyed
into any color.
In that case,
would you be able to stop him?
Even if you have to kill Sasuke?
Could you weigh Sasuke against
the Hidden Leaf on a set of scales?
I would defend the Leaf Village!
And I would find a way to stop
Sasuke without killing him!
You're such a child…
What you speak of
are all fantasies.
A shinobi must be capable of
making very harsh decisions.
Someone else tried to tell me
the same thing before.
But for me, there is no choice.
I never go back on my word…
That's my ninja way.
I see.
You've come…
That Sharingan…
How much can you actually see?
What I'm seeing right now…
Is your death, Itachi.
My death, huh?
Well then…
…make it happen.
If I had been open with you
from the start…
and looked you straight in
the eyes and told you the truth,
Forgive me, Sasuke…
This is the end.
then I wouldn't have had
to stand before you,
from above, as a failure,
telling you all of this.
So this time, I want to impart
this truth to you…
You don't ever have to forgive me.
And no matter what you do
from here on out, know this…
I will love you always.