He's coming along nicely. Now...
Will you still emerge as a snake?
Or will you transform into a hawk?
We shall see, Sasuke...
That girl's late...
How long does it take to
pick up supplies...?
I wish it would get dark soon...
After Jugo and Suigetsu turn in,
I'll make my move on Sasuke
while he sleeps!
I'm so excited!
This feeling...
Well, Kiba?!
I'm concentrating, trying to
single out Sasuke's faint scent!
So shut up! You're distracting me!
There's no mistake...
They're steadily approaching.
One... two...
Their chakra is strong too.
There are quite a few.
I sense non-human chakra too.
Dogs?
Are they tracking our scent?
Is it Akatsuki?
Or maybe the Hidden Leaf?
Jugo.
I'm going to go check on Karin.
Yeah.
Wh-What...?
Wake up, Sasuke!
We're going to have company!
What do we do?!
Sasuke just waking up... is also nice!
We're escaping. Get ready.
Jugo, mark every Akatsuki hideout
that we know of.
You're okay now, Sasuke?
Yeah. I've been healing a lot faster
since I absorbed Orochimaru's power.
So this is the Power of the White Snake...
Whether it's Akatsuki
or the Hidden Leaf,
they might have information
on Itachi.
So why don't we ambush them, Sasuke?
Based on the numbers you reported,
it's most likely the Hidden Leaf.
Akatsuki always work
in two-man cells.
Which means an ambush
would be a waste of time.
Exactly. Forget the Hidden Leaf.
Then what'll we do?
Itachi is our only priority.
Once we locate him...
If worst comes to worst,
you three must stop the Hidden Leaf.
For now, Team Hebi will use
the information gathered by Jugo
and check out Akatsuki hideouts
one by one.
All right...
Let's go.
Help me out for a second.
With that?
Can you gather as many birds
as you can?
What do you plan on doing?
This is Sasuke's old outfit.
It's soaked with his sweat and scent,
so we'll use this to...
Why would you have an outfit
that Sasuke threw away?
Uh...! Th-That...
That's not important...
Y-You jerk!
A-Anyway...
I hate to do this, but...
Sensory-type ninja from different
villages have their own specialties.
The Hidden Leaf often
uses ninja hounds.
So we'll use that to
our advantage.
What's wrong, Kiba?
This is bad! Sasuke is starting to move!
Let's hurry!
Sasuke is going after Itachi!
Hold it, something's wrong!
Sasuke's scent is dispersing!
Not only that,
it's scattering in all directions!
He's onto us and is taking countermeasures.
On to us? But how?!
I don't know what kind of power.
But I'm guessing he has a
skilled sensory-type ninja on his side.
The distance is too great,
so I can't guide you by wireless.
I'm the only one
who can pursue him...
But they're all the same scent.
Which one do we follow?
I'll find him if I have to search
every blade of grass!
With whatever means necessary!
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Water Style: Four Shark Shower!
As good as you are,
even you can't dodge all these...
I stand corrected.
I've always wanted to go
head-to-head with you like this.
Even Samehada is happy.
Water Style:
Water Shark Bomb Jutsu!
Fire Style:
Fireball Jutsu!
It's over.
With the Sharingan, you're able
to find my faint shadow from behind
and attack even in the mist...
Impressive...
Is what I'd normally say.
So you saw through me and
used a water clone, huh?
It's been a long time
since I've had to do this...
Hmph... So happy to see
you using that visual jutsu.
Never thought you'd be serious
enough to use Amaterasu like that.
Too bad that visual jutsu
uses up too much chakra.
Won't that hurt your chances when
you go up against Sasuke after this?
Why don't we call it a day...?
Just seeing you like this
is satisfying enough for me.
I didn't want to
fight you like this...
Look at you go...
I can't remember the
last time I sweated this much.
I want to fight
Sasuke one on one.
Do me a favor and keep
everyone else out of it.
Fair enough. But, still...
It's a little sad
parting with you like this.
After everything
we've been through together.
It's up ahead...
You guys wait for my signal.
I'll scout ahead.
Who's that...?
Sharingan?!
Sasuke?!
Th-That's--!
Itachi... Uchiha!
Come on out... Naruto Uzumaki.
You've come to capture me?
No... I didn't.
I just came to talk to you.
Like I'd ever trust you!
I know that you're alone.
So why don't you run?
Hah! I can become a thousand in an instant!
Besides, I can't run away!
If I capture you, I get to see Sasuke!
Why are you so attached to my brother?
He's a rogue ninja.
That's because unlike you...
I think of him as a brother
more than you ever would.
You're already under my genjutsu.
Damn it!!
I'll say it again.
I just wanted to talk to you
for a moment.
You've been trying to take
Sasuke back to the village.
But... what if it doesn't
go the way you want?
I'll do anything
to make it happen.
Even by force?
If, by some turn of luck,
Sasuke willingly goes with you, great.
But what if the
exact opposite happens?
What does that mean?
You just said...
you consider Sasuke
to be like a brother...
What if Sasuke were
to attack the Leaf village?
What would you do then?
What? Why would Sasuke...?
There's no way
he'd do something like that!
Sasuke is still naive.
He can easily be dyed any color.
In such a case,
could you stop him?
Even if you had to kill him?
Can you weigh Sasuke
against the Leaf on a set of scales?
I would defend the Leaf!
But I would stop Sasuke
without killing him!
You're such a child...
What you speak of
is nothing but a fantasy.
Shinobi must sometimes
make very harsh decisions.
Someone tried telling
me something similar before...
But for me, there is no choice.
I never go back on my word...
That's my ninja way!
I have shared some of
my power with you.
Though...
I hope the day never comes
when you have to use it...
Wh-What's going on?
Aren't you after me?
Then this is your...!
I'm going now...
I have an important task to do.
Shadow Clone...
What was that?
Damn! This one's a bust too!
What's wrong, Naruto?
Oh, nothing...
Did something happen?
I just tripped.
Never mind that.
Kiba, track the next scent.
So you've come...
Who's there?!
It's me... Sasuke.
You've grown a bit taller.
And you're still the same.
Even those cold eyes...
Not going to scream and attack
like you did before?
You don't know a thing about me...
How much hatred I carry inside me...
And how strong I have become
because of that hatred.
You don't know me at all.
You've become... strong.
Come to the Uchiha hideout alone.
I'll let you settle things there.
Sasuke!
I told you not to move until
you received orders.
Karin said she sensed another chakra,
so we were worried.
Feathers?
Follow me. Let's go!
The same chakra is all over the place!
What's going on?!
Should we change course, Sasuke?
Ignore it. We'll forge straight ahead.
Good. Taking the long way
would've been tiring.
Sasuke!
What was that?!
A Shadow Clone.
Naruto, eh?
What a pest.
Multi-Shadow Clones... I get it now...
The same chakra I sense all over
the place belongs to him.
Found him!
Good job!
Which way?!
This way!
I'm not letting you get away
this time, Sasuke!
What is this?!
A humongous chakra! And it's fast!
Incoming!
You're...!
Only Sasuke may go beyond this point.
It's Itachi's orders.
The rest of you are welcome
to wait here.
All right. Besides, we were only
traveling as a squad
in order to prevent interference
with my showdown...
This will do.
No, you can't, Sasuke!
Let's take him down and
go in together!
I have no intention of fighting.
But if you insist on going with him,
I will show no mercy.
Karin... Stay put.
This is my vendetta.
Kisame Hoshigaki...
and the great sword, Samehada.
Hmm?
Have you forgotten me?
I'm Suigetsu Hozuki,
the younger brother of Mangetsu Hozuki.
Oh... I didn't recognize you!
You've grown, Suigetsu.
I don't want to just wait around
for Sasuke...
Will you let me kill some time
and have some fun with you,
Kisame-senpai?!
Unlike your brother,
you're quite cocky, aren't you?
Maybe I should grind you down a bit.
Suigetsu... Shouldn't we abide
by Sasuke's orders?
Don't be stupid! You blockhead!
This way, guys!
Wait! Naruto...
This chakra...
Howdy!
What the-?!
Well now... How's it going there,
there, and there?
Imagine running into the Hidden Leaf
in a place like this...
I mean... It's two, four, six...
Eight against one. Such bad timing.
That robe...
You're a member of the Akatsuki!
Though he wasn't on the list
that Kabuto left us.
Oh, I'm a newbie. Nice to meet you.
Hah! Think you're funny?!
Don't waste our time!
Don't be rash. Study the situation first.
Right now, we have him outnumbered.
Oh dear...
Am I being underestimated?
By you guys?
So this is an Akatsuki member...
Another weirdo...
They keep getting between us and
Sasuke over and over again!
Don't get in our way!
A Shadow Clone?!
Just kidding...
It seems you're more proficient
with the blade than that kid.
Kid?!
You mean, Zabuza-senpai?
My great sword Samehada
wasn't made for dueling, you know!
Same here. This one's...
for killing!
Tsk! Have fun? As if!
They're dead serious!
Hey! Jugo... Tell him...
It's okay... The birds are telling me
there's no one nearby who will interfere
with their fighting.
Honestly... What if something happens
to Sasuke
while these idiots are going at it?
Even the Hidden Leaf are in pursuit!
The Hidden Leaf have stopped?
You're so full of yourself!
Just what can a kid like you do?!
Naruto...
Thank goodness...
Hinata!
Naruto can handle the damage!
Don't take your eyes off the enemy!
Hmm? Are you guys analyzing
my strength right now?
The Hidden Leaf are very shrewd...
But for a newbie, I'm pretty good...
don't you think?
He's dodged every one
of Naruto's attacks.
He's toying with us.
But what is he after?
Now then... What shall we play,
Hidden Leaf folks?
We don't have time to waste
on the likes of you!
He's right!
That's because we have to go
after Sasuke.
Shino, you didn't get to go on
the last mission to retrieve Sasuke!
We're counting on you this time!
Our bond, is it?
All right... everyone.
Let's end this quickly.
We'll go with Formation B.
Roger!
- Right!
- Yes sir!
Ohh? Seems you're serious.
Well, I'd better get fired up.
You jerk... Quit kidding around!
Naruto, concentrate on the formation!
Yeah, I know.
Let's do it.
Kiba, are you ready on your side?
Anytime. Right, Akamaru?!
Then here goes!
Oh my, so high...
That girl has such brute power.
Oops! They distracted me with the decoy...
And now those three are surrounding me!
I don't know which one to dodge!
S-Say, that's no fair!
- No time for you to look!
- Oh dear...
What...?
Cha! Cha!
Olé!
Three against one?!
You Hidden Leaf cowards!
Rasengan!
You weren't the decoy?
You got me...!
Not!
Ninja Art: Blockade Jutsu!
Honestly... You said you were going
to do it all together...
And I believed you!
Don't stop, everyone!
Separate and force your way through!
Accha! Ni-Ni-Ninja Art:
Ai-ai-ai-ai! Mo-!
What kind of jutsu is that?
I got it! I'm going to name this jutsu...
Ninja Art: Whack-A-Mole Jutsu!
Except the roles for
hitting are reversed...
Senpai...
I know...
Unless we finish him off for good,
he won't let us move forward.
Damn it!
Say, say... What shall we play next?
We can't be wasting time
in a place like this!
I know that.
We'll go with Battle Formation A next.
My foolish little brother...
That Sharingan...
How much can you actually see?
How much can I see with these?
What I'm seeing right now, Itachi...
is your death.
My death, huh?
Well then...
make it happen.
Chidori!
Chidori Stream!
You've become... strong.
Itachi... I have one last thing to ask...
You've become... strong
The same line as before...
and the bird...
Another farce with
your special genjutsu?
What do you want to know?
It's not over, but I'll hear you out.
I'll say it once more...
Genjutsu...
I have one last thing to ask...
That's what I said, you bastard!
Answer my question.
That pain in your chest
won't subside until you answer.
So you purposely missed a vital spot...
You said back then...
If you awaken
the Mangekyo Sharingan,
there will be three, including myself,
who possess its powers.
Then...
there will be meaning
in letting you live.
The third person...
The other one with a Sharingan...
Who in the Uchiha Clan is it?
Why... the curiosity about such a thing?
I'm going to kill him after you.
That's why.
Kill?
When you killed off the entire clan,
you mentioned the existence
of another person.
So that Uchiha member you didn't kill
was a co-conspirator.
Even you couldn't have killed the
entire Military Police Force alone.
So you figured it out...
Who is it?!
It's Madara Uchiha...
Madara... Uchiha?!
One of the founders of
the Hidden Leaf Village...
The man who first possessed
the Mangekyo Sharingan.
Founder?
Then Madara should be long dead!
Are you making fun of me?!
Madara is alive...
It's up to you whether you believe
that or not.
Stop joking around!
In order to survive, we cling to
all we know and understand.
And we label it reality.
But knowledge and understanding
are ambiguous.
That reality could be an illusion.
All people live, bound by their
own knowledge and perception.
Isn't that another way
of looking at it?
Just what are you trying to say?
It's only your assumption
that Madara is dead.
In exactly the same way
you once assumed that
I was your kind older brother.
What happened that night...
I was so young and thought
it was all an illusion.
That I was caught in
a cruel genjutsu...
I wanted to believe that.
But that was... unmistakably reality!
My eye is not like it was
in the past!
My Sharingan can see
through genjutsu!
You still speak with such confidence.
But for now, I'll take your word for it.
Why don't we end this little charade?
Being confident is fine.
But Sasuke, your eye still isn't
the same as mine.
Then one day, come before me with
the same eye that I possess.
So... you couldn't kill the friend
who is most dear to you.
And you dared to appear before me
with such weak resolve?
Then hurry and try to kill me
with your Mangekyo Sharingan!
Or is it too difficult to test
your capability against me now?
You're pretty sure of yourself...
Neither of them has moved
for a while.
They're just feeling each other out
with genjutsu.
Mangekyo Sharingan...
This eye is special...
From the moment it awakens,
it goes towards the dark.
And the more it is used,
the more it is sealed.
What do you mean?
In time, the Mangekyo Sharingan
loses its light.
Blindness...
Is that the trade-off for the power
to control the Nine-Tails?
You did as I instructed and read
the stone tablet in the main hall?
Madara... Exactly who and what is he?
The first one ever to use that eye
to tame the Nine-Tails.
An immortal man who is both
my partner and my mentor...
And the only one to uncover the
other secret of the Mangekyo Sharingan.
That... is Madara Uchiha.
It has another ocular power aside
from taming the Nine-Tails?
Yes... One more secret.
The most important secret.
What is it?! Answer me!
Let me tell you a little
about the past.
It concerns the history
of the Uchiha.
Long ago, Madara had a brother...
A younger brother.
Madara Uchiha and
his younger brother...
From the time they were little,
they honed their skills and
competed with each other.
The Mangekyo Sharingan awakened
in them both...
and in time, they came to stand
at the center of their clan.
Both sought to sharpen
their ocular powers
and competed against each other.
And so, the two brothers...
they killed their closest friends
and finally awakened
the Mangekyo Sharingan.
It had never before been seen
among the Uchiha.
The brothers used their
ocular powers to take control
and Madara became the leader.
However, a change began to
occur in Madara
whose eyesight had been perfect until then.
As I mentioned earlier,
this eye is special.
The more you use it,
the more your vision is sealed away...
until you end up with total darkness.
That is the ultimate fate of
the Mangekyo Sharingan.
The price for such power is that
you extinguish it with your own hands...
and lose the light forever.
In order to regain his sight,
Madara tried every means possible...
yet nothing worked.
He was in despair.
Madara became obsessed by the
Mangekyo Sharingan and craved the light.
Forgive me...
He took both eyes from
his younger brother.
Madara now possessed new light.
And... never again did the light fade
from his eyes.
An eternal Mangekyo Sharingan!
It is said that his younger brother's eyes
gained eternal light
when they found a new host...
And it triggered a change.
A new, unique ocular jutsu was born
in those eyes.
However, the exchange of eyes can
only be conducted among clan members.
Furthermore, not everyone can attain
new powers from this method.
That is the truth of our history,
forged through countless sacrifices.
That is the other secret of this eye...
Madara used his power and took control
of one ninja clan after another.
Ultimately, he formed an alliance
with the Senju Clan,
which was touted as
the strongest ninja clan
and established a new organization.
Later, he clashed with the leader
of the Senju Clan,
the future First Hokage,
over the course the village would take.
He lost the battle over leadership,
but Madara still lives with
his ocular powers intact.
He formed a new organization
called the Akatsuki
and hides himself in its shadows.
Sixteen years ago,
Madara instigated the Nine-Tails' attack
on the Leaf Village.
But that too was foiled by
the Fourth Hokage.
Madara is a bitter, defeated loser...
He is not worthy of becoming
the best among the Uchiha.
I am the one...
who shall surpass Madara and
become the ultimate ninja!
And now... I can finally obtain
a power that exceeds even Madara's!
Sasuke! You are my new light!
You are my spare!
Originally, the Uchiha Clan
killed off friends
in order to possess
Mangekyo Sharingan.
Parents and siblings killed one another
to possess eternal ocular power...
And they showed off this power...
They are a tainted clan!
And, from the day you were born,
you have been inevitably bound
to this blood-stained fate!
Now come! My little brother!
I shall kill you...
and free myself from this fate
and bring about true change!
I will be free of the constraints
that bind me!
But, we only have each other
as siblings.
I'm always going to be there for you,
even if it's only as an obstacle
for you to overcome.
We are each other's spares!
You've been jealous of me
and resented me.
You've harbored hopes
of surpassing me.
That is why I am allowing you to live.
For my sake...
This is the true bond between
the brothers of the Uchiha!
So it was all for this...
My name is Sasuke Uchiha.
There are lots of things I hate.
And not many things I like.
Also... I have no intention
of saying I have a dream.
But I do have ambition!
To restore my clan... and kill...
a certain man.
I've finally arrived...
The moment to fulfill my goal!
You say you can see my death...
But you cannot win against
my Mangekyo Sharingan.
Unfortunately, your ambition
will end as a mere illusion.
Because you do not possess
the Mangekyo Sharingan.
You can use your eyes all you like,
but my hatred will make
this illusion a reality!
Your reality...
is death!
He wove signs for a
Shadow Clone mid-attack!
You pierced him with Chidori?!
Forgive me, Sasuke...
This is my reality...
Give me your light.
I told you.
You do not possess
the Mangekyo Sharingan.
You can never win against
my eyes.
I’ll take the other one too.
So that is the power of
the Curse Mark...
This is the difference in
our strength.
And...
the difference between
your ocular powers and mine.
You broke through... my Tsukuyomi?!
Like I told you...
No matter how much you use
those eyes of yours,
my hatred will make this illusion a reality.
Humph... Making illusions a reality...?
Then let me throw those words
right back at you.
You saw your eyes gouged out
during the Tsukuyomi just now.
Well, allow me to make that a reality.
The air around Itachi has shifted!
He’s gotten serious.
Which means,
we might get to see the Amaterasu.
What? The Amaterasu?!
I can’t wait to see it!
We were right to come see this,
after all!
A rigged shuriken?!
That last shuriken did the job.
That’s strange...
What is it?
It’s just that Itachi should have been
able to dodge something like that.
Backlash from that earlier Tsukuyomi?
I like that.
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
Wounds like this won’t slow me down.
Phew... We almost got caught in that!
– Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
Amaterasu!
Ohh... There it is!
I-Incredible...
He put out fire with fire.
With that jutsu,
he eyes whatever he wants to burn
and once the target is in focus,
black flames burst forth.
The black flame cannot
be extinguished
until the one it targets
is totally incinerated.
Even if the target is also fire.
This is what I’ve been waiting for!
Fire Style: Dragon Flame Jutsu!
That Amaterasu earlier seems to have
taken quite a toll on you.
This will probably be my last jutsu.
The Sharingan can assess chakra.
Stop bluffing...
I can see that you’re out of chakra.
You used an Orochimaru-style
Substitution Jutsu to evade my Amaterasu.
A well-made substitution to deceive,
but it uses an enormous amount
of chakra.
You’re right.
I don’t have any chakra left.
I used it up in that
last Fire Style Jutsu.
However...
Do you really think I would
come here to kill you unprepared?
It will be instantaneous.
This jutsu is just like Amaterasu.
It is impossible to dodge.
Now...
As you wished, I’ll recreate...
your death!
I get it!
That's what Sasuke's Fire Style Jutsu
was for earlier!
What do you mean?
The target of that Fire Style attack was
never Itachi to begin with!
So what does that mean?
He purposely released
his Fire Style attack into the sky,
causing a sudden warmth
in the atmosphere
and he created an ascending air current!
Ascending air current?
To form cumulonimbus...
In other words, thunderclouds!
So what does that mean?
Instead of using his own chakra...
he intends to take advantage of
the massive energy in the atmosphere
to create a Lightning Style Jutsu!
What kind?
In any case, it'll be on
a totally different scale
than what anyone can create
using change in chakra Nature alone.
I see...
Sasuke purposely lured Itachi outside,
so he could also use the heat
created by Amaterasu.
This jutsu brings down thunder
from the heavens.
I merely direct its power toward you.
Just as I thought...
Which is why it cannot be evaded.
Why not?!
A bolt of lightning is
1/1000th of a second.
It's faster than sound!
The name of this jutsu is Kirin.
Come!
Vanish with the roar of thunder...
It's... over.
It's over!
Is this... the death you
wanted to recreate?
Damn you!
That's...!
Without this, I would have been dead.
What is that?!
You really have... gotten stronger...
Sasuke.
This time...
I shall show you my final trump card...
The Susano'o.
Susano'o?
Tsukuyomi and Amaterasu...
When these two powers awakened,
one more jutsu took root in my eyes.
Sasuke, is that it for your jutsu?
If you are hiding another power,
don't hold back.
The real battle is only beginning.
The sky is clearing...
It seems that last jutsu is limited
to one shot.
What's the matter?
Have you used up your chakra
and run out of options?
What?!
I can give it to you...
I can lend you power...
Damn it!
You need me, don't you, Sasuke?
I thought you were going to
get revenge on Itachi?
Now, release my power!
Then your wish...
Judging by the feel of it...
This is Orochimaru's
Eight-Headed Serpent Jutsu.
Finally, it comes out...
This is it!
This is what I have been waiting for!
Thanks to you, the chakra Sasuke
was using to suppress me is gone!
Now is my chance to take over
this boy's body!
And...!
You think I can be beaten
with that level of attack?
Now then, Sasuke...
What will you do next?
This sword! It can't be...!
The Totsuka Blade?!
Itachi... You had it hidden
in your possession...?!
What is that sword anyway?
The Sword of Totsuka, also known
as the Sakegari Longsword,
is a sword of sealing.
It is said to trap and seal away
those it pierces
in a genjutsu world of drunken stupor
for all eternity.
The blade itself is imbued with
a Sealing Jutsu
and is a variant of the Snake Sword.
Orochimaru has long searched for it.
Itachi's power really is immense!
This is it... Sasuke.
Now... your eyes are mine.
I will take my time retrieving them.
Damn it!
That jutsu he called Susano'o...
Its shield is repelling every attack!
There's no mistake about it...
That is also a spirit weapon.
It's called the Yata Mirror and
is said to deflect all things.
Combined with the Totsuka Blade
for attacks, he's invincible.
They're my eyes... Mine...
No way?! Itachi is...
Itachi is dead?
He was so close to getting
Sasuke's eyes too...
Let's go, Akamaru!
- Yamato!
- Yes sir!
Fang Over Fang!
Rasengan!
What?!
You're mine!
Huh?! Whoa! What?!
I-I can't breathe...
I'm keeping you restrained like that!
Impossible!
I'm really flexible, you see?
Now to fight back!
Hidden Jutsu:
Retreat! Naruto! Kiba!
Frill-Necked Lizard!
That's all there is to this jutsu.
He's toying with us...
This formation didn't work either.
He skillfully dodged all of our attacks.
Kakashi-sensei...
Yeah... I know.
Naruto... Our formation attack
was timed perfectly, right?
Yeah...
He should have taken a direct hit!
So how was he able to evade it?!
We probably did hit him.
Huh?
It was the same when I first
attacked him with my Rasengan.
I was sure I hit him...
In other words, he made it look like
he evaded it, when in actuality;
he allowed you and your jutsu
to slip right through his body.
Is that what you're saying, Naruto?
Humph... Huh...
Seriously, Shino! It's hard to follow
what you're trying to say!
Maybe it's a clone...
or some sort of genjutsu that makes
you see illusions or visions?
I-I thought so too,
so I used my Byakugan
to increase my field of vision
and checked the chakra.
The only chakra I detected is
the one where he is.
There we go!
Slipped through... No wonder...
Kakashi-senpai...
What do you think?
No doubt about it.
That's some unique jutsu
only he possesses.
Which makes it a real bother, but...
Shino...
I know.
For this type of situation,
someone like Shino who uses
Hidden Jutsu is useful.
Whoa! You're from the Aburame clan!
Man, all wiggly and gross!
Heh! Shino!
You look eager for a change!
Of course.
That's because I was left out of
that last Sasuke rescue mission.
Go!
Gross, I tell ya!
Disperse!
Is he dodging or
just slipping through?
I'll figure out his jutsu!
Do it!
Hidden Jutsu: Insect Sphere!
Wait a sec!
Well, Hinata?
Y-Yes! I'm able to detect
the target's chakra.
He is definitely inside the swarm
of Shino's insects.
- Yamato!
- Right!
What's going on?
My insects,
which were reacting to his chakra,
have suddenly lost him.
This is impossible...
Teleportation Jutsu?
No, it wasn't teleportation.
Because if it was teleportation,
my insects would respond
and follow in his direction.
They wouldn't let him escape.
Then he used Space-Time Ninjutsu?
No... that's impossible.
But he... suddenly... just vanished.
He traveled through space
without weaving signs,
summoning, or using marks?
That's a Space-Time Ninjutsu that
far surpasses the Fourth Hokage's!
He erased his entire body.
Can he erase his very presence at will?
No way...
But if we accept the fact that
he can erase his existence at will,
then it follows that he can also erase
just a part of his body as well.
Which explains why
a part of his body,
which should have been hit by
an external attack, disappeared.
And to us, it would look like
the attack went right through him.
So he didn't evade the attacks,
they really were slipping right
through him.
I found him!
Over there!
Oh! Hello, hello.
Don't think you can escape
my nose!
Tunneling Fang!
Hey, Kiba! Don't be reckless!
Did he slip away again? Damn!
Kiba... I think this time,
he simply dodged.
How did it go?
It's over.
What... is that?
He was on the Akatsuki roster
Kabuto left us with.
We keep getting interference!
Sasuke has won.
Itachi Uchiha is dead.
What?! I don't believe it!
Just kidding...
It's as I expected.
S-Sasuke... killed... Itachi?
Sasuke's down too, but...
I wonder how he is?
He's in pretty bad shape.
Hey! You there, spiky aloe guy!
Where's Sasuke now?!
Aloe?!
Don't bother with him.
I'll take you on another time.
That's... a Sharingan?!
Who... in the world is he?!
Later.
We must find Sasuke
before they do!
Hinata! Check in the direction
of four o'clock.
Y-Yes, sir!
Byakugan!
I can see a powerful
chakra across a wide area
about ten kilometers ahead.
Also... for some reason...
the forest is burning...
from black flames.
Amaterasu?!
That's it!
Everyone, follow me!
This time for sure!
Full speed ahead!
You're late.
Unlike you, I'm not that fast.
If you were watching,
you better have recorded all of it.
Relax. Everything is recorded.
I'll take a good look later.
We're taking Itachi's corpse too.
We should go now.
I detected their scents.
They've already reached
where Sasuke is.
Damn them!
So this is Amaterasu...
I've never seen it before!
What is that?
That is Itachi's jutsu!
Be careful!
That fire will not go out until it
completely incinerates anything it ignites.
Yamato!
Yes, Senpai!
Earth Style: Planet Splitter!
Please proceed!
Right! Everyone, except Yamato,
follow me!
Quit wasting time.
You're...
Zetsu.
Tsk. We're not wasting time.
So it's over?
Yeah, it's settled.
What about Sasuke?
He's okay. Sasuke won.
And... where's Sasuke?
He's already been evacuated
to a safe place.
Safe place?
Akatsuki's hideout in the east.
You should head there too.
The Hidden Leaf will come here
very shortly.
Let's go... to where Sasuke is!
What will you do, Kisame?
With Itachi gone, I suppose
I'll be on my own for a while.
I see... Do as you please.
I can still smell a faint trail, but...
We were too late...
Naruto...
Why?
Why can't I ever reach Sasuke?