Oh, Senpai!
Over there...
There's a dango shop!
Let's take a break.
We've been walking all day.
I'm exhausted!
You don't look exhausted at all.
How can you be so carefree?
But Senpai, we're trying to
catch a Tailed Beast,
yet we don't even know where it is.
So there's no need to rush.
By the way,
what are we going to catch again?
Three-Tails! Three-Tails!
One-Tail, Two-Tails...
And I'm Tobi! Just kidding!
Here's dango for you.
Wow! It looks yummy!
Let's see...
Munch time!
Man, it's so good!
This sauce is excellent.
It's not too sweet, nor too salty.
It's a masterpiece!
Ahh... It was great.
Oh! Senpai, Senpai, look at that!
Huh?
That looks exactly like
your work, doesn't it?
Could it be that your art is...
a rip-off?
You...!
I'm going to kill you!
Th-This is...
The Three-Tails is about to appear!
What's this feeling...?
What's the matter, Shino?
My insects... feel a weird chakra.
Weird chakra?
They've never felt so much chakra before.
It looks like Akamaru feels
the same thing as your insects!
Then it must be there!
Let's hurry up.
This feeling... The air is charged,
and there's a sense of panic...
This isn't from the guys
from the Hidden Leaf.
What's happening?
Right there?!
What the hell is that?
A fog...?
It looks like the bats are flying
toward the fog.
No question about it!
A huge amount of chakra
is coming from over there.
Is it inside that fog?
Yes, but we can't identify it.
Let's dive in and find out!
Hey, slow down.
Let's get ready first.
Heh! That's what I wanted to hear!
Everyone, prepare for action!
But don't rush!
- Roger!
Understood!
They're increasing in number.
Did they call for reinforcements?
I think they can easily see us!
It doesn't matter!
Let's drop in!
We're outnumbered.
Let's buy some time until
Guren gets here!
Kihou, lay a smoke screen!
Understood.
Kakashi-senpai!
A smoke screen...
They're lying in wait for us.
But if we stay here too long,
we won't be able to find out
what's happening at the lake.
We should split into two groups...
Naruto, you go by yourself.
What?! I'm not attacking?
Our primary mission is to investigate the lake.
Oh, that's right...
We'll create a diversion and
you head off to the center of the lake.
But don't attack.
Yes, understood.
Are you sure? Only Naruto...?
Let's show him a bit of trust.
No one is a better survivor than Naruto.
Good luck, Naruto.
You're the Hidden Leaf's number one...
unpredictable ninja.
No reaction...
It looks like nobody's here.
Let's go!
Damn it! I can't see anything.
Did they escape already?
They must be buying time.
Keep your guard up!
All right, I think from here...
I'm going to head into the lake!
I went in too deep...
Snack for me.
Hey, right after we got home,
you called us over here!
You're working us toads too hard!
Come on, I'll give you something in return.
But, this intense chakra...
I wonder what's behind the fog?
It's coming!
This is the Three-Tails...
It's more than we expected...
What is this...?!
This intimidating presence...!
We did it... It was a success.
Yuukimaru is controlling the Three-Tails!
Yuukimaru!
Damn! If he keeps using his power...!
If he fails,
what will happen to the Three-Tails?
Your job is to stop that from happening!
Even Yuukimaru's power can't control
the Three-Tails...!
Yuukimaru!
What's that sound?!
Guren!
Stop this beast immediately!
Stop being so bossy!
This beast!
Although he's huge, he's quick!
Right now!
Gozu!
Hurry!
Crystal Style: Divine Pathway jutsu!
There!
My crystal shattered?!
Giant Crystal Hexagonal Shuriken!
This is so hard!
You filthy turtle!
Guren! What are you doing?
Are you trying to kill the Three-Tails?!
Contain him! Or we'll all die!
Large-scale jutsu need preparation!
It's too late!
Gozu...!
Hurry...
Crystal Style:
Crystal Wall, 8th Formation!
Eat this, turtle bastard!
She did it...!
Crystal Style...
I never knew Guren
had this much ability...
I used a bit too much... chakra...
Hey Shino,
don't get too close to me!
I wouldn't get too close to you.
Then why did your shoulder brush
against me?!
Because we're closing ranks.
Keep your mouth shut!
Focus on finding the enemy.
But, Kakashi-sensei!
Above us! Watch out!
Our ambush failed!
Kakashi-sensei!
Thanks, Sakura, Sai.
Hinata, are you feeling better already?
Yeah!
But still, how did she...?
I see, her Byakugan...
We'd better be careful with
that little girl's jutsu.
Even if we were in a smoke screen,
she would find us...
Damn it!
What kind of place is this?!
There are no waves,
and I don't see any fish.
It's really weird...
I see something.
Oh! It's a turtle!
There's a turtle inside!
Brother! What kind of turtle is this?
Na-Naruto, th-this is a Tailed Beast!
Tailed Beast?
Yeah! It's the Three-Tails!
Three-Tails...?
Even that huge jutsu couldn't stop it?!
Guren! Take Yuukimaru and run!
Gozu! You, too!
Gozu, protect Yuukimaru!
All right!
Guren...!
You fight with me!
She's...!
Why is she fighting with the Three-Tails?!
Guren!
What are you doing here...?!
Don't tell me...
Where there's someone thinking of me,
that's where I go home to.
His place to return is...
with them?!
Don't underestimate me...
Filthy turtle!
Guren!
This camellia will never wither.
As long as I'm alive.
Guren...
Gozu...!
What are you doing?!
Take Yuukimaru and...
get out of here!
Guren...
I figured out where to return home to.
You...
What?! The Three-Tails
has stopped moving.
It can't be...!
He... can control the Three-Tails?!
What?!
Kakashi-senpai!
That's...!
What?!
That's the dimension where
the Three-Tails appeared!
If we're swallowed by it...!
Are you all right?
So warm...
Here!
You... This is...!
Yuukimaru...!
All my chakra is going to this jutsu...!
What an impressive Tailed Beast.
The ordinary method
doesn't work, after all.
Well, it doesn't matter...
I'll just move on to the next step.
Hey, are you all right?
Yeah... more or less.
It doesn't seem like
the Leaf ninja are nearby.
But I can't figure out the situation.
Say, what was that huge wave just now?
And I heard a cry of some sort...
Just what are Guren
and the others doing...?
It's probably better for us
if we don't know.
Oh, Gozu... You're alive.
Yeah... Where's Guren?
I dunno.
You should be able to find her!
We'd like nothing better,
but suddenly the bats stopped responding.
Frankly, I'm stumped.
Where do you think you're going?
She may be injured...
Hey, finding her is...
Hey Gozu!
Oh, man. He's got a crush on her.
Owww...
Damn it! I was put through hell.
How far did I get washed away?
I know!
Him...?
What was he doing with
Orochimaru's ally?
Now listen, follow that person!
Don't let that person go!
Uh-huh...!
That kid...
Could it have been my fault...?!
Damn it! This fog...!
Where am I?
Sasuke?!
Don't interfere.
Why you--!
What are you going to do with Sasuke?!
I'm going to begin
the Reanimation Jutsu.
What...?!
That is his wish.
He will attain power...
And I will attain him.
As if I'd let you!
We're going to take Sasuke
back to our village!
How silly.
He doesn't desire such a thing.
Still, home is where people
think of you. I believe that...
I wonder if that's true...
Shut up...!
You... will regret it.
Shut up!
Stop! Naruto!
Phew... That was close.
Kakashi-sensei...?!
Look, we finally found you.
What do you think you're doing?!
Huh?! But Orochimaru was right here...
Huh? I don't pick up any scents.
It seems... that was an illusion.
Huh...? But...
Are you all right, Naruto?
We've assembled everyone.
But it doesn't mean
our problems are over.
Hmm?
Look...
This is...?!
They've started acting strangely.
They've lost their sense of direction.
We can't use them for reconnaissance.
Hey, hey, are you serious...?
It started after the fog became thicker.
On our side, Naruto saw an illusion.
It seems this is no ordinary fog.
Naruto... What happened at that lake?
Huh?
There was... this giant rampaging turtle.
Those guys we fought earlier
were fighting it.
Hmm?
What...? A turtle...?!
Hey... are you saying that
giant chakra was actually a turtle?
Shut up! I'm telling the truth!
Anyway, the turtle caused
that giant wave!
Gamakichi saw that thing and
said it was a Three-Tails...
Three-Tails...?!
A Tailed Beast appeared here?
Probably... It's not like
he actually counted its tails, though.
Senpai...
Just when I thought we figured out
their target...
We've come across
another puzzling thing...
In any case, we must retreat to
somewhere this fog can't reach us.
We'll go through all our data
and plan our next strategy.
Why didn't you kill him?
What was that just now...?
Guren...
Yuukimaru...?
I see... I fought with the Three-Tails
and lost consciousness.
I never imagined that the Three-Tails
would have such power...
That raging current probably
swallowed up the rest.
If the Hidden Leaf are on the move,
I need to regroup with Rinji and the others,
but in this fog...
What happened to the Three-Tails?
I don't know...
It suddenly got quiet...
I see...
But I'm glad. That you woke up...
You were moaning the whole time...
You wouldn't wake up,
no matter how many times
I called out your name...
I get it...
He stayed by me
the whole time I was unconscious...
Now then. Shall we go find the others?
Uh-huh. But I wonder...
What?
It's strange...
I don't have any strength in my body.
You have a fever again!
Since when...?
Byakugan!
Oh! Amazing...!
Did you see something?
Yes. Let's go back.
All right...
How did it go?
Yes... That's definitely not an ordinary fog.
There's quite a bit of chakra inside it.
Furthermore, it has totally
enveloped the lake.
It's a considerable amount of chakra.
I guess we're right to conclude that
the fog was produced by the Three-Tails.
Yes...
According to what Naruto said,
that fog has the power to
make you hallucinate.
It's like a kind of barrier.
It's dangerous to approach the lake.
That's bad!
He's still inside there...!
He...?
Remember Sakura, I told you before.
I met him on the way here.
Oh, that's right...
Oh, when you were delirious...
Quit being so rude!
Anyway, he's still on the lake!
Inside the fog...!
The lake?
Please, Kakashi-sensei!
He's not a ninja!
I have to find out if he's okay...
Sorry, Naruto. I can't allow it...
Kakashi-sensei!
Earlier, you were ensnared
by the Three-Tails' illusion
and almost ended up killing
your comrade.
Acting on your own
is out of the question.
I... I know that, but...
But Kakashi-sensei...
The problem is... what'll we do now?
Whatever has developed,
we've fallen far off track from
searching for Orochimaru's hideout.
Well, the situation has escalated
beyond my authority to make a decision.
And so, I've already sent Pakkun
back to Hidden Leaf Village.
We'll wait here until we get orders
from Lady Tsunade.
In the meantime, stay outside
the perimeter of the fog
and keep an eye on
the Three-Tails and those others.
Understood?
- Yes!
That's the gist of it.
I had heard that the Three-Tails
disappeared after the last Great War.
But to have it reappear in this form...
Orochimaru has gotten involved
in something troubling.
But the Akatsuki are desperately
searching for Tailed Beasts.
Perhaps the fact that we discovered it
first is a blessing in disguise.
Yes... But if the Akatsuki get wind of this,
it's certain to turn into a tug-of-war
for the Three-Tails.
We cannot hand it over to anyone.
You'll capture it then?
I don't think it will be easy...
However, there must be
some kind of precedent...
I'm going to look it up in
our existing documents.
I want you to summon
the members I've written there.
Understood!
All done...
Thank you for your help today.
Really...?!
Yes... Please keep up the good work.
Yes!
I can't go on...
We're just beginning, Tenten.
The real challenge begins now!
Well said, Lee!
Words of weakness in the midst
of your youth are forbidden, Tenten!
Right!
To be mutually aware of one's partner
and to watch each other's back!
To hone one's skills in taijutsu
to form an unbeatable combination.
Let us do that!
And trying to keep up with
all your showboating is wearing me out!
Hmm?! Lee, what is the purpose
of this training?
Huh?
Coordination with one's partners.
It's training to build up synergy!
Correct!
However, do you think you are
in harmony with Tenten right now?
She's breathing hard... Oh no!
I understand, Sensei.
It seems my feelings have
gotten ahead of hers.
That's my student!
You catch on quickly!
Man, we've been at this nonstop
for five hours.
No matter how much stamina I have,
I can't keep this up.
I still have a lot left in me!
Well said, Lee!
As soon as Tenten has caught her breath,
we'll resume training!
I'm going to perform a taijutsu attack
without holding back,
so counter me with all your might!
Right, Guy-sensei!
We're going to continue anyway...?
Wait, look...!
We're being called up?
All right.
We'll continue after you get back!
Go, you two! Show them the results
of your long, arduous training!
- Right!
- Yes!
And that's the gist of the situation.
You will go to support Kakashi
and the others
who have gone ahead of you.
You are probably aware by now
that the most critical thing is
to seal the Three-Tails.
Sealing the Three-Tails will require
extremely delicate chakra control.
medical ninja consisting
of myself and Ino;
plus Sakura and Hinata,
who are already there,
will form the Sealing unit.
Right! I'll do my best!
Lee and Tenten,
I need you to cover for Hinata
and Sakura while they're gone.
As long as the enemy is after
the Three-Tails,
confrontation will be inevitable.
You can count on us!
We'll fight with the full power
of our youth!
I will lead you to the site.
Don't fall behind!
Seriously... It’s no good if the one
looking after him collapses too.
This is my second time
taking care of him...
If you give him that much medicine...
Could those pills be the cause...?
In any case, I must avoid a battle
with the enemy while I have him.
Hey, Yuukimaru. Wake up.
You know...
The place I can return to... is by you.
Huh?
I finally... found it.
We're supposed to be on watch
until the next shift. That Naruto!
Don't slack off.
Huh?
Sakura... I've been thinking...
But I can't find an answer by myself.
Back then, when I was training...
the Pervy Sage said something to me.
Jiraiya?
"Wherever someone thinks of you,
that's where home is."
That's a nice saying.
But... is that really true?
If that's true, then if we keep
thinking about someone,
that person would return, right?
Yes... I'd like to think that.
But no matter how much we think of
someone, there are some who won't return.
It's a very difficult thing...
to have your thoughts reach someone.
Yet, if you give up... and there's no one
to think about that person...
That's sad.
Yes. If we give up, then there really
won't be a place to return to.
Yes!
No matter what anyone says,
we just have to keep thinking of him...
and create a place where
he can return freely at any time.
Sakura!
Okay?
You're right.
We just can't give up. Right!
I feel much better,
thanks to you, Sakura!
I'm going back to my position.
In thirty minutes,
the next two-man team will relieve us.
So stay alert.
Thank you! Sakura...
She's right...
So if someone is thinking about me,
then that's the place I go back to?
Yup... No matter what anyone says,
just keep thinking about him.
But... if he really has no place to go...
I'll be the one he can come home to.
Are we getting close
to our destination?
At this rate, we'll get there
around noon tomorrow.
Stop asking me the same question
every five minutes!
Lee, don't be so antsy!
What are you saying?! Our comrades
are anxiously waiting for us!
Our mission is to move at full speed
and get there as soon as possible!
You waste so much energy...
Shizune-senpai...
Hmm?
If the enemy has made contact
with the Three-Tails...
That means they have a jutsu
to take the Three-Tails
into their possession, right?
Yes. Probably a Sealing Jutsu,
or some jutsu we don't know about.
Once we get there, we'll have to use
our Sealing Jutsu immediately.
We can't have them beat us to it.
Then it's decided!
Let's pick up our pace to twice,
no, three times the speed!
Not that nonsense again...
But I fully agree.
Pakkun, lead the way!
Seems I have no choice.
Everyone, don't fall behind!
Well, that's about it.
What do you think, Senpai?
Yeah, looks good.
You haven't turned a page in a while.
Is something on your mind?
Hmm?
Oh, this and that...
Yamato, how do you think those guys
intended to capture the Three-Tails?
Well, it's a Tailed Beast, after all...
Our opponent's Crystal Style
is powerful,
but I doubt that it's enough
to suppress the Tailed Beast...
Which means they must have been using
another method at the same time.
But back then, we weren't restrained
for very long.
I can't believe that they were able
to set up such an elaborate ritual
in that time.
That's true...
But didn't Naruto say he saw
a child by the lake?
That bothers me...
On top of that, we'll be facing
that Crystal Style user very soon...
Where are you going?
Let's analyze the situation and
do whatever we can now.
Kakashi-sensei...
Sorry to interrupt,
but I want to discuss something.
Okay...
Umm... you're the one I come back to.
Come back to... huh...?
I wonder where he went.
He's from the Hidden Leaf...
It'll be a bother if he gets any closer.
Don't move from this spot.
I'm here to relieve you.
Right. So far, there's been
nothing unusual.
- Um... Sakura...
- Huh?
- Sai?
- Hey!
This isn't your position.
Oh, I know that, but...
Do you know where Naruto is?
Huh? Isn't he in his assigned spot?
Well, I don't see him.
That guy, did he go back early?
If so, we would've crossed paths...
You're right. Even Naruto wouldn't
just abandon his post...!
No way...
If that wave took him,
there wouldn't be any trace left...
Who are you?!
You should be grateful!
I came just for you.
You're...
Lurking around all by yourself...
If your purpose was to spy,
you came across the worst opponent.
It seems this is no illusion...
Crystal Style: Jade Crystal Blade!
Die!
I'm not spying!
I'm searching!
For that kid who was with you!
Answer me! Where is he?!
Guren...?
I... have to go.
What?! Naruto has disappeared?
What is the possibility that
he came under attack?
I didn't pick up
any suspicious scents at the site.
I think he just took off on his own.
He seemed to have something
on his mind...
But to go off like this...
Naruto...
Honestly... In any case, we have
to find Naruto at once.
Then we all...
No, like I said before...
It's dangerous to go
into the fog recklessly.
Yamato and I will search for him.
Summoning Jutsu!
It's very rare for you to summon me.
Pakkun is out on a mission, so Biscuit,
I need you to find Naruto right away.
Gotcha.
Shino, Kiba and Hinata,
search outside the fog.
Sakura and Sai will do
aerial reconnaissance.
- Yes!
Do not act alone.
Where is the little kid?
Is he okay?!
This guy...
Why's he asking about Yuukimaru...?
I see... He was watching that...
Well, it's none of your business!
It is my business!
So petty!
Tell me! I need to take him back!
Are you crazy?
Take him back?
He was on our side from the beginning.
No! It's all my fault that
he ended up going back to your side!
All because of the unnecessary stuff
I said to him...
Unnecessary?
Thank you.
You taught me, didn't you?
Y-You...
Yuukimaru...
Wherever someone thinks of you
is the place you go home to...
Hey, don't move!
I'm really grateful.
I finally found the place
where I can go back to.
Right, Guren?
Sorry.
Yuukimaru!
Don't move!
So you were hiding one
of your Shadow Clones.
Guren!
So your name is Yuukimaru?
I'm Naruto.
Naruto...
Yuukimaru, you're going home
with me to Hidden Leaf Village.
Why?
She's not the one you're going home to!
She serves Orochimaru.
And this guy Orochimaru will
do anything to achieve his ambition.
He's a bastard who thinks nothing
of taking people's lives.
Anyone who serves a guy like
that can't be a decent human being!
Guren will protect me...
She's kind to me and she thinks of me...
It's obvious she's just using you!
Shut up!
His home isn't with you!
Guren...
Something's coming...
The Hidden Leaf...
I'm taking him by force, if necessary!
Hexagonal Crystal Shuriken:
Wild Dance!
What?!
Take this!
I won't let you get away!
Naruto, stop!
Stabilized and secured.
Let me go!
I'm taking him...!
It's no use. They've disappeared.
Damn it...
Guren, are you hurt?
Don't bother me!
She's not the one you're going home to.
That kid... When I see him again...
I'm sorry... But...
I'm glad you're all right.
Yuukimaru!
I'm going back.
Right. Thanks.
What's with you?
Surely, you knew that if
you went off on your own,
you knew you'd run into
that Crystal Style user?
I know.
But I... I just had to find him...
Don't make excuses.
You're lucky; you could've
been dead by now.
You put your comrades in danger
because you gave in to your emotions.
How can you face Lady Tsunade,
who put her trust in you and
sent you on this mission?
Alright, I get it.
This mission involves a dangerous,
unpredictable foe.
Recklessly acting on your own
could spell death for everyone.
Don't let yourself forget that.
Right.
Shall we return?
Yes.
By the way, Naruto,
you said you saw a child at the lake.
Huh? What about it?
Something's been bothering me.
Tell me the details of that incident.
Guren! I'm glad you're okay.
Sorry. But I couldn't use my search net
near the lake.
Forget it... It seems we haven't
lost any fighting power...
Although, there's at least one
I would've preferred to lose.
So I'm blessed with the luck of evil.
It's mutual.
He's weakened, but it's tolerable.
He's exhausted. Let him rest.
Unfortunately...
I don't think we can afford to
hang around here.
I just can't imagine why those guys
would take an ordinary kid along,
when they're facing the huge challenge
of capturing the Three-Tails.
He's no ordinary kid, I tell you...
What if he possesses some
special power against the Three-Tails?
Now that you mention it...
He did something and...
it seemed as though
the Three-Tails stopped moving.
It figures...
You mean a human was
controlling a Tailed Beast?
I don't know what trick they used,
but we're dealing with Orochimaru...
It's probably no mistake
that they intend to use a child
to capture the Three-Tails.
Which means, this child...
We can't just ignore him.
What do you mean by that?
We'll wait for an opportunity,
and then we'll secure him.
Secure him?
As long as they don't have the boy,
they have no method to
capture the Three-Tails.
And I can't believe that
Orochimaru will be satisfied with
just capturing the Three-Tails...
Sooner or later,
he'll think of ways to create
a Jinchuriki that is easy to control.
For him, a boy with the ability
to synergize with a Tailed Beast
is merely a useful tool.
I won't let him do that!
You're absolutely right.
Besides, I'm sure they would want
to examine his powers back at the village.
Well, it all depends
on Lady Tsunade's reply.
Naruto!
Sakura!
Is this what they call... "tough love"?
This is far more effective
than us trying to lecture him.
Kakashi-sensei,
I gave Naruto an earful.
Was he sorry?
I'm so... sorry...
Never mind that.
There's good news!
Reinforcements from the Hidden Leaf?
The enemy is reacting quickly.
No doubt, they will try to seal
the Three-Tails.
No way! The Three-Tails belongs
to Lord Orochimaru.
Of course!
And that is why, this time, Guren...
You must use Yuukimaru
to suppress the Three-Tails.
But Yuukimaru is still...
Don't worry. If we build up his stamina
and allow him to rest a bit,
we'll be able to use him.
He's going to give him that drug again...
But Yuukimaru still looks awfully weak.
If you force him...
Are you sure he'll be all right?
Well, I wonder...
Don't look at me like that.
You should know that Yuukimaru is
simply a tool to capture the Three-Tails.
Unless we make use of him now,
there's no meaning in his very existence.
But if he collapses and the plan fails...
My credibility will be totally ruined!
Guren, I'm hoping that
the plan is a success.
That's why I...
Well, it's irritating.
You tend to stick your nose into
other people's business too often.
Guren... You...
The main thing is to prevent
the Hidden Leaf from sealing
the Three-Tails, right?
Well then, I'll destroy the Leaf!
Had an argument?
I can't stand that four-eyed bastard!
Does he want to kill Yuukimaru?
Oh...
What?
It's unlike you to worry
so much about Yuukimaru.
Don't be ridiculous.
I'm just concerned about our mission.
Concerned about the mission, eh...?
Reinforcements are here? Who?
Just wait and see.
I've had it... I can't run any further.
Sakura, who's come to help...?
You're so reckless, Naruto!
It's okay! Recklessness and youth
go hand in hand!
Stop affirming his actions!
Hey! You guys...!
Oh! I'm glad you're here,
Bushy Brow!
Everyone! Now that I'm here,
you have nothing to fear!
Hey!
It's "we're here." You are too eager.
Well, you can relax.
You're as confident as always,
but have you mastered
the ABCs of medical ninjutsu?
What?! For someone who started
medical ninjutsu just a tad before me,
you sound pretty confident yourself.
Well sure. It's not as though
I started yesterday.
Well, you need that handicap.
After all, we're not equals,
Billboard Brow.
I haven't been called that
in a while... Ino Pig!
What?!
So their nicknames are
Billboard Brow and Ino Pig...?
Huh?
What... did... I...?
Lady Tsunade briefed us on the basics.
But can you give us the specifics
of the situation?
Well, there's a new development...
- What's with him?
- Let's do our best!
What did I do?
What were you writing?
Let's see it.
Yes... We'll explain over there.
There are four shinobi who can
move freely inside a smoke screen.
Also, the big guy I fought,
and then there's a Crystal Style user...
They were in the lake dealing
with a Tailed Beast
which we believe is a Three-Tails.
Hmm... That was included
in our information.
Well, we'd better get started quickly
so we can seal it.
If the enemy takes possession of
the Three-Tails' fighting power,
we're in trouble.
There's one more thing...
a new development.
Huh?!
Naruto witnessed a child
at the lake.
And he says that child
controls the Tailed Beast.
No way... Someone who can
control a Tailed Beast...?
Furthermore, Naruto later encountered
the child with the Crystal Style user.
What's their relationship?
It seems they're quite close...
According to Naruto, the Crystal Style user
is the place the child can "return home" to.
Just who is this child?
The Three-Tails doesn't have a Jinchuriki...
Not yet...
After all, we're dealing with Orochimaru.
Maybe he's aiming to make
that child a Jinchuriki.
It seems we have yet another
troubling thing to deal with.
We knew we had to deal
with human foes,
but no one said a thing about
a Tailed Beast!
No kidding. That thing caused
a huge flood just by appearing.
What the hell are they starting?
But it's too late for us to run away.
Say, think of a way we can get out of this.
We were lucky to make it
out of that camp alive.
I'm not about to give my life
to some damned beast!
We're counting on you, Rinji.
Just how simple are
these guys anyway?
Look, I'll work things out.
Leave the rest to me.
Just as I expected, Rinji!
Where are you going?
If you're going to report to Guren,
I'll go.
I can't trust you...
Well, how you feel is up to you.
Do you intend to betray Guren?
Whether I forgive you or not
depends on your answer...
Contrary to what you believe,
my loyalties are with Guren.
I wonder... about that...
This is just between you and me...
Why do you think I'm here?
I left a sickly kid sister back
in the village...
In order to protect her, I need money.
That's why...
I can't afford to lose my life here.
What you make of my story
is totally up to you.
Oh?
You're up?
Where's Guren?
Oh...
How about it?
Want to go back to Lord Orochimaru?
Will Guren come with us?
Guren...? She's just a sacrifice
to Lord Orochimaru...
Huh?!
Don't forget...
You belong to Lord Orochimaru.
No! The place I return to...
is the place where Guren is--!
Move away from Yuukimaru!
Guren!
What do you intend to do to him?!
I'm... just disciplining him a bit.
I'm the one who's going to be
in trouble with Lord Orochimaru
if anything should happen
to Yuukimaru.
I mustn't disappoint him.
He wasn't able to even talk properly.
I'm amazed at how much
you've taught him.
If you ever lay a hand on Yuukimaru again,
I'll show you no mercy.
Humph! Well then...
Keep a good eye on our test subject.
Are you all right?
Uh-huh! I'm going to stay
with you, right?
Guren... I don't want to go back
to the hideout.
Rinji...?
Can you believe that?
She was so hung up on
Lord Orochimaru and now it's the kid...
I hope it doesn't interfere
with her mission...
I'm worried that she's getting
a bit too attached to him.
Well, we'll just leave her
to Lord Orochimaru.
I want you to continue
to watch her closely...
and make sure she's not up to anything.
Continue... eh?
I'd be happy to be the one reporting
to Lord Orochimaru...
You?
I've done many things for you
as your spy.
I posed as a convict at that prison and
got accepted by those reconstructed men
and sent you reports.
That was dangerous work.
Even this job...
It's because I'm putting my life
at risk like this...
that you're able to get
the data you want.
What are you trying to say?
It's simple. I want you to value me
a little bit more.
You want to cut a deal?
No such thing...
I've never considered myself
to be your subordinate.
I serve Lord Orochimaru.
Oh...
I just want Lord Orochimaru himself
to recognize my efforts.
At least here, in this location,
I'm the one who can get Kigiri, Kihou
and Nurari to act.
I have more fighting power than you.
I mean, if you're the one who's killed
by the Hidden Leaf first,
I can rush to Lord Orochimaru
and report it to him.
All right, I'll let you see him.
But if you don't keep
your expectations realistic,
you'll end up being destroyed...
Now listen. It's going to get noisy
outside for a bit.
Just be a good boy and wait here.
What about you, Guren?
As soon as I take care of some business,
I will come back. I promise.
All you need to think about
is resting your body.
I'm okay. I feel a little better.
No, not yet.
You need to heal completely.
Umm... I want to ask you for a favor...
Can you... fix this?
I see...
Rather than fixing this,
I'll make you a better one.
But...
What's the matter?
I want to keep this one.
This is the first flower you gave me...
Oh right...
Here, it's fixed.
Thank you.
Umm, you won't go anywhere, right?
Huh...?
The place I return to is with you...
This is stupid...
Just what... am I doing?
Naruto...
Kakashi-sensei...
What's the matter?
What's on your mind?
That guy!
The strategy meeting has begun.
What's keeping him?!
She's always upset when
it comes to Naruto...
Huh...?
What's the matter?
Did you find Naruto?
What do you plan on doing
with that kid?
Why are you so worried about him?
He's being used!
He believes there's someone
he can return to...
But he's sure to be betrayed.
When that happens...
He won't have anywhere to go.
If wherever someone thinks of you
is the place you return to...
Then... I'll keep thinking of him.
Then he wasn't talking about Sasuke...
It may be important to think
about people.
But I wonder if things always
go that smoothly?
After all, everyone has
different thoughts and feelings.
That's not true.
Feelings always get through to others!
Naruto...
Let me go over Lady Tsunade's orders
regarding strategy and a change
in team formation.
The search-and-aid mission
to Orochimaru's hideout is now over.
Sakura, Hinata and Ino...
you will be under my command.
- Yes.
Yes.
Kakashi will lead the rest.
Right. Our new mission is to seal
the Tailed Beast, the Three-Tails.
And, to protect the child from the enemy.
He seems to be connected in
some way to this Tailed Beast.
Huh?!
It is not just the Akatsuki who
covet the Tailed Beast.
If it becomes known that there is
a Tailed Beast that has no Jinchuriki,
other nations are bound to join the hunt.
So that boy was brought here to turn him
into a Jinchuriki?
Right, Naruto?
- Huh?
- Sai!
Huh? Oh right...
You're a Jinchuriki too, Naruto.
Humph!
You always say things without thinking.
Still, you're right about what you said.
Sealing the Three-Tails
and protecting that kid...
That's so he doesn't end up
like Gaara and me, right, Shizune?
Yes... that's right.
Our goal is not to capture
the Tailed Beast.
Even if we seal the Beast,
we will make it disappear into
a space where no one else can touch it.
That is Lady Tsunade's...
the Hokage's will.
All right! Let's do it!
But... the Tailed Beast has
a huge mass of chakra, right?
I don't see how we can put a seal on it.
Yes. It will take an extremely
delicate amount
of chakra control and concentration.
Sakura and Ino...
Both of you are training
in medical ninjutsu.
Your experience will be very useful.
And Hinata...
Umm, I have no experience
in medical ninjutsu.
What's important is your ability
to control chakra.
You may not know medical ninjutsu,
but your mastery of the Gentle Fist
and your Byakugan, which can
see the flow of chakra, will be useful.
You will be fine.
Hinata, you're amazing!
N-No I'm not...
I understand.
I guess girls are better at
delicate chakra control. Yup, yup...
Huh? But Tenten...
How come she hasn't been chosen?
All the girls are on the Sealing team.
So I guess my chakra control is too clumsy!?
I-I didn't mean it like that!
The rest of you will work under Yamato
and I to provide protection.
I'm sure you've already thought
about it...
But those guys who are after
the Three-Tails won't sit by and watch
while we finish sealing the beast.
They are bound to attack.
Those guys with the Crystal Style user!
Bring them on!
How will we team up for this?
Yeah, about that...
I have an idea.
C'mon, don't hold back. Tell us!
The most critical part of this battle
is to stop the Crystal Style user.
However, if we all confront her,
the Sealing team won't have protection...
So I'm thinking of splitting up
this team into two,
with one team focusing on her.
Naruto, Sai, Shino!
- Right!
- Gotcha!
You three will work under me
to fight the Crystal Style user!
As for the rest...
Yamato, you guys take care of them.
Understood...
Okay, those of you who
weren't called, gather 'round!
He makes it sound like
we're the rejects...
Now, now...
Let's go for it with
the eagerness of youth!
Yeah...
What were you doing?
Isn't it obvious?
I was reporting to Kabuto...
about the movements of the Leaf.
And... Kabuto said he was going back
to see Lord Orochimaru immediately.
At a time like this...?
Well, I guess he has lots of things
on his mind.
I see...
Rinji...
Huh?
About earlier, I believe you...
Preventing the sealing
of the Three-Tails,
and the destruction of the Hidden Leaf.
Things are about to get busy...
The Hidden Leaf are here.
First, we have to destroy them.
Capturing Three-Tails comes after that.
Hah! Who cares?
Lord Orochimaru has
high hopes for me.
My wish... my wish is to be
with Lord Orochimaru.
And this guy Orochimaru will do
anything to achieve his ambitions.
He's a bastard who thinks nothing
of taking peoples' lives!
Anyone who serves a guy like
that can't be a decent human being!
Damn! What's wrong with me...?
What are you doing in a place like this?
Thinking up a strategy?
This guy...
When did he show up?
Sort of...
How long has he been here?
Oh... the mist is clearing.
Yes, it's time to move!
All of you, have you memorized
the plan of action?
If that child is discovered during
our operation, protect him.
All right, let's begin.
Tenten, please show it to us.
Yes.
This is the giant scroll that was
specially prepared by Lady Tsunade
for the sealing of the Three-Tails!
Here! Naruto!
Huh?! We're going to use
this massive scroll?
Yes. We have to suppress
a huge amount of chakra.
Kakashi, we're counting on you.
You got it!
Guard Team 2, in your positions!
- Right!
Naruto! We go our separate ways now.
Good luck.
Yeah!
Leave it to me!
All right, let's begin.
Everyone, in your positions!
Let's go!
Well, we'll get started too!
Why do you look so depressed?
Huh?
I'm not depressed...
Just disappointed that
I'm not on the team
that's going to battle
this amazing Crystal Style user.
Hey, hey... We're Chunin now.
I understand you wanting
to fight someone strong,
but this isn't the time to be selfish.
And besides,
her henchmen are ridiculously strong too.
Really?
Please tell me all the details!
Y-Yeah sure.
They were a ton of trouble...
Can I listen in?
Sure... Anyway, they lay a smoke screen,
which is a real pain.
A smoke screen?
Is it toxic? Or...
Just listen until the end.
Then will you just get on with it?
Oh, right.
You two have never met before.
Sharp of you to notice, Naruto.
This here is Sai.
He came from the ANBU Black Ops
and he's sorta gloomy and depressing...
like he's missing something...
Just a weird guy who's
constantly reading books.
Naruto...
But he draws great!
And he's pretty strong!
And this guy is Shino.
Umm... Shino is...
well, Shino.
You're Shino Aburame.
You're the son of Shibi Aburame.
You have participated in
numerous missions
relying on your skill in combat,
as a bodyguard, and in search and seizure.
You're a specialist in the Secret Jutsu
of manipulating Parasitic Insects.
Right?
Hey, Sai. How come you know so much?
You've done your research.
But I guess that goes without saying.
After all, you're a former
ANBU Black Ops member.
Well, now that you know each other,
we can be a team.
Naruto.
My favorite foods are wild grass salad
and winter melon.
Huh?
I don't like...
foods that have a strong odor.
I see.
So what of it?
Since we're on the same team,
we should know about each other.
It affects our teamwork.
Shino...
It really doesn't matter
what kind of foods you like.
Wh-What?
Naruto... You really need to
know more about me.
Because it would be strange
if a newcomer knows more
about me than an old friend.
I guess I'm just not on
the same wavelength as you guys.
Gozu...
Yes?
What do you think about Kabuto?
I just don't like the guy...
Well, forget it.
After I get rid of the Leaf,
I can grab his ponytail and...
Yuukimaru is simply a tool
to control the Three-Tails.
Why the hell am I feeling
so irritated! Damn it!
Let's go!
I will accompany you,
no matter where you go...
It's all clear.
Damn! I'm soaking wet!
You're lucky you don't get wet, Nurari!
What is that? Your pet?
Good work.
All right... Shall we go
with the usual strategy?
Bro...?
Huh?
Yeah... Let's do it the usual way.
We will proceed with
the Four-Corner Sealing Barrier.
First, we'll locate the Three-Tails
and then move on to the Sealing jutsu.
I've already shown you
the hand signs. Ready?
Four-Corner Sealing Barrier... Search!
All right, let's go right
into the jutsu.
This should do for now.
We'll maintain this chakra balance,
and slowly enlarge the opening.
If the Three-Tails is
below the barrier,
we'll get a reaction.
Ready?
Please wait a minute!
If we continue with
such delicate chakra control...
and the enemy appears...
We won't be able to oppose them.
We won't have to fight back.
Huh?!
You just concentrate on
your chakra control.
And believe that your comrades
will take care of the enemy.
I understand.
- Ino!
- Oh!
Are you all right?!
How can I stay alert for the enemy?
I don't even know if I can maintain
this level of chakra control...
You'll be fine, Ino.
I know you can do this...
Sakura...
Chakra control is basic to us, right?
You'll be fine, Ino!
You can do it, I'm telling you!
Chakra control is the foundation
of medical ninjutsu.
Now, let's try again.
Get a fix on the opening!
Gently... Keep it very fine...
You've persevered too...
Hah, don't belittle me!
Of course, I...
can do this!
You got it? What do you-?
The strategy to capture
the enemy, of course!
Like I told you earlier...
In that smoke screen,
visibility is almost zero...
And as much as I hate to admit it,
even Akamaru's nose is useless...
Yet the enemy knows our position
and keeps attacking...
Basically, we should avoid fighting
inside the smoke screen, but...
No!
That's just running away
from the enemy,
and will only make it harder
to defeat them.
That's why I said they're a nuisance--
And I'm saying I figured out a way!
Lee, you've really started using
your head since becoming a Chunin.
You aren't just a training freak.
Good job...
Well then, why don't you tell us your plan?
All right, the strategy is...
- The strategy is...?
The strategy is...
Is...?
It's...
Guts! If we have the guts,
there's no enemy we can't beat!
Huh?
What's the matter, everyone?
Why you--!
Keeping us in suspense!
And that's all you have?
- Quit fooling around!
- Wh-What?
What did I do?!
I take it back.
He's just a workout addict, after all.
All right! Let's go!
Right...
Shino, how's it going over there?
I need a little more time...
All right...
Sai. Basically, we'll keep
the same formation...
that Yamato used when he was captain.
Yes... Senpai.
Huh? Oh right.
You also came from there.
Huh? There?
ANBU Black Ops.
The way they fight,
Their code doesn't include
protecting comrades.
But this time, we're fighting to protect
our comrades at all cost.
I want you to keep that in mind...
Don't worry.
Having faith in my comrades...
I'm here because
that's something I believe in now.
Hey, you're beginning to understand...
The place where someone
thinks of you,
that's the place you go back to...
That's right.
There are friends thinking of you.
That's why you can return to them...
Friends who have faith in you...
I finally found the place...
where I can go back to.
Right, Guren?
He still doesn't understand the true
meaning of thinking about someone.
She's deceiving him...
They're coming!
Anyway, I need to keep
my distance from Shino...
You won't get away this time.
Why you--!
I finally found the place
where I can go back to.
You've deceived Yuukimaru into
believing you're a friend!
Shut up!
Too easy!
Naruto!
It's begun...
Here they come!
Captain Yamato!
It's the smoke-screen guy!
So he's the vanguard...
Well then...!
Nice, Captain Yamato!
Wait, Lee!
Leaf... Whirlwind!
What?
Eat this!
Vanishing Smoke Prison!
- This is bad...
- I told you!
I'm going to back up Lee!
No! You may end up
attacking each other...
This is the smoke screen
Kiba talked about...
He was right.
I can't see in front of me. Then...
Rinji, we're ready anytime.
How's his position?
Rinji?
There's something I must do...
Huh? Hey, Rinji?
I can't sense anyone's presence...
How far does the smoke spread?
Is everyone else caught up in it?
What should I do?
Lee...
A ninja never gives up,
even if all his senses are shut down.
Yes, Guy-sensei...
If you recall your days of harsh training,
this is nothing.
We have something stronger than
the five senses, the vision of the heart.
The vision of the heart...
Right!
Seize the enemy with
your Spirit sensor
which you developed through
unceasing diligence and determination!
Spirit sensor!
Wise words, Guy-sensei!
All right! Spirit sensor... On!
Rinji! How can you change
the strategy now?!
I've got something through
my Spirit sensor!
Without Rinji's power,
this strategy won't...
What? What is that?
What happened, Kihou?! Hey!
Damn... Where the hell is he...?
Shadow Dance!
Severe Leaf Hurricane!
He did it!
It's over!
That guy! Making us worry.
That means...
Only the enemy is in
that smoke screen now.
Rising Dragon Control!
What's going on?!
Damn it!
Our positions are totally reversed!
Just get rid of
this damned smoke screen!
It's not over yet...
Right now,
it's worse if we can't see.
Wh-What's happening?
Were these guys this weak?
They're not much, these guys.
I expected more of a fight.
At this rate,
I'm going to look like a useless ninja.
And besides, her henchmen
are ridiculously strong too.
We can't stay like this, Akamaru...
- Th-This is bad!
- Let's run!
Akamaru!
Dynamic Marking!
Wh-What is this?! It stinks!
I can erase the smell!
Vanishing Smoke Prison!
Everyone, retreat!
How did you know our position?!
Akamaru's Dynamic Marking is special.
Even your gas cannot eliminate the scent.
You guys made a fool out of me...
Eat this!
Fang Over Fang!
You did it!
- We did it!
- Oh well...
I guess there was no role for me to play.
I was a diversion so that
he couldn't accumulate fighting power...
Kakashi-senpai read
the situation perfectly.
But this Crystal Style Counter team...
They're coming!
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Stay out of this, small fry!
Kakashi-sensei!
Come at me with all your might!
Sharingan Kakashi!
Unfortunately,
I'm not the hot-blooded type.
Where'd you hide Yuukimaru?!
That's none of your business!
It's my fault that he went over
to you guys!
I won't let you use him
like some kind of tool!
I'm going to beat you
and rescue Yuukimaru!
Shut up!
As if... you understand!
Damn! Damn it!
Not yet?
These guys require more chakra
than the usual Parasitic Insects.
And that's...
in order to bring down
the Crystal Style user!
The small fry can stay out of this!
All right! Come at me, Kakashi!
So this is the power
she kept hidden...
So persistent...
So you just run away when
your ink drawings don't work?
Is that your ninja art?
There are other uses for my ink.
What...?
Ninja Art: Ink Flush.
What's the matter?
Come at me!
I'm fed up...
When we last fought,
she didn't release all her power?
The next one's for real!
Crystal Style:
Burst Crystal Falling Dragon!
Wha--?!
Die!
She can turn anything
she touches into crystal.
In other words, Water, Earth
nor Wood Styles have any effect.
However... this will...!
Did I do it...?
So naïve...
Too bad, Kakashi.
The three-tailed dragon was
just a diversion to keep me here...
For all the rumors,
your Sharingan isn't that impressive.
Well now, playtime is over.
It's useless.
H-Hey!
Ino... focus on the chakra
for the barrier!
R-Right!
The Hidden Leaf...
are looking for Three-Tails?
Okay, let's settle this!
Kakashi-sensei...!
Prepare to die...!
What?!
Oh! Shino!
Just in the nick of time.
Are they ready?
If they weren't, I wouldn't have come.
Humph... If it isn't the Insect user.
Your jutsu is useless against me.
It's useless!
Didn't I tell you? It's useless.
I wonder about that...
What?!
It can't be!
Your jutsu won't work against me.
That is because my insects
are capable of infinite evolution.
They are now resistant to your jutsu.
Yes, you did it! That's amazing!
That's impossible...
My Crystal Style can't be defeated...
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
I won't let you get away now!
Stay still!
Where is Yuukimaru?!
Why do you...?!
You want that boy's power too?
I don't need anything like that!
I wonder about that...
Now...! Her Crystal Style
has been sealed!
Tell us!
Where is Yuukimaru?!
Why you--!
This is...!
Guren...
This is... mud?
It seems that Crystal
mends itself right away.
Damn it! There's no end to this!
Focus the Insects' attack on one spot.
Guren...
I can't keep up...!
Lightning Blade!
A mud wall?!
Gozu?!
Gozu, you...
What are you doing?!
Let go! I'm going to kill them...!
Gozu...?
I won't let you through!
Guren!
Are you all right, Kakashi-sensei?!
Yeah... But...
Guren got away.
She was the key to finding Yuukimaru...!
It's regrettable...
My insects performed flawlessly,
yet she got away...
All right, we'll split up and search!
Naruto, you go with Shino.
Sai, come with me!
You said that they were formidable,
so I was burning with
the desire to fight...
What was that?
They were so easy to beat.
Yup... They were so different
from the last time.
Are you sure about these next guys?
Don't let your guard down.
Y-Yes!
Kakashi-senpai had
his hands full with her.
The Crystal Style user is no joke!
I'd love to face her in battle...
to see if my taijutsu is effective
against her!
Let's split up into two groups here.
Lee and Tenten will guard
the Sealing team by the lake!
And we will reinforce with Senpai's team
against the Crystal Style user!
Right!
Huh? I won't be able to fight
the Crystal Style user?
We don't know where
the enemy may appear.
I just told you not to
let your guard down...!
- Y-Yes!
- Yes!
Huh?! Just now...!
I know... It's close...
Directly below us...
It's finally come...
We are switching from the "search" mode
of the Four-Corner Sealing Barrier.
Keep your breathing soft and steady.
Here we go!
- Four-Corner Sealing Barrier: Bind!
We'll quietly sink the net.
Do not let the Three-Tails detect us!
The enemy...!
Concentrate!
But!
Leaf Hurricane!
What?!
Lee! Tenten!
We've taken care of
the enemy on that side,
so we rushed over.
I'm glad we made it in time!
Now that I'm here,
I won't allow you to lay
a finger on these four!
There should've been others to stop you...
Oh, them...
They were no match for us.
Damn... So Kigiri and
the others were beaten...
Now then, I am your opponent!
What? Running away?!
Humph...
They're all useless, every last one of them.
The Hidden Leaf ritual aims
to seal the Three-Tails.
They've chosen a path which will
prevent anyone from using the Three-Tails.
But I won't allow that.
Yuukimaru...?
Guren...
No... The white camellia
cannot become a red one.
You promised... that you'll come back!
Gozu... You...
Yuukimaru...?
No! This grass whistle...
No way...
No way... It's impossible...
Did I kill that boy's mother...?!
That's... That's...!
Guren...
We must go.
You?! I thought you'd returned
to Lord Orochimaru.
There's something more pressing.
The Hidden Leaf has started
to seal the Three-Tails.
What?
We'll use Yuukimaru to
control the Three-Tails.
And we'll destroy their barrier.
Kabuto, I need to talk to you.
What, at a time like this?
I know that.
But you of all people should know
what would happen
if we make Yuukimaru use
his powers any further...
Huh? Is that all?
Tell me the truth!
Why are you so upset?
It's none of your business
whether Yuukimaru lives or dies.
It is... my business.
Oh? So even the devil sheds tears?
To think that you,
who have killed countless people,
would have a soft spot for Yuukimaru.
Now that is a surprise.
He's special...
Because you killed his mother?
How did you...?
There's nothing unusual about that.
It's as Lord Orochimaru predicted.
He knew that you would
have feelings for the boy.
That's exactly why he chose you.
If you like,
I can tell Yuukimaru for you...
That the kind, gentle Guren
whom he believes
is the one he should return to...
is the very person
who killed his mother...
Stop!
Then, carry out my orders.
Tenten...
We don't know when
the enemy will appear again.
Please stay alert.
You endeared him to you very skillfully...
Lord Orochimaru...
I hate to admit it,
but you were right to select that woman...
Guren will grow to love Yuukimaru?
Is that even possible?
Kabuto, you have much to learn.
The more time you spend with someone,
the stronger the bond becomes.
That is human nature.
Is that so...?
Those two...
Their ties go deep indeed.
It's likely that Guren will disobey
my order and betray me.
Then...
I guess that time has come...
Lord Orochimaru...
We're almost there.
Are you ready, Yuukimaru?
Do I really have to do this?
That is your duty.
But I know it's going to make me
feel awful again...
How is it?
There's been no reaction.
I see...
She used up considerable chakra
during that last encounter.
This is the time to strike.
I don't want to give her too much time.
I agree. I'm going to widen
the scope of my search.
Damn, what's going on...?
This is the pits.
You guys are on the verge of death.
Hah! Speak for yourself.
Oh... I feel like I'm going to faint...
As if I'm going to die in a place like this!
Not after we survived
that hellhole of a camp.
That's the seal to capture the Three-Tails.
This is bad. They're well into the ritual.
Now then, Yuukimaru...
We don't have time...!
Hey Guren, do something.
Guren...
Never mind!
You... Are you going to betray us?
I have no intention of defying you.
But that jutsu will
cause too much damage.
So please...
Let me try one more time.
Not that again?
At a time like this?
In your reluctance to use Yuukimaru,
you've lost almost all your men.
On top of that,
you yourself have been beaten...
And you still think you can fight?
That's...
The least you can do in that state is...
Well... There is a way without
using Yuukimaru.
But time is of the essence.
This is on the condition that
you follow my orders completely.
I understand.
The minute you show signs of defiance,
or if you fail, I won't
hesitate to use him.
Yeah...
Humph, all right then.
Come, Yuukimaru.
Don't worry.
I'm taking him where he'll be safe.
And what's the plan?
I'll tell Rinji the plan.
You just follow his instructions.
The Three-Tails' power
won't reach you here.
Will Guren be okay...?
She's the one who insisted on this.
She'll have to do it even if it kills her.
Do not move from this spot.
Tell me the plan.
Guren...
Hurry it up. You're wasting time.
Yes. According to Kabuto,
there are two guarding the seal;
one is a weapons user
and the other a taijutsu user.
They've already gone through
a surprise attack,
so they've increased their guard.
I see.
In other words, the way to catch
their attention is a flashy diversion.
A decoy is necessary.
All right. Let's do it.
I'll take care of those two in front.
But are you sure about this, Guren...?
I have enough chakra to be a decoy.
You focus on finding
the right moment to break the seal.
The Three-Tails is completely
ensnared within the seal.
Good. Now let's narrow the sphere
of the Four-Corner Sealing Barrier
until the Three-Tails' freedom
is totally restricted!
- Yes!
- Huh?! Tenten!
- I know!
Who's there?!
Two kids protecting the precious seal?
What a laugh.
That jutsu...!
Are you the Crystal Style user?!
Isn't the Crystal Style Counter team
supposed to deal with her?!
So what'll you do?
Are you going to run with
your tails between your legs?
No such thing!
I'd like nothing better than to battle
the Crystal Style user
everyone's been talking about!
That's some confidence...
for a kid from the Hidden Leaf!
Concentrate, everyone!
The net is tight enough!
Now we'll lock it from all four sides
and completely seal the Three-Tails!
- Right!
Four-Corner Sealing Barrier... Lock!
I'm your opponent!
This resistance is strange...
It's as though...
Too bad.
She covered her body with crystal...?
Damn...
Normally, I'd have beaten enemies
like them long ago.
Not yet!
Judging from the chakra I have left,
there's just one or two more jutsu
I can use.
If that's the case!
I'll end it with this next one!
Ino!
My control...
Did we fail?
I'm sorry!
The net isn't broken yet! Synchronize!
We'll lock the seal once more!
Die!
Now!
- This is bad!
- Crap!
Eat this!
Collaboration Ninjutsu!
Wind Style: Toad Water Pistol!
What?!
Naruto...!
Yay, we did it!
That's the way it should be!
I finally found you, Crystal Style user!
Why you--!
Whatever it takes...
that seal must be broken!
Shino!
Wh-What?!
The seal!
Senpai.
Hmm?
It's you, Yamato.
As you predicted, we encountered
the enemy's diversionary team.
But they weren't very strong and ran off.
Then we split up into two...
I sent Lee and Tenten
to protect the Sealing team.
How about you?
It's bad.
We found a way to counter
the Crystal Style,
but she gave us the slip.
What?!
Quickly, go help protect
the Sealing team.
Damn it!
We won't be able to sustain the barrier!
I-It's so huge...!
Wha--?! What is this?!
Oh no!
What chakra! This is the Three-Tails...!
The barrier is broken!
Brother... I'm scared!
That shock wave...!
What kind of dangerous place
have you summoned us to this time?!
This isn't the time to talk like that!
Our goal has been achieved.
You've lost the jutsu
to seal the Three-Tails.
Why you... I can't forgive you!
Rinji, pull back!
You won't get away!
No!
Guren...
G-Guren!
Get away!
Where'd they go...?
There...
No!
No...!
Stop...!
Don't!
No...!
Kabuto... You seem to be
having a hard time
drawing out Yuukimaru's power.
If you try to force it out,
it won't be real power.
When there is true desire in the heart
and that desire is strong...
that is when he finds real strength
that even he did not know he had!
What is that...?
I've seen it before...
It's just like back then...
Yuukimaru!
Huh?!
Guren...!
That Tailed Beast was going crazy...
so what happened to it?
Is everyone all right?!
Thank you, Lee.
We've used up considerable chakra,
but we're all right.
The Three-Tails' chakra was enormous
and yet...
Captain Yamato!
Yeah, I know!
But recouping takes priority.
We will join up with
the Sealing team as ordered.
Right!
Just what happened anyway...?
I'm concerned about Naruto
and the others. Let's hurry!
Yes.
Guren's crisis triggered
the power surge?
Well now... This is worth testing.
I'm glad... that you're all right, Guren.
But...
My mother never returned.
Everyone has left.
Is he talking about his hometown?
He lost the place
where he could return to...
Yuukimaru...?
What have I done...?
Forgive me... Yuukimaru...
Guren, hurry...
Run...
That's...!
You... This is...!
I have this, so...
You know...
This one is for you, Guren.
You want to exchange it, right?
All right.
This time, I'll hold your hand...
Hurry... hurry...
And yet...
Someone like me...
is in your thoughts?!
Yuukimaru!
Guren!
I told you to wait...
But... I was worried about you...
And I thought if I keep thinking about you,
you'll come back.
The place where Yuukimaru
can return to...
I stole that from him...
What I can do for him is...
If I'll do...
If that's what you want...
I'll... I'll be the place
you can return to.
Is the touching reunion over?
Rinji?!
Yuukimaru! Get down!
We successfully thwarted
the sealing of the Three-Tails.
I'm taking Yuukimaru and leaving.
So you were the one.
What are you babbling about?
Look, for Lord Orochimaru's sake,
let's be friends.
After all, you're the tool that
controls the beast.
You're the one who can trigger
Yuukimaru's actions.
You... Why?!
Guren!
Are you all right?! Guren!
I'm okay...
I'm glad...
Because... I have this.
Uh-huh...
Me too.
Huh?! Guren!
That was Mom's grass whistle just now.
I can see the red camellia at last!
Mother...!
No...
This can't be...
Yuukimaru!
Yuukimaru.
Guren is in no condition to move.
You have to stop the Three-Tails...
Yuukimaru!
Guren will die if you don't do anything!
No...
Guren is the place I return to.
Yes, Yuukimaru.
When your beloved Guren
is in danger,
that is when your powers awaken.
If you don't stop the Three-Tails,
Guren will be killed!
No...
Not that...
I don't want that to happen!
Wow, that's amazing...
It worked even better than I expected!
I have no doubt... Yuukimaru is here!
Naruto!
You're late, Kakashi-sensei!
What's that light? What's going on?
It's him! Yuukimaru is here!
You mean, the boy who controls
the Three-Tails?
We have to go and save him!
Wait, Naruto!
There's been a change of plans.
We're going to protect the boy
who controls the Three-Tails.
Let's follow Naruto!
- Right!
Wait for me, Yuukimaru!
That's his limit?
He's a kid, after all...
He's running out of chakra.
Damn it!
I have to save her!
I have to save Guren...!
Don't come! Go away! Guren is...
Guren is the place I can return to!
Guren!
I won't let you kill Yuukimaru!
You stay back, got it?
Okay.
Crystal Style: Crimson Fruit!
Guren!
If you stay there,
you'll be safe from any kind of attack.
Okay.
Stay there and wait for me.
Be careful, Guren!
There's no need to worry about me!
I'm coming for you, Yuukimaru!
I have to keep it away from Yuukimaru.
Damn it...
We can't carelessly close in...
Naruto!
Yuukimaru!
Where are you, Yuukimaru?!
Crystal Style: Hexagonal Shuriken Wild Dance!
He's...
going for Yuukimaru!
Like I'd let you!
I have to stop him somehow...
Guren...
Not... yet!
Crystal Style: Crystal Wall, 8th Formation!
I guess...
my chakra is reaching its limit...
The Three-Tails?
She's...!
Is that... Yuukimaru?
He's... the ninja from the Leaf!
What?!
Crap!
Come on!
I-It's too big!
I won't let you touch Yuukimaru!
I'm here to take him from you!
But before that...
It seems there's something
I have to do!
Go!
Damn, he's so tough!
I can't find a single weakness.
You're pretty dumb, aren't you?
Are you picking a fight with me?!
The fact that a guy like him defends it
means there's a spot that
he doesn't want you to attack, right?
You're all talk! Damn!
A short time... Just a short while...
Change my life into chakra...
Chakra points! Life and Death!
Guren!
Crystal Style: Arrow of Light!
There's no way to harden an eyeball,
that's for sure!
Eat this!
Giant Rasengan!
That did it!
You're pretty good.
Next, I'll settle things with you!
What?!
This is the boy Naruto was talking about.
Damn... This is an utter failure...
I must get Yuukimaru back,
no matter what...