I'm counting on you.
Take it to the Hokage.
You're so reckless...!
Don't get so upset...
And don't talk back!
Scrapes and bruises...
these injuries aren't too serious...
The real problem is this arm.
It's broken in several places.
His body isn't able to withstand
his jutsu.
I see...
So Hidan and Kakuzu are dead.
Yes. It appears Naruto's team killed them.
Oh...?
We thought they would take down
another Akatsuki
if we let them live...
Seems like it went quite well.
Not bad at all.
I'm sure even the Akatsuki
would never have expected
to lose two of their members
at once.
Still, they now have the Two-Tails.
Maybe we should push
a little harder to weaken them.
How is that child?
Yes.
I'm planning a final test
in a few days.
But judging from the data,
I'm certain there is no mistake.
I'm looking forward to it.
We're almost at the final step.
But for that to happen,
we need one more pawn.
Say, Kabuto. That woman...
Would you bring her here?
That woman?
All right, done.
Now you just have to take it easy.
Thanks, Sakura.
Say, Naruto.
This new jutsu, use it only
when absolutely necessary.
Do not use it too often!
Don't worry.
As long as you're around to heal me-
I'm not talking about that!
Medical ninjutsu can't heal
everything instantly!
But this kind of makes me happy.
Huh?
I feel like you and I are
getting closer to Sasuke.
Honestly...
Quite the welcome... Guren.
Oh, it's just you, Kabuto.
I thought it was an intruder.
You did that on purpose, didn't you?
Of course not.
Besides, I wouldn't want
someone who'd die so easily
to be standing beside
Lord Orochimaru!
An order from Lord Orochimaru...
From Lord Orochimaru...?
That is the order of Lord Orochimaru.
Is that so...?
From Lord Orochimaru himself!
So he hasn't forgotten about me!
When I was sent to take care
of this remote hideout,
I was sure I had been forsaken.
Did I say something funny, Guren?
Humph... All we have to do is
make them kill each other.
The sound of bones being crushed!
Piercing screams!
Just the thought of it
gives me a thrill.
It's to select members for
Lord Orochimaru's next operation...
There's no point if they all die.
Yes, I know that!
Men! You all heard that, didn't you?
If you want to leave this hideout
and breathe free air again, you must win!
Then, you will be able to work
for Lord Orochimaru under my command!
You are such fortunate men!
Now, begin!
Fight all you want!
Enter!
A shinobi bird sent by
the ANBU Black Ops has just arrived.
Where is Kakashi?
He is probably with Naruto.
Regarding that matter, huh...?
Tell him to see me when he's done.
Have they tracked down
Orochimaru's hideout?
No... It says they nearly had him
when they were suddenly attacked.
We must select members for
a search team to be sent off immediately.
Yes, ma'am.
There's likely no traces left of
the ANBU Black Ops
who sent this message...
The ANBU have a rule:
"When you die, leave no corpse behind."
He can't possibly rest in peace
unless we discover that hideout.
Here you go!
Miso-flavored pork bone stock
with roast pork...
The two thick slices of
roast pork are on the house.
Thank you!
Just what I've been waiting for.
Oh... It's hot!
Be careful.
Our ramen stays hot until the very end.
It's just not easy eating
with my left hand.
Here, lend me those chopsticks.
D-Don't tell me, Sakura...
You're going to feed me...?
Oh!
Say ahh...!
This isn't the time for you to interfere!
What...?!
Yo...
Not "What"!
Huh...?!
What's going on?
Just when Sakura was
about to feed me!
When a friend is in trouble,
you must help him.
That's what a true friend does
according to this book...
Forget what's in your book
and read the room for once!
How can I read something
that I cannot see?
You're such a pain!
What's with all this noise?
Kakashi-sensei!
Naruto can't eat with
his right hand...
and we're having a little disagreement
over who's going to feed him.
Here, eat!
So in the end, it's Kakashi-sensei?!
By the way, Kakashi-sensei,
I'm surprised that
you haven't landed in the hospital
after a huge mission like that.
So that's how people see me now...?
What a shock...
Well, this time, I didn't need to use
my Mangekyo Sharingan, you see.
If you all hadn't arrived in time,
I would have used it again for sure.
Sorry... We're late.
Then, just as you imagined,
I'd probably be lying in bed now.
Naruto...
You have definitely gotten stronger.
You're equal to me,
or even stronger...
But keep in mind that the greater
the jutsu you use,
the greater the risk to you.
Yeah...
Kakashi... This new jutsu...
the Wind Style: Rasen Shuriken.
Forbid Naruto from using it again.
If he continues using this new jutsu,
Naruto will lose his ability
to mold chakra.
If the cells are disconnected
from the body's chakra network,
even my medical skills won't cure him.
Be certain to emphasize
that to Naruto.
Naruto...
That new jutsu of yours...
Kakashi-sensei...
I know myself best!
I'm going to be the Hokage one day,
you know.
I'm really powerful,
so there's nothing to worry about!
I shouldn't have bothered
worrying about him.
I guess these should be the members
of the search team.
Isn't Kakashi here yet?
He's been notified. He's probably
got his hands full with Naruto.
I wonder if Kakashi will be able
to talk him into it.
We'd better put a guard on him
for a while.
He's sure to start training
on that new jutsu.
I can't just let that slide.
Yo! It's been a while...
Weren't you investigating
the Akatsuki?
I stopped by because
I was a little worried.
Tell me the details on what
you said just now.
Thanks for the ramen, Pops!
Give Kakashi-sensei the bill!
What?!
Thanks...!
Thank you.
Wait, what...?
So, you've finally learned
to do the Shadow Clone...
What...? What's going on?
Then... Let me see how much
you've improved.
- Here I come, Big Brother Naruto.
- Sexy Two-girl Jutsu!
Whoa...!
So that's your new move?!
What do you think, big brother?!
The two girls are...
Are you all right, Konohamaru?!
Hey, Moegi, what are you doing?
What are you doing in
front of us ladies...?!
This is like déjà vu...
You two!
This isn't what you always do
when you get together, is it?
W-Well, this jutsu is
a good diversionary tactic...
Besides, you could say this is
a serious competition
between the two of us.
You two shouldn't be
escalating things like this.
You two are the only ones who
would fall for a jutsu like this!
You guys...
You seem to be having fun, as usual.
Oh! It's the Pervy Sage!
Here's another one
that would fall for it...
Oh... You're looking better
than I expected, Naruto!
Oh, well this is nothing.
Idiot! The bones haven't healed yet!
You haven't changed at all.
So, was Naruto convinced?
He has matured.
I left the rest up to that man...
That is for the best...
There's something I want you to do.
It's a search mission...
It hasn't been confirmed yet,
but the ANBU Black Ops have discovered
what could be Orochimaru's hideout.
However, the operative
has been killed
and the map he sent me only
shows the general area.
I see.
Do you have a problem with
the members that I have chosen?
I'm impressed...
You have chosen the best possible
members for this search team.
Enter.
Lord Orochimaru,
it's time for your medicine.
Oh, you're back...?
Yes. I returned a little while ago.
How's Guren?
The same...
I just don't understand why
you make such a fuss
over that woman.
You've never liked her, have you?
She may not look it, but at one
time, she was my top candidate.
Of course, time was not on her side
and Genyumaru was chosen instead.
I am aware of that.
When Sasuke achieves
the skills he needs...
The time for my reanimation
will be near.
When that happens, both the Akatsuki
and the Leaf will be a hindrance...
Our current operation is preparation
for when that happens.
Lord Orochimaru, it's because of
the plans scheduled after your reanimation
that I believe there are too many
flaws in that woman's character...
This job can be carried out by
no one but Guren.
Speed up that test...
Yes, sir...
We may be able to leave today.
I'm coming in.
Tell me... Do you like red camellias?
White camellias?
Camellias don't lose their petals;
the whole flower falls off.
You can get oil from the nuts, and
the tree makes very good charcoal.
Don't come in here...
Go back!
Go back?
I wonder where I can go back to?
Where should I go back to?
Is this where I'm supposed
to return to?
But, something's not right.
This is not the place where
I'm supposed to return to.
That's right...
You wouldn't know that, would you?
Say, do you have somewhere
to go back to?
Such a place does not exist for me.
So here you are, Yuukimaru...
It's time to leave.
All right.
Sorry to bother you.
See you again, Sasuke...
In order to carry out
Lord Orochimaru's plan,
it is necessary to draw out
Yuukimaru's power...
I must produce results with these tests
before handing him to Guren.
I'll use whatever measures
are necessary to do it...
You really can't tell until you try it.
Huh?
You can't tell where to tie gaiters until
you've wrapped them around a few times...
You're supposed to be able
to tell when you put it on.
But you don't know until
you finish wrapping it around.
Let's go.
It's almost time.
Kakashi-sensei...
Is everyone here?
I'm sure you've already heard
about our mission.
Yes... It is to pinpoint the hideout
that's thought to belong to Orochimaru.
Yes... With all of your abilities,
it should not be very difficult to do.
First, I'll get a head start and
release my parasitic insects
to search out the area where chakra
is in the highest concentration.
Akamaru and I will do the rest!
His nose will pinpoint their hideout.
Once we find the hideout,
I should search out the enemies' chakra
using my Byakugan, right?
I'm counting on you...
If that is really
Orochimaru's hideout,
there's a chance that Sasuke is there...?
Yes...
Does Naruto know that?!
That's a silly question.
If he knew that,
he'd never sit still.
That's true.
Yes. Naruto hasn't been told
about this mission...
Orochimaru, huh...
Multiple Legs Barrage!
I swore to myself that
I'd never let Akamaru
go through anything like that again.
Akamaru...
Kiba, what are you thinking?
Well, I was just thinking about
our mission to rescue Sasuke.
But this time... if it's really
going to be at Orochimaru's hideout,
maybe the same type of people
will appear...
What? Getting nervous?
Just the opposite, Kakashi-sensei!
In addition to Shikamaru, word has it that
even Naruto beat the Akatsuki.
I've been training hard too.
I have to show the others
that I won't lose either!
Then I'll have to demonstrate
the results of my training too.
Huh?
That's because unlike you guys,
I've rarely been on missions consistently
with the same members.
Are you still bitter because you
couldn't be a part of the last mission?
That plus the fact that Naruto didn't
even recognize his comrade's face.
Of course, Naruto wouldn't
recognize you!
Your face is practically
covered in that get-up!
That shouldn't matter...
among comrades.
C'mon, let's all do our best together.
I won't lose either!
I've done my best
so that Naruto will acknowledge me.
Before I knew it, they've all
become so strong and reliable.
Even him.
Tsunade told me about it.
You've perfected
the Wind Style: Rasen-shuriken...
Well done!
It's no good...
Huh? What do you mean?
You have accomplished a feat not
even the Fourth Hokage was able to.
Have more confidence in yourself.
If this is the result,
then it's no good.
I mastered an instant kill jutsu.
But... it's pointless
if I'm only going to waste
my chakra on top of getting injured!
I see...
This isn't a jutsu that can
be used over and over.
I have to learn a couple jutsu that
use less chakra but are effective.
Is that what you were
worrying about?
In that case, all you have to do
is train some more.
At your current level, there are sure
to be other jutsu that you can master.
What do you say?
Will you come with me on another journey
to gather writing material?
I'm asking you if you have the will
to train with me once more.
Yeah! Take me with you!
All right. Then we'll leave at once!
Where are we going?
First, we must heal that arm!
Shall we visit a hot spring?
What do you mean, "hot spring"?!
I can see exactly where your thoughts
are headed, you Pervy Sage!
But I found a mixed hot spring and
that's good for healing broken bones...
See, that is your motive, after all!
Yes, well that's too bad.
Maybe I'll invite Sakura, then.
What?!
Yes, yes, I'll go.
Wait for me!
Come on, take me with you.
I'm injured, you know...
Don't leave me behind, Pervy Sage!
This is...
the ANBU Black Ops who
sent the message...
What is it? You sense something?
This is more than just a sense,
right, Akamaru?
The smell of death.
There're quite a few dead bodies
up ahead.
My nose is pretty sharp,
but... Which way?
This way.
Proceed with caution.
This is...!
H-Help...
A Curse Mark!
This guy has Orochimaru's Curse Mark!
Without a doubt,
this is Orochimaru's hideout.
However...
What happened here?!
Faint traces of chakra!
One... two... There are so many!
Let's go, Kakashi-sensei!
We have no time to waste.
Be wary of traps. Let's go.
How terrible...
What is this?!
Looks like they fought each other.
A split in the ranks?
We'd better find out from them.
What's the matter, Akamaru?!
Damn it!
We'd have been in big trouble if
Akamaru hadn't found an escape route.
Heh heh, Good boy, Akamaru!
But to think they laid a trap.
I don't think so.
I don't think the enemy
knew that we were close.
That trap was set to
destroy any evidence;
to destroy the hideout itself.
But there were survivors...!
Yeah... What a cruel thing to do.
I can't forgive him,
that Orochimaru!
Quit wasting time!
We've succeeded in our mission
to locate Orochimaru's hideout, but...
We can't say we succeeded.
Because we can't return
to the village
without any information
about Orochimaru.
He's right, Kakashi-sensei!
Um... We can still gather information.
The enemy set a time device here...
In other words, there are people
who left this site.
You're right. The enemy who
has information is still close by.
Then it's decided!
Let's pursue them.
Leave the enemy search to me.
This is a specialty of
my Parasitic Insects.
Hey! Don't forget
my Akamaru's sharp nose!
E-Even I...!
Where are we headed?
Heh, isn't it Orochimaru's hideout?
Do you understand what
that means?
S-Stop... Please stop!
There's no guarantee we're safe
if he messes around
with our bodies again.
That's for sure...
B-But I'm scared of Orochimaru...
I can't defy him...
Right now, it's only that woman.
Y-You're right...
If we kill that one woman,
we'll be free!
Yeah!
Let's kill her!
Who said you can take a break?
I did!
One, two, three...
We won't listen to you anymore.
We'll kill you and go free!
It's decided!
Ten, eleven, twelve... sixteen of you.
Are you scared...?!
Well, are you?
Fool.
You think you can beat
all of us here?! Woman!
How pitiful! You're not able to
judge your opponent's strength!
Crystal Style:
Crystal Prison!
My insects have detected the enemy.
Well, since they don't even know
if they're a match for their opponent...
They're not just weak, they're being stupid.
Are you trying to say you're smarter?
What will you do? Are you coming?
I-I...
Of course! We're coming.
We didn't run away...
We just wanted to avoid a fight.
I can't face Lord Orochimaru
if I don't have any henchmen.
I pledge my loyalty.
No need to.
If you betray me, you'll just die.
A jutsu that ensnares
the enemy in green crystal?
Earth Style?
I've never seen anything
like it before...
My parasitic insects have been
destroyed in the same way.
This couldn't be...
Young lady,
the dango here is truly wonderful!
Of course, with a beautiful lady
like you serving it,
there is no way
it can't be delicious!
Oh dear, don't call me
beautiful like that.
The dango sure is good,
but I'll bet you're much tastier,
ain't that right?
We're finally here!
Pervy Sage, let's start training!
What are you saying?
First, we wash off the dirt
from our travels.
Healing your arm is also
part of training.
The hot spring here is
good for broken bones.
Besides...
Hot springs... are so much fun.
It's research... Research!
You haven't changed, Pervy Sage.
Weren't you nearly killed
by Grandma Tsunade
for peeking into the women's bath?
No!
The last time I came,
I'm sure it was a mixed bath.
Funny...
Maybe they separated the bath
because of guys like you?
Huh? Just what have you
been learning from your teacher?
Why do you think I do these things?
'Cuz you're a pervert.
You idiot!
The research for
the Make-Out series is a cover.
This is actually ninja training
to make oneself go unnoticed
by women who are on guard.
Yeah yeah.
Ahem... Anyway, being here
at these hot springs
is really to treat your broken bone.
Think of soaking in the bath
as part of training.
Pervy Sage, hurry and train me...!
Seriously... You're such an annoying kid!
Huh?
No need to worry about this now.
I've trained so that instead of...
relying on Nine-Tails' power...
rather than use a power
that hurts everyone...
I've trained to attain the power
to protect, but it's just not enough!
Pervy Sage, isn't there a
long-distance type jutsu that I can learn?
Talking as though
he's a full-fledged ninja...
Pervy Sage, do you think I've gotten
a bit stronger at least?
What are you saying?
You're the same novice
you were three years ago.
I see... I guess so...
If that's what being wise means,
then I don't care if I'm a fool
for the rest of my life.
Even without a teacher,
I'll create some awesome jutsu
and rescue Sasuke, no matter what!
Tell me... Have your feelings changed
since three years ago?
I never take back my word.
That's my ninja way!
Hmm, I guess so.
I was concerned about my friend,
and what I gained from it was
a sense of helplessness and regret.
Yet Naruto has lived
with the same regret for three years
without giving up
on his friend...
He has never forgotten Sasuke
and has continued to train...
Earnest in his desire to bring
Sasuke back home to Hidden Leaf Village.
Even if his own body is battered...
The idiot has matured in his idiot way.
I'll acknowledge that.
Just a little bit.
Really?
But in order to bring him back,
I've have to get much stronger.
Maybe he can...
They say, "a place where
someone still thinks of you;
that's a place you can call home."
Yeah.
What is it, Kakashi?
Take this to the village.
Have the Fifth Hokage analyze it.
What is this...?
One of Shino's parasitic insects
which fell victim to a jutsu...
It was an enemy believed to be
a follower of Orochimaru.
Orochimaru?!
According to the footprints,
there are five or six more
that we must pursue.
Move quickly.
Leave it to me!
I'm counting on you.
All right, we're going to
pursue the enemy.
Increase the range...
spread out and search.
Don't miss a single trace of them!
Right!
Yeah.
Don't worry. I, Rinji, will handle
things while you're away.
I'm counting on you.
I guess she still
can't trust us.
She doesn't want us to learn
about Orochimaru's hideout,
so we're shoved into
a place like this...
She's extremely cautious.
It's why she rarely
makes mistakes.
So conversely, we can trust her.
The ones who were killed
were trying to run away
because they didn't want
to see Orochimaru.
Can you really trust her?
Those are cattails.
Huh?
Grab the tips.
This is the lake.
It's true, lake water
isn't salty at all.
It's different from the ocean.
Although... I've never seen
the ocean either.
Just now...
Hmm?
Well, around here should do...
What's so funny?
I have a feeling something fun
is about to start.
Yeah, we're going to
have some fun.
Can you put this on?
This is a special medicine,
which will draw out your power...
no, make something
interesting happen.
It's coming...
That's the limit.
It's there... no doubt about it.
In this lake...
And... this child...
we can use him.
Lord Orochimaru...
Well now, shall we begin training?
Yeah! I'm ready!
Maybe we'll do a simple jutsu using
your Wind chakra this time.
A simple jutsu?!
Do you remember the training
we did during our last journey?
I remember doing all kinds of things...
Remember,
you trained with the toad?
Th-That's the one character
I couldn't handle.
You remember?
I figured it was a bit
too early back then,
but you can do it now.
It's a collaboration ninjutsu with a toad!
Combining two jutsu to transform them
into one stronger jutsu
is known as a collaboration jutsu.
Hey, I know that!
When we beat that Akatsuki fellow,
Captain Yamato combined
his Water Style with my Wind Style
to form the Hurricane Vortex Jutsu.
Good, that makes it easier.
Summoning Jutsu!
Oh Jira-chan... it's been so long.
Gamariki, sorry to make you
come so far.
Oh, don't mention it.
You and I are old friends.
Why... Why is Gamariki here...?!
Oh, Naruto. You're here too?
Unless the ninja duo is completely
in sync,
a combination ninjutsu is impossible.
Yamato must have had perfect timing
with his Hurricane Vortex jutsu.
Oh, then it's useless.
Not him... there's no way
he can synchronize with me.
Shut up! Shut up!
If we can't, then it's your fault!
Besides, why do I have to sync up
with Gamariki?!
To perfect a new jutsu, right?
From this moment on,
you will train to synch your timing
with Gamariki's timing.
Well, I guess if you insist,
Jiraiya, I have no choice...
B-But! Don't you think it'll be
an even greater Combination ninjutsu
if you and I did it, Pervy Sage?
I can't be with you all the time.
But you can summon the toad.
But, you know...
is this jutsu really strong?
Gamariki...
Watch carefully.
Be gentle, okay?
Wow... I didn't know you were
so strong, Gamariki.
With perfect timing, my chakra flowed
into Gamariki's Water Pistol.
Your Wind chakra will go well
with the Water.
If you practice, you'll be able to perfect
an even stronger jutsu.
An even stronger jutsu...
All right! I'll do it! Just bring it on!
First comes special rhythm training.
S-Special rhythm training?
- One, two, one, two...
- One, two, one-!
Gamariki and I...
Naruto and I...
- aren't compatible!
- Aren't compatible!
Maybe it's not possible.
One, two... One, two...
You're working hard, Naruto.
Gamariki's sternness will temper you
like steel and nurture you...
– Awesome!
– An outdoor bath!
And before long, your body
will be tough enough...
to repel any temptation
of the world--!
Can't repel...
any temptation of the world...
Goodness! Can you even do
something this simple?!
What're you saying?!
It's the way you teach that's bad!
Oh? You're blaming me?
You think you're better than me?
Humph! Forget it!
I can't take this anymore!
Hey! Stop right there!
Love Smack!
Damn it!
Coming at me from behind...
That's cowardly!
– Take this! And that!
– Stop!
What is this?!
The water's all gone.
Let's go.
No!
You call this training?!
Slobbering around like that--?!
This is the Love Smack!
Forget your Love Smack!
This duo is disbanded!
Fine with me!
That's enough! Both of you!
As if Naruto isn't enough...
But you too, Gamariki...
Well, you know Jira-chan,
it's not like I don't understand.
I do, but...
For a collaboration ninjutsu using
the Wind Style and Water Style,
nothing is more important
than synchronizing with the toad.
All the more reason why...
our bodies must be compatible,
or it's useless for me.
Yeah well, we aren't compatible,
so it'll be faster if
we find someone who is.
Hmm... That may be a good idea.
However... you can't summon
with that arm, can you?
Hah! You haven't forgotten
how fast I recover, have you?
Pervy Sage!
Summoning Jutsu!
H-Huh?!
Long time no see...
Hello, Naruto!
Huh?! Gamakichi and Tatsu...?
Oh, you've grown!
You guys have gotten pretty big.
Of course we have!
It's because of all the snacks
we've eaten.
Anyway, why'd you summon us?
Oh yeah, I have some
important business!
I want to work on our compatibility.
What?!
Does that taste good?
Lord Orochimaru!
That's...
You're late.
Lord Orochimaru has
chosen Genyumaru.
And that was Sasuke Uchiha
just now...
Lord Orochimaru's next vessel...
Sasuke, let me see the results
of your training thus far.
You're my opponent?
By no means.
How impressive.
A thousand enemies stand before you,
and you don't even flinch.
That man... How strong is he...?
Begin.
Sasuke... You are truly...
The power you have...
I'm interested.
Come with me.
Back then...
I was the one captivated
by your power...
Your strength...
To become like you... was my dream.
There's only one reason
why you were summoned...
I need you to do something for me.
Of course. That is the reason
why I serve you, Lord Orochimaru.
I really want you
for this mission.
In fact... you're the only one
who can do it.
Only me?
Then perhaps,
I may want to reconsider.
Who... is most worthy of
becoming my vessel.
He's quite fatigued...
Perhaps we should rest a bit.
Damn it! How am I supposed to
keep up with those ridiculous moves?!
I guess trying to connect
heart-to-heart is crazy...
especially with the toads.
Can you... connect hearts?
Wh-Who the hell are you?!
Where'd you come from...?
What does it mean to
connect heart-to-heart?
Huh?! W-Well...
My feelings are understood
by someone else...
and that person's feelings
reach me as well.
Then it happens?
Y-Yeah, well sure.
I mean, if you really focus
on it hard...
Then one day... one day,
it will work.
And even Sasuke...
Then that person you're thinking
about will know where home is.
Oh... You wouldn't know
what I mean, would you...
if I start rambling on like that?
So if someone is thinking about me,
then that's the place I go back to?
Yeah... that's home.
That's good to know.
Yeah, right?
By the way, what's your name–
Huh? Hey?
That kid... Where'd he disappear to?
Do you smell something, Akamaru?
Did you find anything, Kiba?
No, we haven't picked up any scents.
I used my Byakugan,
but couldn't see anything.
Oh!
A bat?
There are some signs.
Huh? Where?!
I'm talking about my insects.
So don't get so excited.
Your insects?
Don't get me excited like that.
Well, you had tens of thousands
of insects,
so I wouldn't be surprised
if one of them is still alive.
But that one insect
out of tens of thousands
that managed to survive
becomes a huge asset to us.
... Asset to us?
Because it has survived despite
incurring the enemy's jutsu.
You mean the insects are
now immune to the enemy's jutsu...
My insects' life span is only
a few hours at most.
And the immune insects can breed
in a very short period.
That's amazing!
But it's just a possibility.
I'm not sure if it'll be successful.
Anyway, I must find as many
surviving insects as possible.
We'll help you.
Yeah! Count on us!
There's no need.
What?!
Only I can search for
the insects.
I can't have you stepping on them
while you're searching around blindly.
Can't you refuse our help
with a little more finesse?
I don't want to waste time
by being vague.
That's fine.
Shino, you go find the insects
that survived.
And we'll continue our search.
All right, let's go, Akamaru!
Sorry, but I've had a series
of snake eyes.
Hey man, I hope you're not cheating.
No way!
I was born lucky,
and I'm totally different from you.
No wonder I'm losing.
Since your luck is so strong,
let me roll the dice
that you just used!
She's late.
Ahh! Almost!
Just one more roll!
Want to try?
It's a good way to kill time.
You're ignoring me?
Fine.
Fine. But I'm a little surprised...
That you're waiting for Guren
to come back.
You seemed defiant to me,
so I thought you'd take advantage
of this chance to escape.
Even if I could escape,
I couldn't beat her.
That's a surprising answer.
I didn't know you had decided
to obey Guren.
How about you guys?
Us?
You knew from the beginning...
that a fight for survival
would occur in that hideout.
I thought you had already
joined forces with them.
You're sharp! That's right!
But it's not surprising.
It's better to have people who help
each other in dangerous situations.
So we promised to help each other
when things got rough.
Those who overestimated
their own abilities
and acted thoughtlessly have died.
So I say, our wisdom has
helped us to survive.
Though, at the rate we were going
in that battle royal,
we might've fought each other.
It's true that you were really strong
out there all by yourself.
While we were fighting individually,
we had to keep away from you...
But we are four here.
We won't be beaten
if we stay together, not even by you.
Now we all work for Guren...
You'd better socialize with the others.
Man, why couldn't they find
a better hideout?
Guren isn't nice to us.
She left us in this old shack.
I'm going on patrol.
Did you find something?
What's wrong, Akamaru?!
Deliver this information quickly.
I thought you were out
on patrol.
I had something to think about.
I'm just setting out.
I'll go with you.
Does that mean...
you're heeding my advice?
A dog whistle?
Right. Akamaru said
he definitely heard it.
Do you think the enemy
has a dog?
I doubt it,
because it's harder to mask
a dog's scent than a human's.
And if they have a dog,
Akamaru and I would've
caught its scent long ago.
Then, why the dog whistle?
I don't know.
Do you know which direction
it came from?
No, but I'm sure they're not far away.
A new enemy?
Right. The enemy seems
really hard to beat.
I saw that the team
was really flustered.
Therefore, you're giving this to me?
There's something inside the crystal.
It's Shino's Parasitic Insect that was
overcome by the enemy's jutsu.
Kakashi requested an
analysis right away.
This can't be...
I've only heard about it
through rumors...
Shizune, take this to the forensics team.
It's urgent!
All right!
Frog... I'm a frog...
Gamatatsu's... mind...
I can hear... the frog song.
Read his mind...
and respond to it...
- I can hear...
- the frog song.
- Chinchiro chinchiro chinchirorin.
- I can hear...
Chinchiro chinchiro...
- ... chinchirorin.
- I can hear...
- ... the frog song.
- I can hear... the frog song.
- Chinchiro chinchiro chinchirorin.
Naruto, you don't look like you've
opened up your mind yet!
Don't get swept up by
Gamatatsu's movements!
Communicate with Gamatatsu's mind,
arrange things your way,
then just express yourself!
Yeah!
Huh?
Sorry...
- Look Gamakichi is singing.
- Gero gero gero gero gero...
- Look Gamatatsu is singing too.
- Kero kero kero kero kero...
Gamatatsu's... mind...
Ah, that cloud...
looks like a cream puff...
It looks yummy!
They've finally reached
each other's mind...
Oh? Did you feel something
just now, Gamatatsu?
Why are you asking me this?
A butterfly!
What?!
- Rock, paper, scissors, go!
- Go!
- Go! Go! Go!
- What's your name?
- Gamatatsu!
This doesn't mean
you're on the same wavelength.
- ? I can hear... the frog song.
-? Chinchiro chinchiro chinchirorin
I can't move anymore...
Here!
Eat it!
Thanks.
I think we all have to
acknowledge you.
What?
Gamatatsu, Gamakichi,
Sakura, Tsunade... and I...
We all admit you've worked
really hard.
I wonder what's pushing you forward.
Well, I never give up and I have guts!
Sasuke...
Hmm?
I wonder if Sasuke will...
acknowledge that about me...?
I hope he does...
What...?
I can't tell him about the Akatsuki...
Hey, all of you!
I have something to do,
so I must leave.
Can you go back to the village
and help with the rest
of Naruto's training?
We'll take care of it!
I'll do it if you give me
some snacks.
All right, all right.
I'm counting on you!
Good luck, Naruto!
Work hard and truly become...
the Hokage...
Naruto, good luck with
your never-say-die spirit...
What?! The Pervy Sage disappeared?!
Yeah, he asked me
to give this to you.
Give it to me!
We're going back to our village.
Pack up!
You summoned me?
Yamato, I want you to go
and assist Team Kakashi.
Kakashi-senpai?
I heard it was just a scouting mission.
Has something happened?
The problem is that
they had a run-in with the enemy.
This foe uses a jutsu
we've never seen before.
A jutsu we've never seen before?
We don't understand everything
about it yet.
I'm having the sample Kakashi sent
analyzed right away.
Who shall I take?
Sai who can search from the sky,
and Sakura in case anyone is injured.
But Sakura has gone on
an errand for me.
She's to return at dawn.
Set out as soon as
Sakura comes back.
Understood.
But if this involves Orochimaru,
won't Naruto want to go too?
Now listen! Naruto is not
to find out about this.
And...?
Yes, there should be no problem
with Yuukimaru's strength.
All that remains is
to modify the drug.
When will that be completed?
It won't take very long.
Then order Guren and Yuukimaru
to set out ahead.
I know I've asked before,
but are you sure about that woman?
We have no choice.
This is something
only Guren can do.
This strategy will bear fruit
once Guren and Yuukimaru's powers
become one.
How long are you going
to make me wait?
No more waiting.
Lord Orochimaru has given his order.
Really?!
So naïve.
Yuukimaru!
Are we returning somewhere?
Will that be my home?
Who is this kid?
You're taking him.
This boy.
You expect me to babysit?
Already complaining?
Were you lying about being loyal
to Lord Orochimaru?
Although, with that attitude,
no child will take to you.
Don't act smug just because
you're Lord Orochimaru's aide.
I can kill you anytime.
I see. She's able to instantly
crystallize anything that's nearby.
Although she looks unarmed,
everything around her is a weapon.
So that is the Crystal Style.
No wonder she caught
Lord Orochimaru's eye.
If I die, your reincarnation
will be in jeopardy.
You want to become one
with Lord Orochimaru, don't you?
So pretty!
What are you saying?
Isn't it going to rain more?
Humph, what a weird kid.
You make a nice pair.
Whoa.
I'll catch up right away.
So go on ahead with Yuukimaru.
All right.
But if he gives me any lip,
I'll let him have it.
Be careful. Someone's approaching
from over that way.
What?! How would you know that?
I didn't tell you, did I?
On the way to your hideout,
I took care of an ANBU Black Ops
from the Hidden Leaf Village
who was checking out the area
The Leaf Village is sure
to be on the move.
You don't want to get involved
with them.
Make sure you give them the slip.
I'll be the judge of that.
Remember, if you fail
in this mission with Yuukimaru,
all discussion of
your reincarnation ends.
The Hidden Leaf...
Those guys! They'd better not betray me
and run to the Hidden Leaf!
Am I going home?
I hope I can return home...
But is there a place I can return to?
A place where someone thinks of you,
that's where home is.
I'm sure there is.
Look over here.
These are dog tracks.
A dog...
That was a bad move.
They've become so weak,
I can't feel their response.
Found one!
All right! It's got eggs.
If I can make them hatch...
Is it true the enemy
is prowling around?
I'm sure of it.
They're hiding in this mountain.
Just who are they?
I don't know.
But if they're searching for
Orochimaru's hideout...
Either the Akatsuki...
or the Hidden Leaf.
What'll we do? Should we attack?
Without Guren, there's no guarantee
that we can pull it off.
I was wrong...
About what?
I figured this was your chance...
to make a run for it.
A run for it?
Your chance to run over
to the Hidden Leaf's side
with information
about Orochimaru as a gift.
I see. Well, I never gave it
a thought...
I get it. You want to turn yourself in
to the Hidden Leaf?
Not at all.
Then what's your reason
for sticking with Guren?
It's personal.
Hmm...?
Damn...
If I were alone,
I'd already be there by now.
I don't want to go there anymore.
I get headaches...
No, I want to go back.
But I don't have a place to return to.
Oh... But that person said...
If someone is thinking about me...
that's the place to go home to.
But how do I go about getting
someone to think about me?
Can't you quit babbling
and start walking faster?
Seriously! Just what's with this kid?
A red camellia or a white one.
Which do you prefer?
A camellia...
Camellia?
That...
Oh. Yes, this is a camellia, all right.
Do you like camellias?
Camellias...
I don't like camellias.
This is just coincidence.
Hey!
What's the matter?!
Damn!
Damn! There's no way we can go back
to the hideout in this rain.
I-It's cold.
What? You're cold?
A fever...!
How did it go? Find anything?
No, nothing...
I found nothing either.
Especially when it rains,
these conditions make it impossible
to catch any scents.
So... no progress at all.
Huh?!
Even the bats are inside...
Huh? Bats?!
I'll go out and search once more.
No wait! Don't move.
What's the matter, Kiba?
Well, I've been thinking about it
this whole time...
About that mysterious
dog whistle.
The mysterious dog whistle?
Yeah... There's an animal that uses
ultrasonic waves
with the same frequency
as a dog whistle...
These guys here.
I see.
You're saying the enemy
is manipulating a bat?
But which bat?
Well, I don't know that.
The more we move in the shadows,
the greater the chance
of our being detected.
In fact, they may already
have spotted us.
Once the crystal sample
we sent to the village is analyzed,
we'll know what steps
can be taken next.
Right now, we have to place
our hopes on Shino's insects.
I have to deliver good news
to Lord Orochimaru...!
I can't have you die right now!
You got that? Don't die!
She's late!
When's she coming back?
Yeah, she should have returned by now.
I should've brought Rinji and Gozu.
Be careful. Someone's approaching
from over that way.
I can't waste time
in a place like this...
Are you all right?
So warm.
This is the Parasitic Insect
we got from Shino, isn't it?
Yes.
What's this?!
What is this hexagonal pattern?!
Well, according the report from
the research team...
It means that even the body fluids of
Shino's parasitic insect have crystallized.
I see...
What's the matter, Lady Tsunade?
I never thought it truly existed...
Do you know something about this?
Yes.
In the past, a rumor had spread
about the existence of a ninjutsu
that crystallizes all materials.
It was said to even crystallize
human blood.
It's a ninjutsu technique
called Crystal Style.
It was said that an entire village
disappeared in one night because of it...
After it happened,
there were no reports by witnesses,
so it was dismissed as rumor.
Then, you're saying that
Crystal Style actually existed?
Yes. If we relate the fact that
there were no witnesses for a long time
and the contact that Kakashi
and the others had,
this could possibly be
one of Orochimaru's group.
Does that mean that Orochimaru
has begun moving?
It's already been three years
since Sasuke left the village.
It's about time for Orochimaru's
next reincarnation.
We should consider that Orochimaru
has begun making preparations for it.
We must use that Crystal Style ninja
as a lead to...
to learn Sasuke's whereabouts!
Damn!
What are you doing?
Guren...
Are you feeling better?
I can't have you disappearing
like that.
Lord Orochimaru entrusted you to me.
What's that?
My mom...
By the way, where's... your family?
My mother... didn't return...
So... I don't have anywhere to go.
Camellias... You like them, right?
This camellia will never wither.
As long as I'm alive.
Let's go.
Milk is the best after training!
Oh?
Thank you, come again.
Sai!
Naruto...
What are you doing here?
I just ran out of ninja tool ink...
This store's ink works really well
for molding my chakra.
I see... Oh?
But if you need a refill of ink,
that means...
Did you get a new mission?
Today's mission is supposed
to be a secret.
I think that when a person tells a lie,
they avert their eyes...
Then I'll do the opposite...
What?
I didn't get a new mission.
So continue your training
without worrying.
O-Oh...
But why are you telling me
that all of a sudden?!
By any chance...
Are you hiding something from me?
Well... Not really...
Really?! Are you sure?
N-Nothing like that...
"Practical use of a lie"?
What's going on here?!
I heard about the mission, Grandma!
Really?
Please! Let me join this mission!
Naruto, we didn't tell you
because we were worried about you.
But...!
I understand how you feel, but even if
you manage to find Sasuke,
you're not skilled enough
to bring him back.
Besides, if you use that new jutsu...
I won't use that jutsu...
Wind Style: Rasen shuriken.
I know more about
my body than anyone.
- Then...
- Naruto!
Can you tell me
why you applied for this mission?
Because...
I know I'm not strong enough
to bring back Sasuke...
But when Pervy Sage said something,
I thought...
The place where someone
still thinks of you,
that's called home...
I believe that
if you think about someone,
your feelings will reach them...
I want to tell him...
that this is the place...
where he can return.
Do whatever you want.
Yes! That's the spirit!
An outline of the mission is...
Is this all right with you,
Lady Tsunade?
That Jiraiya...
he knew this would happen.
Sorry, Tsunade!
Naruto is still in training,
but I received some urgent information.
I'll keep track
of the information.
I'm counting on you.
But... Naruto is still an idiot.
But he has a power
to change people.
Someday, he'll change
into something bigger.
Tsunade, a person grows up
when he's able to overcome hardships.
Protection is important,
but there are some things
that a person must learn on his own.
Don't worry,
he got his guts from me...
So I hope you'll trust him
when the time comes...
Lord Jiraiya...
In this mission... Yamato and
Kakashi are also team members.
And... he's not just a kid anymore...
I really need to use
that jutsu for this mission!
A place to return to...
What's that?
If they hadn't betrayed me,
there would be someone
holding down the fort.
Oh...
Hey... Where are you returning to?
Is there anybody waiting for you?
Hey, let's go, Yuukimaru!
Oh...
Hey... If there was a place where
someone was thinking about you,
that would be home, right?
Huh?
Now, Naruto has found out...
I'm sorry...
That's all right.
I didn't think we'd be able to hide it.
I was surprised he went to negotiate
with the Hokage himself...
But Lady Tsunade is not
a person who gives in to pressure.
She made a final decision to
allow him to join the mission.
So don't worry.
Right. And with everyone on board,
it'll be easier to communicate.
Still... Naruto is late.
I wonder what he's doing?
All right! I kind of feel like
I can do it!
That's the spirit, Naruto.
All right! Gamatatsu, one more time.
All right...
I feel it...
Gamatatsu's chakra!
When he stores it up and spits it out...
Naruto, are you all right?!
I think I just got some sort of clue!
I see!
Things have gotten interesting...
All right! I've got to practice while
the sensation's still fresh...
Naruto!
- Huh?
Oh! Sakura!
Come on! Don't waste your time here!
You smell terrible.
Anyway, why are you so sticky
and worn out?!
Well, umm, this is...
This is really important...
Anyway, everyone's tired
of waiting for you!
Let's go!
W-Wait a second, Sakura!
I need to practice right now--!
No excuses!
Gamakichi, Gamatatsu...
I'll call you again...!
Huh? Sure.
Work hard.
Big Brother, can I clean out my mouth?
Damn!
It looks like the rain
washed away the scent.
Don't be so pessimistic!
They're using bats to observe us.
We know that their base is around here,
or they were forced to stay here
for some reason.
You mean, there's a possibility
we'll have to face them?
Yes...
Oh, you're back...
Oh! You were able to find it!
We're really lucky.
I found a female insect that
survived with her eggs.
And they just hatched.
It's the next-generation of insects.
This insect is resistant to that jutsu?
There's a good possibility that
it has a high tolerance.
However...
The problem is, how many...
Right.
I thought you had some
great countermeasure against them.
Kakashi-sensei, we need more time.
What are you going to do?
I'm going to increase the number
of these insects... all at once.
All right.
We need to have a countermeasure
as soon as possible.
Get on it right away.
All right.
Well...
What about us?
The enemy already knows about us.
They could take action
at any moment.
It's possible they'd leave
to avoid wasting time contacting us
or provoking a fight...
In either case,
our mission is to capture the enemy
and obtain information.
If we lose track of the enemy,
they may pose a
threat to the Hidden Leaf later.
We'll keep searching for the enemy.
Right.
It is time to leave.
Shino, try to catch up with me
very soon, okay?
Of course.
Good luck, Shino!
Secret Jutsu: Insect Cocoon
I'm back.
Guren!
I'm surprised a ragtag bunch
like you didn't betray me...
You know us better than that.
We decided to follow you
when we left the hideout.
Hey, which do you like better,
a red camellia or a white camellia?
Who is he?
He's Yuukimaru,
the one Lord Orochimaru asked us
to take good care of.
Lord Orochimaru said that?
Listen, guys!
Lord Orochimaru gave us
an important mission.
That is, we're responsible for
delivering him safely to the lake.
We can't afford to fail!
But... I know some strangers
are following us from the hideout.
That's just what
I'd expect from you, Guren.
You're already aware of them.
We've done some investigating too.
Tell me!
Right.
The enemy has four people
and one ninja Hound.
Gozu and I identified
ninja Hound paw prints.
Currently three people and one dog
are a couple of kilometers away,
and they're slowly heading towards us.
What?! What's wrong with Kihou's jutsu?
I'm sure Kihou's jutsu made
the ninja Hound's nose ineffective.
Because of that,
the Hidden Leaf Village sent
skilled trackers after the enemy.
As we expected,
the Hidden Leaf Village is our enemy...
What should we do?
I know just the thing.
I don't want them to
follow us anymore.
Find them! I'll defeat them here!
Did you find anything?
No. I didn't find anything.
Me neither.
Well... What should we do now?
We can't lose track of our enemy.
There's no guarantee we'll find them
after we lose track of them.
Since they know about us,
the chances of
a confrontation increase dramatically.
But it's better not to fight at this point.
That's why we had better
find them first.
Kiba, can you sniff out the bats' scent?
Huh?
Hey, just now...!
I have something to take care of.
You stay here and wait for me.
I'll come back here when I'm done.
Don't run around...
Lord Orochimaru asked me
to take care of you...
Stay here and wait for me...
I'll come back to pick you up.
But...
my mother never returned.
Huh?
I wanted to see a red camellia...
But that was not the right one...
Actually, that was a white camellia.
Everyone has left.
Is he talking about his hometown?
Here...
You... This is...!
I have this, so...
You know...
This one is for you, Guren.
You want to exchange it, right?
All right.
Kakashi-sensei, I smell something
at our two o'clock.
All right. We'll take a detour.
All right.
But I never thought we'd have
to slip past a formation of bats...
There's a limit on how far away
a bat can sense something.
There're many things to
shield us in the woods,
so if we keep a certain distance,
it won't be easy for them to find us.
I see...
But we can't get completely out
of their search area...
It's bad luck to say that.
You think I'll die?
I sense him!
This is a ninja's chakra.
Look out!
So you're their leader!
Kakashi-sensei!
Sensei!
Don't, Kiba!
What?!
I missed.
But since Gozu is taking care
of their boss,
it looks like things will be easy.
You've got quite the tracking ability...
It really is unfortunate.
Could it be... Is it them?
Yeah. Probably...
They were in that hideout.
Be careful, okay?
Okay. We're up against three of them.
What should we do, Kiba?
Akamaru and my jutsu are linked.
We've got to defeat one of them first
and reduce their numbers.
And after that?
It would be good if we could
defeat them by ourselves,
but our best bet is to stall for time
until Kakashi-sensei gets here.
Okay.
We need to go after one
of the two in front...
But from what I can see,
we should avoid that masked guy.
He looks like he's hiding something.
Which means...
Let's go, Akamaru!
Fang Over Fang!
Kigiri, smoke screen!
Kiba!
Crap! Poison Smoke?!
I see. Thank you, Akamaru!
But does the fact that
it's not poisonous...
mean that it's just a diversion?
What--?! What's this?!
All the scents around me... are gone?
I see.
They use this to erase traces
of their movements...
This is bad...
Aside from the fact that I can't see,
I can't smell anything either...
Wait. It should be the same
for our enemies as well.
So how do they know exactly
where I am?!
Go, Nurari!
They're going to get me!
Duck!
Hinata?!
Stand back, Kiba!
I'll handle this...
Be careful, Hinata!
I'm not sure how,
but they can move freely in this smoke!
It's all right!
Even if they take away my sense
of sight and smell,
they cannot take away my Byakugan!
All right.
Stand back, Akamaru!
I'm your opponent...
What?! Could it be that even
in this smoke screen...?
That's right.
I can see all of your attacks!
Right here!
Just kidding.
It can't be! I missed?!
That's impossible. But how?!
What's this...?
What strength!
Die!
A Shadow Clone...
Correct.
I can't fight someone as
dangerous as you right away.
You've enhanced your muscles
to their limit.
Did Orochimaru do that for you?
Even if you run away,
you can't defeat me.
From what I can see,
your weapons are your speed
and your strength.
You've got destructive power,
but I specialize in predicting movements.
There's no point in resisting.
You're coming back to the village with us.
I refuse.
It looks like it's begun...
First, I need to see how skilled
my enemies and allies are.
I should take action as well...
How unfortunate.
Even though you can see me,
it's pointless.
Something's surrounding his body...
That's why he's not affected,
no matter how much chakra
I hit him with...
It seems that you use
the Gentle Fist.
I'm a bad match for you.
Do you want that boy to help you?
No. If I call for Kiba,
I'll be playing right into his hands...
Hinata!
Crap! Isn't there something I can do?!
That's it!
This just might work!
Let's go, Akamaru!
Over here!
He's even faster than before...
But his attacks are straightforward!
They're easy to read!
What?!
Will I make it?!
Finish her off, Nurari!
Understood.
Wh-What's this...?!
Once more!
Fang Over Fang!
K-Kiba...?
What is this?!
Hinata!
Sorry I'm late.
H-Hey, are you all right?
Kiba, how did you find me?
Well, I used the spin of
my Fang Over Fang
to stir the air around me.
Once the air circulation improved,
that annoying smoke cleared up.
With my sense of sight and smell back,
we've got the advantage.
You may have done
whatever you wanted before,
but prepare yourselves!
Are you sure you're not the ones
who should be prepared?
Crap! Others were waiting
to ambush us...?
Too bad.
Well, now that we know all about you...
We're going to kill them
with our next attack!
- Understood!
What?!
That's impossible...
This feeling. We're surrounded...
Hey, man?!
Kigiri, a smoke screen! Retreat!
What?!
What the hell are they doing?
It seems that the enemy
has good senses as well.
Shino!
How unfortunate...
I was just about to finish casting
a net around them...
Is everyone all right?
Kakashi-sensei!
We're all together.
Yeah. But Hinata is...
How is it? Can you move?
Yes, somewhat...
Sensei, did you get that big guy?
No...
I couldn't get him...
I see...
They got away from us too.
Then the battle's not over yet.
There should be
another jutsu user nearby...
Oh? How interesting.
I never expected to be pursued by
the Copy Ninja, Kakashi...
It may have been too much
for Gozu and Rinji.
My preparation went well.
I guess it's my turn!
Mother...
Halt!
If things were going according to plan,
he would have left some sign.
I didn't see anything like that...
Man! They better not have forgotten
about the group behind them!
They're not you, you know!
We should assume something happened
to the search team!
- Sai.
- Yes?
Can you do reconnaissance from the sky?
Understood.
Ninja Art: Super Beast Scroll
We've got some time
until Sai comes back.
Wait for me here a while.
We're on duty!
Where do you think you're going?
I've have to pee!
Good grief!
I don't see anything that looks
like the search team.
Camellia?
I'd better take this chance to review
my training some more...
I've forgotten the timing I had earlier.
Huh? What's that?!
You're that kid I saw the other day!
It is you, after all...
What are you doing here?
Not all camellia trees are short.
Some that grow in the wild are this tall.
What are you talking about?
It's me!
You know, from the hot springs!
Everyone has someplace to go home to.
Wherever someone's thinking of you,
that's where you go home to.
Isn't that what I taught you?
Never mind that, though.
You're alone, aren't you?
Where are your friends? Your family?
The white camellias turned... red...
Then they disappeared... All of them.
Just as I thought, you're all alone,
aren't you?
If that's the case,
do you want to come with us?!
Come with us to our hometown.
We're on a mission right now,
but when we're done,
we'll come back for you.
Something just came up. Wait here.
I have to wait...
Huh?!
Where there's someone thinking of me,
that's where I go home to.
Yes, that's right!
Is there anyone thinking of me?
I hope there is.
Could it be that
there's someone thinking of you?
When I had a fever, that person
stayed up all night caring for me.
I see! That shows that person
was thinking of you!
I hope so...
Listen, follow that person!
Don't let that person go!
Uh-huh.
- Shino's insect?!
- Naruto...
Sorry. I'm on a mission...
Huh?! Where'd he go?!
Oh well, it seems he has
a place to go home to.
We found Shino's parasitic insects!
We need to pursue them immediately.
Right.
What took you so long?!
Sorry... I ran into someone I knew.
He's lying, of course.
There's no way he'd run into
someone he knew out here.
He was really there, I'm telling you!
A boy about this tall and...
Humph, you're a pitiful lot!
We're ashamed.
Those guys were quite skilled...
Well, because of that,
we got a look at what they can do.
Kakashi's about the only troublesome one.
The first thing we need to do
is stop Kakashi.
We can't let those guys interfere
with Lord Orochimaru's plans.
I'll see to the rest...
The trap is looking good...
The seed of the Octangular Jade Crystal
placed in the 8 Trigrams
Octagonal Formation.
When this shines, the light
inside the Jade Crystal
will bounce around,
trapped for all eternity.
Blossom!
Crystal Style: Jade Crystal Labyrinth!
Shino?! Can you follow it?!
No problem.
Because the only place where
the Parasitic Insects' net was not complete
was in this ten o'clock direction.
Yeah, looks like we'll have to
determine their objective.
- Then, let's go.
- No, hold on.
What is it, Shino?!
The Parasitic Insects are
behaving strangely...
It's as though they can't
find their way out.
What do you mean?
How do I describe it...?
The Parasitic Insects seem to
have lost all of their senses
and seem to be wandering aimlessly.
Could it be some sort of genjutsu?
They didn't use anything
except physical attacks.
No, it's also possible that
they simply chose not to use it on us.
You mean they kept their secrets hidden?
Hinata, check to see if
there is a Sealing jutsu or a barrier.
Will do.
Byakugan!
What's the matter, Hinata?!
Infinite... images... of us...
The Byakugan was overcome?
Crystal Style: Jade Crystal Mirror
Lovely as always...
Jade Crystal Clone Jutsu
Seems they were sealed
within some sort of barrier.
We thought we had the enemy sealed off
with the Parasitic Insects.
But their outer perimeter was further off,
is that it?
The enemy!
Scatter!
Crystal Style: Jade Crystal Blade!
So it's a jutsu that
crystallizes material...
If it crystallizes the moisture in the air,
there are an infinite number
of weapons to use for attacks.
We can't let this battle draw out.
Kakashi the Copy Ninja...
So that's your Sharingan...
But it's no use.
My Crystal Style cannot be copied.
It's no use! I can't use Byakugan.
I hear you've got good eyes...
But inside my Jade Crystal,
light is refracted.
Your good eyesight works against you.
I have more than just Byakugan!
You want to fight me face-to-face?
What can you do with your eyes sealed?
For a long time...
I've trained as hard I could
so Naruto would acknowledge my ability.
Are you that anxious to die?
I might not be at
my cousin Neji's level, but I...
Concentrate only on the enemy...
Gentle Fist 8 Trigrams 32 Palms!
8 Trigrams 2 Palms! 4 Palms!
8 Palms!
16 Palms!
32 Palms!
It worked!
Crystal Style: Jade Crystal Prison!
What's happening?!
- What happened?
- She just up and left.
The same thing happened with me.
Where's Hinata?
Here's your friend.
Hinata!
Damn!
What the hell is this?!
Crystals...
This is unmistakably the enemy's jutsu.
And it seems huge.
- Sai!
- Right! Gotcha.
Just as I thought.
I think it's about a kilometer across.
One kilometer...
It must be the work of
someone very skilled.
Let's break it down right away.
Hold on a minute, Naruto.
There's a kind of barrier here.
We can't risk the possibility
that it's been rigged somehow...
It's okay. It doesn't react to
an attack from outside.
Kakashi-senpai and the others
must be trapped inside.
If they're only trapped
inside, that's fine.
But if there's a trap set up inside,
this is going to be trouble.
Captain Yamato,
can't we just break through the wall
the way we did when we snuck
into Orochimaru's hideout?
I'm afraid that this crystal possesses
an extremely tight structure
at the molecular level.
Unlike the clay wall,
there are no weak spots.
But... if we went from underground...
Even the ground itself is encased in
crystal. There are no weak spots at all.
It appears very strong.
It doesn't look like we could break it
with a jutsu concentrated at one point.
I agree...
With something this large,
the force would be dispersed equally,
weakening the power of the attack.
Yes. It would have to be
a jutsu that could do
both widespread and powerful damage...
- Sounds like fun!
- You mustn't, Naruto!
I'll be fine, Sakura.
I won't use that jutsu.
Let me try out a jutsu
I've been working on!
Naruto...
Summoning Jutsu!
- Yo!
- We've been summoned!
What? Summoning?
Oh... you can do
the Summoning Jutsu, Naruto?
What are you going to do
with Summoning Jutsu?
Just watch and see!
Here's what we're going to do!
We haven't perfected it yet,
but it's all we've got!
Light sealed inside the Jade Crystal
can never get out.
Don't move!
If you guys follow us around any longer,
your friend will end up
as shattered shards of light!
I'm ready to go.
Okay listen.
Use the timing we worked on earlier
to pour in the chakra.
Right.
What are they going to do?
Well, let's see what they've got.
Let's do it, Gamatatsu!
Mold chakra in your stomach
and inhale through the nose!
Hold it in... then
exhale it out all at once.
Now!
Wind Style: Toad Water Pistol!
What?!
They broke the barrier.
They're not bad.
Guren...
Huh? H-Hey!
Kakashi-sensei!
Humph! Back up, huh?
Is everybody all right?
Naruto, what was that...?
That was collaboration ninjutsu with
a toad. We learned it from Pervy Sage.
Oh...!
Now, it's my turn!
You have nowhere to run!
Here comes that really loud guy!
Hinata!
You! What did you do to Hinata?!
What are you going to do,
Kakashi-sensei?!
We can't attack them recklessly
since Hinata has been taken hostage.
Besides, any small shock will
cause that crystal to shatter.
What a mess.
- Sai, wait for your chance...
- You realize your situation,
- to attack from the sky.
- So just return to the Leaf!
Right!
- Gamatatsu, can you do that once more?
- If you go back, I'll let this kid go.
Yeah... Just one more time...
I must control my Wind chakra
so Hinata won't get hurt.
Freeze!
- Now, Gamatatsu!
- Stop, Naruto!
Wind Style: Toad Water Pistol!
What?!
My Crystal Style can
crystallize all materials.
You need ten more years of experience
before you can challenge me.
Crystal Style:
Burst Crystal Falling Dragon
Gamatatsu, run away!
Is everyone safe?
- Yes!
Damn it! What was that?!
She crystallized your jutsu
and turned it into her own jutsu.
Listen, Naruto! I'll get her attention.
You protect Hinata,
then pull out from the battle!
- What?!
- Hinata's life is the top priority right now.
Right.
It's useless to hide.
Don't forget I have a hostage!
They seem to have given up.
Let Hinata go.
Take me as your hostage instead.
What?!
That's wishful thinking!
Now, Naruto!
Gamatatsu!
I won't let you get away!
Damn it! My clothes are so filthy now.
Guren!
- Are you all right?
- Yeah...
I'm relieved.
I must say, they ran away rather quickly.
Rinji, don't lose track of them!
All right.
All right, Gamatatsu,
you can bring Hinata out now.
Gamatatsu! Gently, gently!
Gently, gently.
Good! Just like that, slowly, slowly.
Oh!
A fly!
Hinata!
You fool! What are you doing, idiot?!
Huh?!
No! Stop! Please stop!
Hinata!
It... stopped...
Damn! We're too late...
Pakkun!
They finished analyzing
Shino's Parasitic Insect.
It appears the enemy's jutsu
was definitely the Crystal Style.
Just as we suspected...
And the analyst confirmed
that several materials from the crystal
encased the Parasitic Insect.
It was true what she said about it
crystallizing all materials.
Sai's Super Beast Scroll was also
crystallized. It's a troublesome jutsu.
Not only the jutsu
itself, but also its effects.
- So, that means...
- Right...
They said that even the biological fluid
of the Parasitic Insect was crystallized.
What?! Then...
And Hinata?
Is Hinata all right, Kakashi-sensei?
Y-Yeah...
We should take her
to the village immediately.
I know! We'll take her to Grandma Tsunade!
She can save her.
Calm down, Naruto!
Hinata!
Sakura...!
Don't worry! She's alive.
- Are you sure?
- What a relief!
Wow, that scared me...
Idiot! How can you be so distracted
by a mere fly?!
Wha--?
What's the matter, Shino?
I was thinking about
my Parasitic Insects...
After it was defeated by
the Crystal Style Jutsu,
the insect shattered in my hand.
And yet, Hinata survived...
True. When we first encountered
the Crystal Style, it shattered.
I wonder what the insect that survived
and Hinata have in common?
I...
Oh, don't move so soon.
When I received the jutsu...
I released my chakra from
my chakra points all at once,
to create a thin film to cover myself with.
I see. That's why, even her Crystal Style
failed to crystallize chakra.
Although you faced the unexpected,
you did a great job, Hinata.
Right...
Only a Hyuga family member could
pull that off. Hinata, you're awesome!
I'm glad you're okay.
Sorry you had to worry about me, Naruto...
You don't need to apologize.
Naruto...
Well, Senpai, what are we going to do now?
Well... Let's see...
I-I'm all right.
Don't force yourself just yet.
I think we were lucky because Hinata
was the only victim of the Crystal Style...
We don't have any countermeasures
against the Crystal Style at this point,
so retreating is the best option for now.
But then, they'll get away!
Right. Unless we stay on the look out,
we'll lose them.
It was so much trouble finding them.
I'm afraid that if we let them go now,
we'll never find them again...
Then here's the plan.
We have enough members,
so let's split into two groups.
Sai and Sakura, you two stand by here
to wait for Hinata's recovery.
- Right!
The others will track them.
But as they move,
they're erasing their scent.
It's impossible to track them,
even for Akamaru.
It looks like they're extremely cautious.
Then how can we find someone
that seems so impossible to track?
We can use their monitoring bats.
However, if we get too close to a bat,
they'll find us first.
So we should be very careful
from this point on.
I see...
It's a pain, but we don't have a choice...
I have something to add.
We also should be careful about the Crystal
Style barrier which Naruto just broke.
Even if you find them, don't attack.
After all, our goal is to investigate them.
- Understood!
Then we're going home.
We'll see you the next time
we need your help.
I'm going home too, Kakashi.
Good work today, Pakkun.
- See you!
- Good bye!
Then let's go, everyone!
Guren!
Is everything all right?
I ran into someone I know.
What?
Who was that?
The man with the headband.
Headband?
Could it be the guy we just met?
How do you know about him?
Well... That's right!
When I went out with Kabuto the other day,
I met him.
The man said he has a place to return to.
And he asked me to return with him,
but I didn't.
Because I thought that was not
the kind of place where I could return to.
Was that just coincidence?
I think so. Because there's no way
they saw us and this kid together.
Well, what should we do, Guren?
There can only be one answer.
Good boy, thanks for coming back.
You're not returning to them.
You're returning to me.
Yeah.
But if he's your friend,
I want to say hello to him.
Where did you see him?
Are you going to track them?
Yes.
Once I decide to go after something,
I stick with it.
That's the way I do things.
Guren, that's a bad habit.
Kabuto!
- It's easy for you to go overboard.
- What?!
I trust you've learned your lesson.
Based on the story I just heard,
I think you were very lucky that
they didn't take Yuukimaru away.
If you lose Yuukimaru...
Guren, you'll lose credibility
with Lord Orochimaru.
Damn it! We shouldn't have taken
our eyes off them, even for a moment!
We have to start tracking them
all over again!
Because of the bats,
we can't move freely!
We have no choice.
Shall we try it the risky way?
Shino, do you have an idea?
Let's change our way of thinking.
Not wanting the bats to find us
is a problem.
But if we assume the bats will find us,
we can take advantage of them.
Huh? What does that mean?
The supersonic waves of the bats
won't work far away.
When the bats sense our presence,
how do they report it to the enemy?
Oh, I get it now!
Now that you mention it, you're right.
Good work figuring it out, Shino.
H-Hold on!
Does everyone understand?
Who doesn't understand?
We're all chunin and jonin.
Oops! There's one genin.
You, are you trying to pick a fight?!
Fine! I understand, too!
Really?
Let's get back to what
we were talking about.
So, what should we do?
Let's try it!
Naruto, make three Shadow Clones,
line them up ten meters away
from each other
and have them run around the grounds!
But if I do that...
Hurry up!
I know!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
But won't the bats' radar detect us
if I do this?!
- That's what we want!
- What?
I found them! That must be it!
Because there's no reason
for the bats to be flying around
during the daytime without
a good reason.
All right! Let's go, everyone!
By the way,
why are we following the bats?
Duh! See, you don't understand, do you?!
Those bats will return to their hideout
to let them know they've found us!
Um...?
That means, if we follow them,
we'll find where the enemy is hiding.
Oh, I get it!
Good grief! You're really slow.
Humph! Don't act all high and might
just because you're a chunin!
Take this!
That stinks!
Heh, heh! Look at yourself!
Sorry, but you guys must stay here
and watch out for the guys
from the Hidden Leaf.
We don't want any distractions.
What?! We can't come with you?!
Rinji, this time
just do what Kabuto says!
All right. If you say so, Guren...
Sorry...
Let's go.
From now on,
the fewer people, the better.
Is there something that
you don't want us to see?
Well, there's something
you don't see very often.
Just wait until you see it.
What's the matter?
Kabuto... I have a bad feeling...
When I took the medicine,
my head really hurt.
Don't worry. Nothing will go wrong.
When something happens,
Guren will protect you.
- Really?
- Y-Yeah. That's true.
Every time I come to this place,
I feel really weird...
What are you going to do here?
Well... I'll perform a little test.
With him and... Guren.
Here, put this on.
If you give him that much medicine...!
Huh?
Are you trying to disrupt
Lord Orochimaru's plan?
Don't worry. Let's start something fun.
This medicine is different from
what you took before.
This medicine won't bring you
any suffering.
You can't go back until you take this.
Guren, it's your turn.
Stop being so bossy all the time!
Crystal Style:
Jade Crystal Hexagonal Column!
Oh!
What? What is going to happen?
What is this...?
Be careful! It's coming!
It's coming?
The test was successful!
It'll appear!
What will appear?!
A Tailed Beast.
Tailed Beast...?
This is the Three-Tailed Beast.