Danzo may be thinking about
conspiring with Orochimaru
and have him attack the Leaf Village
one more time...
in order to force Lady Tsunade
from her position as Hokage...
So, you're saying they want to destroy
the Leaf Village just because of that?
It's not only because of that!
He wants to build his ideal village
after destroying the regime...
and take center stage as Hokage.
The reason Danzo is making
his move now is...
... because he sees it's been three years
since the last attack,
so there has been enough time for
Orochimaru to fully regain his forces.
I think that's also part of it.
Or he may have thought
Orochimaru is more cautious now
because of the failure
of the last attack.
If he acts now, he thinks
the negotiations with Orochimaru...
will proceed more easily.
That means he's going to propose a
village-endorsed collaboration, right?
Yes...
You mean,
Sai's top secret mission...
... is probably to earn Orochimaru's trust
and serve as a liaison between
Danzo and Orochimaru.
He thought the odds of him
running into Orochimaru...
would be high
if he was in our group.
That can't be...!
Then we might have to eliminate Sai.
Eliminate?
Sakura!
Sakura...
That wound is...
Chakra of the Nine-Tailed Fox
must have entered...
through the wound like poison...
That's why...
That's why I'm even more surprised
that Naruto has been able
to endure that chakra.
This... was done by Orochimaru.
Well, it hurts only a little, so...
I'm okay.
Don't push yourself
too hard, Sakura.
I got it...
Let's take a little break.
Sakura is our team's
only medical ninja...
In other words, she's a crucial part
of this mission's success.
I'm all right. If we don't leave now...
I mean, there is a difference between
hurrying and recklessness.
I agree!
Captain Yamato is right!
You are the only medical ninja
in our group
with monstrous strength...
So, you're our precious cornerstone...
I told you that you don't need
to add "monstrous strength"!
- What, what?!
- Shut up!
I'm just complimenting your...
O-Okay, okay...
I apologize!
Naruto!
Since Sai's out, you'll be
my partner for the battle.
Let's work out some combination attacks
while we have time.
Can you come over here for a bit?
Got it.
This is far enough...
All right! So, what are
we going to do first?
But before that...
There's something I need to tell you.
You're the one...
who hurt Sakura, Naruto.
Naruto...
you...
don't... remember anything...?
Then... that bridge...
and that crater...
Yes, you did it...
Sakura didn't want
to hurt you...
so she lied to you.
I'm also responsible
for Sakura getting injured.
And here I was assigned
to Team Kakashi...
for a time like this...
I have special powers...
with which I can control
your Nine-Tails power.
So you don't really
need to worry.
At least...
while I'm by your side.
In other words, I didn't have
to go to the trouble
of telling you the truth
at this point...
But why did I tell you?
There's no doubt that
using that power
might be the fastest way for you
to save Sasuke.
But strength gained
from relying on the Nine-Tails...
is not your true power.
You'll end up tormenting yourself
if you rely on the power...
of the Nine-Tails from here on.
And it could turn into a power
that hurts your friends.
Like what happened this time.
You must have already realized it,
at least vaguely.
But you didn't attempt to stop
the release of the power...
That's because
you were impatient, right?
I will now completely suppress
your Nine-Tails power.
But you're sorely mistaken if you think
that will make you weaker.
You should be sufficiently powerful...
without having to rely on that chakra.
The source of your strength
isn't the Nine-Tails chakra.
It's the power of your own chakra...
that can withstand the formidable
Nine-Tails chakra.
If you want to save Sasuke,
do it with your own power.
If you want to see Sasuke...
do it with your own eyes,
not the Nine-Tails.
And if you want
to protect Sakura...
do it with your own power,
not the Nine-Tails!
Right!
It's okay...
The pain's starting to go away.
Are Naruto and the captain
still at it?
Oh yeah...
Come to think of it,
the thing I picked up earlier...
It's gone...
Here it is...
What's the deal...
with this book...?
And then...
in a scenario like this...
Hey, are you listen—
Both of you, come here a minute!
Oh! That's Sai's...
That's the picture book Sai drew
that we picked up, right?
What's in it?
It kind of...
looks like a story about the two boys
on the front and back covers...
And... it's got the story
of the two boys...
starting from both the front and back
of the book...
and progressing to the middle...
When you look at the book starting with
this boy with black hair...
the next page...
always has the same boy
on the right page...
And there's a different person
drawn on each left page...
See...?
Hmm, it looks like it's a story
where the boy defeats enemies...
Look at this...
After fighting,
he takes the enemy's weapon
and armor...
The positioning is reversed...
but this boy with the white hair
is the same, too.
So it's a story where these boys
grow by battling enemies, huh...?
Just a minute...
If they're defeating enemies
from both sides...
then what happens at the end?!
Let's go.
Yes, sir.
Over there, huh...?
Could it be...?!
It appears my clone
has located the hideout.
Let's get going.
That's...
You're late.
Weren't you supposed to join me
for some new jutsu training
this afternoon, Orochimaru?
Speaking so rudely again...
Don't get so angry.
Instead, I got a little present
for you today...
This is a shinobi from the Leaf,
just like you...
You guys should be able
to exchange...
nostalgic stories of home, right?
How do you do?
My name is Sai.
So you're Sasuke Uchiha—?
Get lost.
It seems I'm the type of person
people tend to dislike...
even if I try to make a smile...
Just recently,
Naruto also expressed
his dislike towards me...
But I get the feeling
I'll be able...
to get along better with you
compared to Naruto.
Sasuke!
I'm sweating...?
It's probably not a good idea...
to joke around
with Sasuke too much.
He's even more troublesome
than I am, you see.
I don't care about that guy.
Join me right now...
Orochimaru.
I've heard a lot about you
from Naruto.
It seems he was looking for you
over the last three years...
There was a guy like that, wasn't there?
Let's go, Orochimaru.
Naruto said he thinks of you like...
He thinks of you like
a real brother...
That's what I heard from Sakura.
I only have... one brother...
the man I want to kill.
Okay, I'll be going, too.
Kabuto, make a Bingo Book using this.
Yes.
Then I'll leave the rest to you.
What's this?
A copy of the list of ANBU members
under the direct command of the Hokage?
It looks like the real thing.
This is the place, huh...?
The entrance is straight ahead
beneath that rocky area.
All right! Let's go!
Just a minute.
Go after you swallow this,
Naruto.
Here. You, too, Sakura.
Now even if we get separated,
I'll know where you guys are
right away.
What is this?
To put it simply, this seed
is a tracking transmitter.
It's a ninja tool that resonates
only with my chakra.
It's the same thing I placed
in Sai's clothing and food.
I get it. That's how you were able
to track him this far.
When did you do that,
Captain Yamato?
Do you remember when
I got out of the hot spring first?
Come to think of it...
Now you know why I went to the
trouble of letting you guys enjoy...
the hot springs and magnificent food
at my expense, right?
It wasn't just
to improve our rapport, huh?
And Lady Tsunade told me...
to take particular caution
regarding Sai.
But never mind that.
Swallow that quickly.
Got it!
All right!
Let's get going, you two.
- Okay!
- Right!
The formation for infiltration will be
in the following order:
me, Sakura, and Naruto.
How will we infiltrate?
We'll go by the book...
and infiltrate from underground
using Earth Style.
First, we'll open up
a pit in this area.
And then, once we've made
a degree of progress digging...
we'll move forward little by little
by digging a tunnel...
heading for that rocky area
where the entrance is.
Right!
Okay, understood.
Okay, let's begin.
We finally did it...
We found you.
Okay, come on inside...
This is your room.
Sorry about this place being
so dull with nothing in it.
The bathroom is in the back.
When you don't have
anything to do...
stay in here nice and quiet.
We'll let you know from our end
if something comes up.
Sorry, but I'll be locking the door
from the outside for now.
After all, you're...
You know, right?
It appears the hideout...
is surrounded by rocks,
just as I thought...
I'll smash this thing right away!
With my Rasengan!
Just a minute!
They'll spot us immediately if you use
a powerful jutsu like that!
Infiltration must be done
quietly all the way...
But how do we do that...?
Here it is!
The harder the rock...
by applying just a little force
to a small crack...
Look, just like this.
Well, that's a successful infiltration,
more or less.
First, we need to find Sai.
This way.
Clear. Let's go.
Now then, if I don't get right
to making the Bingo Book...
Lord Orochimaru will scold me again.
We're almost there...
I knew you'd be here.
I'd expect no less from
the ANBU Black Ops...
under the direct command
of the Hokage.
Now tell us everything.
What's this about?
You jerk!
Why did you betray us?!
You shouldn't make too much
of a commotion here.
That would become troublesome, you see.
- You jerk!
- Naruto!
Here... take this.
It's yours, isn't it?
Thank you.
It was an order
from Danzo, right?
Danzo has teamed up
with Orochimaru...
What are they planning?
With Orochimaru, he's planning to...
once again destroy the Leaf Village...
Isn't that right?
No, that's not—
I can tell right away that
your smile is a lie!
And I can tell right away that
what you're saying is a lie!
Now that you have found me...
my mission is considered
a failure.
I can't handle all of you by myself.
And... if you know that much...
then there's no point
in hiding anything.
You're exactly right.
We're going to crush
the current Leaf Village.
Say what...?!
The real mission I was given was
to gain the favor of Orochimaru...
and create an opportunity for
a collaboration...
in order to crush the Leaf Village.
I also have the duty
of secretly sending...
information about Orochimaru
to Lord Danzo...
In other words, I have also been
entrusted with a mission as a spy.
You've been given such
a dangerous mission...
Orochimaru will definitely betray us...
once the Leaf Village
has been crushed.
It's to make sure we've always
got the advantage.
Danzo wants to make
the Leaf Village his own, huh?
You made preparations
for that all by yourself...
The information I wrote
in black ink
transforms into small animals...
and carries the information out
while protecting itself, you see.
This ability of mine
was valued highly...
and so I was selected
for this mission.
Many people will die, once again...
if things become turbulent
in the Leaf Village!
Do you even know why
you're doing this?!
No idea...
They're my orders, so...
Sai, you...
Let me tell you
one more thing...
Sai is the name I was given
just for this mission...
I'm nobody.
I am a tool for Lord Danzo.
I don't exist.
So no matter what you say
to me, it's pointless.
Then why...
do you hold on to
that picture book with such care?!
The two kids on the cover...
are you and
your older brother, right?
You're holding on to
that picture book with such care...
because it's the only thing
that proves your existence, isn't it?
You haven't been able to discard
your emotions as completely as you say.
Even shinobi can't completely
discard their emotions.
As proof of that...
when I handed
the picture book to you earlier...
You said thanks and took it.
Why does having this picture book
prove my own existence?
The reason why you don't want
to part with that book...
is that you can't forsake yourself
as a younger brother...
Do you know why?
It's because your bonds with
your older brother...
were that important to you!
You don't want to erase the bonds
you have with your older brother...
Sorry, but we had a look
inside the picture book.
Only the picture in
the center-facing pages is unfinished.
Sai, I also know that you're from
the Foundation.
And I also know that
you received special training...
from Danzo in order
to suppress your emotions.
Special training...?
It's the same as the evil practice...
once conducted in the Village Hidden in the Mist,
also known as the "Village of the Bloody Mist,"
in order to take away emotions.
Looking at the flow
of the picture book,
it appears you're
defeating enemies...
and taking away
their weapons and armor...
On the facing pages at the center...
you will end up fighting
your older brother...
You killed your older brother—
No!
I was planning on
giving this to him.
But when I was just about finished
with the picture book, he...
died from sickness.
In the Foundation, there were
many children of broken families...
brought about by battle.
He was one of those children.
I became close with him,
like a brother.
We weren't related by blood...
But he often said nice things
about my drawings.
In this picture book...
what I wanted to show him
most of all...
was what were supposed to be the final
pictures on the facing pages.
But after he died...
I couldn't remember
what I was going to draw.
Unfortunately Sai...
I'll be having my clone
stand guard over you here.
All right!
Now it's back to square one...
We're going to save Sasuke!
I wouldn't bother.
I...
met Sasuke.
Sasuke always has Orochimaru
with him.
You'll just be chopped into pieces...
and used as a test subject
if you pursue him recklessly.
And...
And what?!
Sasuke said he doesn't care
about you...
Sakura said you think of Sasuke like
a brother.
And yet...
For a guy like that, why...?
Why? When nobody is ordering you to?
I used to really hate Sasuke.
Even though, like me,
he didn't have a family...
he was elite and
I was always at the bottom.
But it was actually fun
being with him.
He...
He's the person
who acknowledged me...
more than anyone else.
Sasuke...
is my friend.
It's a special bond
I was finally able to make.
A bond.
Even so...
Even so, with Orochimaru
as your opponent...
It doesn't matter who the opponent is!
If my arms get torn off,
I'll kick him to death.
If my legs get torn off,
I'll bite him to death.
If my head gets torn off,
I'll stare him to death.
If my eyes get gouged out,
I'll curse him from the grave!
Even if I get chopped up
into pieces...
I'll take Sasuke back
from Orochimaru!
We'll go after
I create the guard.
I thought we'd completely
given our pursuers the slip...
I guess I should say...
I'd expect no less from one of
Lord Orochimaru's test subjects...
Kabuto...!
Sai...
Judging from your condition,
it appears you've been captured.
Don't interfere.
If you do...
I won't hold back!
It's futile.
We won't know that until we try!
You've got it wrong.
I'm not talking about that.
Ah! That was impressive...
I guess with three against one,
the odds are against me, huh?
I'll trust you... since it seems
you haven't betrayed us.
Seriously, watching you is just pathetic.
You in particular, Naruto.
Watching you...
What I'm saying is, it's futile
even if you beat me.
People change...
Sasuke isn't the same person he was.
Wha—?!
People change...
Then the same goes for me.
What?!
But there are things
that don't change...
Sai... You...
Bonds...
I want to see for myself...
Sai...
Hold him down.
What's so funny?!
You guys don't know
the real Sasuke...
He's probably done
with his training right about now...
and is in a room deeper
inside the hideout.
Where exactly is this room...?
I don't know, either.
There are several rooms
scattered about in here.
The inner part of the hideout
isn't just one or two rooms.
In that case!
We just have to search
every single one of them!
You're right.
You might find it
if you search at random.
However...
That's also where Lord Orochimaru's
private chambers are.
Thanks for speaking honestly.
No need to thank me.
Are you saying you'll turn
the tables on us?
Yeah.
You jerk!
That's something we won't know
until we try.
Let's go.
We won't know
until we try... huh?
Truly... pathetic...
Now we're going to split up
and search for Sasuke.
Sakura and I on one team.
Naruto and Sai on the other.
If something comes up,
build up your chakra.
It'll be the signal for me
to rush over immediately.
Sasuke...
All right!
Let's go!
For me, you've become...
my closest friend.
Sasuke...!
Sakura...
Thanks...
Sasuke...
Naruto!
Right!
This isn't the place.
Not here, either!
He's not here, either.
He's not here!
He's not here.
Damn it!
Sasuke...
Where are you?!
We've... finally made it this far!
Sasuke...!
Sasuke!
Naruto...!
We're split up
into two search teams.
You should stay calm
and rest a little...
Shut up...!
I can't be resting!
We're so close... to Sasuke...
Damn it...!
The damage I took from using the
Nine-Tails' power still hasn't...
It seems you're awake...
Boy... you really resemble him.
My older brother...
He was talkative and hot-headed...
He had no manners...
and his equipment was—
Well, never mind...
But yeah... like you,
he put his all into everything he did.
When I look at you,
I kind of remember him...
What's the matter?
I remembered... I remembered!
You mean...
This is what I wanted
to show him.
The picture of our dreams...
Now then... Sai...
whose side will you take?
Striking Shadow Snake!
Just as I thought. It seems
you're taking that side, huh...?
Sai or whatever...
I'll stop him here.
Sai, you go find Sasuke.
Hurry!
Okay... I'll find Sasuke...
and save him!
So you came to take back
Sasuke, huh...?
Your persistence is impressive,
but will it really be that easy?
It doesn't make any difference that
you're one of the Legendary Sannin
like Pervy Sage and Lady Tsunade!
I'll defeat you...
and take Sasuke back!
He's not here, either...
It appears something
has happened...
Let's go!
Right!
Striking Shadow Snake!
Rasengan!
What happened to all
your energy from earlier?
Your power...
The power of the Nine-Tails...
There must be more to it
than this, right?
Show me all you've got.
Striking Shadow Snake!
Orochimaru again, huh...?
Ninja Art: Super Beast Scroll
Naruto...
I'll still let you live...
Please dispose of as many Akatsuki members
as you can for me.
Wh-What?!
More importantly,
I've got business with Sai...
So I'll be leaving now.
Where's Sai?
Sai's looking for Sasuke!
We have to do something
before Orochimaru finds him!
I'll have to use up all of
my chakra,
but I'll try searching with
my Multi-Shadow Clone...
Captain Yamato and Sakura,
you guys search that side.
What's this...?
He... was able to remember...
They're both smiling...
Yeah... He truly smiled for
the first time when he drew that.
Smiled from the bottom of his heart.
Wh-What's this...?!
It was in Sai's bag...
This is an assassination list
that has...
an ANBU member's assigned targets
recorded...
It's called a Bingo Book.
Why does Sai have such a thing...?
Look at this...
I get it...
So that's what this is about?
What do you mean?!
Sai...
His mission wasn't to act as a liaison
between Orochimaru and Danzo.
Sai's true classified mission...
was to assassinate Sasuke.
That could never be!
Unlike before, he's now...
What if that was all...
an act in order
to forestall you, Naruto?
The owner of this Bingo Book...
could indeed be capable
of something like that.
Look at this...
This man in the book
next to Sasuke...
He's a Jonin from the Hidden Mist...
and a man who took a hard-line
stance against the Leaf.
Sai... defeated him, huh...?
He couldn't have been
an easy opponent to defeat...
It's quite clear by looking
at each of the people listed...
in this Bingo Book...
Sai was tasked with eliminating those
who posed a threat to the Leaf.
And Sasuke is also
one such dangerous person.
Danzo's goal...
was to eliminate Orochimaru's next
vessel... to eliminate Sasuke.
In order to do that,
Sai attempted
to approach Orochimaru...
He didn't betray the Leaf.
It was for the sake of the Leaf.
That's exactly the kind of plan someone from
a hard-line military faction would devise.
There's no point in going on
about that here...
I felt Sai's chakra earlier.
We need to go quickly.
Who's there?
So, you found me.
But... I've already made
the first move.
What is your objective?
Lord Danzo's objective is
to bury you...
I'm going to...
... take you back to the Leaf!
Although at the beginning,
I came here with the intention
of killing you...
He's the person who acknowledged me
more than anyone else.
I want to protect his bond with you,
the one he's so desperately trying
to protect.
Bond...
You interrupted my sleep
for something like that...?
What was that...?
Sasuke, huh...?
That kid wakes up in
a bad mood, you see...
Impressive...
To think he'd break free
from my jutsu by force...
I found him!
Sakura!
You!
What are you really after?!
How many times do you have
to betray us until you're satisfied...?
Sakura, huh?
Sa... su... ke...
Sasuke...
Naruto, huh...?
So even you were here, huh?
Then is Kakashi also with you?
Sorry, it's not Kakashi...
I'm his substitute.
Team Kakashi will now be taking you
back to the Leaf.
Team Kakashi, huh?
Sai! I knew it!
So he's my replacement, huh...?
So they've brought another
soft-hearted one into the mix.
He said he wanted to protect
the bond...
between Naruto and me, but...
Sai... I thought your mission
was to kill Sasuke.
My classified mission was indeed
the assassination of Sasuke...
But I've had enough of orders...
I now want to act on my own beliefs.
I think Naruto will get me to remember...
my past emotions.
I kind of get the feeling...
it's something very important to me.
I don't know you very well.
But there must be some kind
of reason why Naruto and Sakura...
have pursued you so desperately.
They don't want to sever
their bonds with you...
They're giving it their all
to secure those bonds.
I still don't understand it
all that clearly...
But Sasuke...
you should understand.
Yeah... I did understand.
That's why I severed the bonds.
I have different bonds...
Bonds of hatred with
my older brother...
Numerous bonds...
mislead you...
and weaken the most important desires...
and cherished memories.
If that's the case, then why...?
Why didn't you kill me
back then?!
You think that could
break our bond, Sasuke?!
The reason's simple...
It's not that I couldn't break
the bond with you...
You're one...
who might be able to use the same
Mangekyo Sharingan as mine...
However, there's a condition.
You must kill...
your closest friend.
That's...!
The thought of it was just irritating
to me.
Obtaining power based on
the method he told me.
What do you mean?!
It's not necessary
to explain that to you.
What I can say to you is...
Back then...
You're only alive
because of my passing whim.
He's fast!
When did he...?
Come to think of it,
wasn't it your dream
to become the Hokage...?
If you had the time
to be chasing after me,
you should have spent that time training.
Right, Naruto?
And so this time around...
you'll lose your life...
because of my passing whim.
No way can a guy who can't
even save one friend...
become the Hokage.
That manner of defense...
was correct.
All right!
Chidori Stream!
He's unleashing Chidori
from his entire body...!
I'll stop Sasuke...
with my own power!
Those eyes.
This guy's bad news.
That manner of defense...
was a mistake.
This snake sword of mine
is somewhat special, you see.
It's impossible to guard.
My body is getting numb...
This is...
Is he sending a Chidori
through the blade...?
I get it... It paralyzes you
with numbness after cutting...
while also increasing its
cutting power to the extreme.
Now's your chance, Naruto...
Show him... our...
powers.
What's the matter...?
Why do you hesitate...?
You need my power, don't you?
Now then...
Who do you want to kill...?
Don't... come out anymore!
What are you afraid of?
Shut up...!
I don't need anything like
your power anymore!
Who was the one
who had the nerve...
to ask for my help
at every opportunity?
You should know that you can't
do anything on your own.
Break the seal completely!
I'll grant you all of my powers
if you do.
Get lost!
You...
I see...
So you're an Uchiha...
My, how you've grown...
What are you doing here...?
I can see it now...
So this is your true power?
Who would've thought...
you'd have something like this
inside of you...
To think you'd become able
to see me within Naruto...
That dreadful Sharingan...
So that's the power of
the cursed clan, huh?
It seems this isn't the first time
you've seen the Sharingan.
Then...
you must be
the Nine-Tailed Fox, huh...?
That vision and chakra
more ominous than mine...
It's just like Madara Uchiha's
from back then...
Uchiha...
I don't know anyone by that name.
I never thought...
you would go so far as
to suppress my power...
This might be the end...
But let me tell you... one thing...
Don't... kill... Naruto...
You'll...
regret... it...
Wood Style: Domed Wall!
Why...?
Why don't you get it?!
Soon, Orochimaru's going
to take your body!
If it happens, it happens...
You're still a kid, Naruto.
Revenge is everything to me.
If I can carry out my revenge,
I don't care what happens to me,
or to this world.
Put simply, neither I nor Orochimaru
can defeat Itachi right now.
But if I can obtain the power
to accomplish that
by giving my body to Orochimaru,
then I'll give him as much of
this life of mine as he wants.
The talking's over.
Naruto and Sakura...
I didn't want to get rough
in front of you two...
but I'm going to get serious now.
Captain Yamato!
What do you mean, serious...?
I can't just let those
who abandoned the village just like
Orochimaru run loose.
So I'll do whatever I have to do
to haul Sasuke back to the Hidden Leaf.
The Hidden Leaf, huh...?
I've had enough of you guys...
Don't bother with that jutsu, Sasuke.
Let go of me...
Hey-hey...
Don't talk to
Lord Orochimaru like that...
I've got no reason to stop.
You know what the Akatsuki
are up to, don't you?
We want these guys from
the Hidden Leaf
to take care of the Akatsuki for us.
As many of them as possible...
Your revenge won't turn out well
if the other Akatsuki
get in the way, right?
That's a pathetic reason.
It should increase your chances of
revenge, even by a single percent.
Isn't that right?
Let's go.
Once again...
Once again... I couldn't stop him...
I'm... so pathetic...
Crying...
Crying won't bring Sasuke back home!
I'm here! I'll get stronger with you!
We've got...
close to six months left, right?
And three of us are better than two,
right?
Besides, I'm pretty strong myself.
Thanks...
What did you say?!
Naruto and the others fought Sasuke?!
Yes...
So... then what happened?
I see...
I never thought you'd fail
the special mission...
That's very unlike you...
I have a favor to ask.
A favor, you say?
Yes.
Could you keep me in Team Kakashi
under this name for a while?
That smile on his face...
I've already taken that up
with Tsunade.
But you understand, don't you, Sai?
Emotions create hatred.
And hate creates battles.
That might be so.
But...
He's the person who acknowledged
me more than anyone else.
It's a special bond
I was finally able to make.
Hey! Sai!
We're having a meeting about
our next mission!
Hurry up!
Right, I'm coming.