Uncle Asuma...
Where is Shikamaru?
I thought my mom said
that he left already...
Hey, I told you not to play
on the roof!
- Yes.
- I'm sorry.
Oh, Shikamaru!
Oh hello.
I haven't seen you in a while,
have you been busy?
Yeah.
Come by again.
Say hello to Asuma-sensei
and Choji for me.
Oh yeah, I need to remind Asuma-sensei
to pay off his tab.
Um... Asuma is...
Huh?
He was killed in action.
Then... the one who died yesterday...
This can't be...
Shikamaru...
It's almost dinner...
It's okay. I don't feel like eating.
Shikamaru.
Come with me.
You're pretty forceful today.
You can't win that way.
Shut up.
Akatsuki, huh?
Are they... strong?
Yeah.
So, what are you going to do?
If Asuma couldn't defeat them,
then there's nothing you can do.
He was a remarkable man.
Yeah.
He wasn't great at shogi, though.
Are you sure about that?
Stop criticizing my moves.
I'm not talking about that.
What are you going to do?
Well, I guess you're not stupid
enough to walk to your death.
As a parent, that's a relief.
The last thing I want is my son's funeral.
You're doing well and I'm proud to be
your father.
You're sharp and you have talent.
You're capable of shouldering
the future of the Hidden Leaf.
But...
Asuma died.
What are you trying to say?
The truth.
You're pissing me off with all this talk!
Fine! So I'm just a useless coward!
No.
Then what?!
Just let it all out.
Let out all your sadness,
fear, and anger...
and everything else!
And it all starts from there...
I'll always be here for you.
Hello!
Hey!
Shikamaru!
Hello...
It must have been hard to handle
what happened to Asuma...
I don't know what to say...
Choji is also...
Shikamaru.
You...
You want to see Choji, right?
He's by the hill in the back.
Sheesh!
Looks like you dug deep.
Huh?! Shikamaru!
Your mom told me to give you this.
So, when?
We're going to do it, right?!
What am I supposed to do?
Umm... are you telling me...
Then, can I ask you to
do something for me?
Yeah!
Shikamaru!
We're going to do it, right?!
Sorry I'm late...
But I won't hesitate anymore.
What we're about to do is
incredibly risky...
Please look after us...
Asuma-sensei...
Asuma... Sensei.
Are you ready?
Let's go, Shikamaru.
Yeah.
Wait!
Fifth Hokage...
Where are you going?
The mission order is still active,
isn't it?
We've formed a new team and are
heading out to execute the mission.
I will not permit such selfish behavior!
Shikamaru, I will have you
join the new unit I form.
You will go after we've formulated
a proper plan.
You can just send support for us later.
Our team has already come up
with a plan.
Enough!
Asuma is dead.
You're a three-man squad now.
Asuma is with us.
Are you planning to avenge him
in this battle?
It's not like you.
Do you want to die in vain?!
We are not that stupid.
I have no intention to die...
But...
I can't just back down without
doing something about this.
I don't want to live a pathetic life
like that.
Grow up...
Death is a constant companion
to a shinobi.
This keepsake lighter.
When I have this, it's as if
Asuma-sensei is nearby...
It's as if he is protecting us.
It just feels that way.
Until this battle comes to an end,
this lighter will always be with us...
Get real.
You're only a three-man cell.
A squad requires four members—!
It's fine if there are four, right?
- Huh?
- Kakashi-sensei?
I will join as the captain of Team 10.
How about that?
Kakashi, you...
They'll go whether you try to stop them
or not.
But if I go, I can supervise them...
I will not allow them to go overboard.
Fine. Do as you wish!
All right!
Kakashi-sensei...
How about Naruto?
Your right arm...?
Don't worry about him.
He doesn't need my help anymore.
Plus, there is another captain
with them.
Naruto...
Well then, Team Asuma, let's go!
- Right!
- Yes!
So...
How is Naruto's training going?
Well, according to Kakashi-sensei,
it seems like he's finally
getting the hang of it.
But he said it'll take
a little longer to complete it.
I see...
Now that Kakashi-sensei
has joined Team 10,
Team 7, our team, should support them
given our close alliance with them...
right?
You're sharp, as expected.
But, we don't know when
Naruto will complete his new jutsu.
Wouldn't it be better to
send another team?
Sakura!
Tell Yamato...
To have Naruto complete
his new jutsu in 24 hours!
If not, I will send another team
as reinforcements!
Yes!
So, it's starting.
Shikamaru... Let's hear your plan first.
Now that you have joined,
I want to change the plan a bit.
I got it.
Please explain.
I will explain by dividing it
into several scenarios.
Make sure all of you listen carefully.
The sealing of the Two-Tails
is now complete...
Finally!
We're going to
Hidden Leaf Village. Hidan.
Hidden Leaf Village...?
Kakuzu, Hidan, if you are going
to Hidden Leaf Village.
- I'll give you one warning...
- hmm.
There's a guy named Naruto Uzumaki
who's a Jinchuriki.
- If you see him you should be careful...
- Hmm.
Hey hey hey!
Don't assume I'm the same as you,
Deidara!
You're the one who got his arms
stitched up by Kakuzu!
It's better than his head...
Hey! Hey, Kakuzu!
Whose side are you on?!
Aren't we teammates?
- That's why you--!
- Shut up Hidan!
Let's just go.
I've been sitting still for three days!
I'm about to lose it...
Here I come, bounty.
Hey, where are you going, Kakuzu?
The collection office is this way!
Are you stupid?
What?!
Our target is the Jinchuriki.
There's no point in returning there
only to walk into an ambush.
Let's take a different route to
the Hidden Leaf Village.
It has been three days.
The Hidden Leaf Village should have
retrieved that bounty by now.
Well, that's right.
Oh yeah...
What?!
That scar is embarrassing.
Cover it up with this!
Hey! This is my Headband.
Oh, you actually picked it up for me...?
Kakuzu! You're pretty nice!
Shut up Hidan! Hurry, let's go!
Oh! Hey! Wait! Hey! Kakuzu!
Tell me the truth, you like me, right?
Keep talking and I'll kill you.
Don't be shy...
Kakashi-sensei, take this...
please use it
when there's an opening.
I'll let you keep it.
I got it.
I'm impressed at how much you
observed about your opponent
from just one encounter.
But the other one's power
is still unknown...
On top of that, you've readjusted
the plan to fit the new member...
It's remarkable.
That's the plan I developed with
the limited information I had.
After you memorize the plans,
simulate them in your head
three times or more.
The success rate of
the plan highly depends
on whether or not
you do image training.
Yes.
Okay!
S-Such power...
All right. It's almost complete.
And now... I can catch up to Sasuke.
Indeed, you can...
However, you must be wary of
Sasuke's Fire Style.
Huh?!
I guess I should explain
the comparative strengths of the
five great nature transformations.
Comparative strengths?
Basically, it means the five
chakra natures of Fire, Water,
Earth, Lightning and Wind
are all connected, each with
their own strengths and weaknesses.
It's easier to explain with a diagram.
There are five main
chakra nature transformations.
First you draw...
- ... the five in a circle.
- Right.
For example, let's take Fire...
I'll draw its strength
and weakness in this diagram.
Fire is strong against the Wind next to it
but weak against Water on
the opposite side.
Each of the five natures has
strengths and weaknesses
in relation to the others.
Naruto...
your Wind Style jutsu is weak against
Sasuke's Fire Style jutsu.
Huh?!
Only Water can beat Fire.
Why can't Wind beat Fire?
Think of it this way:
wood burns hotter when the wind blows...
but fire can be put out when
water is poured on it.
That means if you strike
Sasuke's Fire Style jutsu...
with a Wind jutsu of equal strength,
you'd actually make his flames
even bigger.
However, look at the Wind's
other relationship.
Wind is weak against Fire,
but it is strong against Lightning.
In other words, your new jutsu...
will be strong against Sasuke's
Lightning Style Chidori.
Naruto...
It's a good thing your chakra nature
isn't Earth Style.
So I'm a good match-up against Sasuke...?
Yes, only Wind can defeat Lightning.
No, that's not what I meant.
Hmm?
I mean only the power of Wind
can help Fire
by fanning its flames and
making it even stronger.
Yeah, that's right...
I found them.
There's no mistake... they're headed
straight for the Hidden Leaf Village.
That was close!
Did they notice?!
I think it's okay.
Just as I thought. They're taking a
different route to the Hidden Leaf.
They're in the 2 o'clock direction.
We will run into them in ten minutes.
All right. Let's go!
- Hidan...
- Yeah...
- Damn it!
- It's a paper bomb!
Kakuzu!
I hardened my arm.
I'm not injured.
Forget that, watch out for the shadow...
I won't fall for it twice!
Hidan, look up!
It's another paper bomb!
Hidan, dodge it!
It didn't explode?!
They got us...
Shadow Possession Shuriken Jutsu...
Success.
I can't move.
You bastard... I dodged the shadow,
so how did you...
The thing I threw is a chakra blade.
I bet you know that it's made
from a special metal
that absorbs the user's
chakra characteristics.
Kakuzu, what is he saying?
Idiot! Shut up, Hidan.
Due to the chakra absorbed,
it exhibits power based
on the user's jutsu.
Basically, the chakra blade itself
is exhibiting my Shadow Possession Jutsu.
That chakra blade is a memento
of Asuma, the man you killed.
35 million ryo, huh...?
He's pretty clever.
Well, let's finish this.
Hey!
Why the hell have you been so quiet?!
What are you doing getting caught in it,
too?!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Seriously, aren't we
totally screwed here?!
Screwed?
According to my plan,
it was over the moment I caught you.
You did a good job...
You bastard...
I'm not going to mess up
the order this time.
Damn it!
I know your face now!
No matter what happens to me,
I'm going to kill you.
You're stupid, aren't you?
Kakuzu! Dodge it!
All right!
Just what I'd expect
of the Akatsuki.
They all use insane abilities!
You said we were finished,
but you still don't know
what I'm capable of.
So you kept your distance when you
made your next move.
You're intelligent, unlike my partner.
But even if you analyze the fight,
it doesn't mean everything
will go as planned.
Kakuzu! What do you mean
"unlike my partner"?
Just as I said, you idiot.
Damn it! My body...!
Kakuzu, do something!
I can't believe you're forcing me back.
Crap!
Now, Choji!
Spiky Human Boulder!
Kakuzu!
What's going on?
I knew it.
It's just as Raido-senpai said...
It might be a jutsu
for hardening his body.
That's his power...
Nice analysis...
That's right.
No physical attack will work on me.
It can't be...
You snuck up behind me...
without me sensing you...
Too bad...
What?! What's up with that?!
I thought physical attacks
weren't supposed to work on you!
I saw everything.
I saw the jutsu you use
for hardening your body.
Judging from how you formed
your seal earlier,
I'd say you've got an
Earth change in chakra nature.
In that instant...
you read the speed of my seal?
And using Lightning Style at this level...
I see!
You're... Sharingan Kakashi...
Earth is weak against Lightning...
We're not a good match-up...
You're finished.
Kakashi-sensei is amazing, as expected!
Now all that's left is the other one!
In an instant...
Just what I'd expect from Kakashi-sensei!
Yeah. We needed to take care
of the mortal one first...
It'd be trouble, after all.
Are you okay, Shikamaru?
This isn't looking good.
Kakashi-sensei!
His Shadow Possession
has reached its limit, huh?
He nailed your heart in one shot?
How can you get hammered
right off the bat like that?!
For crying out loud...
You're next.
Oh, boy.
And here you acted all cool and
said, "You're finished."
What's going on...?
I'm sure I didn't miss the vital spot.
All right, let's settle this right now.
I intend to!
Hey, Shikamaru.
What's happening?
And why didn't he die even though...
the Lightning Blade nailed him?
Who knows...?
But with these guys, nothing would
surprise me at this point.
Oh, boy...
I can finally move...
What are... those?
Now... shall we do this, Kakuzu?
Sure...
Lord Jashin! Watch me!
I'm going to get serious! I mean it!
I'll rip out their guts!
Kakuzu! Hey! Hey! Hey!
One of them died right after
our verbal assault!
God, you really stink!
Since one of the masks that
came out of his body died...
it must've been that mask I hit
with my Lightning Blade earlier.
Hidan, stand down for a while.
I'll take care of this.
Hey... Just a minute!
We've been getting our asses kicked
the whole time and it's ticking me off.
Let's go with the usual.
Wind Style: Pressure Damage!
Choji! Watch out!
No way...
He even attacked his own partner?!
I get it! He's taking advantage
of the immortality!
Here he comes, Choji!
Lightning Style: False Darkness!
Are you okay?
Well... somehow, I guess...
These guys... are powerful...
That masked guy in particular...
But no one should be able
to use such high-level jutsu
unless they are compatible with
that person's own chakra nature.
And he uses Earth, Wind and Lightning...
Fire Style: Searing Migraine!
He can even use the Fire Style?
Choji! Ino! You guys okay?
Yes!
Yeah...!
You're pretty good, just as I thought...
Kakashi-sensei!
Are you okay?
Yeah...
That being said,
I've used the Lightning Blade four
times while my Sharingan is active...
I can't afford to just sit back.
They're using great combos.
And here Kakashi-sensei definitely
nailed him with the Lightning Blade...
I'm sure I crushed his heart.
He really should be dead.
But what I killed was one
of the monsters
that came out of his body.
We can assume that it died
in place of his real body.
It was the same when he broke
my Shadow Possession Shuriken Jutsu...
Something that looked like
a heart was attached
to the arm that had been
separated from his body
and it was moving on its own.
What... does that mean?
If you include his real body,
each monster that came out of his body
has a heart, and they are all his.
In other words,
it means he probably has five hearts.
What?!
How can he...?
But he just lost one of them to
Kakashi-sensei's Lightning Blade.
Then that means we have
to crush his other four hearts
in order to take him out completely?
Yeah...
You're very perceptive.
That's exactly right...
I took each of these hearts
from shinobi I once fought.
I can always replenish my stock...
with your hearts.
I get it...
By connecting his chakra network
to the others' hearts,
he incorporates their chakra natures
as well, huh?
No wonder he's able to
use several different natures.
By the way, does the Hidden Leaf Village
bury its dead?
Burials are such a pain, you see.
I bet Kakuzu's going to say,
"We're going to dig up the body
and exchange him for money."
And here I thought I could have
some fun with that bearded jerk...
He was nothing special, after all.
You're one to talk, especially since
you got your head chopped off...
Shut up. You keep quiet!
I'm sure you guys are intent
on revenge.
But you're all too weak for that.
You all look like kids.
I guess you were his students, huh?
Well, with trash like him as your teacher,
no wonder you're all so pathetic.
Don't insult Asuma-sensei!
Choji.
Beautiful loving bonds between
student and teacher, huh?
Heh, how stupid!
You jerk...!
Choji!
What's so great about an idiot like that?
Fatty?!
Choji!
You idiot!
What's the point of getting stirred up
by such an obvious trick?!
I-I'm sorry...
Choji!
Die.
Little girl...
Shikamaru!
You small fry.
Die.
It's over for you, too.
Oh, boy.
How pathetic...
Are you okay?
Y-Yeah...
Somehow.
How pathetic. You're a disgrace.
You, too. How could you not realize
it was a shadow clone?
Uh-oh... You saw that?
Shikamaru... How shall we fight?
Let's separate those two.
Our best plan would be to
attack them separately.
Yeah.
After we eliminate their ability
to do combo attacks,
we'll focus on destroying
his four remaining hearts.
If we're going to do that,
we'll need someone to stall Hidan...
I'll do it!
I have the most chakra
stored up right now.
And I won't be much use
in a direct assault...
I'll use my Mind Transfer Jutsu...
No! The Mind Transfer is
primarily a combo jutsu
used after stopping an opponent's movements
with my Shadow Possession.
If you miss,
you won't be able to return to
your own body for several minutes.
It's too risky!
I'll do it.
- Huh?
- What?!
We'll separate them after I restrain him
with my Shadow Possession Jutsu.
But how do you plan on restraining him?
We'll need a diversion, either way.
Then I'll take care of that.
That won't do, either!
You're finished if he lands a single
scratch on you and gets your blood.
It'll be just like before.
It'd be a bad move for us to
approach him and attack!
Choji.
You and Kakashi-sensei will take on the
masked one. Build up your chakra for it.
Right!
I'll capture him by myself.
And...
I'll handle that role!
Got it. I'll leave it to you, Shikamaru.
Take this.
Right...
That again?!
Are you that afraid of my powerful scythe?
I'm your opponent.
Hey-hey-hey!
Sneaking around like that from a distance?
How pathetic!
Too slow!
What--?!
He picked it up...
and threw it with his shadow?!
You wish!
If I just focus on the shadow,
a jutsu like this is worthless!
What?
I'm not just sneaking around
from a distance!
The Shadow Possession Jutsu
is a success.
You... jerk!
Go, Shikamaru!
Leave this to us!
We're counting on you!
Right...
Let's take a nice little walk...
just the two of us.
Hey, where are we going?
Are you trying to separate me
from Kakuzu?!
You... jerk!
Shouldn't someone go with him?
You're really underestimating Hidan.
And to think that kid, Shikamaru or
whatever his name is...
could have become
a high-value bounty someday.
Now...
he's dead.
But your decision was the right one.
I'm... powerful.
There's a great difference in battle
experience between us.
Seeing those headbands reminds me
of the first Hidden Leaf shinobi
I ever fought...
The First Hokage.
What?
How old is this guy?!
Are you really immortal?
No. True immortality doesn't exist...
I simply prolong my life.
I maintain a stock by taking
the hearts of those I kill
before my own gives out.
So you won't let me get away, huh?
This shadow technique...
only lasts about five minutes, right?
And it's just the two of us...
That works out well for me, too. You idiot!
I can stock five hearts including my own.
Kakashi... I will take your heart to
replace the one you took from me!
So the Fire Style...
and Wind Style masks merged, huh?
He's trying to force me
into an open area
where he can shoot me down.
Is that your idea of hiding?
Not again!
Water Style: Water Wall!
Fire amplified by Wind Style...
can't be extinguished with
Water Style alone.
Looks like I'll have to confront him
at close range, after all.
Your heart... is mine.
Die!
How do you like that?
It's an intoxicating pain, isn't it?
How worthless...
Lord Jashin must be disappointed...
Kakuzu must be about done by now, too...
Wh-What did you do?
It seems...
he made it just in time...
Time to go...
Not deep enough?!
You jerk...
Why are you alive?!
I just pretended...
I was dead.
The blood on that weapon... isn't mine.
It's your partner's blood.
I-Impossible...
Yes, it is possible.
Your own blood was used
for your partner's ritual.
Shikamaru knew his opponent's ability
utilized blood, after all.
He'd prepared capsules
of blood in advance.
What does that mean?
Anyone would've been fine...
If given an opportunity,
we needed to get your partner's blood.
In this capsule, you see...
It can't be...
When did you have the chance?!
When I pierced you with
my Lightning Blade...
I took your blood at the same time.
Heh. That was... our plan all along.
You bastard...!
No way...
That kid... He planned that far ahead...
That's about the size of it.
You should've handled him
more carefully...
You guys really underestimated him.
There's no way he would
let the information
that cost Asuma his own life
go to waste.
You people who take lives without
a second thought
could probably never understand
how he feels.
Kakashi-sensei!
Are you okay?
Yeah... somehow.
Slowly! Make sure not to damage
the vessels.
I'll treat you immediately
with my medical ninjutsu.
The treatment can wait!
What?!
Here they come!
Expansion Jutsu!
Super Slap!
What?!
Two of my hearts... gone.
It's been a long time...
since that happened...
Even I can tell,
and I'm not all that bright...
You've used it so many times already.
Any idiot could figure out your jutsu
after seeing it so many times.
What did you say?
It seems your jutsu isn't as strong
as it was before.
I didn't even need five minutes...
I can move!
The endurance of your jutsu power
and its effect
gradually decreases each time
you use it.
Basically, the longer you use it,
the weaker it gets.
You're just about out of chakra,
aren't you?!
You won't get away... this time.
Here he comes!
- Right!
He's fast!
Damn it!
I can't move...!
Kakashi Hatake...
I was going to replace the hearts
I lost with yours...
But I've changed my mind...
I can get more hearts
anytime I want, after all...
Die!
Wind Style: Rasengan!
Water Style: Ripping Torrent!
Hurricane Vortex Jutsu!
Sorry... we're late.
Perfect timing...
I've never seen you this beaten up.
Sorry about that.
This enemy... must be pretty strong.
More strange people...
And he looks pretty banged up already...
Naruto, are you okay?
Where is Shikamaru?
He's a little ways from here,
fighting the other one.
I want two of you to
head towards Shikamaru.
Preferably, a long-range fighter
and a medic.
I'll take care of it.
All right!
Sai and Sakura follow Pakkun's lead
and support Shikamaru!
Yes!
Yes.
Huh! What's this disorganized mob
planning to do?
Now there are more hearts for me
to choose from.
From here on, this one's mine.
Did you... complete it?
No... only about 50 percent.
I see...
But...
Well, just watch.
Naruto is not the same person
he used to be.
Multiple shadow clones...
I see... You are the
Nine-Tails Jinchuriki.
What's the situation?
What are the enemy's abilities?
The enemy is two Akatsuki.
As I said before,
Shikamaru is fighting one of them...
and the other one is in front of us.
This guy has the power to split.
Those two masks on the shoulders
split from the torso.
Each mask has a separate heart
and moves independently.
He originally had five hearts.
He lost two and has only three now.
What do you mean?
We've killed him twice already.
We need to kill him three more times
to finish him off.
Plus, he's a mid-to-long-range fighter
and can use jutsu from multiple
chakra natures.
No wonder you were
having a hard time...
Naruto!
I heard it!
It's no use charging in recklessly!
You can only make shadow clones?
You can't beat me with that.
Based on his attack speed
and fighting style,
I need at least three shadow clones
to distract him.
He's gathering experience from each
clone and processing it in real time...
and using it to simulate the battle.
His ability to use
shadow clones has advanced.
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
What's... that?
Such a... high-pitched sound
from his chakra!
What... are they...?
All right... To test its ability, let's
collide it with my Rasengan. Get ready.
What?! If we do that,
what's going to happen?
If the jutsu is near completion,
my Rasengan will have no effect.
The Fourth...?!
What... is that jutsu...?!
If I get hit by that... then I'm...
definitely doomed.
Wind Style: Rasen Shuriken!
This is the end!
- Yes!
I'll back him up, too!
No!
Don't get close to Naruto,
or you'll also get caught!
So this is the power of
the Nine-Tailed Fox's Jinchuriki...
A fitting jutsu for a monster.
What?!
Failed...
Always the unpredictable ninja.
He did it again...
- Yamato!
- Right!
Damn!
Damn it!
Oh, acting all tough...
That's so like Naruto.
Since it was called Rasen Shuriken
or whatever,
I thought you'd let it fly...
Do you really have to run up
and hit them with it?
Hey! When it hits the target,
it causes some serious damage!
It's called the Rasen Shuriken, but...
you must hit at point-blank range.
That's why this jutsu relies on
shadow clones as a diversion.
The duration of this
new jutsu is too short.
It only lasted a couple seconds.
Exactly.
You'll never hit the target with that.
Not against someone like him.
That Nine-Tailed kid's jutsu...
It seemed very powerful...
but I'll be safe as long
as I keep my distance.
As long as I avoid close-range combat
and watch the one using that jutsu,
I have nothing to fear.
Please let me try one more time.
You're against the Akatsuki!
If you do the same thing,
he'll just dodge it again!
If he detects our diversion,
we're done for.
Let's fight him together...
That's true...
As it stands, it's five against one.
There's no need to take chances.
So... what's their next move?
Kakashi-sensei...
Do you remember what
you told me when I was training?
You said you believe
I'm the only shinobi
who can surpass the Fourth Hokage.
Naruto...
I know teamwork is important.
I also know that
this is a very risky path.
Even so, I want to take this risk alone.
If I can't overcome this on my own,
I'll never be able to truly grow.
So please...
Please...
don't take this path away from me.
Yamato, what do you think?
Yeah...
You haven't even seen it yet,
after all.
You haven't seen how
he's a completely different Naruto now.
Then it's settled...
Go, Naruto.
Right!
That kid's going to attack again...?
Just to be safe, I should switch
to a long-range attack style.
He didn't just change
the shape of his body.
He's built up quite a bit of chakra.
It's to counter Naruto's jutsu.
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Here he comes...
It's ready!
I can ignore the diversionary
shadow clones behind me.
I just need to aim for the original.
I've got nothing to fear if
I can just smash that jutsu...
What?! That was a shadow clone?!
Huh?!
He mixed himself in with
the diversionary clones!
Eat this!
That was an extraordinary amount
of attacks.
I couldn't even count them all
with the Sharingan.
What a jutsu...
- Awe...
- Awesome.
Naruto...
You...
You... finally...
All right... I did it.
If you had believed in Lord Jashin,
you may have gotten a helping hand
in your time of need.
If you'll believe in Lord Jashin
from now on...
to mark your conversion...
As if I'd forgive you! Idiot!
I don't care about his forgiveness.
Shadow Pull Jutsu!
You...
Wh-What are you doing?!
Just watch...
What?!
What happened?!
When did you do this...?!
I had this trap prepared beforehand.
So he didn't just separate us on a whim,
but he purposely lured me here?
Then... this was all his plan!
When you curse someone,
you dig two holes.
You know what that means?
What?!
If you curse to kill someone,
you also get killed in retribution,
If you're going to curse someone,
you seal your own fate in the process,
You cursed and killed my teacher.
Don't think for a second I'm going
to let you die an easy death.
This hole is your grave.
I am not going to die...
Even if my body is dismembered
into pieces and only my head remains,
I'll drag myself out of here
and bite your throat out!
What?
Deer?
These woods are a special place
in the Land of Fire.
Only members of our clan are permitted
to enter. No one else ever comes here.
Our clan will watch over you
for all eternity.
You did a great job, Shikamaru.
Yeah...
My Will of Fire... is now yours.
You... why are you lighting that?
It's the Will of Fire...
the will to protect our village.
Goodbye... Sensei.
This is a sorry state...
How dare you do this to me?!
Lord Jashin will punish you for this!
A greater judgment will be
handed down by Jashin himself!
That doesn't scare me.
We believe in different things.
I believe in the Will of Fire.
My "God" isn't some pathetic creature
like Jashin.
Now... I will hand down judgment...
You bastard...!
I told you, judgment will be handed down
to you by Lord Jashin!
And I'm the one who'll carry it out!
All I need are my teeth to kill you!
I'll chew you to pieces!
We found you!
Reinforcements? You're a little late.
Wh-What?!
Shikamaru...
You defeated an Akatsuki by yourself?
You're more impressive than I thought.
I guess...
I just had to do this myself,
no matter what.
That's right...
Naruto, are you all right?
Okay, Choji keep him still like that.
Right now, I can only give
emergency first-aid.
But, who would've guessed...
that the original was hidden
among the clones.
You're not up to
Shikamaru's level...
but you're pretty sharp yourself, Naruto.
Don't compare me with Shikamaru...
Still, I'm impressed you could use
that new jutsu three times.
Even during training,
two was the limit.
His quick thinking in making
his next move after failing only once...
His unshakable confidence...
Naruto has truly become strong.
Perfecting, to this level,
the jutsu that even the Fourth Hokage
could not master...
Looks like it's time to put
our trust in the next generation.
He's surpassed me...
Do you feel it?
You're the one Naruto always
envisions before him.
You are making him steadily stronger...
Isn't that so, Sasuke?
Senpai, we should get going...
Yeah...
How could I lose...
to a bunch of brats...?
Well, you're someone who's fought
against the First Hokage...
so we may seem like kids to you.
But to us,
you're just a washed-up old man.
That's why you're on the verge of death,
groveling at our feet.
One after another,
a new generation will succeed us.
Good work, everyone.
The immediate danger has passed,
but the Akatsuki still remain...
Do not let down your guard.
Naruto, those wounds are...?
Yeah, my badge of honor.
We did some emergency treatment...
Just in case, get it checked thoroughly
at the Leaf Hospital.
Nah, I don't need...
Yes, you do!
Don't worry, Master.
I'll take full responsibility
and take him there.
- Got it, Naruto?
- Yes!
All right then, I order you
to take a few days off.
Rest your minds and your bodies.
Dismissed!
Did you notice?
Yes.
You mean about Naruto's wound?
I wonder what it could be?
I've never seen anything like it...
What's the status of the Akatsuki body
Kakashi brought back?
It's already been sent to the
Autopsy Division.
We must notify
the supervising Jonin about this...
Summon Kakashi and Yamato
to the coroner's room.
The autopsy is not complete yet...
But as we examined the corpse,
we've learned something about
Naruto's new jutsu.
The damage this fellow sustained
was caused by
something totally different
from the usual barrage of hits.
What do you mean?
Every chakra network connecting
his body cells has been severed.
His chakra network...?!
Yes. A condition like this
is usually unimaginable.
Wind Style: Rasen Shuriken...
is this powerful...?
It's less like a standard attack
and more like a poison.
A microscopic attack that inflicts
damage at the cellular level...
I'm assuming that the Wind chakra
transformed into countless
microscopic blades...
attacking all the cells
within his body.
What a jutsu...
Hmm... Poison...
Rather than the number of attacks,
it's like countless strikes
focused into one
And the user of the jutsu, Naruto, is...
That's the problem.
I see...
Kakashi... This new jutsu...
The Wind Style: Rasen Shuriken.
Forbid Naruto from using it again.
It's that serious...?!
The same condition afflicts
Naruto's right hand.
Although it's not nearly
as bad as this one.
If he continues using
this new jutsu,
Naruto will lose his ability
to mold chakra.
If the cells are disconnected
from the body's chakra network,
even my medical skills
won't cure him.
Be certain to emphasize that
to Naruto.
Is it okay to be up and about?
Shikamaru!
Your shogi partner is gone...
You were Asuma's favorite,
so I imagine you must be lonely...
He taught me so much,
from important lessons to silly things...
Shogi was one of them.
I'd be lying if I said
I didn't feel lonely.
But I can't afford to act
like a kid anymore...
I can't keep crying.
I always complain about
what a bother things are,
and because of that,
I messed up a lot as a kid.
And each time,
Asuma was there to protect me...
Maybe that's why...
although he was such
an evasive and odd teacher...
To me, he was the coolest adult I knew.
And that's why...
this time it's my turn.
When that child is born,
it'll be my turn to be the teacher
who protects them.
So I've have to become
a cool grown-up too.
Thank you...
You know Dad...
Unlike Asuma, you're good...
Hmm... A Climbing Silver?
What you'd call a necessary sacrifice
to protect the king
against a higher opponent.
If you escape there,
then a knight will come here.
So whichever the pawn runs to,
your bishop will be supported...
That knight sure is a nasty piece...
Well, if you're to compare
a Hidden Leaf ninja to shogi pieces,
I'm a knight.
What does that mean?
Asuma said so.
I guess Asuma knew
your personality very well.
Then, who would be the king?
The children who will one day carry
the future of the Hidden Leaf...
They are the "King".
You know what it's all about.
All right, checkmate.
You still don't have what it takes
to protect the King.
You better work harder!
Damn!