You dodge well...
I'm the slowest attacker in the Akatsuki.
I can't seem to hit a thing, can I?
I see... So you're from the Akatsuki.
Well, you're pretty good.
Hey, Hidan.
She's the Two-Tails Jinchuriki.
You'll die if you get careless.
Don't give me that, Kakuzu!
I'd like her to kill me anyway.
Let's do this.
Hold it.
Before doing that...
I must pray to my God.
You’re always nothing but trouble.
Even I think it's a pain.
However, the commandments are strict,
so I have no choice, do I?!
You probably think
you've got me cornered...
But you don't.
I'm the one who lured you here!
Now that I know you're with the Akatsuki,
I cannot let you escape.
Oh, man...
We're trapped, Kakuzu...
No problem.
Actually, this is favorable for us.
I am Yugito Nii of the Hidden Cloud...
and I'll kill you!
Huh...? What?
What's with this "I'll kill you," act?
When people show me all
that enthusiasm and stuff...
I start to get irritated.
And when I'm irritated, I become enraged.
And when I become enraged...
Shut up, Hidan.
Okay. okay...
But you know, when I become enraged,
I start feeling like,
"I don't care about our objective.
I just want to smash everything."
Knock it off, Hidan.
The objective is absolute.
This mission doesn't go along
with my religion in the first place.
The doctrine of Jashinism is
total slaughter.
Leaving people alive goes
against the commandments.
From the outset,
I'm not inclined to take part in a
mission that breaks the commandments.
I may not look it,
but I'm quite devout!
So not being able to kill
is a pain in the neck.
How about we just talk this out?
Talk this out, you say?
Why don't you just come quietly?
Stop messing around!
Huh...? Looks like that's a no.
Are you an idiot?
Come on. Are you kidding me?
What's up with this Jinchuriki?
She's completely transformed
into her Tailed Beast.
Oh man...
Uh-oh!
Hot!
Don't cats have sensitive tongues
for hot stuff?
So this is the Two-Tails monster cat
known as the Wraith.
And I'm a rat in a cage, no less.
This is not amusing...
In order to have others quickly
understand you...
first, you must get closer
to their spirits.
For example, when calling people
by their names,
It's too impersonal to add "-san"
or "-kun" to someone's name.
You will never get closer
to them like that.
You might first try taking the plunge
and call people by
their first name only...
or try using a nickname or
term of endearment.
If you do that, others will feel
much closer to you...
as a special person...
I get it...
Oh, found it.
What...? Isn't that Sai?
Make-Out Paradise is...
Did you come looking for a book
of paintings or something?
Sakura...
So, you read books, huh...?
Well... a little bit.
So even Sai has quite
a human side to him, huh...?
Naruto and I were just on our way
to visit Kakashi-sensei
in the hospital...
Why don't you come with us?
Kakashi... Sensei...
You're on Team Kakashi too,
so you should meet him...
Naruto!
What? Sai's with you, too?
I bumped into him at the library.
Oh... and here I was working out
my plan to walk with you,
just the two of us,
like we were on a date!
If you've got the time to be
doing that,
you should be studying up
on ninjutsu or something!
Study, huh...?
How can you guys even go to
a stuffy place like that?
Naruto, it would be better if you trained
your head a little and not just your body.
Because you truly are an idiot.
I knew it... Sakura is calling
Naruto only by his first name...
That's harsh, Sakura.
N-Naruto, S-Sakura...
Could you guys include me
in the conversation, too?
Oh! Well, I read in a book...
about how to open up to
other people right away...
And in the book, it said to call people
by their first names only
and to use nicknames and
terms of endearment...
It said if I did that there would
be a sense of friendliness
and we'd be able
to get along right away.
Oh, so you're concerned
about stuff like that, huh?
So that's what you were doing
in the library...
Yeah.
And... I was thinking about nicknames
and terms of endearment
for you guys...
But I couldn't really come up
with anything good...
So I'll just call you guys by
just your first names for now...
You don't need to think about stuff
like that.
It just happens naturally!
For nicknames or terms of endearment,
You should just use one
of their defining traits.
For example,
if you're talking about Naruto...
Like "Idiot Naruto" or "Moron Naruto"!
Sakura, you're taking things
too far with that.
I get it... A person's character trait...
I can't believe this is Sai...
He's totally different from
when I first met him...
Thank you. I've got
the hang of it now...
Ugly.
Sai, you're really taking things
too far with that!
Huh? What do you mean?
Sakura, why'd you have to
hit me, too...?
I see... You're the new team member.
Sai, was it? Nice to meet you.
Right.
Kakashi-sensei...
About our previous mission...
I heard about everything
from Yamato.
About Sasuke, too...
We don't have time...
At this rate, he'll soon be...
But I can't bring Sasuke back
with the power I have now...
He's gotten too powerful...
Well then, you just have to get
more powerful, right?
But... the speed of Sasuke's development
was extraordinary even in my eyes.
When I asked Lady Tsunade,
she said there's a possibility
they're using Forbidden Jutsu
and perhaps drugs in his training...
And they've got Kabuto with them, so...
There's probably no way to find out,
in a book like this,
how people who conduct
experiments on humans think...
Then we just have to
rapidly get more powerful.
But how do we do that?
Did you think I was just lying here
not thinking about anything?
I thought about that the whole time.
And... I figured it out.
However, this approach is
suited for Naruto...
Or rather, it's a method only
Naruto can use.
With this training...
You might even surpass me, Naruto.
I'll... surpass you, Kakashi-sensei?
That's right.
I'll be with you the whole time
on this training.
And it will be a different
type of training...
Wh-What are we going to do...?
We're going to create an
ultimate ninjutsu just for you.
In other words,
you're going to learn a new ninjutsu
that will exceed the Rasengan.
However, the acquisition
of such a power
will require an enormous amount
of time and effort.
An enormous amount of time...
But I just said we don't have time!
Sasuke will be...
What I'm saying is, I figured out a way
to do it in a short amount of time.
How do we do it...?
Well...
How're you doing, Kakashi?
Asuma-sensei, you could
at least knock!
Hello.
Oh, it's Naruto and Sakura...
Is your mission already...
You're that guy from back then...
Wh-Who is he...?
Why is all of this happening
so suddenly today...?
Relax. First, smile...
Hello.
Oh, so that's what was going on.
I buy that.
My name's Sai.
Please just call me by my first name.
Hey, he's pretty cute...
He kind of resembles Sasuke, too.
On the outside.
But he's quite different on the inside.
He's not very good at reading the room.
I heard about Sasuke from Lady Tsunade.
I'll help you guys out in the future
should something happen.
I'm finished with those troublesome
Chunin Exams, after all.
You missed out on becoming
a Chunin again, huh?
Yeah...
Well, I guess that was the least
of your problems, huh...?
What are you doing here
with the whole gang in town?
This isn't a break room, you know.
That's right...
You guys go on ahead to the barbecue.
You guys from Team Kakashi
should go too if you want.
Yay! Barbecue!
I second that!
I'll sit next to Sai!
I need to talk to Kakashi alone
about a few things.
The barbecue is on me, okay?
Hey, just a minute!
Listen! Listen!
What about the rest of the discussion
about my training?!
That's right... Hmm...
Well, we'll get to that later.
Later?! I'm really curious about it!
Well, we can't start training while
I'm still in the hospital.
Don't be so impatient.
What a nice day.
Hm? Yeah... it is.
Naruto and Sakura are
coming along very well.
And so are Shikamaru,
Choji and Ino...
The next generation is
growing up quickly.
They'll overtake us just like that...
Come on.
I still won't be giving in to them.
But this is something the Hidden Leaf
should be very pleased about.
So...
What did you want to talk about?
Hm? Oh, as it happens...
There you are...
I finally found you.
Kurenai...
Did you need something?
I heard Asuma was here, you see...
No kidding...?
So, Asuma...
What did you want to talk about?
Uh, I'll tell you later... Sorry.
Now I really want to know...
What took you so long, Sakura?
What? Where's Shikamaru?
He said he was going home
to help his father to collect
deer antlers for medecine.
No kidding?
He always shows up
for end-of-mission parties...
This is a first for him...
She isn't taking my advice...
All right! I'll eat Shikamaru's share!
Hey, Choji!
We have to introduce ourselves
to Sai before we eat.
Oh, oh... right.
Hi...
First meetings are very important
in order to quickly open up to people...
I have to decide on nicknames
and terms of endearment right away...
Uh, I'm Choji Akimichi
of the Akimichi Clan.
Nice to meet you.
Uh, you're Sai, right?
Nice to meet you... uh...
Character trait... character trait...
Don't tell me...
He's not going to say
that taboo word, is he?!
Fa...
Sai! The word "fatty" is absolutely
forbidden around Choji! Got it?!
Did he... start to say something just now?
No, it's nothing...
I see.
It sure is tough coming up
with nicknames...
My name's Ino Yamanaka.
My family owns
the Yamanaka Flower Shop.
Nice to meet you.
In the case of a girl,
saying a character trait
just makes them angry...
In other words, if I say the opposite...
Nice to meet you... beautiful.
Why do you say that
when it's Ino?!
Stop it, Sakura!
It's already been thirty minutes.
Aren't you done yet, Hidan?
Shut up!
Don't interfere with the ritual!
Ouch...
Can't you skip some of that
perverse praying
you do each and every time?
Let's get right to the next one.
This is a pain in the neck for me too.
But I have no choice
but to follow the commandments.
And what do you mean by skip?!
That's blasphemy against God!
One more to go for our mission.
One by one...
Next is the Land of Fire.
Zetsu, huh?
It appears it's done.
Finally finished with
your drawn-out ritual, huh?
Nothing but annoying atheist jerks
who don't understand prayer!
When you're sad and alone,
you can only trust in yourself.
No, you're wrong.
You can only trust in money.
Oh, here we go!
We've fallen behind with
our Jinchuriki hunt
mostly because of your side job!
I teamed up with you because
you said religion is profitable.
I've been left in charge
of Akatsuki finances.
Put yourself in my shoes.
Money is important.
More importantly,
search for the next one immediately.
I'll take care of the Two-Tails...
How deep into the mountains is it?
We're almost there.
You've been saying that
the whole time!
Come on. Give me a break!
We've got to climb again?!
What if it turns out
there's no Jinchuriki?!
I'll be really upset!
I don't give a damn about you.
If you keep wailing like a little kid...
I'll kill you.
Come on.
Don't give me that, Kakuzu!
Oh, man!
What an anti-social jerk.
This is a temple.
Is there a Jinchuriki in a place like this?
Who knows?
But this isn't an ordinary temple,
so there's a good possibility.
What was that?!
Someone destroyed the Iron Wall Seal!
Report this to Lord Chiriku!
It doesn't look like these guys
want to convert to Jashinism.
None of these guys do...
That cloak... It's the rumored...
No doubt about it! It's the Akatsuki!
We have intruders!
Who are they?
They are with the Akatsuki!
I knew they'd come here eventually, but...
I'll go!
Everyone else provide backup.
Looks like we've got another
virtuous looking one...
He's not just virtuous.
He's got a 30 million-ryo bounty
on his head in our Bingo Book.
Hey...
You're not after money, are you?
You'll go to hell if you kill
a monk for something like that.
Money is the key that opens all doors.
That's just what I want.
I don't know what you guys want.
But please leave quietly.
No meaningless slaughter, huh?
But it doesn't work like that
in my religion.
The Fire Temple is the greatest
shinobi temple in the Land of Fire.
And it is said that all the monks
control the special power
known as the Gift of the Sages.
And the 30 million-ryo man is a ninja
who was once chosen as a member
of the Guardian Shinobi Twelve
who protected the Feudal Lord
of the Land of Fire.
And the proof is that sash with
the Land of Fire emblem on it.
No kidding? Is he that incredible?
Don't get careless. You'll die.
Don't give me that...
Kakuzu!
What's that?!
I don't care.
Let's keep going.
You're mine!
- Oh.
- Lord Chiriku won!
I'll give you a funeral.
Who would accept
a different religion's funeral?
I'd receive divine retribution
from Lord Jashin...
Now I'm mad...
Hey...
If this guy isn't a Jinchuriki...
I can defend my commandments, right?
Do as you like.
But his body is worth money.
Don't go overboard...
Make sure he's recognizable.
Trading a life for money...
that's not what a person does.
Good grief.
Kakuzu! Stay out of this!
I'll take care of... this guy!
Chiriku of the Fire Temple will
not lose to wicked men like you!
Raigo:
A Thousand Hand Strike!
Okay, time for some training.
What is it?
Well, it's been a long time
since I've trained with you...
I don't really know why,
but I'm glad...
I see.
Laugh it up while you can.
Time won't wait for us, so...
As I told you at the hospital,
the purpose of this training is
to create a ninjutsu
of ultimate power just for you.
A jutsu that will exceed
the Rasengan.
Two techniques,
"Change in Chakra Nature"
and "Change in Chakra Form,"
are crucial for that...
Change in chakra form
and change in... chakra nature?
Let's see...
Take Chidori for example...
This is a jutsu activated
by simultaneously creating
both the change in chakra nature
and change in chakra form...
Watch this. I concentrate
chakra in my right hand...
I change the nature of this chakra
to lightning.
So this is the change in chakra nature...
That's right.
And now I shift the form
so it will discharge electricity
and then I determine the range
and strength of the attack.
In order to learn a jutsu above
that of the Rasengan,
this combination of
the change in chakra form
and change in chakra nature is absolutely
necessary, like with the Chidori.
Then I'll be able to complete
a new jutsu in a flash
if I add that change in chakra nature
to my Rasengan!
Listen. That's easier said than done.
And you don't even know your own
chakra nature, do you?
Huh?! What's a chakra nature?
Well, I figured I'd have to start
explaining from there...
Listen up.
There are five basic chakra natures...
The five types are Fire, Wind,
Water, Lightning and Earth.
These basic properties are the basis
for the names of the "Five Great Nations"
and they're also the foundations
of all ninjutsu.
No kidding. Really...?
Everyone generally has chakra
that falls under one of these properties.
For example, the Uchiha clan
has the property of Fire,
and Fire Style jutsu is their strength.
Wind has the Wind Style.
And lightning has the Lightning Style.
Chidori is a Lightning Style jutsu.
So that means Sasuke has two natures:
Fire and Lightning?
And you currently don't have any.
Plus, we don't know your
natural chakra affinity.
I'll find that out with
this strip of paper.
How are you going to do that...?
The paper gets wrinkled if you have
a Lightning nature.
It'll get cut if it's Wind.
It'll burn if it's Fire.
It'll get wet if it's Water.
It'll crumble if it's Earth.
This is litmus paper that reacts
easily to chakra.
It's made from a special tree
that grows while absorbing chakra.
If you flow your chakra into this paper,
you'll find out what your nature is.
All right...
Now I get the feeling...
I kind of understand what
you were talking about.
I'm sorry I left the Hidden Leaf...
and just did whatever I wanted.
I have no regrets, though.
Now I feel like it wasn't so bad
being born into the Sarutobi Clan.
You properly fulfilled your duty
as leader of the village...
You were a cool dad...
Your chakra nature is Wind.
Wind...
It tears and cuts through
all sorts of things.
It's chakra with
outstanding battle strength.
Ooh! I'm awesome!
No, you've still only just figured
out your property...
Now at last,
we've come to the training for learning
the change in chakra nature for Wind...
Right!
However, it will take an enormous
amount of time to learn that technique.
And so I hit upon a way to
drastically reduce that time.
Awesome!
And the way to do that is...
Captain Yamato!
Huh? Why, why?
Kakashi asked me to help out
with this training.
I'm sorry for interrupting you,
Kakashi-senpai...
No problem...
- And you see...
- Hey! Hey!
What type of change in chakra nature
is your Wood Style, Captain Yamato?
Huh?
Well...
Uh-huh...
Then...
Earth Style: Rampart of Flowing Soil
Whoa! What?!
Water Style: Waterfall Basin Jutsu!
He made a waterfall...
I have two chakra natures:
Earth and Water.
What?! You have two of them,
Captain Yamato?!
Jonin-class ninja generally
have two or more.
I've also got properties other
than Lightning that I can use.
Then, Captain Yamato has
three natures including the Wood Style?
No, that's not how it works.
Huh?
I can only use Earth and Water.
There is no fundamental nature
known as "Wood" to begin with.
Then how do you do it?
He does it simultaneously.
He does the change in chakra nature
for Earth and Water at the same time
and generates the new Wood nature.
Earth with my right hand...
and Water with my left hand.
That's awesome...
If you have two chakra natures...
it's not that difficult to use
each one independently.
But when it comes to generating
two change in chakra natures
at the same time...
It's a different story...
The power to generate a
new chakra nature
by using two change in chakra natures
simultaneously
is called Kekkei Genkai.
You've at least heard of
that expression, haven't you?
Yeah...
That boy you once fought, Haku, used it.
He was able to use the Kekkei Genkai
known as the Ice Style...
But he generated "Ice" by using
the two change in chakra natures
of Wind and Water at the same time.
It's a special jutsu
only those from a clan possessing
the Kekkei Genkai can use.
Haku, too, huh...?
So I couldn't copy it even with
my Sharingan...
Then what about Shikamaru's
Shadow Possession Jutsu
or Choji's Expansion Jutsu?
And what about medical ninjutsu
and genjutsu?
Kakashi-senpai...
Why don't you save the Yin and Yang of
change in chakra nature for another time?
Yin? And Yang?
What's that?
Right.
You wouldn't understand even
if I told you now.
Now, what were we talking about again?
Oh... Something about a shortcut
for my training time...
Reduce the time.
Yeah, that. So, how do we do that?
Multiple Shadow Clones.
Huh?
Listen up...
You know that the Shadow Clone Jutsu
doesn’t create illusions
like the ordinary Clone Jutsu does, right?
Yeah, of course I do!
Well, you can also call it a ninjutsu
for creating a copy of yourself.
I know because I can also use the Shadow
Clone Jutsu, though not to your extent.
There is a particular effect this
jutsu has on the caster.
And since you're always using it,
I'm sure you've picked up on this...
Anything experienced by
the shadow clone
is also experienced by the caster
after the clone has returned
to the original's body.
I knew you hadn't picked up on it.
I mean, I have no idea
what you're talking about.
Then let's both try
creating shadow clones.
Oh, one clone will be enough.
Right.
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
All right! Now let's split up into
"original" and "shadow clone" teams...
The shadow clone team will
hide in the woods over there.
Come with me, shadow clone Naruto.
Right!
The originals can't see us shadow clones
here in the woods now.
Now, just the two of us will play
rock-paper-scissors.
What for?
Just do it.
What are the shadow clones doing?
You'll find out soon.
Yes!
I won! You owe me a meal, Kakashi-sensei!
Okay, okay. Now we're going to
break the jutsu and vanish.
Right.
What were they doing?
You have to treat me to Ichiraku Ramen,
Kakashi-sensei!
I beat you at rock-paper-scissors!
What are you doing, making promises
on my behalf?
Now you get it, right?
Shadow clone experiences
are accumulated within
the original's body.
I get it...
I never realized it at all
because I was just sort of using
the shadow clones
without really thinking about it.
Normally, this jutsu is used for
scouting dangerous locations
and gathering information by infiltrating
an enemy hideout, you see.
But even having figured that out,
what does that have to do with
reducing the training time?
To put it a different way, it also means,
if you use two people,
it'll take half the time it takes
to train alone.
And it'll take one-third
the time if you use three.
One-thousandth with a thousand.
In other words, training that would
take two days alone
will take one day with two people.
Even training that would take
twenty years alone
will take around a week with
a thousand people.
That's awesome!
So we can do it that way!
He finally got it, huh...?
Now I know why you're so strong,
Kakashi-sensei!
So this is
how you did your training, huh?
No, I've never even once
trained using this approach.
Huh?! Why not?
You can also make
shadow clones, can't you?
Indeed, I can...
But I don't have as much
chakra as you do.
And I can't sustain
my shadow clones as long, either.
And the only types
of jutsu suitable for me,
since I don't have much chakra,
are the ones requiring an
even distribution of chakra.
For real? I have more chakra than you,
Kakashi-sensei?
You've got around four times
more than me.
Huh?! I've got that much?!
I'm pretty awesome, aren't I?!
If you didn't suppress the power
of the Nine-Tails chakra,
you'd have around
a hundred times more.
That's why this is a training approach
only you can do.
But since it requires
a large amount of chakra,
there's a possibility of rousing
the Nine-Tails chakra.
And so I was summoned here in order
to control the Nine-Tails chakra.
I'm ready!
All right! First, you must train
to strengthen your chakra nature.
Right!
Sandwich a leaf between your palms
and cut it just with chakra.
Keep it there until you cut it right
in half, okay?
All right! Let's do this!
And as I said before,
you'll do this training with shadow clones
at all times.
How many clones should I make?
Well, if you take
one person for one leaf...
Maybe around that many.
Huh?!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Already got a little cut in, huh?
This might be quicker than I thought.
It appears there was no Jinchuriki here.
Let's move on to the next one as soon
as I'm done with my prayer.
No...
I'm taking this body to trade in for money.
Money comes first.
Listen, you're really starting
to irritate me. Really...
I've got to inform the Hidden Leaf...
Then let's get going.
The Land of Fire is huge.
Let's take our time.
I knew we were falling behind
because of you.
Ow!
Wait! Hey!
How's it going?
Are you able to control
the Nine-Tails chakra okay, Tenzo?
There are no problems so far.
Also, please call me Yamato,
not Tenzo.
Okay, okay.
Yes! It cut quite a bit!
Damn it!
And mine still hasn't cut at all!
I'm much better than you guys!
We're the same person, idiot!
Yes!
Damn it...
That me over there's pretty good...
I've got to do something...
Say! Say!
I've got something I want to ask you,
Kakashi-sensei...
What is it?
Is there anyone in the Leaf who has
a Wind nature?
You're looking for the trick to it?
Yeah!
Well, you could say
there's a person...
Right about now
he's probably playing shogi...
That's a first for you,
going with a climbing silver
right off the bat.
Let's take it nice and slow.
We've got the time, after all.
It's an advance guard for
breaking through the enemy's defense.
Sometimes you have to be able
to make moves like this.
I thought you didn't like moves like that.
Just like me.
Sacrifice is required in order to protect
the king when your opponent is skilled.
I just now started to understand
the importance of the "king."
Well... The game is over if
you get your king taken in shogi.
If you were to liken the Hidden
Leaf shinobi to a shogi piece...
Shikamaru...
In the end, you would be a knight.
Although weak in strength,
a knight can advance
by jumping over pieces.
This unique movement resembles
your flexible thinking.
Then what would you be?
I'm nothing.
Then... do you know who the "king" is?
The Hokage, right?
That's what I thought
until just recently...
But it's not like that.
Then who is it?
You'll understand when the time comes.
Hey!
Asuma-sensei!
Oh, it's Naruto.
Is there something you need?
As it happens,
there's something I want to ask you...
The trick to the Wind
change in chakra nature, huh...?
Right!
Don't tell me you're doing chakra
change in chakra nature training?
Yeah!
You've got to have a sense
for that kind of thing...
Can you handle it?
That's why I came here
to ask Asuma-sensei.
You've got the same Wind
chakra property as me, right, Sensei?
I never thought you'd have
the Wind chakra property, Naruto...
This is, indeed, a shock.
Asuma-sensei, please teach me
the trick to it... right away.
Let me see...
I could think about it if you'd pay
the barbecue bill
for Team Asuma's
next end-of-mission party...
Oh! That's dirty!
What do you think?
I have no choice.
It's for my training!
All right! It's a deal.
This is my chakra blade...
This blade is made from
a special metal
that absorbs
the owner's chakra property.
That's awesome...
Here, take it.
Try pouring your chakra into the blade.
Right.
My chakra... kind of comes out
different from yours, Asuma-sensei.
Listen up.
The Wind change in chakra nature
splits chakra in two
and grinds them together.
Grinds them together?
And then you build up
the two chakra as if steadily honing them.
As if steadily ... honing them...
That's right...
The trick is steady... and sharp.
Say... um... I was thinking...
What is it?
Even though we've got
ninja tools to start with...
what's the point of this
Wind Nature Transformation?
Wouldn't it be quicker just to cut with
something that cuts right from the start?
And is there a point...
to pouring chakra into
a weapon that already cuts?
Okay. I'll show you whether
or not there's a point to that...
Listen up.
We'll try throwing these chakra blades
toward that tree at the same time.
What for?
Don't worry about that. Let's go.
One, two--!
Th-That's awesome!
It went all the way through...
not just the tree but into that
really hard rock and got lodged inside...
It's dangerous,
so I held back just now.
It would've gone right through
the rock if I'd gone all out.
The quality of the blade
will determine the result
in the case of ninja of the same level
getting into a serious battle.
The Wind property has
the most attack power
in close to medium-range battles.
There really aren't
that many Wind types.
Oh, really...?
Come on by if there's ever
anything else you want to ask me...
But you'll have to pay
for the barbecue.
Right!
Thanks!
Oh, it was a shadow clone?
That Naruto...
He forgot that we've got
Choji on our team.
That's harsh...
I get it! So that's how to do it!
All right!
- Let's do it!
It appears he found out the trick
to it from Asuma.
He's already doing a good job
of applying the attributes of
his shadow clones, that Naruto...
What's that?
I see...
So they even took down Chiriku...
I was out on patrol...
and by the time I returned,
it was too late.
It was most likely the guys
from the Akatsuki.
They're probably going one by one
to locations in the Land of Fire
where there might be a Jinchuriki.
Finally, they've come.
We won't let them out
of the Land of Fire.
Contact the twenty newly formed
squads immediately!
All right! We'll go ahead and
have you accumulate experience.
Lock in the experience from your training,
then release the jutsu!
- Right!
All right! Let's go!
I can manage this...
I'll be able to do it soon...
The drawback is that
you accumulate mental fatigue
right along with the experience.
I knew that from the start...
But... I'm almost there...
Let's take a short break, Naruto.
This isn't the time to be taking it easy!
I'm okay, Kakashi-sensei...
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
What...? Oh! Hey...
Just a minute!
We did it!
How about that, Kakashi-sensei?!
Huh?
Are you awake?
Huh...?
Again... I...
You keep resting.
Fatigue tends to build up
when using the shadow clone
training approach.
Let's start the training again
after you've rested a little while.
What are we going to do next?
Next?
The next step is...
to cut that waterfall!
Put your hands on the waterfall
and cut it
by hammering it
with your Wind chakra.
Cut... the waterfall?
For this, you need to instantly change the
chakra nature of a large amount of chakra.
Or else you won't be able
to cut the waterfall.
You'll more or less be able
to use it in real battle
if you can pass this stage of training.
Kakashi-sensei!
If I can do that,
that means I've mastered my first
Nature Transformation, right?
All right, I'm getting better!
I never thought that clumsy Naruto
would be able to create
a change in chakra nature so soon.
This training approach...
was a big success.
Break time is over!
Let's get right back to training!
Wood Style Jutsu
That will be your training area.
Right.
But hold on!
Whoa... What is it?
You'll need Yamato's chakra control
at all times during this training.
I'm counting on you, Yamato.
Okay.
Preparations complete, Naruto!
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Form a mental image
of my Wind chakra and...
Steady and sharp!
Let's go, guys!
Right!
Damn it! The water should
splash just a bit...
Let's go to the next one!
Right!
As to be expected,
this will probably take a while.
Well, be patient.
You carry him for a while.
Hey, hey, hey.
You're the one always
talking about money.
You carry him all the way.
He's your precious bounty, right?
What's with that look?
I swear, I'm going to kill you someday.
I told you, don't give me that... Kakuzu.
Here you go...
Thanks...
Who are they for...?
Oh, nobody in particular...
See you later...
Say "Hi" to Kurenai-sensei for me!
Wha--?! How did...
you know that?!
Oh, there he is...
Sorry to bother you while you're
on your way to Kurenai-sensei's place...
Huh? You guys, too?
How...?
Huh? Everybody knows...
Shikamaru!
Oh... right...
We received orders
from the Fifth Hokage
for everyone from Team Asuma
including myself, Choji and Ino
to assemble immediately.
What?!
What...? All members from...
the old Team 10...?
Yeah...
Does anyone have any questions?
What is it?
Chiriku, a former member
of the Guardian Shinobi Twelve,
should be there.
What happened to him?
Lord Chiriku died by their hands.
Chiriku was killed?
It can't be...
For the pride of the Hidden Leaf,
and most of all,
for the safety of the Land of Fire,
we cannot allow them to move freely
any longer.
I want to know what they're after,
but they're very dangerous.
Don't let them out of the Land of Fire,
no matter what.
Find them without fail and
if you're unable to restrain them,
kill them!
Go!
Dismissed!
Now then...
Okay, we'll start with
the Temple of Fire.
Someone has to do it.
Let's go.
Kakashi-sensei!
Don't you think I need
more shadow clones?!
You can't cut the waterfall
unless you perform
the change in chakra nature
with a large amount of Wind chakra!
The chakra for each clone will disperse
if there are too many of them!
And we can barely line up ten clones
with the width of that waterfall!
Do you really want me to learn this or not?
Then give us a hint on how to get
even a little better!
You're not holding the chakra
you've built up inside
your body long enough!
Take your time and be more efficient!
But if we don't get a move on,
this won't be of any use in a real battle.
You're in training right now.
You don't need to be thinking
about real battles.
It will get quicker
once you get used to it.
But...
Listen...
Change in chakra nature training
normally takes several years.
Under normal conditions,
it takes six months to even cut a leaf.
You completed that in only
a few hours.
No need to be so impatient.
You're progressing several times
faster than we expected.
It even took a genius like Sasuke
several days to master his
Lightning Nature Transformation
when I taught him the Chidori.
I have to catch up with Sasuke!
Good grief...
Tenzo...
Understood.
That was a little tough on you, huh?
No! Not at all.
N-Not in the least...
It was tough...
How's that, Naruto?!
Now you've got nothing
to gripe about, right?!
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu.
Damn it!
As long as I don't give in
and keep going without
stopping to rest...
I'll arrive at the point where...
Here we go!
All right!
This training is something else, isn't it?
Naruto is progressing
so quickly.
No... It's not just because
of this training approach.
Sasuke has something
to do with it, too.
- We cut the waterfall!
- We really cut it!
Well done.
Now we can start development
of your new original jutsu.
Right... I got it...
You okay, Naruto?!
I guess he overdid it a little.
Wh-What is it?
I'm... hungry...
You really are... something else.
We asked neighboring temples
for help recovering the remains.
This is awful.
Where's Chiriku?
Actually... we have been unable
to find Lord Chiriku's remains.
Umm... Captain Asuma.
I don't really want to bring this up...
But Chiriku has a 30 million-ryo bounty
on his head
on the black market.
A bounty...
If those guys from the Akatsuki
know about the bounty...
Yeah...
Izumo, where's the nearest
collection office?
Including the closest one,
there are five locations in total.
The other teams can rush to the other
four collection offices.
All right, let's hurry.
Please wait a moment,
Lord Asuma Sarutobi.
You have a bounty on your head
for being a former member
of the Guardian Shinobi Twelve...
just like Chiriku.
Please allow me to say a prayer
for all of you who are about to fight.
Okay.
All right, let's get
right back to training!
No, before that...
Huh?
Naruto... I'll show you something cool.
Something cool?
There are some things
I want to explain to you
while we take a little rest after eating.
What?
More complicated explanations?
Don't worry... I'm a good teacher,
so you'll get it.
Here's your bill.
Yamato, you take care of this.
What?! Isn't it usually the senior
who takes care of it?
There are no seniors or juniors
regarding the men I respect.
Well, you're pretty much
the only junior...
I respect.
But I suppose I really should...
- Thank you very much!
- Oh, keep the change.
You really are a slick talker.
Asuma-sensei...
What kind of relationship did
you have with that Chiriku guy?
What's the deal all of a sudden?
You're a heavy smoker, but you haven't
lit up in two whole days.
You always stop smoking...
when something has happened.
You're so observant...
I'm far too soft if you can see
right through to my heart like that.
Well, I can always tell
what move you're going to make
when we play shogi.
You haven't looked like this since
the Third Hokage passed away.
Chiriku and I...
were part of the
Guardian Shinobi Twelve.
I guess you could say...
we were like you and Choji.
You won't stop smoking for long.
I won't stop smoking for long... huh?
Shikamaru, I appreciate you
worrying about me.
But I didn't stop smoking
because of Chiriku.
More importantly, the guys from Akatsuki
are good enough to kill Chiriku.
They're dangerously skilled.
Stay sharp!
Kakashi-sensei,
what are you going to show me?
This is the cool thing...
I wanted to show you.
This is...
R-Rasengan...?
You can also use...
the Rasengan, Kakashi-sensei?!
And all I can do is spin it around
into shape with a clone...
Man, this is too much trouble...
I didn't show you the Rasengan because
I wanted to brag about it or anything.
Listen up. When you take chakra
and add in change in chakra form
and change in chakra nature...
the attack power of a shinobi
rises dramatically.
Well, there are hardly any shinobi
who can use
both change in chakra form
and nature, though.
I knew it. You're bragging.
You obtained the Wind Nature
Transformation in your training earlier.
And you already possess
the ultimate change in chakra form...
Rasengan?
That's right.
Then that means...
I already have both?
Well... that's pretty much the case.
All right! Then it looks like I'll be able
to get a new jutsu just like that!
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
This is going to be easy!
If it were that easy,
it wouldn't have been necessary
for me to develop the Chidori.
I wasn't able to combine
the Rasengan's change in chakra form
with my Lightning Nature Transformation.
Phenomenal technique is
necessary to combine
the change in chakra nature
with the change in chakra form.
Well, it might be better to say one needs
a phenomenal "ability" or "sense."
I wasn't the only one who
was not able to get this far.
It was the same even for
the teacher who invented this jutsu.
Teacher?
That's right...
Even the Fourth Hokage
couldn't do it.
The Fourth Hokage took
the change in chakra form
to the highest possible level.
And that's the Rasengan.
The change in chakra form alone
makes it an A-rank technique.
Even I can somehow copy it
if it's just to this degree.
The problem is what comes after that.
The Fourth Hokage originally
developed the Rasengan
intending to add his own
change in chakra nature to it.
So you're saying the Rasengan was
an unfinished jutsu?
That's pretty much the case.
Any jutsu beyond that would be
an S-rank difficulty level or
maybe even higher.
Furthermore,
it might be impossible to begin with...
I won't be able to teach you
what comes next.
You'll have to discover it for yourself.
Do you know why
I'm telling you this, Naruto?
It's because
I believe you're the only shinobi...
who can surpass the Fourth Hokage.
Well... That's enough talk for now.
I guess we'll start up training again
after a bit more rest.
Just what I'd expect from you, Kakashi.
You really are a good teacher.
No...
I really do believe in him.
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
This is the collection office.
Why put a secret door in a bathroom?
This way.
Put it here.
Okay.
Hurry up and get it done!
No doubt about it.
It's Chiriku.
You got yourself a big one
this time, Kakuzu.
Yeah...
Hey, this place stinks.
Let's get going, Kakuzu.
Wait. I'm going to count the money.
I'm never coming to a place
like this again.
I can't tell if the stench is
from the piss or the corpses.
I'll be outside.
Sure enough, he's quick to tire when
using his Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu.
Damn it...
Let's go!
Right!
Incorporate Wind chakra into this.
Damn it!
It's no use.
And here I need a ton of concentration
just for the Rasengan.
And then I have to add my
Nature Transformation on top of that...
It's like trying to look left and right
at the same time.
Damn it!
This isn't the time to be throwing
in the towel already!
Concentrate...
Like grinding
the two chakra together...
Hey! Tenzo!
I know.
If Naruto keeps doing this, he'll...
And I can't keep stopping that
over and over again...
- I can't...
- No... This is the only way.
Whether or not his jutsu
is completed rides on you.
I understand...
Ohh, it stinks!
Being stuck in a dump like that
for five minutes and the stench
would soak right into my clothes.
Took you long enough, Kakuzu.
Too slow.
We got one to start.
That hurts, you bastards.
What's the meaning of this?
We pierced his vital spots.
Don't push it in deeper like that!
Hey, that hurts!
Is this guy... immortal?
Isn't it obvious?
So... who are you guys?
That mark.
If I remember correctly, it's from
the Guardian Shinobi or something...
Are you kidding me?
Do I have to go back inside that
smelly collection office again?
Chiriku...
We're Hidden Leaf shinobi.
We've been ordered to either
capture or eliminate you Akatsuki.
Akatsuki operate in teams of two.
Our intention was to take down
one of you first
and then capture the other.
But you're pretty tough,
as was expected.
So this is the Akatsuki...
Their abilities are insane.
My Shadow Sewing probably won't...
You jerks went after us
in the wrong order.
Where's the other one?
The jutsu's broken!
Kotetsu, Izumo, get back!
Sure enough, the guy in the middle...
This is a first, you being interested
in money, Hidan.
Kakuzu...
You stay out of this.
I'm going to use these guys for my ritual.
I'll give you the money.
Very well... But don't get careless.
You'll die.
I told you.
Don't give me that.
If they could kill me,
I'd want them to.
Well... I guess it's impossible, huh?!
I'll charge him.
Shikamaru, exploit an opening
and restrain the immortal guy
with your Shadow Sewing.
It doesn't have to be for long.
I'll take his head off immediately
and stop his movements.
That's too risky.
This isn't like you.
I should go with you.
Don't you get it?!
It's the only move we have right now!
I've never seen Asuma
look like this before.
These guys are way
stronger than me.
Izumo, Kotetsu,
you guys back up Shikamaru
while keeping an eye on
the other Akatsuki guy.
If we know what they're capable of,
then all the more reason
we should pull out for now
and plan a strategy.
They won't let us get away
that easily.
If we try to escape
without putting up a fight,
we'll be completely wiped out...
If that happens, the Hidden Leaf
will be in even greater danger.
It's like sending in an advance unit
to break through enemy lines.
Sometimes you have to be able
to make a move like that.
A climbing silver doesn't suit you.
I'm no mere sacrificial pawn.
I've got you with me, after all.
How pathetic...
I can't be the bait and I can't put
pressure on the enemy.
But I'll divert the major pieces
like crazy.
Are you done with
your little strategy session?
Getting cut up like that
hurts like hell! you jerks!
Divine judgment will be passed
upon you bastards
who know nothing of the pain of others.
You've got a nice weapon there!
If combo and pinpoint attacks won't hit...
Burning Ash!
It hurts, doesn't it?
Well?
The judgment has been
handed down.
How about it?
Has this helped you understand
the pain that other people feel,
even a little bit?
Even my arm...
Has his jutsu done something?
No, that can't be...
You have already fallen
under my curse.
The ceremony will now begin.
Well, then...
Why not taste the ultimate pain
with me?!
That's a 35 million ryo bounty.
All the preparations are now complete!
It's going to hurt like crazy,
so get ready!
Take that!
It hurts, doesn't it?!
But this is nothing.
I haven't got you in a vital spot yet!
Trust me, the REAL pain is
something else entirely!
The pain another feels while
dying penetrates into my own body!
I pass through the pain, transcend it,
and turn it into pleasure!
But of course...
His body and mine are connected
with some curse.
In other words, the damage dealt
to our bodies is also linked.
Furthermore, he is immortal.
Where would you like to hurt next?
Hmm? Here? Or here?
How about both legs
at the same time?!
Or...
shall we end now?!
How about it?!
Die--!
Do you think I'd let that happen?!
You did it, Shikamaru!
This won't stop me for long!
Izumo, how many minutes have passed
since you requested backup?
About ten minutes.
It'll be at least another 20 minutes
before reinforcements arrive.
That long?!
Damn...! What should we do?!
If we kill him,
Captain Asuma will also die!
To break a persistent curse-type jutsu,
you usually have to kill the user.
But if that is not possible...
Every jutsu inevitably has rules
associated with it,
as well as risks and pitfalls.
First, I need to calm down
and analyze the opponent.
I was saved,
thanks to Shikamaru.
I must take this chance and
think of a way to break this jutsu.
If this wears on any
longer, I'll lend a hand.
We can't let all the money get away.
I told you to stay out of this, Kakuzu!
I can handle this...!
Remarks, personality, speech patterns...
the clothes they wear...
Grasp their movements
right up to now.
The significance of
each and every action.
And then the connection between actions.
Develop a hypothesis about their abilities
that can be drawn from all these factors.
It's all about observation and analysis.
God's judgment will be handed down!
God... judgment...
You have already fallen under my curse.
The ceremony will now begin.
A curse... the ceremony...
With this, all preparations are complete!
Preparations...!
Did you figure something out, Shikamaru?
Yeah!
It's amazing that you're capable
of such an analysis
while still maintaining your jutsu.
I'm heading out, Captain Asuma...
That shadow jutsu...
Does it force the person it's used on
to mirror the motions of its caster?
Why you... Trying to sniff
out the true nature of my jutsu.
What are you going to do?!
I'll drag that bastard outside of that
circle he drew on the ground!
If I do that,
his curse jutsu will be broken.
What on earth does that mean?!
His weapon...
That huge scythe with three blades.
Judging by its shape, I'd say it's not
designed to land a single fatal blow,
but rather increase
his attack range.
All his weapons are designed to
cause damage from a distance.
In other words, his tactic is to
only injure his opponent
and then buy time to deploy
a lethal jutsu.
And by that you mean the curse?
But what's the connection between
the enemy's wound and the curse?
It's blood...
In order to form a link between himself
and his targeted opponent,
he needs to find a way to incorporate
that opponent's blood into his own body.
Then if he wounds his opponent and even
a little blood adheres to that sickle...
he can place his curse.
But of course...
After licking the blood,
his body changed color.
That is a condition for invoking the curse.
But that's not all.
In order to completely invoke the curse,
one more condition must be met.
One more?
This brat knows his stuff.
A little while ago,
that creep let Asuma's Fire Style jutsu
roll right off him.
He was unfazed,
but he hurried back to that strange pattern
drawn on the ground, remember?
And once he was standing inside that
pattern, he said the ceremony would begin.
And by howling that the preparations
were now complete...
We can assume the ritual
for his curse jutsu
is only complete once he steps
inside that pattern.
You little brat!
You talk too much.
Why you! I'll get you later!
I'll tear you limb from limb!
I'll pulverize you! I'll
turn you inside out!
There isn't going to be a "later"!
We got him out!
All right! The curse is broken!
All right!
Wha--?!
Crap...
I can't move...
I'm at my limit! I don't think
I can hold him any longer.
You did well, Shikamaru.
Kakuzu! Lend me a hand!
Hey! Snap to it!
I told you to keep your wits
about you.
Shikamaru!
Are you all right?
Yeah. Now that leaves...
Only one more left, huh?
If you wanted help,
you should have said so sooner.
You were too slow, Kakuzu!
You did that on purpose, didn't you?!
You were the one who told me
to stay out of this at the beginning.
So are you really in
any position to complain?
Well, I did order you to hold back.
But that wasn't because
I was trying to make a fool of you
or disrespect you.
Well, never mind about that.
Anyway, bring my body over here.
Kakuzu...
Will you bring my body...?
Come on Kakuzu, buddy.
Wha--?! Hey! Wait a minute!
See here, Kakuzu!
What about my body?
I thought I told you to bring
my body over here!
This is lighter.
That's not the issue now, is it?
Are you ignoring me? Hey!
Ouch... it hurts... hey!
Kakuzu, you're pulling my hair!
Stop that!
If you are hurting at all,
it should be in your neck.
You moron!
The pain in my neck isn't just a tickle!
It's excruciating!
This is more than just a simple injury.
That guy...
In that state, he's still alive!
It hurts like crazy! See here!
The nerve of you,
cutting off my head!
This is incredibly painful,
you idiot!
He may be immortal, but right now,
he can't do anything.
That's for sure.
So then, there's only one opponent left.
Yes...
Shikamaru!
Shikamaru has really pushed himself
to his limit.
Captain Asuma is injured too.
We are at an advantage in that
we've immobilized one of the Akatsuki, but...
On the other hand,
you could also say this gives us
the opportunity to escape.
Since you've now asked me
to lend a hand,
I'm going to join in too.
I got it...
Ow! Ouch!
Hey, hold still, will you?
Okay, that should do it.
His head...
It's good to be whole again.
If you move around too much,
it'll come off again.
Kakuzu, you're always such a nag.
What on earth... are we fighting?
An immortal man...
and a man who possesses a jutsu
that can sew back together
a dismembered body...
Damn!
It's just one thing after another.
How powerful are they?!
Your fights, your complaining, and
your rituals are way too long.
You take care of the one with
the price on his head.
Izumo!
Got it!
Right!
Water Style: Syrup Trap!
I suppose you meant to grab
your opponent's attention
with that eye-catching aerial attack
to create an opening.
And then follow-up with
a land attack
by coordinating your movements
with this strange liquid, but...
I think it's half-baked.
There's too much wasted effort.
Now!
Well look at that...
You're mine!
Damn...!
Huh?!
So long.
Asuma!
Behind you!
It's the same moves
over and over again.
Not the same, you moron!
Damn!
Finally...
I finally get to taste that pain.
Captain!
Damn!
It's over.
I-It feels so good...
Asuma...
I'm finished.
I'll just be another minute.
Damn it...
You son of a bitch!
Damn... I'm so powerless...
Feathers...?!
What the hell?!
Do you think you can beat us
with crows?!
I wasn't born yesterday!
Blindfold!
A back sword!
Shikamaru!
We're here to help you.
Ino...
Take Shikamaru somewhere safe!
Yes!
Don't let your guard down, Choji!
Okay!
Reinforcements...
Are you okay?!
Forget me.
First... Captain Asuma...
Asuma-sensei!
He still has a heartbeat!
Choji! Take Asuma-sensei to
the Hidden Leaf Hospital right now!
Ino, you go along with him
and use your medical ninjutsu
to heal him as much as possible!
Hurry!
I got it!
Right!
I'm not giving up my bounty.
Damn...!
We'll hold them back.
You can struggle all you like,
but you'll be sacrificed to God...
That's why...
Huh?!
Can't you wait a little longer?!
Seriously, it was just getting good!
It's time to seal the Two-Tails...
Come right away!
This is the top priority.
See, I told you...
It's almost there!
Knock it off, Hidan!
Are they communicating with someone?!
Tsk...
We'll be right back...
Be prepared!
Let's go, Hidan.
Damn that pigheaded leader...
I'll curse him next time!
What's going on?!
Are they pulling back...?!
Sensei!
Asuma-sensei!
Ino, Choji! Hurry up and
get Asuma out of here! Now!
I'm telling you!
Stay still until we get back!
He's about to die!
Later, losers!
Choji! Ino! Hurry up!
I'll use my medical ninjutsu!
Right!
No... more...
I'm done...
Even I know that...
You all must realize it, too.
Shut up! Don't speak!
Ino!
Okay!
Ino...
They got four vital spots.
There's nothing more I can do...
Now I think I finally realize...
why the Third did... what he did...
I... always took too long...
I have some last words...
I'd like to say...
to Ino, Choji and Shikamaru...
- Sensei, you shouldn't talk anymore!
- Choji!
Ino, you, too.
These are Asuma-sensei's last words...
Listen carefully.
Ino...
Yes...
You're strong-willed, but dependable...
Both Choji and Shikamaru...
They're clumsy...
so please take care of them...
Yes...
And don't let Sakura beat you...
Not in ninjutsu or romance.
Yes!
Choji...
You're a kind man who cares
for his comrades...
That's why...
you'll become a shinobi
who's stronger than anyone else.
Have more confidence... in yourself.
Okay...
And... you may need to diet a little.
That might be impossible... but I'll try!
And... Shikamaru...
You're so sharp...
and have great instincts as a shinobi...
You could definitely become Hokage.
Well... you're lazy...
so you'd probably hate it...
I never once... beat you... at shogi...
Oh yeah... about the "King"...
I'll tell you who the "King" is...
Lend me your ear.
Asuma... you...!
That's why...
I'm counting on you, Shikamaru...
It doesn't matter now, does it?
Even though I quit smoking...
They're in my pouch...
I want one last smoke...
Oh! Sorry about that.
I'm Asuma Sarutobi,
and I'll be leading Team 10 from today.
It's not going to be easy,
so I hope you're all ready!
Oh, please don't cry!
All I said was that I'm going to be strict!
The smoke is getting in our eyes!
More rice! And four more orders
of barbecue ribs!
Thanks for waiting!
Choji, have you ever heard
of the word restraint?!
The bill went up to at least 3,000 ryo.
I'm saying this not because I'm stingy.
I'm just worried about you.
If you keep eating like this,
eventually you're going to be fa--!
That word is taboo!
"Fa-" what?!
Is there something wrong, Shikamaru?!
O-Oh... H-He said
you can order the deluxe course meal.
What--?!
Wow! Really?!
Asuma-sensei, thank you for treating!
Waiter, bring two deluxe course meals
with extra rice, please!
I'm stuffed! I'm satisfied!
Here...
Oh...
Who are they for?!
Oh... nobody in particular...
S-See you later...
Say "Hi" to Kurenai-sensei for me!
What?! How did... you know that...?!
Shogi?! What a pain...
You can create a variety of situations
by utilizing the individual characteristics
of the various pieces.
It's the perfect game for
a person like you
who's good at coming up with strategies.
You should be able to figure out
most of the rules if you read this book.
The rest you'll pick up as you play.
It'll be troublesome, but...
I'll have it down in ten minutes.
I-I lost...
You don't have to go easy on me...
Seriously.
You're the only one who passed
the Chunin Exam this time.
As your Jonin team leader,
I'm very proud of you.
Ino and Choji,
you two keep working hard!
Choji, Ino, you guys did well...
And now along with Shikamaru
who passed last time,
all members of Team 10
are legitimate Chunin.
And now... I will no longer be
in charge of you guys.
From here on,
each of you will become a captain
and lead new teams.
These earrings are a present for you three. Congratulations!
Don't ever forget that
you were members of Team 10!
Sensei!
He died as a true shinobi.
After all... I hate cigarettes...
The smoke... gets in my eyes...
Contact the relevant parties
about the funeral.
I'll tell Kurenai...
No... I'll do it.
I'll tell her.
I have a message for her
from Captain Asuma...
Yes!
Yeah! I'm kind of getting
the hang of it!
I see... So that was
your idea, huh?
You formed the Rasengan
by using a clone
to handle the change in form
while you released the chakra.
Right! I just needed a third clone
to handle the Wind Nature Transformation.
If I can't look left and right by myself...
then I just needed to create clones
to look left and right and
divide up the responsibility!
So my shadow clone stunt earlier
gave you a hint, huh?
That being said,
only Naruto has both the chakra
and the skill with shadow clones
for that method to work.
I couldn't do it like that.
I bet even the Fourth Hokage couldn't.
But he...
Just what I'd expect
from the Number One
Most Unpredictable Ninja, Naruto.
I'm not sure how to say it...
I've really started to
take a liking to you!
Don't say weird stuff like that
out of nowhere, you creep!
The jutsu I went to the trouble of creating
got messed up because you freaked me out!
Uhh, I didn't mean it like that...
Whoa, stay back!
I don't know quite how to say it...
Well...
No!
For crying out loud...
What are those two doing...?
I have a message for you.
Just a minute...
What's going on?
Kakashi-senpai!
We must stop the training for now
and head back to the village!
What?!
Asuma Sarutobi...
... is dead.