What happened here anyway?
What kind of battle would cause this?
Two Sharingan users...
Is the battle between the Uchiha Clan...
this intense?
Where's Sasuke?
I don't detect any other chakra
besides ours in this area.
There's still a faint smell left, but...
We were too late...
Naruto...
Why?
Why is it that I can never
reach Sasuke?
Kakashi-senpai...
If there is even a faint scent
that lingers from Sasuke...
Yeah... that's right.
No way can we give up
after coming this far.
We'll see this through until the end.
Until there's absolutely
no trace of Sasuke's scent.
Byakugan!
Nothing... Please, find him.
Sasuke...
Yeah... I know.
There's no trace of Sasuke's scent.
Damn it...
Where did you go?
We've done what we could...
Let's go back to the Hidden Leaf...
Sasuke...
That seat is reserved for me...
Lord Utakata!
Tonbei is looking for you.
I'm counting on you.
Not again.
They sure went through
a lot of trouble
setting up so many traps in
such an open field.
Someone is breaking through our traps
and approaching our fort.
Just in case, in accordance with
the late master's instructions,
I have alerted the Hidden Leaf.
It's impossible for any ordinary person
to get close to our fort.
However, if the enemy does succeed
in getting here...
The three of us, including Lord Utakata,
just have to fight together!
We'll turn the tables on them!
Why are they targeting us?
What is their purpose?
Most likely...
the Forbidden Jutsu that has been
passed down to our clan.
All these traps, then as you near
the fort, there's a deep ravine...
On top of which is
a barrier beyond that.
Talk about being overly cautious.
Don't you think so, Nango?
Yeah...
You're just not a man of many words...
are you?
Chushin, enough of your rambling.
A loose tongue is a sign of
an empty head.
I'd say you're the one who looks bad
each time you open your mouth.
Benten...
Going through the extremes to
protect something is proof of its value!
Get into your positions.
That must be it...
What?! The barrier has been broken.
These guys... are not ordinary people.
Benten!
Leave them to me!
Next is mountain climbing.
Lady Hotaru, take this...
In order to protect the Forbidden Jutsu
that your grandfather passed down,
you and Lord Utakata must escape
to our hidden village.
What about you?
I will follow immediately.
Now you must hurry...
No! If we're to escape,
the three of us will go together.
The enemy is at our doorstep.
This is not the time for
self-indulgence.
You're not coming?
Go, Lady Hotaru.
Lord Utakata!
Please... take care of Lady Hotaru.
The debt I owe you will be repaid...
Phew, that was close.
This isn't going to be
an ordinary climb, Akaboshi.
I can't wait to see what's waiting
for us at the summit.
Lady Hotaru...
Please be extremely careful
while traveling.
You must not leave Lord Utakata's side.
Tonbei, you must follow us later.
Promise me that!
Lady Hotaru, think only of
your own safety. Nothing else!
Lord En no Gyoja... I promise to buy
as much time as possible...
So I can protect Lady Hotaru!
Lady Tsunade, we received this...
What?!
Lady Katsuyu!
Oh, Kakashi...
What? Lady Katsuyu came
all the way to greet us?
No, she didn't.
There must be trouble.
Because...
Lady Tsunade only uses
Lady Katsuyu during emergencies.
I get it! So there's an urgent situation.
I know how you feel, Shino...
When you aren't allowed to finish
what you wanted to say...
A secret treaty?
During the Third Great Ninja War,
a certain jutsu passed down
by En no Gyoja, the leader
of the Tsuchigumo Clan,
wiped out an entire village.
The Third Hokage demanded that
such a dangerous jutsu
be classified as a Forbidden Jutsu.
And in exchange, it was agreed that
the Hidden Leaf would provide aid
to the Tsuchigumo clan
in time of danger.
Kakashi, you are to report to the village
for details from your last mission.
Understood.
We're battling against time.
Team 7 will go with Captain Yamato
and head for
Mount Katsuragi immediately.
Yes, sir!
Why aren't you coming,
Kakashi-sensei?
Is it a problem if it's just me?
That's not what I meant...
En no Gyoja passed away a year ago
and the fort on Mount Katsuragi
is occupied by his granddaughter,
Hotaru, and her servant.
Whoever is attacking the fort
is undoubtedly
after En no Gyoja's Forbidden Jutsu.
We must prevent the theft of
the Forbidden Jutsu at all costs.
Why did you send Naruto too?
It's a countermeasure against
the Akatsuki.
Did this old man intend to
protect the fort all by himself?
Still, this took longer than planned.
Let's hurry and start the search.
That's the Tsuchigumo clan's fort?!
Captain Yamato!
Hm?
What happened here?
It doesn't look like
this is from a fight...
Sai, how about it?
There are fresh footprints headed
towards the fort...
The enemy is a group of four.
These are from traps surrounding
the fort.
It looks like the enemy avoided them.
Then there are more in this area?
We'll just follow the trail of trap marks.
I get it!
That way, we'll get to the fort
without encountering any fresh traps!
Where is the Forbidden Jutsu
of En no Gyoja?!
You lost, so 'fess up.
I know nothing.
Playing dumb is useless!
The granddaughter.
That's right. En no Gyoja
has a granddaughter.
Did you let her escape?
She has the Forbidden Jutsu?
Is that it? Hey!
Enough. I know where to find her.
We're out of time.
It seems we have some interference.
It's a dead-end, Captain Yamato.
We'll just lay a bridge across it.
Wood Style!
Have to hand it to you, Captain Yamato!
Aren't you glad I was here?
Don't rub it in.
Hang on, old man!
It's weak, but he still has a pulse.
He'll live.
We were one step too late...
Sai, check the area to see
if there are any others.
Right.
You've come to...
We are from the Hidden Leaf
and were dispatched to
provide assistance.
You are Lady Hotaru's servant,
I presume?
I am... Tonbei...
L-Lady Hotaru is headed for the
hidden village of the Tsuchigumo clan.
There is an escape route with
a collapsed entry
in the back of the mansion.
Lady Hotaru went... through there...
I understand. We will follow her.
Sakura, stay here and tend
to Tonbei's injuries.
Right.
Naruto, Sai, let's go.
Lord Utakata, there's something
I'd like to ask you...
Will you teach me jutsu even
after we get to the hidden village?
I don't recall teaching you anything.
But back at the fort,
you trained me in many things.
You did that on your own...
Also, when we reach the village,
I will no longer be needed.
There's no one stronger than you
in the village!
And I want you to teach me.
That time, when you saved me...
I didn't save you that time...
But...!
The ninja who attacked were coming
after me, not you.
I just fought in order to protect myself.
Even so, after watching you,
I knew I wanted to be strong
like you. No, I must.
That is why I wish to learn your jutsu...
Being strong is enough for you?
Huh?
You might regret being taught
by a wanted man.
I trust you, Lord Utakata.
No matter what happens,
I will always consider you my master.
Don't call me your master!
Crap!
Step away from that girl!
A Shadow Clone?
What a bother...
Give it up and be captured--!
No!
He is not an enemy!
Naruto!
Pardon him for jumping to conclusions.
Tonbei had told us only
about Lady Hotaru...
Tonbei is alive and well?
Yes. He's under the care
of our medic.
I'm glad...
From here on, you have
our protection as well.
Hey, I'm really sorry.
I can leave the rest to you then...
Huh?
Sure thing!
I always fulfill my missions...
Huh?
Thanks... Take care.
Lord Utakata!
Hey, where are you going?
Can't you at least stay with me until
we reach the hidden village?
Those guys are strong...
You can rely on them.
I don't need guards!
I need someone to teach me jutsu!
Come with me, please...
I'll be more serious than ever
in my training!
I'll endure anything and
I promise never to cry! And...
And I'll never call you
my master... ever... again...
Stupid Master Utakata!
I told you not to call me that...
I'm not foolish enough to
be called master.
So... the girl has bodyguards now...
I never imagined the Hidden Leaf's
bodyguards would reach her so quickly.
But even so,
there are only four of them.
I say we get rid of them all and take
the Forbidden Jutsu from the girl, Boss.
Don't be so impatient.
Then, what's the plan?
That Forbidden Jutsu is worth
more than money to us.
We can't afford to fail.
That jutsu displayed unbelievable power
during the last great war.
If we steal it, all of us could
go from a motley band of thieves
to lords of our own domains.
But...
The Hidden Leaf people...
Could the Forbidden Jutsu
have fallen into their hands?
Very unlikely.
The previous Hokage and En no Gyoja
forged a secret treaty
to protect the Forbidden Jutsu
at all cost.
The Hidden Leaf is
only fulfilling that promise.
But... if they're the vanguards
of that treaty,
then those bodyguards
must be skilled fighters.
Yeah... and reinforcements
are sure to come!
Nango! Benten!
Have you guys lost your nerve
before the fight even begins?!
Seems it's not just your face,
but your head's bad, too.
What'd you say?!
Consider all the possibilities and
use what you've got up here.
Stop fighting amongst yourselves.
Have you forgotten? We're a team.
We can't afford to lose even one of us.
And it's our unity and
combination jutsu
that helped us live through
chaotic times.
Yeah, fine...
There's no need to rush.
I already know what
their destination is.
They're headed for the Hidden Village
of the Tsuchigumo Clan.
The Hidden Leaf will leave
on their own
once they arrive at the destination.
But won't it be a problem if they
manage to enter the hidden village?
Akaboshi. Seems you still
don't understand humans.
To us, that Forbidden Jutsu
is a treasure,
but to normal people,
it's nothing but a nuisance.
What'd you do that for?!
That's what I want to ask you!
Why are you following me?!
Why? I'm your bodyguard,
that's why!
I'll say it again.
I don't need a bodyguard.
I can protect myself just fine.
You Hidden Leaf people
may leave now!
We can't just say,
"Oh, is that so?" and leave.
Why not?!
Really, please don't bother with me.
We're not bothering you,
we're just guarding!
Naruto, let's do as she says
and leave.
How come?!
We have no choice.
W-Wait here for a sec.
Are you sure?
The enemy could still be close by.
Now, now, don't worry.
Hey!
I get it. Well then, we'll be leaving.
Fine.
No!
No! Get it off! Get it off of me!
There.
Wh-What was that thing?
A mountain leech.
There are a lot of them around here,
so it's not unusual for them
to rain down on you.
Rain down?
Yeah. See you!
Be careful on your way.
All by... yourself!
What'd you step on it for?
Naruto, please stay by me...
I can't touch something like that.
I just can't.
Absolutely impossible.
If leeches rain down on me,
I want you to block them, Naruto.
But you said you didn't need
a bodyguard.
Just until we get out of this forest!
Hmm... What should I do?
Please, Naruto!
I suppose I could...
But now that I think about it,
Lord Utakata would still be
my bodyguard
if you all hadn't shown up.
Utakata... The guy who uses
that weird jutsu?
He is my master. I want to become
strong like Lord Utakata.
Hmm... Your master, eh?
There's no such thing as
a good master.
Take my master, for example...
He's a perv and totally irresponsible...
And on top of that,
he gets carried away a lot.
But well... as a ninja,
he's very strong, dependable,
and above all, kind.
Guess you can't judge a person
by their appearance.
If I could,
I wouldn't mind becoming
a ninja like him some day.
You like your master, too,
don't you, Naruto?
Like him? Who could like
an old pervert like him?
I, too, want to be strong
like Lord Utakata.
If I become strong,
I can master the jutsu
Grandfather left to me.
If I do that...
I could even restore
the Tsuchigumo Clan.
For someone so young, it looks like you're
carrying some heavy responsibilities.
By the way, where could
your master have gone off to?
I don't know.
For some reason,
when I call Lord Utakata "master,"
he gets very upset.
Sai! What's with the numbers?!
You can stop with the leeches now.
Hmm... Does he mean
he wants bigger ones?
Huh? No? Then...
For crying out loud.
Enough is enough...
Huh?!
What are you doing, you idiot Sai!
Read the mood, will ya?!
Come on, you guys...
Now I can go back to
my drifting lifestyle...
She should be okay
if she's with him.
Persistent guys...
What is... that jutsu?
It's amazing!
Now they know my location...
For the time being,
I must stay out of view as I move.
Are you all right?!
That wound...
Allow me to treat it back at our fort.
That's the least I can do
for coming to my aid.
Fort?
Please hang on!
I'm going to get help.
Don't move from this spot!
- Damn! I used too much chakra.
- I'll be right back...
You need to be treated immediately.
Come to our fort...
Looks like no one's coming after me...
My wounds have also healed...
Guess it's time to...
Please take me as your student!
After seeing your fight the other day, I
have nothing but respect for you, master!
Master?
Yes, Master Utakata!
Don't ever call me that again...
Huh? But...
Don't you ever call me master again!
I have no intention of taking
a student.
Lord... Utakata...
But that would be forgetting your
debt to me for accepting my hospitality.
Is it right to eat free meals
and drink free sake?!
So, what would you like
on today's menu of free food?!
You sure hit where it hurts.
Tonbei taught me to say
that if you refused to take me
as your student...
So that old man was in
on this, too, eh?
Look here, you haven't had
any training at all...
If you're talking about ninjutsu,
I have received some training
from Tonbei.
Then why don't you study
with the old man?
It wasn't enough...
That's why I'm asking you!
Okay, then,
try walking on that pond.
On the pond... All right!
Good grief.
At this rate, she won't be able
to do it before I leave.
Lord Utakata! Lord Utakata!
See? Look, Lord Utakata!
You... practiced all night?
Yes. So now will you make me
your student?
N-No. This is just the first step...
Next is this jutsu.
Water Style: Raging Waves!
Amazing!
If you can't even do this,
you can't be my student.
All right!
Water Style: Raging Waves!
Huh?
Huh? Why doesn't it work?
This jutsu cannot be done unless
you possess the Water Style chakra.
Don't take it personally...
Huh? Rain?
Lord Utakata!
Whoa! You're too close!
Please watch this!
Water Style: Raging Waves!
Will you make me your student now?!
Ugh... no... I...
N-Not yet...
W-Wait, Lord Utakata!
I figured you'd be coming to
see me about now.
Come on, give me a break.
What's the big idea,
putting that kid up to that?
I have a big favor.
Would you stay here and
protect Lady Hotaru?
That's... quite a troublesome thing
to ask in return.
Lady Hotaru... carries a heavy destiny.
Judging by the way
you defeated the thieves,
I know you are a person
of extraordinary skills.
And above all, you lack greed.
As you can see, I am already
advanced in years.
If you take her as your student,
Lady Hotaru will be safe.
Won't you please do me this favor?
I'm sorry, but that won't be possible.
I'm sure you must've noticed it.
I'm being pursued.
Death gathers all around me.
How could you even think of leaving
that child with me?
I see.
And besides,
the relationship between
a master and student...
is not something you can count on.
Master! What are you
trying to do, Master!
M-Master?!
I must've dozed off...
Do you really think we can be lords
of our own domain?
Damn right! Isn't that right, Akaboshi?
Yeah. Even if we sold it off,
we'd still get enough money to live
the rest of our lives in leisure!
Hey, what's wrong?
Be on guard!
There's someone nearby.
There!
What the--?!
Damn! What's going on?!
Who the hell are you?!
He doesn't seem to be one of
the Hidden Leaf's reinforcements...
You don't think this guy's after
the Forbidden Jutsu as well?
Oh... The fact that you know about
the Forbidden Jutsu means...
You guys are the band of thieves?
Makes me wonder, though.
Is it that awesome?
That Forbidden Jutsu?
If that's the case,
I think I want that Forbidden Jutsu, too.
What? Are you planning
to grab it from us?
So? What should we do?
Go ahead and kill him!
After him!
What is this slime?
I've been blinded!
Spread out! We'll surround him!
This chakra flow...
Their movements have become faster
all of a sudden.
Barrier jutsu?!
Let's go!
Damn!
It's over!
How far do you intend to follow me?
How far? You're the one who said
until we clear the forest.
I did say that, but...
Thing is, there's only forest
between the fort and the hidden village!
You people, too?
Looks like we'll complete our mission
without incident.
Oh! We reached the village!
What? No one here?
Hello!
Is anyone... anybody here?
Sai.
Yes...
Hey! Hotaru is back! Isn't anyone here?!
Hmm...
Okay! Hold on a sec!
Oh, Naruto!
Good grief...
Emergency! Fire! There's a fire!
Oh, so you were here.
Sorry to startle all of you!
But you all wouldn't come on out.
Hotaru is back after being away
a long time!
You should welcome her!
What? What's the matter
with all of you?
Hotaru!
Uncle...
Thank you for all you've done.
I am responsible for this village.
I heard from Lord En no Gyoja about
what to do if the worse happens.
Please leave the rest to us.
All right then, we will be on our way.
Uh, no, just a moment. We
haven't had a chance to thank you.
- At least let us...
- We appreciate your thoughtfulness.
However, we left our teammate back
at Mount Katsuragi.
I see... That's too bad.
Come on, let's return to Sakura.
Oh, okay...
Naruto.
I...
You'll be fine.
Thank you.
What's the matter, Naruto?
Sorry, Captain Yamato.
Would you mind going on ahead
without me?
I'm returning to that village.
Return?
Something keeps... bothering me.
I can't help but think about
the way those villagers looked at her.
Wait, Naruto!
You must be exhausted after
your long journey, Hotaru.
Come...
Umm...
Follow me.
What is the Chief thinking?
Does he really intend to
shelter her here?
You've got to be kidding.
If something happens, we'll get--
Hush! You talk too much.
Should I have not come back?
Of course not.
You're finally home.
You must get some rest.
Thank you.
Well then...
We finally meet the granddaughter
of En no Gyoja.
Who's there?!
We knew you would rely
on this village.
You're the ones who attacked the fort!
Someone, help! Bandits!
Uncle, please open the door! Uncle!
Somebody!
It's useless.
Now, hand over the Forbidden Jutsu.
No!
Don't give us trouble!
Hey, hey... Be more gentle
when handling a lady.
You should talk.
Bro.
So this is the hidden jutsu in question...
So it was rigged, eh?
Sassy kid...
After her! Don't let her get away.
To think they had already made their move
on the Tsuchigumo village...
I have to get away from here.
So she ran into the forest...
Found you, girlie.
Water Style: Raging Waves!
Don't let a petty jutsu like that
bring you down, Chushin.
Shut up! She just caught me
by surprise, is all.
Playtime is over. Tell me.
Where is the Forbidden Jutsu?
What a pain.
I'd talk now if I were you.
Benten might look like a girl,
but he's scary when he's mad.
I won't talk!
That is my people's last hope.
Argh! This is getting ridiculous.
If you don't want to talk,
I'll help you get into the mood.
Don't kill her.
That's all up to her.
What?!
What's all this racket?
Can't a guy even take a nap?
Lord Utakata!
You! You're still alive?
We got you back there for sure!
Well, sorry to disappoint you.
It's not like I want to fight you guys...
But I have business with her too.
What? She's gone?!
What's up with that?!
I'm not sure myself.
This is where I hid Hotaru.
Then there was a loud noise
and when I rushed over, she was...
All right. I'll help you find her.
Tell me where you've searched already.
Well, um... We haven't started
the search yet.
What?!
Why didn't you search
for her immediately?
Judging by the damage,
it's obvious something happened!
Yes... but...
What's wrong with you?!
Isn't she one of your people?!
Enough, Naruto.
Yelling won't help.
Captain Yamato.
What are you doing here?
We were also worried,
so we rushed back.
It seems we were right.
When did you last see her?
Just a while ago.
After you brought Hotaru here,
I showed her to this room.
Then not much time has passed.
Let's hurry, Naruto.
But...
Her safety is our main concern
right now.
Lord Utakata, you came to save me!
That's not quite the case,
but we'd better do something here.
What's with this guy?
I thought our jutsu hit him that time.
Are you scheming to steal
our treasure away from us?
I won't let you.
Acid Flower!
Nango, come back!
Oh... It missed.
Why you--!
Surround him!
We'll bring him down this time.
He's outside our formation!
So long.
Not so fast!
Lord Utakata!
He's fast.
They can't have gone far.
Let's go after them.
Forget it.
Boss.
Why? Are you just going to let
our treasure get away?
This is the Mist's Bingo Book.
We've stumbled across
a very interesting guy.
Meaning his head's worth enough
to be in this book?
Wow... 50 million ryo.
We're in luck.
The girl's jutsu is worth a fortune,
and now this.
We'll be rolling in money.
But with a bounty this high,
he's bound to be a formidable foe.
Hah! Don't get cold feet now!
This is our big chance.
What? I'm just...
Hey! Pipe down.
So what'll we do, Boss?
Let's see...
It's my fault. I...
I should've returned right away.
Can I ask you a question?
Our mission was to protect the girl
until she reached
Tsuchigumo village safely, right?
That was supposed to be it.
But if we can't guarantee her safety,
then the mission is meaningless.
This mission is based on a treaty
which was drawn up
by the Third Hokage and En no Gyoja
of the Tsuchigumo Clan.
So if the current Tsuchigumo Clan
cannot protect her,
then it's our job to do so.
Sai, can you scan the entire area
and search for her?
Understood.
Ninja Art: Super Beast Scroll.
Hold on...
We'll find you for sure!
Lord Utakata, where are we?
Wow...
So high!
This should be good.
I thought I was done for.
You are amazing, after all.
Don't get me wrong.
I didn't mean to save you.
Then why did you come?
Well... Let's just say
I became curious
about this Forbidden Jutsu
those guys seem to want so badly.
You're lying. You're not like that.
Never can tell.
There's not a person in the world
who doesn't love the smell of money.
Don't pretend to be a villain.
You have a knack for putting me
off balance.
But what will you do now?
Those guys aren't the only ones
who'll target that jutsu.
Others are bound to turn up.
You're right.
That's why I must get stronger.
That's why I want to become
your stu--
Stop right there. I'm not listening.
Besides, this keepsake of
your grandfather or whatever...
Why are you so determined to protect it?
Well...
It's to honor the wishes
of my master.
Grandfather was also my first master.
A master and student must
be one in thought.
That's why I want to fulfill the dream
that my grandfather could not.
In order to restore
the Tsuchigumo Clan,
I cannot lose this jutsu.
Hmph... One in thought?
Such a stupid delusion.
Where are you going?
I'm under no obligation
to stick around.
If you want to play master and student,
go somewhere else.
This isn't a game!
I'm serious about you!
I want to call you my master!
You can't stop me, you know.
I know that.
But my feelings won't change.
That is why...
Huh?!
I-Idiot! What are you doing?!
I want you to see me...
Everything about me.
Hotaru... you...
How could they?
No one knows about this...
But I didn't want to hide it from you.
Please, Lord Utakata...
- I...
- Don't say it!
Damn it!
Hidden Jutsu: Kirisame.
Crap!
As I thought...
This rain is Kirisame...
Utakata.
There is no escape for you now.
What's going on?
We cannot keep the village
waiting any longer.
You guys sure are persistent.
Stay back, Hotaru.
Water Style: Water Whip!
Hotaru!
I'll say it once more.
Cease resisting and come with us.
If you try anything, this girl will die.
Lord Utakata...
Let me make it clear that
she is nothing to me.
I couldn't care less what happens.
I see. We'll see about that.
I see that worked.
Now return to the village with us.
No matter how many times you ask,
the answer will be the same.
Then we have no choice.
Lightning Style: Earth Flash!
Lord Utakata!
Don't take this personally.
We absolutely must take him
back to our village.
Such cruelty... Please stop.
This isn't enough to kill him.
I'm just restricting a little of
his strength.
Stop it! Just what did Lord Utakata
do anyway?!
Utakata is a heinous criminal
who killed his master
and escaped from the village.
We need to tie him up. Get started.
- Yes sir!
Rasengan!
What?!
What's going on?
You guys are pretty rotten,
taking a hostage.
Naruto!
Sorry to keep you waiting!
You people...
Are you all right?
Yeah...
But why are you here?
You were also worried about Hotaru?
Yeah, right. It was just
sheer coincidence.
But... these guys didn't come here
for Hotaru.
What do you mean?
And who are these guys?
That mask...
I see... So their target is...
Master!
Why are the Hidden Leaf here?
Please let that girl go.
No!
In that case! We'll take her back...
by force!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Ninja Art:
Super Beast Scroll!
I'll take the one in the middle.
You handle the ones around him.
We'll attack together.
Got it. But... these Black Ops are...
Let's see how it goes for
a bit longer...
We need to find out what
their purpose is.
Master...
Hidden Jutsu: Kirisame!
What's with this rain?!
It's a jutsu that eats away the chakra
it comes into contact with.
It's called the Kirisame Jutsu!
Why you...!
Go!
Stop! Don't be hasty!
Let's go!
Water Whip!
Wood Style!
Master!
I need you to stay quiet
for a while.
What the hell are you doing?!
Naruto!
Wait.
We are on a mission to guard
that girl.
Please return her to us.
Yeah! Give her back, you!
You are ANBU Black Ops
from the Hidden Mist,
and the one you seek
is this man, correct?
Huh? ANBU Black Ops...
from the Hidden Mist?
I get it now...
So that means he is a...
Utakata is a rogue ninja from
the Hidden Mist
and is listed in the Bingo Book.
These men have come after him.
So these guys...
aren't ninja who are after her?
They're after Utakata?
She has nothing to do with you.
Please release her.
Then we'll exchange her for him.
No.
That, we can't do.
What?!
That girl seems to be very fond
of this man.
If we hand him over to you,
no doubt, she will pursue you.
Then we'll be in trouble.
So we can't turn him over.
Then... neither can we...
If we resort to force,
it may have major effects beyond this
village, and erupt into a full-scale war.
Are you willing to go that far?
The Hidden Mist?
Captain Yamato.
Men of the Hidden Leaf...
I command this unit from
behind the scenes.
I am Tsurugi, head of
the Hidden Mist ANBU Black Ops.
It is certainly not our desire
to escalate this
into a war between nations.
Certainly, we can still negotiate?
Yes, I agree.
You're...
Let us meet. Just you and I...
And Utakata.
Understood.
You two stay here.
Then until you complete
your mission,
we will postpone
apprehending Utakata.
As soon as her safety
is guaranteed,
I will notify you.
Please keep in mind that should
you go back on our agreement,
war between our nations
may be inevitable.
I understand.
Hmm...
You people are absurd.
I'll do as I please.
Not likely.
Until our mission is over,
you will remain with us.
After that, it's all between you
and the Hidden Mist.
Fine.
Tell me...
Just what did you do
in Hidden Mist Village?
That... is none of your business.
My apologies.
I want to speak to him alone.
I'll wait over there.
Captain Yamato!
How did your talk go?
Oh, it went well.
Where are those two?
Having a discussion.
Is it true...
that Utakata is a rogue ninja?
Yeah...
Don't give us trouble.
Return to the Hidden Mist.
Humph! No, thanks!
Why would I go back
just to get killed...?
The village has changed.
We no longer have the practices
that once gave us the nickname,
"Blood Mist Village."
But while things may seem peaceful,
it is a delicate power balance
between the Five Great Nations.
The importance of what you possess
increases each year,
and research into its use
has also been stepped up.
The village needs that power,
so you certainly won't be killed.
I don't trust anyone anymore.
My master... tried to kill me...
along with that thing inside me.
I sacrificed myself for the sake
of the village.
I trusted my master's words...
and did as he ordered.
And he betrayed my trust...
he tried to kill me!
What?!
Th-This... power...
Wait!
Stop! Stop!
No, Utakata! He didn't...
Harusame didn't try to kill you.
It wasn't like that.
That cursed deed he performed on you...
He was trying to separate it
from you.
He was trying to save you.
Like I'd believe such a story...
You've grown senile.
I speak the truth...
My master... No, that man used me
and tried to kill me.
And in the aftermath... he died.
If you ask the villagers,
they will say I killed him.
Utakata... Return to the village.
Then you will know that
I am not lying.
No, thanks.
Then, we have no choice
but to kill you.
As you please.
And I will do as I please.
Master!
Let her go.
Yes, sir!
Master!
Enough!
Never call me that again.
Understand?
Men of the Hidden Leaf, as agreed,
we will retreat for now.
Let us pray that both our missions
are successful.
However, we will continue to
keep watch over you.
Understood.
Farewell.
Scatter!
Oh dear...
Now then, where do
we go from here?
It's best that we don't return
to the Tsuchigumo village.
Yes, you're right.
If it's no longer secure as a ninja
village, her safety is questionable.
Then it may be better to return to
Mount Katsuragi and rethink our stance.
I also wish to go back.
I want to make sure Tonbei
is all right.
Although, the ones after
the Forbidden Jutsu
may also go back to Katsuragi,
so it may not be safe either.
Let's join up with
Tonbei and Sakura,
then decide on our next move.
Utakata, you too.
Are you all right?
Uh-huh...
I wonder why he doesn't want me
to call him "Master."
Utakata is a heinous criminal
who killed his master
and escaped from the village.
Just what happened between...
Lord Utakata and his master?
We don't know what
the relationship is
between Utakata and
the Hidden Mist.
But that's not important.
If you've already decided
you want to be his student,
then who cares?
It matters.
I want to become strong.
In order to restore my clan's honor.
That's why I want to
learn from him.
I can tell. You want him to
teach you personally, right?
It's not like that...
Well, I felt the same way too.
I don't have any memories
of my parents.
Huh?
So maybe that's why...
when I traveled with the Pervy Sage...
I wondered if that's what
it felt like to have a parent.
And I acted spoiled
with him sometimes.
But training isn't that easy.
You have to think things
through yourself,
and learn the technique by yourself.
Otherwise, you'll never get better.
If the Pervy Sage hadn't been there,
I wouldn't even have realized
something that basic.
We're not alone...
Just the thought that
someone is nearby,
watching over us...
that alone makes us strong.
I understand how you feel.
I envy you, Naruto.
Just like you, I'm going to think of
Lord Utakata as my master and...
Hey... you look pale...
I'm... okay...
Hey!
You're burning up...
You're hurt!
Is it from that fight?!
Captain Yamato!
I'll see to her.
Can you go and get some
medicinal herbs?
The dokudami plant should be
abundant around here in the moist areas.
It has heart-shaped leaves
which are purple underneath.
The leaves are purple underneath, right?
Yes.
All right!
What's wrong?
Hotaru is injured...
Let us be.
All right...
Moist areas...
I guess I should search
by the riverbank!
There! That's have to be it.
Huh? What the hell?!
This is just Dokudami!
Aw man, there were lots
of 'em along the way!
Damn it!
I wasted so much time!
What the...?
What the hell is this...?
The Forbidden Jutsu of
the Tsuchigumo Clan
It was engraved...
into this child's very own body.
How could they do such a thing?
To hell with Forbidden Jutsu...
To hell with the clan...
To hell with one's master!
And all these selfish guys who
do atrocious things
to those who serve them
without a hint of remorse.
They think of us... as mere tools.
Tools... who don't speak.
Hotaru...