I'm coming in, Tsunade.
Jiraiya? Did you learn anything?
I discovered the whereabouts
of the Akatsuki leader.
What?! Is that true?!
Tell me more!
We'll use that information
to plan a surprise attack!
Don't be hasty, now.
This isn't like plotting
a sequel to your novel!
We don't have the time to waste!
Haste makes waste.
Especially with the stakes
this high...
Say, why don't we grab
a drink together?
Just you and me.
I'll tell you everything there.
You fool! I am the Hokage!
And you're asking me to go drinking
in the middle of the day?!
Have you no shame when
our ninja are on duty?!
You know...
You really ought to take your own words
a bit more to heart.
Drinking sake straight out
of the bottle...
Remember, you are the Hokage, right?
This Akatsuki leader is in
the Hidden Rain Village, correct?
Yes.
But that place conducts
thorough checks of anyone
entering and exiting their territory
and they track how long visitors stay.
Just preparing for the Joint
Chunin Exams is difficult each time
because the village is
so closed off to others.
Doesn't seem like a place where
the Akatsuki leader can move about freely.
However... because security is so strict,
they're able to keep other nations
from learning about their internal affairs,
and hence, keep a lid on any shame.
Shame?
It seems that land has seen
much internal strife,
and the village itself
has been split into two.
Word has it that the leader of one side
is also the leader of Akatsuki.
That land is surrounded by the three
great nations of Earth, Wind and Fire.
And from ages past, it has been
the battleground of their conflicts.
As a result, there has never been
domestic stability
and the number of refugees
is continually on the rise.
That is why I will infiltrate and verify
the information we have gathered.
Then we can plan strategy...
It's too dangerous to go alone!
I am one of the Legendary Sannin
of the Leaf.
You know what that means as well.
I'm sorry...
that you always get
the short end of the stick.
What's with you?!
I'm saying, you were
supposed to be Hokage.
The Third Hokage always wanted you
to be the next to--
I was never cut out for
that sort of thing.
Being on my own suits me too well...
You regretted not being able
to stop Orochimaru.
So all that time, you were tracking
his movements alone, isn't that right?
I no longer need to do so.
That means I get to release
the sequel to my novel sooner.
Fact is stranger than fiction, isn't it?
Who would have imagined that
Orochimaru would die...
Remember how the three of us would
go up against Old Man Third and...
The flat-chested Tsunade has
become the big-bosomed Hokage!
Times are changing by the second.
You were beautiful back then...
and now, you're a
fifty-something granny.
It pains me to see how all the memories
of your lost friends and loved ones
are stored inside
that big breast of yours.
And you know, the number
will continue to grow.
I guess I shouldn't
wallow in sadness.
My duty is to be a model
for the next generation
and to help them.
For that, I'd happily give my life.
It's what makes us old folks cool, see?
Your drinking habits are
worse than mine...
Want to stop and rest somewhere?
It's late. We have to go home.
- Okay!
Hey, wait up!
Akatsuki...
The leader is capable of organizing
a group so powerful...
Who knows how strong he may be?
You'll be walking right into
the enemy's territory.
Well then... I should set out.
Come back alive...
If I lost you too... I...
You'll cry for me?
That'll make me happy!
But I doubt that it'll be
like the time Dan died.
You idiot!
Then how about making a bet with me?
You bet that I will die.
After all, you always lose.
But if I make it back alive...
Joking! I'm just joking!
You know, I'm grateful to you.
Rejection makes a man stronger.
In other words,
you can't call yourself a real man
unless you can laugh off stuff like that.
Better yet, make a joke out of it.
So a man's duty is to be strong?
Kind of...
And besides... men aren't the only ones
who seek happiness.
Humph... Stop trying to act so cool.
Without a woman,
you guys can't be rejected.
That's so true.
If anything happens,
contact me through your toad.
I'll rush over myself.
No need for that.
You must not leave here.
The village relies on you now.
There are other candidates
for Hokage.
There can be no stability
if the Hokage keeps changing.
Right now, you are the only one
who can be Hokage.
There's Kakashi.
And eventually, there's also Naruto...
You're really sold on Naruto, aren't you?
But Naruto still has a long way to go,
even though you gave him your necklace.
You have high hopes
for him too...
You taught him the Rasengan.
Oh that... Well, call it nostalgia.
It reminded me of the days
when I taught Minato.
Minato Namikaze...
True, Naruto does resemble him.
Minato was a genius that appears
only once in a generation.
There won't be another like him.
He was kind-hearted,
but had nerves of steel.
He rose to become
the Fourth Hokage so swiftly.
I've never been a parent, so I don't know
much about these things...
but if he had been my son,
I think I'd have been awfully proud.
Now that you mention it...
Naruto might not resemble him, after all.
Rather than a son
you boast about,
he'd be the problem child,
always up to mischief.
Naruto is more like his mother...
Wasn't she a former kunoichi
from the Land of Eddies...?
Yeah... His personality and ninjutsu style
is just like Kushina Uzumaki.
Yes... that's her name!
That talkative, red-haired rascal...
She was such a tomboy.
Kushina grew up to be a beauty,
but Naruto looks like his father.
I can see Naruto's father in him...
To me, it feels as though
I'm looking at my grandson.
It is being passed on...
the will of the Leaf,
from the past to the future.
I guess I'll be off.
Oh, that's right!
I had one last warning for you.
Huh?
Beware of the Foundation.
Yeah... I know.
Ah... Good then.
Farewell.
Infiltration is a success.
That was quite easy.
Now then...
What is it?
Someone is disturbing my rain.
This chakra... He is strong.
All right, where do I search first?
Hot, hot!
I'll have one of these, Granny...
Thank you.
I haven't seen your face before.
You're not from around here?
Well... I'm a writer.
I travel around and write about regional
cuisine and products for a magazine.
Hmm... I see.
And how do you like my pork buns?
Oh, they're delicious. I heard
about them, and they're amazing.
I know! Aren't they?
I'd like to introduce them
in our magazine. Is that okay?
In a magazine?
Yes. Although, once I write about them,
you'll have such a big crowd
you won't be able to rest.
I-I see. That would be a problem!
It sure is peaceful around here.
Yes.
This village is no longer plagued by war
thanks to Lord Pain.
We're so grateful to him.
Pain?
Yes, Lord Pain.
What happened to
Hanzo of the Salamander?
Huh?
Hanzo of the...
Thanks for your time, Granny.
Thank you for waiting.
Say...
What is that?
Huh?
Oh, that is Lady Angel.
You don't know?
They say it's good fortune to
put up origami
modeled after the Lady Angel
at the shop entrance.
An Angel...
What is going on?
This land isn't divided into two.
Instead, it's already united.
And the Hidden Rain Village
used to have a leader
named Hanzo of the Salamander...
It seems I need to check
this place out very thoroughly.
Konan... When I stop the rain,
seek out the intruder with your jutsu.
Got it.
Ready?
Yes...
What a downpour.
Want to get a drink while
we wait for the rain to stop?
There are no bars at
a low ground level like this.
We'll have to go up higher.
Then let's head upwards
for some cover.
But are you sure?
Didn't you tell your wife
you're heading straight home?
Heh! It's okay.
It's an emergency mission!
I never heard of drinking
being a mission...
Heh heh... We're in luck.
Welcome.
Just two.
Give us sake and some chasers.
Today's not Sunday, is it?
Something must have come up
for Lord Pain.
Maybe he's leaving for another nation.
But it never rained on other days before.
Maybe it's something that
requires that much power.
But if it keeps on raining like this...
Hey! Careful with the words!
Lord Pain works tirelessly
for the people of this village.
Show some tolerance!
Guess you're right...
Sorry to keep you fellows waiting.
Hey...
But there's nothing!
No, no... You're in luck!
Today, we have
our grand opening special.
What? Really?!
What kind of service?
The Club Frog Special Torture Service.
You...! Who the hell are you?!
I'm the one asking the questions.
And I have a lot to ask.
Now! Run!
What?!
Give it up.
Do it, Konan.
Right...
Now then...
From your use of kunai,
I'm guessing you two are lowly ninja.
Am I correct?
Does that rogue ninja mark signify
that you're loyal to Pain?
Damn it!
Where are we?!
Inside the belly of a frog.
You'll never be found here...
No one will come to your aid!
Who the hell are you?!
I told you I'll be the one
asking questions. Remember?
Wh-What are you going to do
with that feather?
Tickle you!
If you don't want to die laughing,
then you'll answer my questions.
Regarding your leader... Pain.
Now talk! Tell me everything
you know about Pain!
Bear with it!
I won't... rat... on my comrade...
You're pretty stubborn, aren't you?
Well, I have another trick.
Wh-What are you going to do?!
If you refuse to talk, then I'll
use my jutsu and turn you into frogs!
Turn... you... to frogs...
What do you want from us?!
Now talk!
We may be lowly ninja,
but we'll never betray our comrades!
No matter what you do to us!
So don't take us lightly!
Hmm... Then I have no choice...
Ninja Art: Toad Transformation!
Stop!!
You bastard! That's not fair!
Now then, you're next.
Are you ready?
The highest tower in the west...
Lord Pain is there.
That's what people say...
Huh? What?! You sure turned
on him easily... didn't you?
Well, no matter...
What did you mean by,
"that's what people say"?
Actually... No one really knows
that much about Lord Pain.
What do you mean?
They say he is of the Fuma Clan lineage.
But no one really knows
what he looks like.
And some claim that
he doesn't even exist.
I walked through the town a bit...
and everyone seems to worship him.
So don't lie!
In this town, Lord Pain is a god.
It's not a question of whether
he exists or not.
He always watches over us.
He has a representative do
all the ceremonial rites,
the speeches and the issuing of orders...
Through the Lady Angel!
Lady Angel...?
He's your leader, isn't he?
Why must he hide his appearance
from you too?
For times like this one.
I see...
You're not a remnant of
the old Hidden Rain, are you?
Just who are you?
Never mind about me.
What's this about
the old Hidden Rain remnants?
Heh... You really don't know
a thing, do you?
So you're an outsider.
Until recently,
those remnants would infiltrate.
But that's not a worry anymore.
Only lucky fellows like you ever
manage to slip in from the outside.
Not a worry? What do you mean?
I heard that this land was
going through a civil war...
It's not surprising that you haven't heard.
This nation is closed to the outside.
Well, I'll tell you...
The civil war ended long ago.
And we won!
That's why Lord Pain is legendary.
He destroyed the Hidden Rain...
by himself.
I can't believe it...
No matter how powerful
this Pain might be,
the leader of the Hidden Rain
was Hanzo of the Salamander.
And there's not a soul in
the ninja world that doesn't know him.
That's right.
But not only was Hanzo powerful,
he was extremely cautious
and made it very difficult for anyone
to approach him.
He had bodyguards on 24-hour duty,
and everyone, including children,
who went near him were strip searched.
So how did he defeat Hanzo?
What ability does Pain possess?
I told you. We don't know anything!
I can't believe it...
He defeated Hanzo by himself?
He's a god. He wields formidable jutsu.
But that is not why Lord Pain
is to be feared.
What is truly frightening is
his merciless heart of steel.
Everyone who threatened his ideals
was ruthlessly extinguished.
He didn't stop with just Hanzo.
Hanzo's parents, his wife and child...
His relatives and friends,
and even their infants, were killed.
Then he burned down their homes.
And he killed the emissaries of villages
allied with Hanzo.
He erased them all.
It was retribution...
Just like a god, don't you think?
A god...
Yes...
Then, just what is your god
trying to accomplish?
Even underlings like you must know.
It's the work of a god.
We wouldn't know what he plans.
I see... Then if not a god...
you must at least know
something about the Akatsuki.
Never heard of such a name.
Your arms and legs are bound,
so that you cannot move.
But that's not all...
Your pulse is being measured.
And if you lie, I'll know instantly.
Tell me everything you know!
Otherwise, you will end up surviving off
dragonflies and flies
for the rest of your life.
Now then...
Time to hunt the infiltrator.
Turn me into a frog or whatever!
I'm not saying anything more!
Even underlings have pride.
I'm a ninja too!
There's nothing I have to say
to an outsider
who knows nothing about our nation!
Hmm... Still a ninja
even if an underling, eh?
Well... I'm not too keen about
interrogation either.
Talk is over. However, you're going
to stay right here.
I'll go ask this god of yours in person.
Jiraiya! What's the big idea,
summoning me?!
If it's about the key to Naruto's...
No, no. It's not about training.
I have my reasons, but I thought of
releasing you for the time being.
Release me? What's going on?
I'm about to fight
a pretty tough opponent.
So tough that you needed to release me?
It's just a precaution.
Anyway, I wish to press
the storage release seal now.
Very well.
There!
How long until you return?
I don't think it'll take too long...
However, if anything happens to me,
go store yourself inside Naruto.
Are you crazy?!
The key that corresponds to
Naruto's Eight Trigrams Seal
is transcribed on my belly!
Each year,
the Fourth Hokage's seal weakens!
The key remains in order to re-seal it
when it becomes necessary!
To place such a key right next
to the safe is unheard of!
Still, Minato entrusted it to us.
It was always meant to be
returned to Naruto.
It's too soon!
Once you talked me into loosening
the Four Symbols Seal...
You haven't forgotten
what the results were, have you?!
Yeah...
However, the fact that Minato left me
the jutsu for the key convinces me...
that he intended for Naruto
to perfect that jutsu one day.
That jutsu? Are you serious?
Yes.
Does Naruto even require such a jutsu?
He would never be able to
control the Nine-Tails' chakra.
Not only that...
When that key was loosened,
Naruto's own chakra was thrust aside
and a large amount of
the Nine-Tails' chakra leaked out.
The Nine-Tails nearly
took control of Naruto.
If the seal weakens any further
and the Nine-Tails completely
overtakes Naruto,
it will be totally against
the will of the Fourth Hokage!
Minato used the Reaper Death Seal only
on the Nine-Tails' yin chakra.
He purposely split the Nine-Tails' power
into yin and yang,
and sealed the yang power into Naruto.
He wanted to leave
the Nine-Tails' chakra to Naruto.
Still...!
Why did Minato go so far
as sealing the Nine-Tails' chakra
into his own son?
Who knows? Maybe it just turned out
that way by coincidence...
Or perhaps, as a parent, he wanted
to pass on the power to his son.
I know because I was Minato's teacher.
Hmm?
He never did anything without
good reason.
Minato must have known
something important.
And he entrusted the Nine-Tails' power
to his own son because of that.
I think you're reading too much into it.
Do you really think so?
The Nine-Tailed Fox Demon that
attacked the Hidden Leaf Village long ago
is said to have been a natural disaster.
Lately, I've begun to suspect
that it wasn't a natural phenomenon.
It may have been manually summoned.
You fool!
It's always been known that the Nine-Tails
is a natural disaster that mysteriously
appears whenever humanity
becomes steeped in evil!
Besides, there is no one
in this world powerful enough
to summon the likes of the Nine-Tails!
That's the thing.
There was one person.
Huh?!
The founder of the Uchiha Clan...
Madara Uchiha.
You fool! Madara Uchiha lived
during the era
when the Hidden Leaf Village.
was established!
He wouldn't have been alive
fifteen, sixteen years ago!
Indeed.
And everyone knows
that the First Hokage defeated
Madara Uchiha at the Valley of the End.
So your theory is pointless.
Perhaps...
But I just have this feeling...
that fills me with unease.
You return to the Leaf Village.
When you get there, see Ibiki.
He already knows you're coming.
I'm counting on you...
Now then, I hope this works.
Here I go!
Well?
It's Jiraiya.
I see... Jiraiya-sensei, huh?
How nostalgic...
What'll you do, Pain?
He's not on our side, right?
Probably not...
Then we'll kill him.
It's far too late for regrets.
I came out in this body personally
to kill the intruder.
Take me to him.
All right.
Pain... I'll handle him until you arrive.
Kill him if you can.
Fire Style: Flame Bombs!
Toad Subjugation...
Shadow Manipulation Jutsu...?
I was hoping to lure out
a fellow named Pain,
but little did I expect you
to take the bait.
You've honed your jutsu magnificently.
But even more,
you've become quite a catch, Konan!
I thought you had died...
Instead, you turned into
a flimsy sheet of paper.
You're his messenger...
The Lady Angel!
And now, an angel?
Which means, Konan,
you're the messenger for
this so-called god?
This guy is an intruder!
You should kill him now!
Move away.
Y-Yes!
Who is Pain?
It's none of your business, Sensei.
And that makes you an angel...?
Does putting on an act like that
have its benefits?
I have received orders from our god.
I will kill you.
Toad Oil Bombs!
Can't spread your wings
with all that oil, can you?
You used to love origami,
and you were the kindest
among the three kids.
What became of the other two?
Nagato... and Yahiko?
I heard they had died.
Were they just rumors too?
I see...
So this Pain is one of them, eh?
What's your purpose? Appearing
before us after all these years...
That wasn't my intention.
If you all hadn't been part
of the Akatsuki...
I heard that you had died.
I never expected this.
I bet now you're thinking...
You should've done what that
Orochimaru suggested back then...
You saved us instead.
But it's too late now...
We've embraced his ideology
and made our move.
I don't regret letting you live at all.
But I'm so disappointed...
I taught you ninjutsu to enable you
to live through those harsh times.
You were all, without a doubt,
my students.
The world may still be a cruel place,
but to attack me without a greeting...
This is too sad.
For a few years after that time,
I heard your names mentioned.
You had made a reputation for
yourselves in a few confrontations,
but I heard later that you had died.
You know nothing about what happened
to us afterward.
No, I don't. But why the Akatsuki?!
What the Akatsuki is doing is wrong!
That is the decision I've made...
Jiraiya-sensei.
You look very different.
But those eyes...
So you were Pain... Nagato!
It seems you've strayed off
the path of good.
What happened?
You don't need to know.
After all, you are an outsider.
You've changed, Nagato.
Summoning Jutsu!
Whoa!
Bubbles! Leave it to my student
to know my weakness!
He intends to wash away the oil.
Konan, stay back.
Art of the Raging Lion's Mane!
Nagato... I want to ask you a few things.
What happened to Yahiko?
Oh yeah...
There was such a guy, wasn't there?
He died a long time ago.
What happened to you?
The old you wouldn't...
Nothing...
Just war.
Too many people die here.
That pain made me grow up.
What do you mean?
Even a stupid, foolish kid will grow up
when he learns what pain is.
Knowing pain controls one's words
and thoughts.
But abandoning one's love for a friend...
Is that what it means
to become an adult?
Sensei... You are still just a man.
However, through this never-ending pain...
I have matured and become
even more than a man.
What?
Yes... From a man...
to a god.
When one becomes a god,
your words and thoughts become absolute.
Sensei, since you are human
it can't be helped
if you don't understand what I'm saying.
Have you become that twisted?
Things I couldn't see when I was human
are clear to me now that I am a god.
And being a god,
I realize that there are things
I can do which man cannot.
To put it simply, evolving beyond man.
Just what are you planning to do?
I am going to put an end to
this senseless, war-torn world.
That is a god's work.
If that is your purpose,
why are you gathering Tailed Beasts?
You are going to die anyway.
So I shall tell you the true purpose.
I will use the Sealed Tailed Beasts...
to develop a new Forbidden Jutsu.
With just one such jutsu,
a large nation can be
destroyed instantaneously.
It will be the most powerful,
the ultimate Forbidden Jutsu weapon.
How will making such a thing
end the fighting?
Won't it simply intensify the conflicts?
There are disputes
throughout the nations.
How would you put a quick end
to them all, Jiraiya-sensei?
That is my question to you!
Answer me!
You give each warring nation
a Forbidden Jutsu weapon.
Once they possess such a power,
they are bound to use it.
What do you mean?
Tens of millions will die instantly...
and people will become scared.
People... and nations will learn
what pain is!
That fear will breed a strong aversion
to war and the fighting will end.
It can be said that this world is still in
the process of growing and stabilizing.
Pain will make the world mature.
In the same way that I matured.
In order for the world to grow up
and become wiser
a god's hand is necessary.
The world is still a child.
Teach the world pain in order to
make it grow up...
Do you believe that is your work?
Yes... because I am the god of peace.
You've gotten good
at telling jokes... Nagato.
Joke? I'm not joking.
My ideal is...
Over here, Sensei.
Is that you're next summoning?
To me, you are a small existence
which never matured.
Summoning Jutsu!
A kid treating me like a kid!
Well, I'm no longer human either!
These tears of blood,
overflowing with rage!
I went from Sannin to Sage!
The Toad Sage of Mount Myoboku!
I am Master Jiraiya...!
You haven't matured at all...
You're just as clumsy as before.
Hey! Gamaken!
Don't wobble while I'm striking a pose!
I'm kind of clumsy...
Against this foe,
there shall be no playing by ear!
I'm coming at you with full force!
I'm summoning the two great sages!
However, it's going to take some time
to summon the two of them.
And I cannot release my hands
during that time.
I'm counting on you.
Buy me some time until then!
All right. Clumsy as I am, I shall try.
He vanished. What a bother...
Where in the world did he find
such a creature?
Now that he's made himself invisible,
we've got to use Barrier Battle Arts.
Hmm... He's a hard one to battle.
As I recall...
This is a barrier ninjutsu that senses and
alerts any intrusion across its boundary.
In that case...
He saw the barrier and switched
to a strong offensive creature!
Mister Gamaken!
Right! Clumsy as I am, here we go!
You're quite skilled!
Not at all... I am clumsy.
What?!
Wh-What is this?!
Are you okay, Gamaken?
Can't you do this a bit more gracefully?
But I am clumsy...
They seem to multiply each time
you clobber them...
I don't even have a clue what it is...
Is this a self-replicating Summoning Jutsu?!
In any case,
we'd better move from this spot.
We'll kill one dog at a time!
Let's lure them into a small space.
Right!
So that's the center of the jutsu...
Were we able to lose it...?
That should buy us some time.
Or not!
We're surrounded already!
Incoming! And they're going
to split up again!
Above you!
There's no end to this.
I am trying my best...
If they keep dividing,
no matter how hard we strike them,
it's a waste of our energy.
Here already?
Damn persistent dogs!
Stupid little...!
Are you all right?!
Gamaken!
I really am...
clumsy...
If you can't move, Mister Gamaken...
then there's no time to summon
the two great sages.
I give up.
But I'm amazed
there are so many of them...
But against the Great Toad
of Mount Myoboku,
you're all nothing but a small snack!
Gone... Along with the dogs.
So he's escaped for now.
I haven't escaped!
Nagato, you're still a novice.
Leaving your back open for an attack!
You're a Shadow Clone too?!
Yes, but that's not all.
At the same time...
Summoning Jutsu!
Damn it!
Huh?
It's one thing after another...
But I'm almost there.
So I can't quit now, but...
Incoming!
Wha--?! So fast!!
I want to attack the caster,
but I need to be able to see him!
Don't you think something
is strange, Gamaken?
I-I am...
too clumsy to understand
what you mean.
He who possessed the same eyes
as the Sage of the Six Paths,
not only mastered every jutsu
I taught him...
he demonstrated the ability to master
all chakra nature transformations.
For a single person to do so
is unheard of.
He was well versed in
all the standard ninjutsu...
and mastered them by the time
he was ten years old.
But why...?
Why is he only using
the Summoning Jutsu against me?!
Does he think I am beneath
the need for direct confrontation?
Gamaken! You've done enough!
I've got it from here, go home!
All right. Thanks.
Whoa! Why do you always summon us
in such tight spots like this?!
It's no wonder Bunta gets so mad!
Aw c'mon, Ma.
Naturally, Jiraiya-boy has his reasons.
You be quiet, Pa!
It's been a while,
and I do apologize for calling you
under these circumstances, Pa, Ma.
But lad... I thought you said
you hated that form,
saying it would make you unpopular
with the ladies!
I can't afford to be particular right now.
After all, my foe has the Rinnegan.
Ah... the Eyes of the Six Paths?!
Someone actually possesses
such an eye?
Well then, you had no choice.
You have to start being able to go into
Sage Mode by yourself, Jiraiya-boy.
Compared to you,
I'm still just a novice.
So please lend me your aid
for just a little while...
Shall we begin?
He went through all that just
to summon those two toads...?
No, there is a transformation
going on with Sensei.
Humph, whether it's Orochimaru or Jiraiya,
the Sannin each have unique powers.
And? Where is the one with
the Eyes of Six Paths?
Your eyes must be degrading with age.
No. He's hidden himself inside
a summoning creature
that can make itself invisible.
It's have to be one of them
chameleon species.
I have erected a probe barrier.
That won't do any good!
Let's drag them out using
creature detection jutsu!
Ma, don't get so excited,
you'll get more wrinkles.
Just hush up, Pa!
But why go so far as to summon us
to fight this fellow, Jiraiya-boy?
He happens to be
a former student of mine...
We never knew you had one!
Then is he...?
Yes...
Then why are you fighting him?
It seems he did not grow up
in the right direction.
And when I heard he had died...
I thought he couldn't have been
the one.
In any case, if he is not righteous,
you must kill him.
Well, that senile old man probably
made up that prophecy.
Don't worry about it!
All right let's do it!
Found him!
It's fast!
Gotcha!
There we go!
Pa!
I'm on it!
That's the Rinnegan?
It certainly looks like the one mentioned
in the legend.
What nasty eyes... I can't
believe he's that child of prophecy.
Great Lord Elder...
I wonder if this is
that moment of selection?
Summoning Jutsu.
This time he's summoned humans.
You turned out to be
a harbinger of destruction...
So as your mentor,
it is my duty to take you down!
Three of them? What's going on?
How could there be three Rinnegans...?
It must be his jutsu...
There's some trick to it.
Just when I was busy preparing dinner...
Ma, never mind that.
Just focus on the opponent before us!
What did you say?!
I guess it's about time
I made my move!
From this moment on,
let Sage Jutsu prevail!
Look above, upon the halos
and heavenly canopies!
Jiraiya the gallant--
- Stop shouting in my ears!
Ugh! Uh...
My entrance pose keeps getting
interrupted today...
Let's end this quickly and go home!
I have to get dinner ready!
Ma, that guy's eye is
more important than dinner!
Stay alert!
It's the ultimate ocular jutsu!
Like I care!
Don't you dare belittle
a housewife's dilemma
of what to cook every day,
you old geezer!
How dare you use such a tone
against me!
I was just looking after you!
Don't give me that!
Who are the ones yakking into
whose ears again?
Not bad...
Now then... Can we put
your marital spat aside
and get this here over with?
Humph... Guess I'll just fry up something.
Boy, you provide the oil.
Pa, you bring the Wind Style!
Yes ma'am!
Sage Art: Bath of Boiling Oil!
The oil vanished?
They ought to have been basted by it.
That one probably has tricks
up his sleeve too.
Shall we find out with close combat?
Yes.
Massive Rasengan!
He's...! He can absorb an entire jutsu?!
So that's what he did earlier...
Behind us!
We got his back!
What?!
He blocked my Sage Mode attack
without looking?!
Sage Art: Kebari Senbon!
Not a single wasted movement.
I would've gotten him if he'd dodged it...
Instead, he blocked it by summoning
without ever turning around.
What's going on?
Blocking my attacks not just once,
but twice!
With no verbal signals or eye contact
between them at all...
Even if all three were sensory types,
they still have to see an attack
coming in order to counter it.
Kebari Senbon is my fastest jutsu
with the widest attack range.
The only way to defend oneself against
it is with a shield, as he just did.
And he did it without looking.
They're no ordinary clones.
You said they have a trick up
their sleeves, and you're right.
Hmm?
Have you noticed?
What is it?
When we got their back earlier,
you picked the target and attacked
from his blind spot, correct?
During that time,
one of the other guys
was watching us the whole time.
I noticed that too.
But there were no signs that
they were signaling each other
either verbally or with eye contact.
That's it! It's their eyes...
All three have the same eyes!
Suppose the three of them can
share what they see with each other...
Enabling their eyes to share images
with one another...
Is that it?
Yes. That's what I suspect...
Still... What in tarnation are they?
This is bad...
Under these circumstances
where my ninjutsu are being nullified...
To face all three at once
is a bit too much.
At this rate, if I enter battle...
I'll be killed,
even in Sage Mode.
I never imagined
they would be this strong...
Fall back for now, Jiraiya-boy.
Yes sir.
He's escaped into the pipes...
Why are we running away?
We need to analyze the
Six Paths technique and form a plan.
And we'll need some time for that.
They may look different,
but all possessed the same eye.
In short, they all have
the Rinnegan of Six Paths...
Even if one of them is Nagato,
I can't believe there would be
so many Rinnegan users crawling around.
So what in the world's going on?!
Which one is the real Pain?
Figuring out the main one
isn't the problem.
The real problem is the fact that
three of them possess
the Rinnegan of Six Paths.
Which means we have to split them up
and fight each one separately.
I'm positive I can win one-on-one...
Since they possess such eyes,
fighting as a team would have to
be their basic mode of attack.
Taijutsu isn't going to work...
and any ninjutsu will just be absorbed.
If taijutsu and ninjutsu won't work,
then it'll have to be genjutsu.
Yes!
But I am hopeless
when it comes to genjutsu.
Ah, but as I recall you two were...
Yes... If they're former students
of yours, Jiraiya-boy,
they know that you don't use genjutsu.
So that might give us an opening.
No way! I'm not going to do it!
Wh-What is it?!
World peace is hanging
on this battle, Ma!
This is no time to be selfish!
I don't care about no old geezer's
senile prophecies!
The Great Lord Elder told us to
get along, remember?!
What is it that you
object to so much?
I can't sing a duet with Pa
at this plump ripe old age!
It's embarrassing!
Huh? A duet?!
Our most powerful genjutsu
involves appealing
to the auditory senses of
the victim through song.
Auditory senses? I see.
That's why we retreated.
Correct... This genjutsu is powerful,
but as soon as we make a sound,
our whereabouts will be revealed,
which is its weakness.
Also, there's the harmony
of the sounds...
In other words, the genjutsu
is placed with a melody.
It requires a little time
before it takes effect.
If they discover our whereabouts
before they are caught in the genjutsu
and attack, we will surely lose.
However, once they are caught
in the genjutsu,
our victory will be assured.
What's wrong?
If both your lives are ever in danger,
I want you to free yourselves
from my shoulders immediately.
Huh? Absolutely not!
The fate of the ninja world depends
on this battle!
I have a plan.
Although it is a gamble as well...
Do tell.
Please begin...
- Right.
What is that?
This is... the croaking of frogs...
Is this a genjutsu?!
It's coming from in there.
A Shadow Clone!
Fire Style: Giant Flame Bombs!
So that's your move!
Good! My gamble's a success!
Just as I suspected,
each of them possesses
only a single type of ability!
Right now, the big fellow's eyes
are focused on the jutsu.
One, I blinded earlier...
So only one of them...
is looking at me!
This one too!
Gotcha!
I can't move.
The dark swamp?!
Just a little more!
Now we're really one-on-one!
I'm not letting you summon!
You got us...
You are inside a genjutsu paralysis
that binds your psyche.
Now none of your bodies,
including your main body,
will be able to move.
Jiraiya-sensei...
I didn't expect
a genjutsu like this from you.
I thought I taught you...
Never let your guard down, no matter
who your opponent is, Nagato...
You erred in your decision.
I just want to protect those two.
No matter what kind of pain
I have to endure.
I see.
Rather than rule the world
through pain...
I wish you had moved past the pain and
harnessed your power to bring
about peace in a positive way.
For just a little while...
I believed you were the one.
Farewell...
Are you both all right?!
This genjutsu is hard on the throat.
It's real hard staying in sync with Pa...
This jutsu ain't that easy at all!
Damages the throat!
Stretches the lower jaw 'til it sags!
Creates wrinkles!
My profound apologies.
Please take your rest now.
For I've made my selection.
Didn't you teach me to never
let down your guard... Jiraiya-sensei?
Lad! Your left arm!
I'm aware of that...
What's going on?!
This one's got a different face
than the other three...
He was probably summoned earlier.
I see! Before they got caught
in our genjutsu!
Now then.
In attendance...
The Six Paths of Pain.
Six?! There are six of them?!
Hey, look close!
The three we just did in are there too!
The newly summoned ones
must have resurrected them
with some sort of jutsu!
There's even a jutsu that can revive
as many as three of them
when they were undoubtedly dead?!
Are they really human?!
Pain... What are you?!
Pain...
That name is an alias that
denotes all six of us.
Y-You're...!
That face...
What's going on?
I thought you said Yahiko died!
Plus, those eyes...
You see Yahiko's image in me?
You really are his former Teacher.
But Yahiko has been dead
for quite some time.
All that remains... is Pain.
Stop speaking in riddles!
Why do you possess the Rinnegan?!
What are you talking about,
Jiraiya-boy?
One of my former students
is among them.
Except he didn't use to
possess those eyes...
What on earth is going on?
You're saying there are
two children of prophecy?
No, that's not it either...
When I saw the Rinnegan, I convinced
myself that the first one was Nagato...
But he's subtly different
from the Nagato I knew of...
Come to think of it,
upon closer inspection,
none of those six remind me of Nagato.
On the other hand,
one of them resembles Yahiko...
but possesses Nagato's Rinnegan...
Are you Yahiko... or Nagato?
Just what exactly are you?!
We are God.
God?!
Yahiko! How could you possess
Nagato's eyes?!
Even if you knew that,
you could not win!
This is... a barrier?
Stomach acid?
Rasengan!
I barely managed to kill one...
only after dragging it into my barrier...
Are you all right, lad?
Somewhat...
My body...?!
My chakra's agitated!
Is it this?!
Their true identity is a mystery,
and they seem to use strange weapons.
They're no longer mortals...
They're something entirely different.
No one really knows what
he looks like.
And some claim that
he doesn't even exist.
That face...
He is unmistakably Yahiko...
And yet,
he possesses Nagato's Rinnegan...
Did Yahiko steal them
from Nagato for some reason?
But...
There are other
Rinnegan bearers as well...
So what's going on?
Plus...
Understanding such pain enables you
to be kind to others...
That's what makes us human.
What do you mean by that...?
It's called growing up.
Growing up? What do you mean?
That, you need to figure out yourself.
Too many people die here.
That pain made me grow up.
In which case,
does that mean he is Nagato?
That's right! Now I remember!
This one is definitely not Nagato!
What's the matter?
This fellow before us...
I've fought him before.
He was a Fuma Clan member
I encountered
right after setting out on my journey,
following the Great Lord Elder's prophecy.
I gave him that scar on his forehead...
So what's a fellow like him
doing here?
Now I'm even more confused
about this whole Pain mystery.
You will guide that revolutionary.
The day will come when you will be
forced to make a critical selection.
What must I do...?
In order to make the right choice?
In my dream, you traveled the world,
writing books.
It can't be...
If this is the prophecy...
I wish to go back and face them
in order to confirm something...
You two please go back.
What?!
Absolutely not! You will be killed
if you go out again!
They have more eyes,
and they will not fall
for the barrier trap twice!
They're not on to us in here yet.
This is our only chance to
make a run for it!
I may be killed if I go out there...
But I may be able to learn
the truth about them.
If I let this chance slip by,
I don't think there's anyone else
who could get as close to Pain.
This is our only chance to
uncover the truth...
Plus...
This is the time for selection
that the Great Lord Elder prophesied!
Boss and Ma'am... please take the
intel on Pain we've gathered so far,
as well as this corpse and go back.
And please tell Tsunade...
Ma should be enough for that.
But...
Just return by dinnertime.
Yup... When we're done here,
I'll bring Jiraiya-boy on over with me.
Thank you...
It's just as I thought!
They're all ninja that
I've encountered before!
That's it!
I've figured out who Pain is!
My throat...
Jiraiya-boy!
You were too late in figuring it out...
I must let Boss know... about
Pain's true identity.
Hang in there, Jiraiya-boy!
It's no good...
My throat has been crushed.
Damn it... At this rate...
It's useless... I'm passing out...
Am I... going to die?
Have I failed...?
It's not how you live,
but how you die in
the ninja world...
A ninja's life is not measured
by how they lived
but rather what they managed
to achieve before their death.
Looking back, my life has
been nothing but failures...
Continually rejected by Tsunade...
Unable to stop my friend...
And unable to protect either
my student or my mentor...
Compared to the great deeds
of the Hokage,
my actions are trifling,
insignificant things indeed.
I wish I could have died like
each of the Hokage.
A tale is only as good as
its final turn of events, the plot twist.
Failures must be seen
as mere amusements!
They are trials, which hone your skills.
I lived believing that...
And in return, I swore I would
accomplish a deed so great
that it would obliterate all
of my failures...
And I'd die a splendid ninja!
At least, that's how it
was supposed to go...
But... with my plot twist...
My tale, ending like this...
The Great Lord Elder prophesied that
I would guide that revolutionary.
A person who will make
a great choice
that will bring either stability
or destruction to the ninja world.
I thought I would defeat Pain,
stop the Akatsuki,
and save the ninja world
from destruction...
But in the end, I failed in
that selection too.
How pitiful...
that this will be the twist to
"The Tale of Jiraiya the Gallant."
What a worthless story...
No, I don't think so.
This tale is wonderful!
I really hope my unborn child
can become a ninja just
like this main character!
Which is why I'd like your permission
to name my son after him.
Yes...
That's right...
I gave that child...
I'm going to become the Hokage!
A Hokage that surpasses
all previous Hokage!
I never go back on my word...
That's my ninja way!
Naruto...
Now that I think about it, Naruto,
you are just like that
novel's main character.
You've inherited Minato and
Kushina's wishes, their hopes...
And yet... I...
You are my sensei!
And you are a great ninja who
possesses the true talent of a ninja!
There's no other like you.
A ninja is one who endures,
one who stands brave.
Let me teach you one thing...
The most important attribute
of a ninja
is not the number of jutsu he masters.
The most important thing is...
the guts to never give up!
Never go back on your word
and never give up...
Naruto, if that is your ninja way...
Then as your mentor...
I have no business whining.
For everyone knows that a student
inherits his ninja way from his teacher!
Isn't that so, Naruto?!
Jiraiya-boy!
I was sure his heart had stopped.
Got it!
Never give up...
That was the true choice
I was supposed to make!
Quite obstinate, isn't he?
Let's finish him off.
All right! Message received!
A dying message...
He wrote it in code, eh?
Naruto... You are the child of prophecy,
I'm sure of it now.
I entrust you with the rest!
The frog... got away.
"The Tale of Jiraiya the Gallant"...
Now it'll end a bit better I hope.
The final chapter will be...
"The Frog within the Well...
Drifts into the Great Ocean."
Not bad... Not bad at all...
Now... It's about time
I put down my pen...
Ah, that's right!
What should I name the sequel?
Let's see...
"The Tale of Naruto Uzumaki."
Yes... That has a nice ring to it...
One of the legendary Sannin...
Jiraiya is no more...
If we didn't have this secret,
we could not have won.
Let us praise him as our teacher.
By the way...
you can come out.
Sure took you a while.
His opponent was Jiraiya,
after all.
That was quite a struggle.
I'm under orders from Madara
to capture the Nine-Tails.