What did Lord Jiraiya say?
It seems the training
is going well.
The day that brat returns
may soon be upon us.
Naruto is a mysterious being...
He's been away from the village
for two whole years and yet...
Inuzuka Style:
Man Beast Transformation Combo!
Two-Headed Wolf!
Wolf Fang Over Fang!
... his presence keeps on growing.
Are you all right?
I'm at my limit!
Just ten more laps!
If you stop now,
Naruto will laugh at you!
Everyone seems to keep Naruto
in their thoughts as they train!
A messenger hawk!
Where?!
Lord Kazekage!
A messenger hawk has arrived
with a message
from the Hidden Leaf's Fifth Hokage.
I was getting tired of waiting.
You're our welcoming party?
Thank you for coming to meet us.
Well, it's a drag,
but seeing as it's Lord Kazekage...
Welcome.
This is the data from
the Chunin Exam two years ago.
A total of 153 entrants.
Information about the entrant's village,
the three tests for this exam,
and the qualifying statistics
are compiled in an easy-to-read format.
But you would know more
about the reason behind
the interruption of the final test
and its chronology.
Due to the suspension
of the last Chunin Exam,
the Hidden Leaf would like to
co-host a Chunin Exam.
Thanks in part to
the Hidden Leaf's cooperation,
the situation in
our village has stabilized
during the last two years...
In particular,
our training curriculum
has been very successful
and we have developed more Genin
who are qualified to take the Chunin Exam.
Then you have no objection
to our sponsoring an event?
Before that, Lady Hokage...
What's your true motive?
"True motive?"
I mean the timing of this thing.
Why hold the Chunin Exam now?
If the reason is lack of personnel...
you could have done this sooner.
All right.
I'll be honest.
The first reason is to gauge
the reactions of
each of the villages
within the Five Great Nations.
All of whom, on the surface,
claim to be at peace.
Their response to having
the combined Chunin Exam
will reveal their true feelings.
The second reason is to
investigate Akatsuki's movements.
It's said that they seek
the Tailed Beasts from each village,
but they've been awfully quiet
these past two years.
You want to use the Chunin Exam
to open the village
to create an opportunity
to lure the Akatsuki out?
Yes. The Akatsuki have
probably grown impatient
and are ready to make a move.
This is a risky—
Hold on.
This Chunin Exam...
The Hidden Sand
would like to host it,
to coincide with
my inauguration as Kazekage.
That will not do.
The Hidden Leaf must
host this Chunin Exam.
It's so that we may finish
what we started previously.
Yes, absolutely.
The Kazekage can't
decide this all by himself.
He must consult the village elders.
Yeah. We need time to contact them.
Let's come back to this again
at the next meeting.
Fine.
We'll settle this during
the next meeting.
This is becoming a drag.
Yeah. I didn't expect Gaara
to make such an announcement.
He really didn't tell you anything?
That came out of nowhere.
Well, he probably
has his own ideas.
I leave it to you.
If the Hokage is right
and the Akatsuki make their move,
you're going to be
their target, right?
If the enemy wants
the Tailed Beasts,
they'll come for me
sooner or later.
Then I'll just be the bait
and take them down.
What are you saying?!
The village has welcomed you
as their new Kazekage
but things are still unstable!
I'm aware of that.
I know that some are not happy
that I have become the Kazekage...
and would welcome
an opportunity to kill me.
Then why would you even consider
hosting the event in our village?!
It is precisely why I want
the Chunin Exam in the
Hidden Sand Village.
You can't be serious!
It's not the Akatsuki
you want to lure out...
But the rebels in the village?
That's just too dangerous.
Regarding the combined
Chunin Exam under discussion...
It is Lord Kazekage's desire
to host this event in
the Hidden Sand Village.
He intends to introduce himself
to the other nations.
Is that wise?
While things have been quiet
for a while now,
it does not change
the fact that Gaara is
"a military weapon to be feared."
As long as Gaara lives,
this village can never
be truly at peace.
For the second test of this exam,
Lord Gaara intends to
suggest the Demon Desert
as a suitable arena.
And we, the Hidden Sand,
will do our utmost to support him!
Yura is on to us.
No... everyone is
uneasy about Gaara.
But that's not enough
to plan a coup d'état.
Well, well... my elders...
Of all places to find you.
What do you want?
We said we are in favor
of Lord Gaara's plan.
Nothing, I just forgot to tell you...
Lord Gaara plans to
personally supervise the test site.
We'll have to be very careful
with preparations.
After all, the second test
is a survival test
and there are always fatalities.
Why who's to say
nothing will happen
to the supervisor himself,
Lord Gaara...
Excuse me...
So this is the perfect opportunity
to get rid of the Kazekage
and make it look purely accidental...
But he is a Jinchuriki.
There's a way.
The first Jinchuriki, Bunpuku,
was able to temporarily seal
Shukaku into a teapot.
We can use that...
What is your decision,
Lady Tsunade?
Two years ago, Jiraiya had intel
that said the Akatsuki would
target Naruto
in three or four years.
And two years have passed...
I'm sure they're itching
to make a move.
You're not going to use Naruto
as bait, are you?
No...
As the Hokage of the
Hidden Leaf Village.
I cannot do such a thing.
Don't tell me... the Kazekage
will assume that role?
As luck would have it,
he was the one who proposed it.
But will the advisors agree?
I'll placate them
by suggesting a joint-sponsorship.
We can't negotiate any further.
I looked over the plans
you submitted...
What do you think about
a joint-sponsorship with the Hidden Leaf?
We'll hold the first test,
the written one,
at the Hidden Leaf...
And the Hidden Sand
will host the site of
the second test, the survival one.
The Forest of Death has
become too familiar as a test site.
I was just thinking a new site
would be necessary.
Hmm... I agree.
We have no objections.
All right then...
We'll meet again at the Chunin Exam.
Yeah...
Come to us if any trouble arises.
We'll take care of it, crybaby.
Damn it. She doesn't change.
The Hidden Sound probably
won't take part this time around...
So should we just send invitations
to everyone else
from the last time?
Yes. In addition,
send invitations for
the introduction of
the new Kazekage
to every village within
the Five Great Nations.
I see...
Then we can monitor
each village's response.
Aside from Akatsuki,
this is the other reason
for reopening the combined Chunin Exam.
Yes, I understand.
Deliver this to every village.
It's the invitation to the Chunin Exam.
– Right!
We've put out the bait...
Now, let's see how they react.
Lady Tsunade.
The Hidden Sand replied right away...
Oh...
They'll be sending nine teams...
27 Genin.
Last time,
they sent 30 in ten teams...
Although that's one team short,
considering the Hidden Sand's
current situation,
one has to commend them
for nurturing this many Genin.
Yes...
Any word from the other villages?
No, not yet.
How will the other Kage respond?
A Chunin Exam, you say?!
Damn that Princess Tsunade!
She's getting carried away!
She probably coaxed
the Kazekage into cooperating...
... and plans to get the jump on us
within the Five Great Nations.
What will you do?
Ignore her!
Just ignore her!
Do not mention a word of this,
or the past, to anyone!
Especially Bee!
Do not let him find out!
Whenever there
are events like this,
he gets excited about live concerts
and what not.
Actually, I already told him.
What?!
He kept asking questions...
I'm sorry.
Bee!
Where is Bee?!
Don't tell me...
Find Bee immediately
and bring him here!
Understood.
This is so dull...
A concert at Hidden Leaf Village...
Tuning up at the Chunin Exam...
Take a lesson from Kin-chan-sensei!
Yay!
Bee! Lord Raikage wants to see you!
Please return!
Fool, ya fool!
What did Lord Raikage say?
Unfortunately, they are swamped
with village business
bv
and don't have enough
time to prepare.
Now why would the Hokage
and Kazekage send a letter?
Seems they're resuming
the Chunin Exam...
What shall we do?
We must consider the matter
with the Fourth, Yagura...
I believe we should concentrate
on rebuilding the village...
You may have a point.
Yes!
We can't be wasting
our time participating
in a ceremony announcing
the new Kazekage...
Ceremony...
Can't waste time for
a ceremony for me?
Shut up or I'll kill you.
What?!
Perhaps we should forego
the Chunin Exam this time.
Let's do that.
It seems the Hidden Mist
are tied up as well.
The Hidden Leaf has
delivered an invitation
to the combined Chunin Exam!
Their ulterior motive
is crystal clear!
They want to test
the strength of the villages
and prepare for the next battle!
Just throw it back in their face!
I intend to do so!
This is what I'll do
to their invitation!
I want you to go here.
To the Hidden Rain Village?
Yes, the most troublesome spot.
As expected, every person
who enters is investigated,
and they're kept under strict
surveillance during their stay.
Hanzo of the Salamander rules it...
Yes, so I've heard.
Even if I'm carrying an invitation
to the combined Chunin Exam,
I doubt if they'll
let me in easily.
There's domestic instability
and even rumors of a coup d'état.
It's so closed off, no one knows
the true state of things.
While I'm at it, shall I look into
their internal affairs then?
Yes, but don't take any chances.
Halt!
Are you a shinobi
of the Hidden Leaf?
Yes, I'm Kakashi Hatake
of the Hidden Leaf Village.
Our Lady Hokage sent me here.
I have a joint letter from the Hidden Leaf
and the Hidden Sand.
Then I will accept it.
No... I've been ordered to
present it to your leader,
Hanzo of the Salamander himself.
Is that a part of your plan
to get close to Lord Hanzo?!
Threatening me is the same as threatening
the Hidden Leaf and the Hidden Sand...
Is that what you really want?
All right...
I'll let them know.
Lord Hanzo will see you now.
Surrender all of your weapons,
and then enter.
As rumored, the immigration inspections
are extremely strict.
So his security is airtight.
Kakashi Hatake...
Nice of you to come.
Put the message you brought
over there.
A letter has arrived from Hanzo of
the Salamander
from the Hidden Rain Village.
Oh! He's sending Genin to join
the Hidden Leaf and the Hidden Sand...
Does this repudiate the rumors
surrounding the Hidden Rain then?
No...
Sending Genin could simply be
a ruse to hide the truth...
Then...
Keep a close watch on the
Hidden Rain Genin who are sent here.
I am so bored...
Fuu! Lord Shibuki wants to see you.
Oh no! Did I do something?
Lord Shibuki, I've brought Fuu.
Hey, Fuu!
What's up, Chief?!
What were you thinking?!
Requesting an application for
the Chunin Exam
from the Hidden Leaf?!
Shouldn't I have?
Then can you recommend me?
What?!
And what will you do if it leaks out
that you're a Jinchuriki?
Well then...
I guess I'll go on my own.
Huh?!
H-Hey wait!
Wait, Fuu!
I want to see the outside world!
If you won't acknowledge me,
I'll just leave the village!
A-All right!
You never give up once
you make up your mind.
Will you forgive me?
Then listen to me.
The Chunin Exam isn't
your run-of-the-mill test.
It's a battle where you
put your life on the line
for your dreams and
the pride of the village.
In the past, the Hidden Waterfall Village
was nowhere near the scale of
the Hidden Leaf or the Hidden Sand,
but we were feared
as a shinobi village that produced
skilled Jonin, one after another.
That's why, although we are
not part of the Five Great Nations,
we are allotted a Tailed Beast.
The Chunin Exam is the ideal opportunity
to make a name for us
and impress the Feudal Lords
who hire shinobi villages,
and other shinobi leaders as well.
It's our chance to restore
our past glory.
As long as you're going
to participate,
go out and fight to make
the Hidden Waterfall Village known.
All right! Got it!
I'll rile up a storm!
However!
Don't let anyone find out...
... that you are a Jinchuriki...
Okay!
Kegon, Yoro...
Hide your Jonin status
and guard Fuu.
– Right!
She's beyond my control now.
Does this mean...
the Hidden Waterfall Village will
send one team of three?
It's almost terrifying
in its brevity,
but it is an official application.
Let's close
the application period soon!
Oh!
What is it?
W-We forgot to call for entrants
from the Hidden Leaf!
What?!
Are you actually going
to supervise?
Yes. I'll oversee the finals
of the second test.
It's so that no fatalities
occur during the test.
What will you achieve
by smoking out the rebels?
It's not like that...
Then what?
Why would you go so far
as to face danger head on?
My feelings haven't changed
from that time.
Don't tell me...
you want to bond with the rebels?
That's impossible!
Even if you're up to it,
they won't listen!
He is...
Naruto is working hard,
to forge bonds with others...
So I won't give up either
until the day comes
when I can share suffering,
sadness, and happiness with others.
I consider this my first test,
as the Kazekage of the Hidden Sand Village.
Once he makes up his mind,
he won't listen... Damn it!
The Hidden Sand will send
the same as last time...
Nine teams, 27 shinobi.
The Hidden Rain will have fifteen.
And the Hidden Grass is sending six.
The Hidden Waterfall sent word
that they are also sending
a team of three.
The Hidden Cloud and the Hidden Mist
sent polite regrets,
but our invitation was sent back
by the Hidden Stone.
As the host village,
we'll have to enter the same number
as the last exam.
I want all of you to list
the Genin under you
and turn in your recommendations.
Are you stupid?
That's barely cooked.
Meat tastes best when
there's still some red left.
Hey, Asuma-sensei...
So what's going to happen
to our team
in the upcoming Chunin Exam?
Considering your skills now,
it's only natural I recommend you.
But Shikamaru is already
a Chunin, so he can't enter.
So we're one member short.
Currently, Team Asuma is
captained by Shikamaru.
If I'm to find a replacement...
It's going to be difficult
to be a stand-in just for the Chunin Exam.
Umm... I have someone in mind.
Someone who rivals Shikamaru
in intelligence?
Is there anyone like that?
She's probably not
as smart as Shikamaru,
but she may just
be tougher than him.
You'll be fine now.
Me? Join Team Asuma?
Both Sasuke and Naruto
are missing from Team 7, right?
Y-Yeah...
So you need to join a three-man team
in order to take the Chunin Exam, right?!
Yeah...
So you'll join, right?
But...
I know your strength
better than anyone.
At the last Chunin Exam...
I got a good taste of your power.
Still... I can't.
Please find someone else.
Why?!
We know that you've trained hard
under Lady Tsunade for two years.
You've grown so much.
If you're just going to wait
for Naruto and Sasuke...
If you do that,
you'll never be able to seize the
opportunities that come your way!
It's not that...
If you add me to your team now,
I'll probably be a nuisance.
That's not true! Please!
You're going to take the Chunin Exam?
Are you serious?
Please...
I already told you I can't authorize it.
The seal for the chakra
of the 100 Healings Jutsu...
and the reservoir for the chakra
I normally use...
I was able to control
both of these reserves
and successfully performed surgery.
I want to see how far I can go.
I want to push myself as far as I can
by participating in this exam.
I'm still a novice...
yet Choji and Ino asked me
to join them.
They asked me to take
the Chunin Exam with them.
I want to honor their trust in me!
Please!
Take this with you.
Thank you very much!
However...
Whatever happens at the Chunin Exam
will be your sole responsibility.
Understood?
Yes!
Okay, with the team of
Ino, Choji and Sakura...
our participant list is complete.
It's not as many as the 29 teams
we had the last time...
But it's a decent list of participants.
Yes.
The time has finally come.
Big Brother Shikamaru,
what's going on?
Hmm?
The first test of the Chunin Exam
will be held here,
so we're just making a few upgrades.
The Chunin Exam!
It's been a while since they last held one!
It's been two years...
That means we get to participate!
We can be Chunin!
You guys are
still Academy students.
You're not even Genin,
you can't participate.
That's kind of a disappointment,
but also a big relief...
I see, so this means
Big Brother Naruto's coming back!
Huh? Naruto?
He's coming back to take
the Chunin Exam, right?
He's not coming.
What?
Who knows where or how
he's training right now.
His whereabouts are still unknown.
I don't know if he even got the news
that we're holding the Chunin Exam.
Does this mean
they're going to proceed
without Big Brother Naruto?
It's not like the village can plan
things to fit his schedule.
Big Bro's going to be left behind.
Our leader's going to
get disqualified!
We're representing the Hidden Sand,
so we have to make Chunin!
It's too soon to get
all worked up.
Calm down, Yukata.
Seems like Shikamaru
will be a proctor.
That's not surprising.
It's because he's already a Chunin.
Then let's buckle down and
get promoted to Chunin too! Right?
Looking forward to
doing this with you!
- Let's kick some ass.
- Yeah!
All right, so the three of you
are taking this exam, correct?
You've been signed up.
There's no trick this time,
like not letting us submit
our applications, is there?
This test is up to
the proctor in charge.
Okay, draw lots.
Three?
Two?
One?
Return the lots and please proceed
to the classroom that you picked.
They're so polite,
it's almost creepy.
Did Shikamaru plan this?
What is he thinking?
Next, please.
You're the entrants from
the Hidden Waterfall Village.
The name's Fuu.
All right, please draw a lot.
We've waited so long for this,
so we have to make it
and become Chunin!
You're so loud!
Is this where the Chunin Exam
is being held?!
Hey! I'm back.
Naruto!
No way...
Is that you, Naruto?!
Are you real?
I'm real!
You really haven't changed much.
Sure, I have! Want to see
the results of all my training?
Sexy Jutsu!
How's that?
Here! There!
He's as stupid as ever...
And that's why Naruto is Naruto.
Byakugan!
All right, I'm going to take part
in this test too.
But you need a team of three.
I just came home and
there's no one left,
so I'll just ask them to
make an exception.
Huh?!
What's the big idea?
Don't get mad at Konohamaru!
Are you all right, Konohamaru?
It's all for Big Brother Naruto.
Naruto?
Because Big Brother can't take this exam.
It's because he won't be able
to be a Chunin.
So you tried to take it
for him instead...
A stand-in test taker...
You don't need to worry
about him.
Naruto is someone who'll keep striving
to become Hokage, regardless of rank.
He's right.
And when he returns,
we'll welcome him with a big smile.
I got it.
Next in line.
One.
Three...
Two...
Okay, leave the lots and
go to your assigned rooms.
Room One is
the classroom up ahead.
Rooms Two and Three
are up the stairs.
Huh? We're being separated?
We're on our own?
I'm in Room One.
Oh!
Big Brother Neji!
Why were we separated
from our teams?
I have no idea.
Huh?
It won't open.
I wonder what's happening?
Isn't the proctor coming?
They're planning something...
Heh, bring it on!
There's a stack of papers here.
You shouldn't go around
carelessly touching things...
Uh... Ahem!
I am Shikamaru Nara,
the proctor for the first test
of the Chunin Exam.
Participants, take one sheet from
the stack on the teacher's desk,
then take any seat.
The first test is a written one,
after all.
Oh good, it's the same as usual.
Is everyone seated?
This is a drag,
so let's get right to it.
This is a drag for him?
We're serious about this!
You guys are lucky.
I'm in charge this year.
He might be right.
Why?
He won't do anything unreasonable.
The first test is a written one.
Read the questions carefully.
Three questions...
The three questions are worth,
from the top:
30 points, 40 points,
and 50 points.
A perfect score is 120 points?
Not 100?
Each of you will answer
just one of three questions.
Your team's total score will
determine if you pass or fail.
If your team total exceeds 100,
the team is disqualified.
That's crazy!
Then, for example...
If the three have...
30, 30, 50 for 110 points...
30, 40, 40 for 110 points...
or 40, 40, 40 for 120 points...
These totals will
disqualify them, right?
Then we'll take the average
of the teams who remain...
and any teams who score below
that average will be disqualified.
Those over the average will pass.
An average score?
Of the teams' totals...?
Just a minute.
How are we supposed to...?!
The test starts now.
Which question should I solve?
I don't understand this test at all!
This test isn't just about
solving the questions...
Please don't say things that
will confuse me even more!
The three questions aren't that hard.
Unless you're really dumb,
anyone can solve
the 50-point question too.
Don't underestimate me!
I won't run! I'll take this test!
I don't care if I have to stay
a Genin for the rest of my life,
because I'll be Hokage someday,
no matter what!
Come to think of it...
there was a guy
who was really that dumb...
He couldn't solve a single question
in the first test, but he passed.
Which means...
They're not testing
our problem-solving skills.
It's the same as the last time!
Now then...
100 points is either...
30, 30 and 40...
Or 50, 50 and 0.
It's been sealed off.
Big Brother Neji?
Double-paned windows, huh...
They made sure that
we couldn't contact our teammates.
Should you be moving around like that?
We were told a few rules,
but no one's cautioned us yet
for talking like this.
I see...
So, they don't care whether we cheat or not.
That's right...
Last time, the first test
was all about cheating.
It won't open...
Leave it to Shikamaru...
This is a difficult problem.
If you can contact your teammates,
you gain an advantage for this test...
But no one on my team has that kind
of ninjutsu.
I wonder if Shino has any ideas...
The only thing left is to try to guess
which question my teammate will solve.
If we choose the number
we each picked...
our point total will be over 100.
Going over 100 points
means immediate disqualification.
We have to avoid that at all cost.
If one of us scores zero points,
we'll avoid going over 100, right?
But there's no guarantee
that the other two will each answer
the 50-point question.
And if the point total is too low,
we'll likely be disqualified
for scoring below the average.
If all of us solve the 30-point question
and get 90 points,
we'll lose to the team
that has 100.
If many teams score 100 points,
and raise the average, teams with
90 points will be disqualified.
I guess finding
a loophole seems impossible.
The choices are 30, 30, 40
or 0, 50, 50 to score 100 points.
So the question is...
figuring out which question
each team member will solve.
How should I know what
questions Ino and Sakura will pick?
What would Shino and Kiba do?
Those two are probably wondering
the same thing right now.
Got it! I finally figured it out!
Huh? You did?
Yes!
I solved the 50-point question!
Oh... I see.
I'm not going to show you.
I won't look.
I don't have to look.
Who are you?
You don't seem to be
an Insect User, but...
I hate to say this,
but if Naruto were here,
this first test would be easy.
Huh? Why?
I mean, he'd score zero for sure.
I think even Naruto could
solve this 30-point question.
Definitely not.
Leave it to Naruto...
It would be much simpler if Lee
on our team were that obviously dumb.
Umm... Excuse me.
Yes?
Can you tell me just what
we're supposed to do
for this first test?
That's what we're trying
to figure out!
You too, huh?
These questions are
really hard, aren't they?
Well... yeah.
Wouldn't you think
the safest thing to do
is for each of us to choose
the 30-point question?
Didn't he say something
about the average score too?
I see... We have to score 100 points,
no matter what.
I can't even figure out
how to get 100 points.
And time keeps on ticking away...
I've trained hard... I'll try it.
First, I have to sense those two.
Hey, you two, please listen...
Is that you, Fuu?
All right.
What are you up to?
My teammates...
Sensory Jutsu!
Four...? I see...
I don't get it.
Choji...
Huh?!
I'll solve the 40-point question,
so Choji, you do the 30-pointer.
Oh, okay. Okay!
I'll get Sakura to do the 30-pointer too.
Hey, Gennai! Inaho!
Can you hear me?!
Tanzo, Minoji!
It's me!
– It's me!
– Hey! It's me!
– What are you trying to do?
– Can you hear me?
At this rate,
no one's voice will be heard.
Do you hear something?
Is someone yelling?
That's right!
If they can hear me
on the other side...!
Hey!
Can you hear me?!
I can hear something.
Someone's yelling.
A lot of people are yelling.
I see.
Hey!
Komugi, Gennai!
Yahoo!
Shouldn't we stop them?!
If I stop them,
this test would be meaningless.
Now then, who's going to do what?
I'll do the 50-point question!
I'll do the 40-point one!
It's so noisy.
Who can hear over all this?
There's shouting in
the other classes too.
Everyone's voices are blending together...
So nothing can be communicated.
Nothing can be communicated?
Just watch...
Sand Letters!
"I'll do the 40-point question."
It's Sajin!
He wants us to do the 30-pointer.
With that we'll total 100 points.
Those fools...
Lady Hinata...
Let's continue your lesson here.
What are you saying, Big Brother Neji?
There's something I want to try.
All right.
Perform the Eight Trigrams: Air Palm...
with all your might.
– Eight Trigrams: Air Palm!
Wh-What the—?!
Hey...
You guys...
What the hell are you guys doing?!
Showing you the answer
to the question.
Any idiot can solve
a question like this.
– Huh?
– Yeah, he's right.
So what question
are you going to solve?
Why should I tell you?
Everyone is in a dilemma
because they don't know...
which one to solve.
It's because they don't know
which ones their teammates
will choose.
Neji is planning something.
But why would he tell the others
what he plans to do?
The method he plans
to use probably necessitates it.
Do you know?
I don't know about
my teammates either.
What is that supposed to mean?
But if there's a way to let them know
how many points I'll get,
I can solve the question.
That's if you can let them know.
I'll communicate the number
to the next room with vibration.
I'll send four vibrations
through the wall.
I'll relay the information without
leaving the room or destroying it.
But will just hitting the wall
get your message across?
How would you interpret
four bangs on the wall?
If I should hear four signals...?
That wouldn't mean the other person
and I should score 40 points.
If two takes 40 each,
that's 80 points.
Then if the one
who signaled takes 50,
40, 30, 0 points...
None of the combinations
totals 100.
So it can be interpreted that the one
who signaled will take the 40-pointer.
And the other two
can take the 30-pointers.
– I see.
– That makes sense.
I wonder if Gennai and Inaho
will think the same way.
I hope Minoji and Tanzo
are okay.
Each village selected three Genin
to make up their teams for the Chunin Exam.
Everyone just has
to trust their teammates.
But why would you teach this
to all of us?
If I suddenly pounded
on the wall four times,
what would you think?
Well... Naturally, I'd get suspicious.
You would, right?
And I didn't want you guys
to do something and interfere.
I figured I'd come clean
and let everyone in on this,
and we can all pass
this stupid written test.
All of us?!
So that's his plan.
Everybody passes...
He really got you there, Proctor.
Well, I've gotten a good look
at his leadership skills.
All of us?
I see... You're right.
But how about letting me pass on
the info to the other classes?
Sure, but why?
I can't let the Hidden Leaf
do all the work.
I'll take the blame if
the classroom is damaged.
I just have to send vibrations, right?
Yes.
One!
Two! Three!
Four!
Hey, that was five times!
What are you doing?
Everyone passes?
You've got to be kidding.
What's the point of a test
if no one gets eliminated?!
Wh-Why you...!
– What a jerk!
– What's going on?
It's too late now.
If you send four vibrations again,
you'll only add
to the confusion.
It doesn't matter
if it's five times.
What?
Three times is fine too.
As long as the message gets out,
anyone can do it.
Anyone? Three, four, or five...
They're all the same?
Yes. Well, it's slightly different.
The question I pick will change.
Huh?
I see...
That was a signal of some sort.
It's definitely more efficient
than yelling something out.
But why five times?
Five times must mean
the 50-point question.
So what are we supposed to do?
I get it...
Even with three times,
my intention
would have been communicated.
In that case,
I'd take the 40-pointer.
How can you tell?
If the grouping is 30, 30,
and 40 for 100 points,
whoever sent the signal
won't take 30.
Because that'll leave
the remaining two
to decide between 30 and 40 points,
and that won't work.
So whoever signals takes
the 40-pointer,
leaving the 30-pointer
to his two teammates.
Damn you.
Why didn't you explain that earlier?
I made it clear, didn't I?
That I didn't want any interference.
I was concerned that jutsu users
who can communicate silently
with their teammates
would foil my plan for everyone
to pass this test.
You can, right?
No one will get in my way.
Well, you're not getting in my way!
Proctor, are you going
to allow fighting?!
If you don't reply,
I'll assume you are.
You want to fight?
Proctor, give us permission!
I made it clear that the first test
is a written one.
Fighting is prohibited!
Stop that racket and answer
the question before the time's up!
You heard him.
That Neji...
He even forced a hint out of me.
In that warning you just issued?
Until now, there was a possibility
that the others would think
I was the one who
pounded five times.
I warned them to keep quiet just now,
thus raising the possibility
that it was someone in
a classroom who made those sounds.
And in truth, it was.
So every team will score 100 points?
No, not necessarily.
If they rationalize it calmly,
they'd agree with Neji...
But just how calm can they remain?
How much faith they have
in their teammates
is another problem altogether.
What's the answer
that you prepared?
You're asking me?
If I were one of the test-takers,
I'd use my Shadow Possession Jutsu...
But this question wouldn't exist
if I weren't the proctor.
That's why there is no point
in me answering that question.
What are you quibbling about?
Anyway, it all boils down
to thinking carefully
about your teammates
and the situation.
Still, there's bound to
be many who pass.
And that'll make
the second test a pain.
I won't make trouble
for the Hidden Sand.
There's another part to this test.
Time's up.
Everyone, flip your sheets over.
Continuing to the second part
of this exam.
– What?!
– Huh?!
Question.
Your team is on a mission
and the enemy spots you.
In order to shake off
their pursuit,
one teammate must stay behind
as a decoy.
Who will you choose...
knowing that the decoy
faces certain death?
Write your answer on
the reverse side of the sheet.
In order to pass,
all three members on the team
must have the same answer.
And the member named as
the decoy will be considered killed
and eliminated from the Chunin Exam.
You have three minutes for this.
Begin!
How does he expect us to choose...?
Sand Letters...
So we'll go with Mijin?
Me?!
Damn it...
In our old Team 7,
it would have been Naruto.
Because he would probably
write his own name down.
The answer isn't Naruto.
My teammates now
are Ino and Choji...
So...
Sakura!
What'll we do?
I can't choose either of you!
What is Shikamaru thinking?
Ino, please relay this to Choji too.
The answer is...
Huh?! But that's...!
I'll be collecting your papers.
Wait in your classrooms
until the papers are graded.
Those who passed will be
called out to the courtyard.
You rarely visit.
To what do I owe this pleasure?
There's something you need to know.
You don't need Hidden Leaf proctors
for the second test?
The Hidden Sand would like
to handle everything ourselves.
And the reason for that?
The site of the second test
is known as the Demon Desert.
It's extremely dangerous even for
those of us familiar with the terrain.
For the sake of security,
we ask for your understanding.
For whose security, may I ask?
Naturally, for the participants.
The Jonin in charge of the entrants
will accompany them
to the Hidden Sand Village.
That is not open to negotiation.
Yes, that's fine.
What do you think?
Sounds suspicious.
Yes, they are hiding something.
But the Sand are not the only ones.
How have the Hidden Rain responded?
Danzo asked to see us earlier.
Even though he's confined
under house arrest,
he still has his connections.
You are aware that I helped
Hanzo of the Salamander,
the leader of the Hidden Rain Village?
That was when you were
in charge of the Foundation.
I continued to communicate with him
secretly even after I was ousted.
Danzo, you didn't...?
But Hanzo abruptly
stopped contacting me.
If he stopped trusting me,
he would've lured me out
and killed me
since I know so many secrets.
But he didn't.
Something has happened to Hanzo.
Like what?
I believe there's been
an incident in Hidden Rain Village.
In the worst case,
he's no longer in this world...
How can that be?
On the outside, Hanzo is still
the leader of the Hidden Rain Village.
Please warn Princess Tsunade
to be extremely wary of the entrants
sent by the Hidden Rain.
Well, you have been warned.
Danzo of all people asked you this?
He may be called a hardliner
and the darkness of the shinobi world...
But there is no doubt
that he operates all for
the sake of the Hidden Leaf.
The Hidden Rain, eh...
We must increase surveillance.
There's also the Sand to think of.
I will inform the Jonin in charge
of the entrants about this.
Just the Jonin of the teams
who pass the first test?
Yes.
Damn it...
Well...
Those of you here have passed
the first test. Congratulations.
Neji, you sent that signal, right?
Thanks to you, we made it.
Actually, it was that guy from
the Hidden Sand.
How come all three of you made it?
Didn't the decoy get disqualified?
The rule said all three had
to have the same answer.
We didn't choose anyone.
What?!
We all turned in a blank sheet.
Blank? All three of you?!
There's no way we'd sacrifice
a comrade.
Take a look...
at how many teams passed
with all three members.
I'm sorry I couldn't figure out
the question.
It's okay!
We coordinated things
with that in mind.
I know!
I trusted you two and
didn't write anything.
More like couldn't, right?
You guys!
We passed the first test!
You can transfer thoughts,
but that backfired on you, eh.
Well...
Thinking about letting a teammate die
was already the wrong answer.
Why you...
I'm Temari of the Hidden Sand.
I'm in charge of the second test.
Too many teams passed the first test,
so we're going to narrow it down
some more.
Hey, what do you mean
"narrow it down"?!
First off, the second test is also
a team battle.
Any team without its third member
will be disqualified!
What?!
Furthermore, the second test will be held
in the Hidden Sand Village.
We will meet at
the Demon Desert checkpoint.
Although there is a clear route
between the Hidden Leaf
and the Hidden Sand Village,
it will take a shinobi three days,
no matter how fast he or she may be.
A messenger hawk has been sent to
the Hidden Sand with these instructions.
"After the first 30 arrive,
all who follow are to be disqualified."
Finally, as in the first test,
fighting is prohibited en route.
You can fight to your heart's content
in the second test.
That is all.
Lee, Tenten...
He's quick to assess a situation,
after all.
What's wrong?
You're dismissed!
Ino, Choji!
Couldn't you at least
have said, "ready, set, go"?
This is the Chunin Exam.
Not the Academy.
Huh?
– Hey, Yukata!
– Get moving!
Maybe next time, we should stick
to an ordinary scholastic test.
Let's get there first!
There's no advantage
to being the first to arrive.
Byakugan!
There's one team ahead of us.
Lord Kazekage...
The first test of the Chunin Exam is over.
The participants are now heading
towards the Hidden Sand Village.
I see.
Get ready for the second test.
Where are you trying to go?
The Kazekage's quarters
are beyond here.
Hold it!
Who the hell are you?!
We seek to reform the Land of Wind!
You think I'd let you get away?!
You have nowhere to run...
Divine Punishment!
Take cover!
Oh, you're back.
Damn it...
Be more careful.
You wanted to talk to me?
Please, Gaara, forget about
supervising the Chunin Exam.
The people targeting you
are stepping up their efforts.
You'll just be playing into
their hands if you continue this!
I already know that.
But if I quit because of that,
it would be like declaring that
I will cave in under pressure.
Maybe so, but...
But this is only the Chunin Exam!
The Chunin Exam is where
everything began for me.
Thanks to him, I've made it this far.
I'll make sure this Chunin Exam
is a success...
... without fail.
We've finally reached
the Hidden Sand territory.
All right, let's go to
the second test site.
Sarutobi-sensei! Yuhi-sensei!
Sorry, but this is as far as you'll go.
Late arrivals are disqualified.
If you're from the Hidden Leaf,
return to the village.
The rest of you can disperse
from here too.
But we ran nonstop for
three days to get here!
If you're complaining,
then maybe it's for the best
that you're being eliminated.
Because beyond this point is hell.
And who knows if you'll even
get out of there alive.
Sakura! Everyone!
You made it!
I must admit,
Guy-sensei's team sure has stamina.
Team Asuma, Team Kurenai...
The main members from
that last time made it through.
Yup! You all gave it your all!
The fortitude you showed in running for
three days and three nights without sleep
has made me so proud!
Why, it takes me back to the time
I took the Chunin Exam...
Sensei... If you're going to
tell us a long story...
Please let us rest already.
I'm starving.
Seems like it.
We've never been to
the Hidden Sand before...
It really is nothing but desert.
To be accurate,
this isn't the Hidden Sand Village.
It's quite far from the village.
Neji, have you ever been to
the Hidden Sand Village?
Once on an errand for the Hyuga.
This is the Demon Desert checkpoint.
I see.
So this is what they're using.
Taking the test in a different village
is sort of nerve-wracking.
I wonder what
the second test will be like.
It's probably like last time.
So we'll be battling teams
from other villages?
There's a good chance of that.
Then we'll have to be wary
of some teams.
We went at full-speed,
yet we weren't the first to arrive.
The Hidden Waterfall team was
the first to arrive.
Not only that,
they got here long before us.
Just what kind of opponents
are they?
C'mon, open up!
What's going on?
The door won't open!
Sorry, Fuu.
Stay in there until morning.
Huh?! Why's that?
We never know what you'll do next.
So please, give us a break and
let us rest up for the next test.
Huh? Hey!
That means I can't go and
have fun with the others!
See, that's what worries us.
Dinner is ready.
Entrants, please assemble
in the cafeteria.
So that's Hidden Sand Village...
Check out the Hidden Sand team...
giving everyone the stink eye.
They sure look mean.
Well, Kiba... You look pretty mean too.
And over there
are the Hidden Rain.
I guess the other side
is the Hidden Grass.
That guy's amazing.
I'll say.
Compared to him, even
our slightly chubby Choji looks normal.
But the way he sweats...
Seriously, that's gross.
Hey...
I'm getting a bad feeling...
Bad feeling?
All that sweat.
If he gets close to the food...
All right! Time to eat dinner!
At this rate...
Our dinner will be...
Damn!
Eight Trigrams Palm Rotation!
S-Saved...
Uh... I do not think so.
What did you do to our dinner?
What are you thinking?
What did you do to our friend?!
Don't misunderstand!
We wanted to protect our food!
So you were going to save your food
and never mind the rest of us, right?
What are you saying?!
We'd never stoop to
something like that!
Your suspicion shows that
Gaara hasn't trained you right!
Did you just criticize Lord Gaara?
That is absolutely unforgivable!
Stop!
Please stop, everyone!
Hey, stop it!
Neji! Aren't you going to stop them?
Sorry, but I'm busy right now.
Burami!
Don't eat food off the ground!
Muyami! You help too!
I'll pass... I'm too shy.
Calm down, every—!
Do not fight—!
Why you...!
Will you stop... and listen to me?!
This room is way too small for
a flashy move like that.
I didn't do that at full strength,
but still...
To be able
to stop me with one hand...
What's that sound?
Fuu!
Ta-dah!
So the party's already started, guys?!
I wonder if I can make a hundred friends?
Wh-Who are you?
I'm Fuu from the Hidden Waterfall Village!
This one...
I came to the Chunin Exam
to make a hundred friends!
So guys, what's the plan
after dinner?
Cards? Backgammon? Musical chairs?
Or...
How about we all take
a bath together?
What's with you?
Oh well, so much for dinner...
I'm going back.
Huh? Hey...
W-Wait!
Don't go!
Hey guys, play with me!
Well...
It took an idiot like that
to stop the ruckus...
Sort of reminds me of someone.
I know... Naruto.
Right, Lee?
Huh? Lee?
Excuse me, please wait!
I realized it when
I made contact earlier.
You are not like the others.
You stopped my attack
with such ease.
It may sound arrogant
coming from me,
but it takes someone
extraordinary to do that.
That's why I can tell...
That you have had to overcome
great odds like me.
What are you trying to say?
Well... that you and I are alike.
I know about you.
You're Rock Lee of the Hidden Leaf.
I'm Shira of the Hidden Sand.
Shira...
I don't know what it is you sensed,
but dwelling on the misfortunes
of birth is meaningless.
Because, for all of one's flaws
and suffering,
we have just one life.
To me, there is only one truth in life.
One truth in life?
Determination never betrays you.
Shira...
Lady Tsunade, I've returned.
I'm glad you made it back.
So how did it go?
As I reported, I wasn't able
to see Hanzo in person.
I intended to sneak back in and
investigate, but...
The infiltrator must be around here!
Find him!
What?
They've discovered
my presence already?
They were on to me from the start.
It was almost as though...
ghosts were watching me.
Well...
I was expecting just
the usual Chunin Exam,
But now that it's started,
we're discovering some
interesting things about each village.
Interesting things?
Choji...
What are you doing?
Ino...
What's that building?
Oh, that's where the Senseis
are staying.
The Senseis?!
Hey, Choji!
I'll bet they'll give us some food
if we go there!
We're not supposed to
wander around at night!
He's so hungry,
he can't think straight!
Let's go after him!
Choji! Where are you?!
– Choji?!
Friends...
Byakugan!
What is that shadow?
Whose voice was that?!
No way...
Did someone go outside?
What?
Oh! Cards? Backgammon?!
Giant scorpions come out at night
during this time of year!
That's why you were told
not to go outside!
You have things like that?!
Hey!
Choji!
I'm here to help you!
What is this thing?!
Hidden Waterfall Hurricane!
Yahoo! This is fun!
No! Stop!
Wh-What's happening?!
Hey!
Stop fooling around,
and take that thing down!
Huh? It's over already...?!
It's dangerous!
Aww... Guess I have no choice!
Sakura, are you all right?
Yeah...
But you're bleeding!
I'm okay.
Please don't move.
This girl...
She's a Medical Ninja like me...
That should do it.
Thank you.
She's got skill.
Yahoo!
Yahoo yahoo-hoo!
Honestly...
What a pain...
Her again...
How'd she show up so fast?
And she brought down
that monster in no time.
Wh-What is this?!
What's going on?
Going outside at night is prohibited.
The second test begins before dawn!
Hurry up and return
to your quarters!
– We're sorry.
– Guy-sensei!
W-We're starving!
You guys are...
Go back now!
Clear your mind of mundane thoughts
and even a fire will go out!
Missing one meal won't kill a person!
Just think of this
as part of training!
Huh? Huh?
Huh?! You're all leaving?
I'm so sad...
You're a good person...
helping foes from other villages.
If you had ignored them, you would've
ended up with fewer rivals.
I don't care about rivals or allies.
I wonder if I'm going to make
a hundred friends!
Hey, let's be friends!
Want to play cards? Backgammon?
Or... want to bathe together?!
That is the Lord Kazekage
and the Jonin supervisors!
Watch what you say!
One hundred...!
– Enough! Let's go back!
– ... friends!
Doesn't care about rivals or allies, huh.
Sounds just like someone I know.
Gaara?
It's nothing.
Now I have more to look forward to
in the Chunin Exam.
Thanks to a few interesting
characters taking part in it.
All right...
I'm going to explain the second test
of the Chunin Exam.
The second test will be
a competition for scrolls
to be held in the Demon Desert.
In other words,
this is the ultimate survival battle!
There are two scrolls,
Heaven and Earth.
Half the teams will be
given Heaven scrolls.
The other half will get Earth scrolls.
The objective of this test
is to obtain both the Heaven
and Earth scrolls
and to bring them back
to the base
located in the center of the Demon Desert.
You have 72 hours.
Find food on your own!
Starting now, there may be fatalities.
Every participating team member
will sign a consent form!
When you turn in the team consent forms,
you will be given a scroll!
Furthermore, to avoid confusion,
each team will start from
a different location.
So be quick,
and go to your starting points!
It's finally starting...
The second test of the Chunin Exam!
We don't know what lies ahead.
So let's stay on our toes.
– Right!
– Okay!