What took you so long?
I flew back as quickly
as I could.
More to the point,
you took too long to send over
a substitute border guard.
Your planning was bad.
That's no way to show
your appreciation.
I carried out your selfish request
while still recovering from an illness.
Well... Shall we get going?
Yeah.
Right!
Neji...
Can you see what's happening
to me here?
Yeah...
The same thing is happening here.
Tenten, what about you?
It's probably...
the same here, too.
Lee!
A strange shadow appeared in the forest
as soon as I removed the tag.
I thought so...
Team Kakashi has infiltrated
just as planned.
What is... this...?
It's probably an enemy trap.
I see...
So that's what this is about.
I find you a worthy opponent.
Gaara!
What are you doing lazing around
in a place like this?!
Stand up!
Gaara!
Hey! Gaara! Are you listening?!
Knock it off!
That's enough, Naruto!
You should know...
That's right. You know, don't you?
That he's already dead.
Oh...
He's definitely... the Jinchuriki.
Give Gaara back!
You bastards!
Calm down...
If you charge ahead without thinking,
we'll be annihilated.
What's up, Master Sasori?
I'll take him.
It seems that Jinchuriki wants
to take him back, so...
You'll probably get mad if I say this...
But I'll take care
of that Jinchuriki.
Our mission is one Jinchuriki each.
Don't get ahead of yourself, Deidara...
An artist's passion starts to dull
unless they seek
greater stimulation, Master...
The rumor is the Nine-Tailed Jinchuriki
is quite powerful.
He's an opponent suitable for my art.
What? You really call those explosions
of yours "art"?
True art is something that
endures beautifully...
far into the future.
Eternal beauty is art!
Eternal beauty... is art?
I do respect you as
a fellow artist, Master...
But art is fleeting! A moment of beauty
that fades instantly.
Deidara, you clearly don't
understand what true art is.
You're the one
who doesn't understand.
No! Eternal beauty is true art.
Don't be a fool.
Art is the beauty of a fleeting moment.
Knock it off!
Do you want to make me angry?
I just told you...
It would probably make
you angry, didn't I...?
You know what happens
when I get angry, don't you?
He blocked the shuriken
without looking at all...
He's just as good with the Puppet
Master technique as he always was.
How about it, Deidara?
Art to me is...
an explosion!
It's a far cry from
your pathetic puppet show!
See you around, Master!
Hey, wait!
All right.
Naruto!
I guess Naruto won't stop, will he?
Naruto and I will take care
of the guy outside.
Sakura and Granny Chiyo...
you two take the one inside.
However...
make sure you don't do
anything rash until Team Guy gets back.
Got it.
He came too, huh...?
Guy, can you hear me?
The enemy has split up.
We need backup.
Return immediately.
I don't think we can.
Sorry Kakashi, it looks like things
will still take a while over here.
Rotation.
If detaining someone is your objective,
there's no better way than this.
If your opponent has exactly
the same abilities as you do...
It probably won't be that easy
to bring matters to a close.
Splendid move, Imposter.
Signing off!
Looks like...
I can't be wasting my time...
I'd heard that you'd retired long ago.
I just wanted to see
my grandson's face again.
I can tell just by facing him.
The incredible difference
in actual battle experience...
and the number of people he's killed.
Sakura, do not fear...
I'm with you. Stay back.
If you're going to defy me,
then I guess I have no choice.
Wh-What's that...?
That's not Sasori's real body...
I can tell that's not his real body.
Yes...
That's... a puppet.
Puppet Masters are supposed to be
pulling the strings from behind, right?
His real body's inside that.
Inside?
Puppet Masters have trouble
with close-range combat.
After all, when controlling a puppet,
they leave themselves open...
That puppet there has basically
surmounted that problem.
The puppet acts as a shield
as well as a weapon.
It's Sasori's specialty, Hiruko.
Lady Chiyo... About that puppet...
I know a lot about it.
Do you know how I make
my collection?
First. I pull out the organs...
Then after I've washed
the body nice and clean...
I extract the blood.
Once I've prepared the body
so it won't decay,
I fill it with hidden weapons
and then...
it becomes a complete addition
to my puppet collection.
Just as the old woman said,
this form you see...
Hiruko, is a part of my collection.
And once I add this girl
and the old hag...
I'll have exactly three hundred
in my collection.
It's my art!
Hiruko is a puppet with
a great attack and defense.
Be that as it may, first we need
to drag Sasori out of Hiruko.
What do we do?
In order to defeat Sasori,
first we must destroy that Hiruko.
However, I don't have that kind
of destructive power.
But Sakura...
You do.
First, get close to him...
and smash the puppet with
your incredible strength.
However, you must dodge all
of his hidden weapon attacks.
Poison, right...?
That's right... Even a scratch
can turn into a fatal wound.
In order to dodge his attacks,
you must figure out the tricks
to the hidden weapons of
the master craftsman's puppet.
And you must also be able to immediately
assess how to dodge his attacks.
I don't think I can do either...
Indeed...
In order to do that,
a lot of actual battle experience
is required.
Then... how can I...?
What do I look like to you?
Do I just look like
some unreliable old hag...?
Or...
Leave it to me...
That's why I'm here!
I have much more actual
battle experience than he does.
And he knows that.
That's why he doesn't attempt
to attack carelessly.
This man who so hates
waiting for people,
and being kept waiting by them...
And besides...
I made the first move.
Sakura. Lend me your ears.
You and I...
will defeat him!
Is it okay for you to be taking me on?
Sharingan Kakashi.
I hate to say this, but...
Master Sasori is stronger than me...
Probably...
Our ideas of art are
quite different, though.
From here, I can't make out
what they're saying...
Understood.
I'll give it a try.
Are you about ready?
You know I hate to
be kept waiting, don't you?
Rest easy. We'll...
... put an end to this soon.
Die!
They completely dodged
my attack just now?
I'd expect it from the old hag.
But that little girl...
I'm being mocked...
I can't believe she's charging at me
head on without any backup...
It won't move!
I get it! Grandma...!
Now, Sakura!
Smash him!
Right!
That's his real body.
After twenty years,
shall we face each other?
As I thought.
Just what I'd expect
from my old granny.
No wonder this little girl was able
to dodge my hidden weapons.
After all, the old lady who can see
past my attacks was controlling
the little girl with chakra threads
used for the Puppet Master jutsu.
He found out.
What's more, you were so kind as to
attach threads of chakra to Hiruko's tail.
But to think that I'd notice it
after the tail's motion had been
brought to a halt...
It was when you first attacked
with the kunai, wasn't it?
Threads of chakra attached
to the kunai
latched onto the tail
when it repelled the kunai.
I suppressed my chakra as much
as possible so as not to be seen,
and yet you still figured it out.
I'm amazed.
But of course.
After all, the one who hammered
the principles of puppetry into me was...
none other than you.
Yes.
But the show ends today.
That is my intention as well.
Now then, I wonder if it'll
really be that simple...
Granny Chiyo...?
What is going on?
He's just as he was before...
He hasn't aged a bit.
What's going on?!
I was told Sasori broke off from
the Hidden Sand 20 years ago...
There's no way that
he could be this young.
You! Return Gaara to us!
It's only a matter of time
before Master Sasori finishes off
the group inside.
If Master comes out,
then the whole point of using this one
to draw out the Jinchuriki will be lost.
You jerk!
I won't let you get away.
Hold it right there!
Naruto, wait a minute!
Kakashi-sensei,
you go look after Sakura!
Good grief.
While I'm at it,
I'll show you something special.
It's guaranteed to move you.
This one gave me quite a bit of trouble
to kill, but...
Three...?
That's why I like this best of all.
Th-That... It couldn't be!
What? What's wrong?!
That's... the Third Kazekage...
Then...
It was over ten years ago
that the Third Kazekage suddenly
disappeared from the village.
We scoured the countryside,
but we were never able to find him.
He was the most powerful
of all the Kazekage, but...
Sasori, you...?
And so what if I did?
Do you mean to say that a retired old lady
with one foot in the grave
is about to avenge the Third Kazekage?
Tough luck...
Retired, with one foot in the grave.
That may be so,
but it was worth dragging
my old bones out here.
I'd have too many regrets
if I were to die now.
It's bad enough that my grandson
got himself mixed up
with a bad crowd...
but to think that you'd betray the village
and try to meddle with the Kazekage,
for the third time!
Third time?
It was Orochimaru
who killed Gaara's father,
the Fourth Kazekage, but...
the one who guided them
was Sasori!
And this time,
Gaara and even the Third Kazekage...
Hey, hey, I don't know anything
about the Fourth Kazekage.
The one who guided them
was my subordinate.
In that case, it's the same
as if you did it yourself.
Can you really say that
you were not involved?
Indeed, I was originally paired with
Orochimaru in the Akatsuki,
so I did lots of things but...
If you were paired
with Orochimaru...
then that means you know
about Orochimaru.
In that case, there are a lot
of questions I need you to answer!
Unfortunately,
I must take you two out
and go capture that Jinchuriki.
I hate to keep people waiting,
so I have no time
to answer your questions.
Well then, shall we get right to it?
Here it comes!
Die!
He's fast!
To think that Hiruko's tail
fell to pieces...
You've got some pretty good moves,
Granny Chiyo.
In that case, how about this?
Oh no!
Take this!
With the old lady manipulating things,
it's impossible to get anywhere.
In that case...
Oh, no! Sakura! Hold your breath!
Is it poison?!
It's a kunai with a rope attached.
You should have repelled it,
rather than dodged it.
I can't hold my breath...
Sakura!
I... can't die...
in a place like this!
What!
Sakura!
Not bad...
She...
Did she use the blast waves
of a paper bomb
to blow away the poisonous smoke?
Along with herself in it,
escaping the trap in the process...
How reckless of her...!
You...!
I will capture you!
Even if my arms and legs
were to be blown off...
Even if I were to swallow poison
and become immobile...
I will capture you, no matter what!
No matter how much
you might resist...
No matter what tricks
you come up with...
I will make you tell me everything
about Orochimaru!
You hear me?!
Huh?!
When a woman is talking,
a man should listen quietly.
Oh... those things...
That's right...
They're the first puppets
you ever made.
The father and...
the mother.
So what do you plan to do
with those now, huh?
Those are puppets I made.
I know all their tricks.
This is stupid...
Sakura! Stand back!
Okay!
Amazing...
This is getting messy...
I better hurry up and use this thing.
As I thought, that puppet...
uses the Third Kazekage's jutsu...!
You haven't seen this in
a while, have you...?
This jutsu is why the Third Kazekage
was praised as the most powerful.
I'm going to turn you guys into mush.
What the hell is that?
That was the most feared weapon
of the Hidden Sand.
The Iron Sand.
Iron Sand...?
The Third developed that jutsu
by adapting the technique used by
Shukaku's former host.
It changes the Iron Sand
into various shapes,
creating weapons according
to the situation.
The Third Kazekage had a special body
that could change the chakra
into magnetism.
Similarly, it appears that puppet
also can change the chakra
into magnetism.
What do you mean?
Even though the actual body of
The Third Kazekage was used,
it's still just a puppet, right?
Why does a puppet have chakra?
No... A Human Puppet made
from an actual living body
is fundamentally different
from these normal ones
like the "mother" and
"father" puppets.
A Human Puppet can only
be made by Sasori...
and that is made while the person's
chakra still resides within them.
And by doing so, it can use the person's
jutsu from its previous life.
That's the biggest benefit
of the "Human Puppet."
That's not all.
After all,
this is my favorite collection.
Sakura, get out of here.
I will take care of the rest.
This is way too unexpected.
You stand no chance against that puppet.
But!
You're too slow!
Iron Sand: Scattered Showers!
Did you alter it a little?
A chakra shield, huh?
Looks like it's been upgraded compared
to the time I was playing with them.
As expected, due to
the Iron Sand, my moves...
Don't you know that you have to dodge
this jutsu and not shield it?
Seems like you could barely
let the girl escape.
I inserted the Iron Sand
into his entire body.
As long as I have the Third's magnetism,
that one's done for.
Let's see... I will aim at both
of you and attack at once.
In order to ensure a definite kill,
I will form it into a lethal weapon.
I won't let you get away
a second time...
With only one puppet,
you can't guard both of you.
What are you going to do, Granny?
Which one of you will die?!
Though only the arm...
Turning your own body into a puppet...
As fellow Puppet Masters,
it seems... we think the same way.
I see. I get it now...
It's the end if the Iron Sand gets in.
Let's see...
The puppet has ceased.
What are you going to do,
Granny Chiyo?
Even the world's greatest Puppet Master...
is nothing, but an ordinary person
without her puppets.
Grandma Chiyo...
Please use me!
What I can do now...
is to become Grandma Chiyo's
puppet and fight.
If you use me, he can't stop
my moves with the Iron Sand.
I am left with one arm.
I can't support you like before.
I'm okay...
True, I don't have a great weapon
like the puppet, but...
Like my master, I have guts!
Princess Tsunade, huh...
The Third's power is magnetism.
Therefore, weapons made from
iron and steel won't work.
Excellent! Like my master, I fight best
with my fists.
That again... Ridiculous.
Here I go!
You...
Here I come!
Sasori's going to get mad at me again
for not being prepared enough...
But it's not my style to think
about every little detail
and always be perfectly prepared.
Dealing with matters with
a flexible mindset,
no matter what the situation,
leads to developing sophistication
as an artist.
What should I do?
Listen up, Naruto.
You're not accustomed to
that kind of enemy.
Not only that, he's a long-range type,
the worst match for someone like you;
who specializes in close-range battle.
There are only two ways to
defeat this type of enemy.
One is to draw the enemy into a
close-range fight and defeat them...
The other is to outdo the enemy with
a long-range attack and defeat them.
But, how do we do that...?
No matter which method is taken,
your squad needs either a comrade
who specializes in long-range attacks
or one who can use support ninjutsu
for long-range battles.
In the event of having neither...
it's impossible to defeat the enemy.
Well, it'd be different if you were
as smart as Shikamaru, though.
Stop beating around the bush!
If that's the case, then what about
you Kakashi-sensei...?
Oh... me, huh?
A Jonin who's as smart as Shikamaru
and possesses support ninjutsu
for long-range battles.
Then we've got what we need!
That's why I told you to calm down.
Then we should get right to it...
It won't work out that easily.
He won't leave himself open
if we just chase him around.
All we can do is create
an opening from our end.
You and me together.
If you were able to
catch on to what I said,
then lend me an ear.
I'll tell you the plan.
She's got impressive strength
for a little girl.
In just this short time,
she's starting to read
Sasori's attack patterns.
So much so, that she can do just fine
even without my help.
I never thought she would be
this good...
She's an impressive girl.
His fingers always move
before he attacks...
That's obvious since
he's controlling the puppet
with the chakra strings on his fingers...
But that's the weakness
of a Puppet Master.
And I've started to read
the direction of Sasori's attacks
with the patterns of his finger
and arm movements.
She's watching very carefully...
At this rate,
this will be too time-consuming...
I have no choice
but to use some chakra.
I guess I'll finish her off with that...
Iron Sand: Unleash!
Its range is huge!
This is not good!
Sakura, are you okay?!
She's been poisoned!
Didn't I tell you...
"That's not all there is"?
As I suspected, he laced the
Iron Sand with poison...
The poison is starting to take effect...
Soon your body will go numb
and you won't be able to move.
If left untreated, you have
three days to live...
But I've got no intention of doing that!
Sakura!
Grandma Chiyo.
What's going on...?
Sakura... You...
I used an antidote.
When did you... get such a thing...?
When I made the antidote for Kankuro
in the Village Hidden in the Sand...
I knew the enemy would use poison,
so I made the other two into injections
and brought them with me.
I see... So that's how...
Yes, I used one of the two.
However, the effects of the antidote
will only last around three minutes.
No matter how often I get hit
with poison during that time,
the effects of the medicine will turn
all of it into harmless proteins.
I couldn't let Sasori find out
that I had this antidote...
I knew I'd have an opportunity
after he revealed his final intentions
and let his guard down.
So I couldn't use it until
the very last moment.
Now there's only one left...
I will hand this over to you,
Grandma Chiyo.
Right...
Are you okay?!
Don't tell me
the poison was neutralized...
If you want to live that badly,
I won't finish you off.
However, that poison will kill you
in less than three days...
Don't tell me they analyzed the components
using the poison from back then...
No, that couldn't be.
Even if by some chance they were able
to analyze the components,
they shouldn't be able to
make an antidote that easily.
The concoction of an antidote
is so difficult
that even the slightest mistake
is not permissible.
Even I, who made the poison,
needed a precise formula
for the mixture...
I'll heal you now.
Now poison won't affect me for
the next three minutes.
Everything depends on
those three minutes!
Right...
Grandma, huh...?
No, I'm the only one with that level
of medical skill in the Sand Village.
I made a poison that
even she wouldn't be able to
immediately create an antidote for.
So this kid's also
a medical ninja, huh...?
If I recall, she's from the Leaf...
The Leaf's Hokage, Tsunade,
is a legendary medical ninja...
Don't tell me...
she made the antidote...?!
Sakura, my left hand's okay now.
O-Okay...
For the time being,
I stopped the bleeding
of the large wounds...
I'll use all of my remaining chakra
to attack!
If I don't finish this during
the next three minutes,
there won't be a next time!
We don't have any time.
Can you fight right away,
Grandma Chiyo?
Let's go, Sakura!
Right!
Heh... I'll admit it.
You're an impressive kid.
Who would've thought she could destroy
my Third Kazekage puppet...
It's useless to use
other Human Puppets any longer.
I haven't used this since
I joined the Akatsuki...
I can't remember when that was...
Wh-What's that?!
He hasn't aged at all since
he left my side.
He's exactly the same as before...
And that's the reason why...
It's really been a long time...
since I used myself.
He turned himself...
into a Human Puppet.
Got it?
Yeah, I got it!
Let's go.
If you're not going to attack me...
The effects of the antidote
will last less than two minutes.
During that time... somehow, I need
to turn this into a close-range battle
and then finish him off...
Then I'll make the first move!
It's useless to hide!
What's the matter...?
Aren't you going to attack?
The effects of the antidote
will last one more minute...
Then...
Water?
Sakura! Get away!
There!
Fifteen seconds... left...
You little—!
Cha!
Three seconds.
Two!
We did it.
Grandma Chiyo, we did it!
Sakura...
You...
What did you do?
That's right.
The fight is just beginning.
This is a jutsu I myself sealed...
I didn't think I'd ever use it again...
But it seems it won't work out
that way.
Now let's put an end to this.
It's said the ability of
a puppet master is measured
by the number of puppets they can use...
I'd expect nothing less from you, old hag.
Th-There's so many...
Ten of them.
Granny Chiyo's secret technique,
the "Ten Fingers."
I'd heard rumors about it...
The device you used to bring down
a castle by yourself...
The Secret White Move:
Chikamatsu's 10 Puppets.
The ten masterpieces by Monzaemon,
the creator of the Puppet Master Jutsu...
It's a great collection of puppets.
However...
I...
used this to bring down a nation!
He's become... this powerful...
I'm appalled at myself.
How long am I going to have to fight
a little girl and an old hag...?
I never thought I'd have to
bring out my final device...
Secret Red Move: Performance
of a Hundred Puppets...
I'll show you...
But let's make this the final act.
Are you ready?
Yes!
Here he comes!
With this many of them...
The only way to thin their numbers
is to fight them one-on-one somehow...
All right!
There are too many of them!
Are you okay, Sakura?!
I'm okay!
Stay sharp!
Right!
There definitely aren't
as many of Sasori's puppets now...
But conversely, it looks like he's
concentrating more on each puppet now.
And on top of that,
we only have one antidote left.
Things will get tough in a hurry
if either Sakura or I get wounded.
Grandma Chiyo!
Oh no...!
Are you okay, Grandma Chiyo?
You don't need to worry about me!
More importantly, aim for Sasori.
I'll keep the other puppets in check!
Right!
Sakura, use that!
Here!
We did it!
You can't move.
That seal completely
suppresses one's chakra.
You can't use
your chakra threads anymore.
It's over, Sasori...
Grandma Chiyo!
Use the antidote quickly!
That kid... has totally calmed down...
What's he planning?
Kakashi-sensei!
Aren't you ready yet?!
Be patient...
I don't have as much chakra
as you, after all...
It's going to take time.
Sakura!
Grandma Chiyo!
Are you okay?
Can you still move?
Oh? Worrying about others
with a wound like that?
Sasori... How...?
Don't tell me...
She's... stopping the bleeding
and healing herself with a sword
still stuck in her body.
She's skilled.
Grandma Chiyo, I'm okay.
So hurry up and
take the antidote.
Sakura.
It looks like the poison
is starting to take effect.
Of course, this sword
is also poisoned, you see.
My body's getting numb
from the poison,
so I can't control
my chakra very well.
So that's the antidote.
Why?
Grandma... Chiyo.
I can't believe how everyone chooses
death for the sake of others...
How stupid...
I won't let go.
This girl's got... incredible strength.
Grandma Chiyo!
It's futile to engage in
a contest of strength with her.
Then...
Die!
You lowered your guard
at the end, Sasori.
What?
Now you can't move.
Am I right?
Although you may have
the body of a puppet,
you still use chakra, so you need
a living core...
That's your weakness.
And the only thing missing from that shell
is the core from your left chest.
You switched...
to a different puppet.
The body of a puppet
is just an empty shell.
Your real body...
is the core in your chest that
produces chakra.
Sakura!
This is not good.
In any event, I've got to
pull out this sword
while closing the wound.
Hang in there.
Just a little more.
It's useless. I struck a vital point.
She'll die soon, even without the poison.
She's lost too much blood.
Since you're also a medical ninja,
I aimed for a spot
you can't easily heal.
I've already administered first aid
with my medical ninjutsu.
What I'm doing right now
isn't medical ninjutsu.
What?
I'm giving her
my own life energy.
Don't tell me...
It's a Reincarnation Jutsu!
A Reincarnation Jutsu?
It's a jutsu I spent years creating
originally for you...
one that only I can use.
With this jutsu...
life can even be given to puppets.
But only in exchange for the
caster's own life...
Sasori.
But now I see, it's a dream
that will never come true...
How stupid...
Have a safe trip.
It... It can't be...!
Damn you...
White Fang of the Leaf!
Grandma Chiyo!
Are Mommy and Daddy back?
They're not?
W-Well, your mommy and daddy were
suddenly sent on another mission...
It looks like they won't be back
for a little while.
I just heard from them and they want
you to wait with me for them to return.
Can you wait, Sasori?
Yeah.
Sasori! How've you been?
Huh?
Granny Chiyo said
your last puppet was incredible.
Someday, I want to be
a shinobi like you,
where everyone praises my puppets...
Hey! Are you listening?!
Hey, it's me!
Komushi has come to see you!
Hey! Answer me!
H-Hey, I didn't mean it.
I'm sorry.
But you're treating me worse
than a puppet.
Oh well, I guess I'll be
waiting forever
to get a response from you.
I have a message from Granny Chiyo.
She wants the puppets
she ordered finished soon...
The Crow, Black Ant and Salamander...
Oh...
Everything she requested is done.
Oh, so these are your new creations.
That was so quick...
I don't like to keep people waiting.
Yeah... That's true.
Hey... That's amazing.
They look so human!
Oh, I almost forgot.
About your new creation...
She asked me to ask about
the poison for the Crow puppet.
Huh?
These are all rare medicinal plants!
You're going to make poison out of these?
This is going to require permission.
All right!
I, Komushi, will handle the negotiations!
Just give me some time.
I don't want to wait.
I guess not. Then let's go!
It's me, Komushi!
What is it?
Oh... Did you relay my message...?
Granny Chiyo, Sasori has a request.
What is it?
There's not much I can say
without knowing the formula
for the poison.
But since this is coming from you,
I have no issues with it.
I'll clear it with
the Pharmaceuticals Division.
I'm busy with my research,
so you can go now.
Ahhh... you've got it made, Sasori.
You're still young, but you're already
contributing to the village.
Granny Chiyo must be so proud of you.
Are you listening to me?
Granny Chiyo is always
worried about you.
I can't wait to be acknowledged
as a full-fledged shinobi...
just like your puppets!
My own parents still treat me
like a kid!
They tell me I'm not suited
to being a shinobi...
But this time,
I was assigned to border security.
It's just guard duty,
but if I can prove myself...
Komushi!
What have you been doing
at this hour?!
I was so worried!
Wait... Cut it out,
you're embarrassing me!
I'm going to be assigned border
security missions from now on...
You can turn down things
like missions!
I'll take care of you
for the rest of my life.
Mom, stop it!
Thanks, Sasori!
I heard that you were injured on duty?
I messed up.
But...
That's... a puppet arm!
That's not all!
I feel stronger than before.
And it fits perfectly.
It feels like it's always been
a part of my body.
How could you poison yourself?!
Granny Chiyo...
He's... He's not to blame.
I'm the one... who messed up...
Where is Sasori?!
Do we have the formula
for the poison yet?
Please heal him...
Heal him! Please!
You attached his right arm too, right?
Then his left arm can be...
His legs, his body...
You can even heal his soul, can't you?!
Give him back to me!
Heal my Komushi and
give him back to me!
I don't like to make people wait.
I expected you to have made
more progress by now.
Sasori! What are you doing?!
You barely got it to
the standard size...
Sasori!
It's Komushi?!
As requested...
The specimen is complete.
How stupid.
When did you get so senile, granny?
Sakura, are you okay?
Yes.
What about you, Grandma Chiyo?
That's strange.
I thought the caster of that
Reincarnation Jutsu or whatever
was supposed to die
in exchange for breathing life
into someone dead.
Sakura's wound was severe,
but she wasn't dead...
So my life was spared.
That's unfortunate.
I'd stop that.
This body doesn't
even feel pain.
The more you hit me,
the more your own fists will hurt.
Women certainly like
to do pointless things.
I won't feel anything
even if my own grandmother
were to die.
My heart is just like this body.
I've killed hundreds, thousands of people.
She'd be the same as one of them.
Things are simpler that way.
What is a human life to you?!
What is family to you?!
Come on... Is that what
a shinobi should be saying?
Sakura...
That's enough.
But...!
It was the twisted customs of the
Sand Village that made him this way.
Granny Chiyo.
Do you want to have
a body like this?
If you did,
you might understand
what I'm talking about.
This body won't decay, and
it's not bound by a lifespan.
A puppet can be recreated
over and over again.
I can create as many people
as I want with puppets.
If you want, that is...
It's not just about increasing
the amount.
A collection is all about quality.
What the hell are you?!
I'd venture to say
I am a human who failed
to become a complete... puppet.
I'm a puppet,
but an incomplete puppet
possessing a living core.
I'm not a person...
nor am I a puppet.
I'll soon stop moving.
Before that, I think
I'll do something pointless...
It's your reward for defeating me.
You wanted to know
about Orochimaru, right?
At midday in ten days,
go to the Tenchi Bridge
in the Hidden Grass Village.
What do you mean?
I've got a spy working...
as one of Orochimaru's
subordinates...
I was supposed to rendezvous...
with him... there...
It's over, Granny Chiyo.
Excellent work.
No. I was the one who should've...
been defeated.
What?
Sasori read my final attack.
But for some reason,
he didn't dodge it.
A slight opening was revealed.
Could it be that he...?
I'll heal you now!
I've got to do something...
about the poison that
entered her body...
Let's hurry back to the village.
I'll make another antidote
immediately...
No...
Why?!
We've finished what
we were supposed to do.
We need to return to the village
and make an antidote
for the poison immediately...
More importantly...
I've still got...
something I must... do.
Kakashi-sensei,
aren't you ready yet?
It's ready.
That's what you were talking
about before?
That's right.
It's my new Sharingan.
Let's go, Naruto!
Right!
Mangekyo Sharingan!
A visual jutsu...?!
What is this jutsu...?
It's amazing...
My arm's getting sucked into space...?!
What kind of jutsu is this?!
I guess I still can't control
the location or size
of the dimensional barrier very well...
But I won't... miss next time...
Rasengan!
Shadow Clone Jutsu.
Gaara!
Gaara! Gaara!
Kakashi-sensei, are you okay?
Yeah... somehow...
Gaara!
Hey... Hey, Gaara!
It was fine using the Kazekage
as bait to lure out the Jinchuriki.
But I didn't plan on...
him coming along...
My left arm...
was crushed by the Sand Jinchuriki.
Now my right arm, too...
Now I can't even use a jutsu.
I guess this is it...
But... I never thought there was anyone
with dojutsu as good as Itachi.
This Jinchuriki's nothing special.
Kakashi's the more important issue...
I'll crush you!
Fine, fine.
I'll take you on again one of these days.
You let your guard down...
Naruto...
It's clay... It was a substitution!
What is... that...?
That's... what Master Jiraiya
was talking about...
The Nine-Tails' Cloak...?
So that's the Jinchuriki's...
No wonder...
his punches were so hard...
It's so hot...!
Listen carefully, Kakashi.
At some point...
the Nine-Tails' chakra may
leak out of Naruto's body...
and take the form
of the Fox Spirit.
The chakra will turn
into the Fox Spirit?!
You can refer to it as
the Nine-Tails' Cloak.
The Nine-Tails' Cloak...?
Listen carefully...
You must stop it while
there's still only one tail...
If you don't...
you'll end up seeing
something frightening...
Right from the start...
Calm down, Naruto!
He's lost his ability
to think calmly and rationally.
It's dangerous to
approach him carelessly...
If the need arises... use this.
With this, you can immediately
suppress the chakra.
He was formidable.
I'd expect no less from my imposter.
Everyone! Have things been settled?
Yes, Guy-sensei!
- Yeah...
- Naturally!
All right!
Let's go back up Team Kakashi!
- Roger!
Have you calmed down, Naruto?
What in the world
did Master Jiraiya see?
I got to see something pretty cool.
Someone's... coming...
We finally meet up.
S-Sakura...
Good job finding us.
We felt a huge tremor earlier...
You guys... did it, huh?
Yeah...
It looks like you're still...
having some trouble here...
Unfortunately...
What happened with Gaara...?
All right...
Don't tell me...
I can't believe Master Sasori got
beaten by a little girl and an old hag...
"Eternal beauty that lasts forever,"
my ass.
He goes and dies just like that...
He was too confident in a body
that paraded its only weakness!
Well, from my standpoint,
it was an ending befitting of an artist.
Good work, Neji.
You used those eyes to approach me
from my blind spot, huh...?
It's the first time
I've seen the real deal...
I'd like to see how it's different
from Itachi's Sharingan.
But I think escaping from
this situation comes first now.
Heh! Now that Team Guy,
the Leaf's mightiest team, is here...
you can't escape!
Exactly!
Prepare yourself!
Team Guy, huh?
Not bad.
Severe Leaf Hurricane!
Looks like it's impossible
to escape on foot...
Here I go!
8 Trigrams:
Air Palm!
These guys are so persistent!
I'm sure it's around here...
Down there, huh?!
He went down!
We don't know what he's planning.
Don't lower your guard!
- Roger!
Be careful, everyone!
He's a long-range type
who uses explosives!
I'll show you my ultimate work of art...
He's concentrating his chakra
in one spot all at once!
Get back quickly, everyone!
Art is an explosion!
We won't make it in time!
What's going on?!
I somehow made it in time...
Are you okay, Kakashi-sensei?
What in the world...
did you do?
I blew the explosion...
into another dimension.
This is... a Sharingan visual jutsu...
I don't really get what happened,
but the enemy has
been defeated, right, Tenten?
Hey! Don't ask me that.
More importantly...
Is everyone okay?
Sakura...
Why...? Why did it have to be...?
Why is it always Gaara?
Did he have to die like this...?!
He's the Kazekage...
He just became the Kazekage...
Calm down, Naruto Uzumaki...
Shut up!
This wouldn't have happened
if you Sand shinobi hadn't put
a monster inside Gaara!
Did you even ask Gaara at all
about how he felt?!
Jinchuriki, my ass!
You have no right to act so
high and mighty, labeling us...
with that word you created!
Naruto...
I can't save Sasuke...
And I can't save... Gaara...
I trained so hard for three years.
Nothing's changed
since three years ago...
Granny Chiyo...
That jutsu will...!
This is what Granny Chiyo
was talking about...
Is that...?
Yeah...
Hey, what are you doing?!
She's going to bring
Gaara back to life!
Bring him back to life...
Is such a thing...
really possible?
This jutsu...
is a special jutsu that
only Grandma Chiyo can perform...
Really?!
There's no way that such
an extraordinary jutsu could exist...
That chakra flow...
No doubt...
It is accompanied by
a considerable risk...
Damn...!
I don't have enough chakra...
You can use my chakra!
Would that be possible?
Granny...
Place your hand on top of mine.
Naruto...
Naruto has a mysterious power...
However small the words he exchanges,
he makes friends immediately...
with everyone he meets...
Amidst this shinobi world created
by us foolish old people...
I am glad that a person
like you showed up...
The things I did in the past
were nothing but mistakes...
But now, at the very end,
it seems I can finally do something right.
The Sand... and the Leaf.
The future that's coming will surely
be different from the one in our time...
Your mysterious power
that Kakashi spoke of...
That power will surely
alter the future greatly...
when you become a Hokage
like none before...
And you, Sakura...!
Yes...
Next time, help the person
you cherish most...
not an old hag with
one foot in the grave...
You are very much like me...
There aren't many women
with your kind of spirit...
You will surely become
a Kunoichi who surpasses her master...
Naruto, this old lady has
a favor to ask you...
You're the only one in this world
who truly understands Gaara's pain...
And Gaara...
He understands your pain, too...
Please... help Gaara...
Gaara!
Gaara...!
Who are you... calling...?
Whose is it...? This hand...
Oh... It's just my hand again...
My hand...
Me...?
Who am I...?
I...
I am...
Gaara...
Naruto...
This is...
Everyone came running to help you.
Lord Gaara!
Are you all right?!
- Yes!
- Hurrah!
Thank heavens...
That's great!
Putting us to all this trouble!
Good grief.
You're such a pain, little brother,
making us worry.
What's with you guys...
acting arrogant like that?!
Gaara is the Kazekage, you know.
Don't be so disrespectful!
You're nothing but subordinates!
Gaara... How do you feel?
You shouldn't try to
get up so quickly.
Your body hasn't completely healed.
Thank heavens...!
I thought Lord Kazekage...
might really die...
There's no way that Lord Gaara
would die that easily!
Lord Gaara is reserved, cool,
strong, handsome, an elite, and...
Yes, yes, but he's still kind
of cute somehow...
And yet, he is the Kazekage...
This time, I'll show them for sure...
that I can protect Lord Gaara in a crisis!
No, I will!
I will!
Lord Gaara!
Out of the way, underling!
Come to think of it,
I am still a Genin.
Don't feel so depressed.
It's a well known fact that women
have a weakness for the cool, elite type.
I think Shikamaru was saying
something like that too...
Thank you... Naruto!
If you're going to say that,
you should be thanking
the old lady, not me...
She saved Gaara with
an incredible medical ninjutsu...
She got tired out,
so she's sleeping now, but...
When the old lady gets back
to the village, she'll get well again...
No, you're wrong...
Granny Chiyo used that jutsu...
What do you mean I'm wrong?
I...
She wasn't just using medical ninjutsu...
She used a Reincarnation Jutsu.
Granny Chiyo is dead.
Reincarnation Jutsu?
Wh-What do you mean by that?
It's a ninjutsu that allows you
to bring a dead person back to life
in exchange for your own...
It can't be...!
As I thought...
Guy-sensei...
At one time, in the Sand Puppet Unit,
they were doing research to develop
a jutsu that could bring puppets to life.
Granny Chiyo headed up
the project...
They succeeded in developing
the jutsu in theory,
but midway, they decided
that the risks were too great.
Before it reached the stage
of human experiments,
it was designated a Forbidden Jutsu
and was sealed away.
Your mysterious power
that Kakashi spoke of...
That power will surely
alter the future greatly...
when you become a Hokage
like none before...
She looks as if she could start
laughing at any minute.
Her face looks so... peaceful...
Yes...
Naruto, you are a mysterious one,
after all.
You have the power to change people.
Granny Chiyo always used to say she
didn't care about the village's future...
She was not the kind of person
to do such a thing for Gaara.
Granny Chiyo entrusted the future
to Gaara and you...
Hers was a magnificent end,
befitting of a shinobi.
Yeah... just like Gramps, the Third.
You're right...
Yeah.
Now, I clearly understand
the old woman's wish.
Lord Gaara...!
It's okay...
Everyone, let us pray
for Granny Chiyo...
Granny Chiyo...
That's...
Heh... what a lavish welcome.
Awesome...!
There are so many people...!
Just as would be expected
for the Kazekage...
Yeah...
I'm so glad you're safe...
It's thanks to everyone...
Naruto Uzumaki, I am truly grateful!
No, I...
I really wasn't able to do anything.
Lord Kazekage,
the villagers are waiting for you.
Right this way...
She said she didn't want
a grave.
But I thought it would
be better to have one.
I felt that everyone needed
a place to gather...
Everybody, say your farewells...
Okay.
Let's go.
Okay...
Sakura, Naruto... we should be going now.
Okay!
Let's go, Sakura.
Granny Chiyo, thank you...
See you...
Uh... yeah...
Normally, at time like this,
people shake hands and say goodbye...
but I'm not really good at that sort
of thing, so this will have to do...
Sensei! You guys are too slow!
Uh... I'm sorry, Guy.
When I use that new Sharingan,
it takes a toll on my body
for quite a while...
Hurry!
H-Hey...!
Huh?
What is it?
That's... kinda disgusting...
Old men giving each other
a piggyback...
That's more sickening than I imagined.
Good grief... That's annoying...
I see! It's training, isn't it!
Now this way, it'll be faster!
Move, move, move!
You guys...
You think you can keep up with me?!
And adding movement to it
just makes it even more disgusting.
- Neji...
- I refuse!
I've already pulled
some strings behind the scenes...
So that you'll be posted with
Kakashi's squad.
Not only are you close in age
with Naruto Uzumaki,
but you are also stronger than anyone
in the village of the same generation...
And above all else, I admire
your superb talent for painting...
From today until the completion
of this mission...
Your name is... Sai.
Sai. Right...
Don't put on a fake smile
like that in front of me.
I'm sorry...
It said in a book that
to get along with people,
you first have to be able to smile.
I've been practicing, but...
I still have difficulty in creating
facial expressions.
Gimme a break...
I wouldn't have thought that
my Self-Destructing Clone
would be warped away too...
What I lost was...
only up to about my elbow.
I must search for my right arm and ring...
So this is Sasori's true form, huh...
Here it is!
Zetsu, here it is!
I wonder if I can now become
a member of the Akatsuki...
One slot has opened up after all...
You idiot... It's not that easy...
Oh come on,
why don't you just let him join...
Tobi's a good boy...
Let's go.
Give me a second, Zetsu!
I'm sure...
It's around here somewhere.
Uh, hey, Zetsu!
Wait, please! Zetsu...