There's a paper bomb left here, too!
It's a type that explodes
the instant it's peeled off...
We'll just have to detonate it.
I see.
We're detonating a paper bomb!
Stop working and take cover!
This is no time to be discussing
candidates for a new Kazekage!
But if you think about
the worst-case scenario,
isn't it important to seize
the initiative?
More importantly, rescuing Lord Kazekage
should be our priority!
Securing village safety
is what's important!
We must not break up
our limited forces in conditions like this.
What did you say?!
Reporting!
The bodies of the sky watch
have all been identified.
There's little doubt the enemy infiltrated
the center of the village from the sky...
Excuse me!
What?!
We have been contacted
by the tracking unit.
Kankuro was discovered about half
a day's travel from the village.
He is unconscious and
in serious condition.
Kankuro...
Some members of the tracking unit
have recovered Kankuro and his puppets.
They are on their way
back to the village.
What about the location
of Lord Kazekage?
The remaining members of
the tracking unit are in pursuit.
There should be a report soon...
Master Sasori, you're late.
I thought you didn't like to
keep people waiting.
But... I had enough fun
to make up for that.
What's up with that?
Don't get so touchy.
You did capture your target,
the One-Tail, after all.
My mission is next...
once I've taken care of this guy.
But the one you're after...
Yeah, I still don't know where he is...
It'd be easier if
he'd just come to me...
Yeah... That's right...
What kind of Jinchuriki
was he again?
Well, worst case scenario,
even if I can't find him...
nobody can complain
since we caught one of the Jinchuriki.
Temari!
Hurry up and get him
to the operating room!
Is this... poison?!
Prepare an antidote!
Gaara...
What?! Gaara was...?!
It'll take about two and a half days
to reach the Sand from here...
Let's hurry.
Right.
The wounds weren't that serious...
The problem is...
The poison, huh...?
Yes, it's a completely new poison.
We have absolutely no idea
how to neutralize it.
Gaara... and now Kankuro, too...
Naruto! I told you not to break formation.
I don't like it!
Even I know why they're after
people like Gaara and me...
You know it already,
don't you, Sakura...?
That I've got...
... the Nine-Tailed Fox
sealed inside me...
Gaara and I both...
have monsters inside us...
That's what they're after!
That's what I don't like!
They only see us as monsters!
I don't like their selfish way
of viewing us!
Everything about us...
was the same...
And he... fought all by himself
a lot more than me...
The Akatsuki was after him!
It's just like me this time, too...
And yet,
why does he always get
the short end of the stick?
It's always him!
That's why I can't be wasting
any time getting to him!
Naruto...
Thank you...
You say Kankuro's regained
consciousness?
He has, but he's just barely
able to respond to us...
His condition has worsened
since yesterday.
Baki... Is that you...?
Kankuro!
It's... it's him...
Don't raise your voice!
It's not good for you
in your condition!
Th-the Red Sand...
I see... So that explains it...
Lord Baki...?
Oh, Lord Baki.
Contact the tracking unit!
Tell them to turn back immediately!
Actually, we haven't heard
anything from them
since recovering Kankuro yesterday...
We were too late...
Huh? What is it?
Nothing...
I'm... going out for a bit.
Oh, but...!
I have no choice but to consult
with the Elder Siblings...
But I wonder...
will they come to our aid willingly?
Naruto.
You've met him before, haven't you?
Itachi Uchiha...
And he's after you.
I didn't just train over these past
two and a half years.
I got into Master Tsunade's library
and did outside investigations
the best I could.
And now... what was bothering me
finally makes sense!
The person Sasuke wants to kill...
is his own older brother
Itachi Uchiha, right...?
A member of the Akatsuki!
That's why Sasuke is with Orochimaru
in an attempt to obtain power...
But Orochimaru is
after Sasuke's body, right?
And we only have six months left!
Sakura knows about that too...
And Orochimaru used to be
a member of the Akatsuki.
Basically, what I'm trying to say is...
The closer we get to the Akatsuki,
the closer we get to information
about Orochimaru...
If that happens...
we'll eventually get closer to Sasuke!
And after that, Itachi Uchiha...
Our worst enemy who
plagued Sasuke for so long...
and the one who's after Naruto...
It appears someone's come...
Say, Big Sister...
Are you dead?
Gotcha! I was playing dead.
Cut it out. That senility act's
a little too real, Sis.
Honorable Elders...
I have come to request
your assistance.
Old books are supposed
to be tied in a bundle
and left up on a high shelf...
What can we possibly do now...?
An organization called the Akatsuki
has taken the Shukaku.
If we leave things as they stand now,
there will be great trouble.
It's your generation's problem now.
You deal with it yourselves.
You two have powerful connections
with each land,
including villages in lands
we are not allied with...
There's only so much information
we can gather on our own...
We've long since been retired.
We no longer have
any attachments to the world.
Although I guess it'd be nice to see
my grandchild's face one more time...
That's very convenient.
Your grandson is a member
of the Akatsuki.
Granny Chiyo...
Who are they?
Oh, that's...
Granny Chiyo... and Ebizo.
No way. I thought they were supposed
to have long since been retired.
Hm? If I'm not mistaken, this is...
It's Kankuro.
The current Kazekage's older brother.
Oh, that's right.
I've never seen...
a composition like this before.
Ordinarily, he would just finish them off...
It appears he's very confident
about his poison.
Leaving his prey as is
on purpose is just like Sasori.
This is not good.
Poisons are my specialty,
but even I can't analyze this.
Even you, Lady Chiyo...?
At best, he has one day...
He may not even make it
to dawn tomorrow, I'd say.
That Sasori has sure grown considerably.
What in the world should we do?
Well, the only one who might
know more about antidotes than me
would be the Leaf's Slug Princess, Tsunade.
I had a lot of trouble with her
during the Great War.
She would decipher all the poisons
I created and concoct antidotes.
And now we're allies with the Leaf.
All we can do is send for her and
have her look at Kankuro.
But she is now the Hokage
and would not be able to
leave her village so easily.
And even if she were to come,
it takes three days to get here
from the Leaf.
I know. Nobody's seriously thinking
of summoning her.
I don't like that slug girl, anyway.
Did you call me, Lady Tsunade?
Yes...
I want to send reinforcements to
the Village Hidden in the Sand.
Reinforcements?
They should be about done
with their previous mission
and on their way back by now.
Them?
Oh. Yes, ma'am. I'll make
the preparations immediately.
Should we consider the worst-case scenario?
You're late. Prepare immediately.
The Jinchuriki was unexpectedly strong.
All right, gather.
Now, let us begin.
From now, it will take three days
and three nights.
Keep an eye on your real bodies as well.
And Zetsu, use your real body
to keep watch outside for now.
Use the longest range.
I know.
Three days?
Shouldn't we consider that it might
take a bit longer
since we don't have Orochimaru?
If that's what you think,
then get right to it.
Sealing Jutsu: Nine Phantom Dragons
I'm giving you guys the same mission
as Team Kakashi.
Head for the Sand and
complete the mission
by providing backup for Kakashi
and the others.
Got it?!
Yes, ma'am!
Please leave it to us.
Roger.
Understood.
All right!
Team Guy heading into action.
You catch a cold?
No, my hay fever started
acting up before...
All right, we'll make it to
the Sand in one day.
Sensei, let's make it in half a day.
It'll take three days, no matter
how you consider it.
Sorry to interrupt your excitement,
but we should head out now!
All right, we're leaving!
Let's go, everyone! A youthful dash!
Yes, Guy-sensei!
How embarrassing.
Give it up, Tenten.
They're as energetic as ever.
It's been awhile
since we've seen Naruto.
I'm looking forward to seeing
how much he's grown.
Yeah.
Oh!
We've been expecting you.
So you were with them, Temari?
Please, come this way.
What?! They got Kankuro, too?
Yes, Lord Kazekage was taken and
Kankuro followed in pursuit.
Kankuro was poisoned by the enemy
and we don't know how to neutralize it.
At this rate... he won't...
Damn it!
Let's hurry, Temari.
I'll take a look at him.
Kankuro!
He's... the White Fang of the Leaf!
You jerk!
Huh?
Prepare yourself!
Why you--!
What's the big idea, pouncing on
Kakashi-sensei like that?!
You wrinkly old hag!
This old hag... is good...
I'll never forget what
you did back then!
White Fang of the Leaf,
I shall avenge my son's death
by defeating you today!
Er... no, you see... I'm...
No questions or answers!
Sister... Take a good look at him!
He resembles him closely,
but this one is not the White Fang!
Huh?
Uh... hello...
Moreover, the White Fang
of the Leaf died long ago.
Remember?
When you got word of it,
you cried tears of regret,
since you could not avenge
your son.
Gotcha, I was only pretending
to have gone senile.
Kankuro!
Let me take a look.
Please do.
Kakashi-sensei and the rest of you,
please stand back a bit.
Got it.
They seem to have used
a heavy metal-based toxin.
It's the type that acts upon
the muscles to destroy the cells.
Just from that brief examination...
You could tell that much...
His medical record please.
Ah, here it is.
This is the list
of toxic ingredients.
There are blank spaces here
and there, but...
I can predict the general outcome.
The cardiac muscle
will be destroyed,
and the heart could stop beating
at any time, so...
It's difficult to say whether
we can concoct an antidote in time...
You don't mean that!
Isn't there anything we can do?
Please assemble the items
I request immediately.
Roger!
It's quite a crude treatment, but
it's the only option we have left.
Hold him down firmly,
as this will be
a very delicate operation.
- Right.
- Understood.
Here... goes...
Hold him down firmly!
- Yes!
I'll cause the chakra
to flow into his body...
It will cause the toxin to
surface from the cells.
It will then be absorbed
by this liquid...
and extracted!
So that's the toxin...
Yes!
Next!
- Yes!
Say... Kakashi-sensei...
Huh?
What sort of person was
that White Fang of the Leaf
that this old lady here
was talking about?
Well, that's hard to say...
Hmm, let's see...
Well, in a word...
He was my father.
Hey, you there...
Are you the son
of the White Fang?
Yes...
But of course...
So that's why you look
so much like him...
I directly extracted the toxin.
With this, his life should
no longer be in danger.
But we still can't rest easy.
I will now concoct an antidote
for the traces of toxin
that remain in his body.
Got it.
If you need anything,
don't hesitate to ask.
Well then, first, I need a list
of the medicinal herbs
that can be found in this village,
or something like that...
I'll bring it.
Please replace all of
his bandages.
Yes.
And then prepare an IV drip.
Also, please set aside a small amount
of the extracted toxin.
I will need it later.
Sakura... You're so cool.
You're just like the Slug Princess.
To think that a girl just
like you would come here...
Yes, Lady Tsunade is my master.
And besides, I was told by
my master to come here.
Here is the list of medicinal herbs.
Thank you.
I say, Sister... Time moves slowly,
but it does move on.
I never imagined I'd find
this assortment
of medicinal herbs here
in the Hidden Sand.
Still, the soil is not well suited
to growing medicinal herbs...
In particular, we only have
a small amount of "Scurvy Grass."
No, this much is plenty.
I can make at least three antidotes.
Kankuro, are you all right?!
What, you're back already, Temari...?
I heard the village was in crisis.
Sorry... for making you worry.
You fool, don't talk
such nonsense!
Please lead me to the place
where Kankuro did battle.
I may not look it,
but I'm a tracking expert...
If just the slightest trace
of their scent remains...
There's no need of that.
My puppets... have all been recovered,
haven't they?
The enemy force was two.
One of them led Gaara away...
All you have to do it follow
Gaara's scent.
Even if they split up into two,
one of them...
That one has his scent on it...
In Crow's hand...
I left him holding a scrap
of his clothes...
Even in defeat, you don't go down
without a fight.
Just what I'd expect from
a Sand ninja.
Kankuro! Are you all right?
Y-Yeah...
Naruto... Uzumaki... is it?
Hey...
I see...
Summoning Jutsu!
Pakkun!
Hey! Is that you, Naruto?!
Long time no see.
I need you to get to work
right away!
I want you to determine
which way he headed.
Now, go!
We'll contact you right away
when we find something.
We're counting on you.
Kankuro...!
Granny Chiyo?
Grandpa Ebizo, too?!
I want to hear it one more time,
directly from your mouth...
There's no doubt that one of the two enemies
was Sasori.
Is that right?
What about it, Kankuro?
Yeah... It was Sasori
of the Red Sand.
He said so himself.
Sasori of the Red Sand, you say?
We might be able to find out more
about Akatsuki.
Please...
Be sure to drink it all down...
You should be all right now, I think.
Just lie there and rest for
a while without moving
until the numbness goes away.
You should all get
a good night's rest as well.
I've prepared a room for you to use.
But we've got to find Gaara quickly...
I'll take advantage of
your kindness, if I may.
We're going on
a harsh march from tomorrow.
I understand...
I just have to work hard and
carve out a future for myself.
And I must not run away
from my path of solitude.
If I do that, someday...
Someday... I can be like him...
Naruto Uzumaki...
Mm?
Take care of my little brother...
Heh, you can leave it to me.
After all, I'm going to be Hokage someday!
So I'll get on the Kazekage's good side early!
Sister...
Are you taking those with you?
Fate must have meant for this to happen...
Nothing will serve me better than
these if I'm going to fight against him...
I've lived too long a life...
Over there, huh...
Any closer and I'll be noticed...
So... that's where his hideout is.
Most likely.
Gaara's scent was also coming
from that same place.
I see.
I have one more favor to ask you.
Huh?
Hey, are you awake, Naruto?
Huh? Pakkun...
Okay, Pakkun, I'm counting on you.
See you around then, Naruto!
Kakashi-sensei!
Could it be that you've found
the Akatsuki's hideout?
Yeah... We're heading out immediately.
All right, as soon
as the Sand is ready,
we'll join them for Gaara's rescue.
Got it?
Sorry to have kept you waiting!
Temari!
Everyone's here...
All right! Then let's head out!
Wait!
Temari... You and the others stay here
in the village and patrol the border.
What do you mean by that?!
That's an order from... above.
Huh...?
Their reasoning is...
if it becomes widely known that
the Kazekage is absent,
there's no telling when other villages
will attack our village...
I can't believe this...
That's all the more reason that
we have to get Gaara back
as soon as possible!
These Leaf people came
all this way
for the very purpose of
going to Gaara's aid!
Gaara is our Kazekage, right?!
What's the point if we, his own villagers,
don't go to save him?!
But...
I'm going.
The only Sand shinobi
you need is me!
Granny Chiyo!
But that's...
I am already retired, you know...
I can do whatever I like.
You really shouldn't overdo it...!
Don't you dare treat me
like an old woman!
She jumped!
Wha--?!
I haven't had a chance to dote on my dear
grandson in a while, after all.
All right, we'll head out.
I'm sorry. I'll try to convince the council...
We'll follow behind later, no matter what!
Gaara will be long rescued by that time!
See you later!
Hey, we're going a little too fast!
We haven't stopped running
since we left!
Let's take a little break!
Tenten, you need more training!
Lee! In front of you!
Wait, Guy!
Pakkun!
Kakashi directed us,
the Eight Ninja Hounds,
to fan out in every direction
to follow the Akatsuki's scent.
While we were doing that,
we realized that
those guys were headed towards
the Land of Rivers
which is situated between
the Leaf and Sand.
The Land of Rivers...?
That's right.
In other words,
you guys are closest to the Akatsuki
at this point in time.
You, who were heading from
the Leaf to the Sand Village.
I see...
Follow me...
I'll explain the details as we run.
All right! Let's go, everybody!
Huh? Already?
An enemy is nearing
this hideout.
An enemy, you said?
And a highly skilled one at that.
His name is... Might Guy.
Who's that?
A Leaf Jonin ninja who
uses taijutsu.
He's one clever operator.
Don't underestimate him.
Ah! That strange beast...
We will use that jutsu...
In that case, I'll go...
I was getting irritated for not
having any luck finding a Jinchuriki.
No, I'll go...
I have something of a personal quarrel
with him, you see...
You're right. That jutsu is more suited
to someone like you.
Among the Akatsuki,
you have the most chakra, Kisame.
Yes...
Even so, I'll take 30%
of your chakra.
Well, well, well...
It looks like I'll finally be
able to get pay back
for that kick he gave me...
Naruto!
Can I ask you something?
Since when have you been
targeted by the Akatsuki?
I don't know...
There was that one time when
two people from the Akatsuki
came to the Leaf Village in order to
make contact with Naruto.
But that was three years ago...
and they've just started
making a move now.
I don't know why.
Why did they wait three years?
It could be that it's not because
they didn't want to,
but because they couldn't.
Because Lord Jiraiya was always
hanging close to Naruto...
No...
There's quite a bit of preparation involved
to draw out a Tailed Beast that's sealed
within someone.
They encountered difficulties with that.
What's this "Tailed Beast"
that you were talking about?
What?!
You're Tsunade's disciple
and you don't even know that?!
The Leaf Village had
the Nine-Tailed Fox...
The Nine-Tailed Fox is treated as
top secret amongst the Leaf Village...
Well, that's not surprising, I guess...
A Tailed Beast refers to
Beast Spirits with tails.
Long, long ago,
the Sand had the One-Tail.
That's the Shukaku sealed
within Gaara.
One-Tail?
Do you mean that there are
other beasts
besides the Nine-Tailed Fox?
That's right...
There are a total of nine
tailed beasts in this world...
Tailed beasts have
special characteristics.
Each of them have
a different number of tails.
The One-Tail has one tail.
The Two-Tails has two.
And up to the Nine-Tails
as the name suggests,
each name represents
the number of tails the beast has.
The Tailed Beasts have
immense chakra
and in the world of ninja,
they were used for military purposes
by Hidden Villages around the world.
They competed to get their hands on them.
But no one could control a power
that surpassed human understanding.
I don't know why the Akatsuki is after it,
but that power is too dangerous...
But in this new peaceful age,
the Tailed Beasts apparently...
still exist, having scattered
all around the world...
What's up?!
Someone's coming!
Byakugan!
Behind us!
You...
Do you know him, Guy-sensei?!
Don't tell me you're...
It appears that you've remembered...
Have we met before...?
It seems the strange beast has
the intelligence of a beast as well.
Well... I'll make you remember soon...
So this is the Akatsuki!
Water Style:
Exploding Water Shock Wave!
Here I go!
Leaf Rising Wind!
8 Trigrams: Air Palm!
It's programmed!
Damn! I let him get away!
Where did he go?
In front! He's coming up.
Seriously... what a bunch of annoying brats.
It's so bothersome.
The Water Style ninjutsu
and that big sword...
You are...!
It seems like you have
finally remembered.
I do feel like we have met somewhere.
You still can't remember, huh...
You really are good
at hurting people's feelings.
Until you recall...
I will take my time putting you
through pain.
Another guest...
It's a little noisy this time,
isn't it, Deidara!
Well, the Jinchuriki was
stronger than the other two...
I told you at the start, didn't I?
Your jutsu wasn't suited
for covert operations.
I'd say your traps were
pretty loud too, weren't they?
What!
Stop fighting amongst yourselves!
Concentrate on the jutsu!
Now then...
who should I send this time...
This time it's my turn,
without any doubt.
Another Leaf shinobi...
Damn!
In that case, it's decided...
Everybody, halt!
Who is that?
Out of the blue, huh...
That guy... those eyes...
Itachi... Uchiha!
Th-That guy is...
Ah, so he is that brat...
who killed his entire clan.
It's been a while, Kakashi... Naruto.
You bastard...
First me, and now you've taken Gaara too!
I'm going to destroy you!
Everyone! Don't look directly
at his eyes! It's dangerous!
But then...
How should we fight him?
Well...
Guy, how did you fight with Itachi?
Huh?
Well...
You predict his moves by focusing
on his body and footwork alone.
That seems pretty hard.
The Uchiha clan, eh?
It's been a while since
I went up against a Sharingan.
You don't have to be that surprised.
There are a few fighting techniques
to counter this dojutsu.
What should we do?
"If it's one against one,
then you must flee."
"If it's two against one,
then take the back."
I see.
Amazing! Guess that's the wisdom of old age!
Then I'll take his back--
Wait!
Are you saying my strategy against
the Sharingan is wrong?
That would work if it's an ordinary genjutsu,
but it's a bit more complicated
in his case.
What?
He uses Mangekyo Sharingan
which is a much stronger dojutsu
than an ordinary Sharingan.
It's not a matter of ending
or not ending the genjutsu.
He's a handful... Just who is this guy?
Impressive Kakashi.
It seems suffering my Tsukiyomi
wasn't a total waste for you.
That is not all that I know...
After you used the visual jutsu,
you were quite exhausted
and you ended the battle immediately
and tried to leave.
But Itachi...
Even for you, it is dangerous
to use that "eye" too much...
You've analyzed me quite well
from just one encounter.
Hey Itachi.
Your eyesight... How much has it weakened?
Kakashi... Could it be that you...?
I underestimated you back then.
But I'm not that pathetic.
It's not going to work
the way it did before, you see.
It's a huge mistake if you think
I'm the same as before!
Naruto, I'll deal with him.
Y-You mean more of that non-combat teamwork?
No. This time, cover me.
To be honest, I want to be cool
and say, "Go on ahead," but...
Against him, even I can't hold him off alone.
Now!
Water Clone Jutsu!
Water Prison Jutsu!
Damn it!
These kids are better
than I thought...
I'm surprised.
Now we can fight without
any interference.
This blade, Samehada, only allows me
to wield it.
I see...
Then I'll use mine, too...
This is going to be interesting.
Now, shall we begin?!
Guy-sensei...!
I'm running out of breath...
Tenten's reached her limit, huh...?
What incredible power...
Don't think I'm done settling
the score just yet.
That guy...
I know I've met him somewhere...
Water Style:
Five Hungry Sharks!
No effect, huh...?
Tenten!
This is not good...
She's reached her limit...
I can't be slowed down any further...
I have no choice...
What's he planning?
The Eight Inner Gates: Sixth Gate
of Joy... Open!
What's this?!
That stance is...!
He's fast...!
Is that...?
Yeah...
Game over!
Asakujaku!
Looks like it's over...
It's about time for you to come with me...
Naruto.
I'll go first!
Shadow Clone?!
Rasengan!
This is also a Shadow Clone!
Sakura! Granny!
Sakura...?
Kakashi-sensei!
What's going on?!
Are they Shadow Clones?
And I didn't even look
at his eyes...!
Damn it... How did I get caught
in his genjutsu?
These eyes aren't the only way
I can activate a genjutsu.
I can cast it with a single finger.
It's about time for you to
come with me...
Naruto.
It must've been back then...
Rest easy.
I won't use the Mangekyo Sharingan.
Or rather, I can't use it right now.
More importantly, it's about time
you went to sleep.
Damn it...
And I was so careful...
I can't believe I got caught
in a genjutsu...!
He has grown.
But... he's still not strong enough.
Damn it! This hurts.
But this is... a genjutsu...
I've got to overpower it!
Naruto...
I failed to kill you back then,
you see...
Why... didn't you stop Sasuke?
I believed in you...
You couldn't protect your friends...
I was counting on you...
I'm so disappointed.
You always...
You always come out ahead...
You always... achieve happiness...
Someone... give me some chakra!
K-Kakashi-sensei... Sakura...
Please... give me chakra!
You okay, Naruto?!
You were caught in a genjutsu!
But you're okay now!
We poured our chakra in you
and broke the genjutsu!
Now, it's about time for the main event.
Get it together, Naruto!
Hey! Get a grip!
Naruto, I'll show you how it's done.
Fire Style:
Phoenix Flower Jutsu!
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
Lightning Blade!
Rasengan!
I see... He sure has learned
an interesting jutsu.
However...
Damn it! I guess
it won't be that easy.
This isn't going to work without
a combination attack with Kakashi-sensei.
On top of that, I'll need a powerful jutsu
that can beat him in one shot...
I'll have to try out that jutsu...
The Hidden Mist Jutsu...
It's indeed an effective jutsu
for making it difficult
to cast a genjutsu...
But it's meaningless against me,
who possesses the Sharingan...
Shall we stop this childish game
of hide-and-seek, Kakashi?
I suppose we could...
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
The Fireball Jutsu...
But I noticed earlier,
something's off...
No wonder... my genjutsu had no effect.
This is a Shadow Clone.
Naruto!
- I know!
- Giant Rasengan!
A-Amazing...!
Ooh... He's...!
What... was up with that smile?
H-He's...
Wh-What's this...?
While we were fighting,
I felt like something wasn't right...
What do you mean?!
It's one of... their jutsu or something...
He's...
What is this?
What in the world does this mean?
I don't know...
But... there's one thing I can say...
I don't know this man, after all!
Do you know him...?
Yes...
That's Yura... a Jonin from our village.
A Sand...
What does this mean?
I don't know either...
But... he went missing right around
the time Gaara was taken.
Could it be that...
he was a spy for the Akatsuki?
I don't believe it.
He served on the council
for four years...
Was he disguised with
the Transformation Jutsu?
No.
This is a jutsu of
a much greater level...
The Fireball Jutsu was created
by the Uchiha Clan
and it's one of their signature jutsu.
And that jutsu was the real thing.
It looks like you're done as well.
Yes... I'm out of chakra.
Well, the chakra we sacrificed was only
about thirty percent of our own.
Although it's a jutsu handy
for creating exact duplicates of us,
the amount of chakra we gave them
wasn't that large.
And the jutsu they can use
are proportionate to that quantity.
But it was more than enough
to buy us time.
The jutsu wore off, huh...?
However, we were able
to buy quite a bit of time...
This should be enough...
Well done, Itachi, Kisame.
That's easy to say.
The two who became sacrifices
and gave up their bodies
for your jutsu...
were both my subordinates.
You should be
the one thanking me...
With my Impersonation Jutsu,
they were both able to become
members of the Akatsuki,
although only for a short time.
It's almost time...
Damn it! This means the real one
is in the hideout, huh...?
I suppose their goal was to stall us
and gather information.
Now that we know that,
there's no point in hanging around here.
All right! Let's hurry!
This way!
Just as I thought...
They were clearly stalling for time...
They certainly have a formidable jutsu.
Using a jutsu like this
to stall us means...
they're undoubtedly already
extracting the Tailed Beast!
We don't have time.
We must save Gaara right away.
- E-Excuse me...
- Hm?
What do you mean...
extract the Tailed Beast...?
It's likely that they're trying to create
a new Jinchuriki using the One-Tail.
Jinchuriki...?
I explained before
how the Tailed Beasts possess
a power beyond
human comprehension, didn't I?
And how each land attempted
to use them as military weapons.
The Jinchuriki...
is what you might call...
the one who controls that power.
But earlier you said...
The Tailed Beasts have
immense chakra,
and in the world of ninja were
used for military purposes
by Hidden Villages around the world.
They competed to
get their hands on them.
But none was able to control that power
which had surpassed human intelligence.
In the end, that is...
But in the past, there were those
who attempted to control that power.
They attempted to control
the Tailed Beasts...
by sealing them inside people.
By doing so,
they tried to suppress
the extreme power of the Tailed Beast
and then control that power.
And the ones with the Tailed Beast
sealed within them...
in other words, people like Gaara
were called the Jinchuriki.
The striking feature of the Jinchuriki is
how they utilize unbelievable power by
resonating with the Tailed Beast.
Including Gaara, there have been three
Jinchuriki in the history of the Sand.
I'm counting on you.
How can a Tailed Beast be extracted?
What's required is
a Sealing Jutsu with the ability...
to instantaneously balance
the power of the Tailed Beast,
in addition to plenty of time.
But if that's done, the Jinchuriki...
Don't tell me...
That's right...
A Jinchuriki that has
his Tailed Beast extracted...
dies.
The two people I mentioned earlier...
The Sand Jinchuriki other than Gaara
both had the Shukaku
within them extracted...
and died as a result.
You're sentimental as always, huh?
Sakura...
Don't worry.
I'll be saving Gaara!
I-I was worried... about you!
Let's hurry.
Naruto...
Zetsu.
Dispose of the two we used for
the Impersonation Jutsu.
Understood.
Itachi, tell me about the enemy's
number and their features.
They're a four-man squad with
Kakashi Hatake, Sakura Haruno,
and the Nine-Tails Jinchuriki
Naruto Uzumaki from the Leaf,
and Chiyo, the Sand's advisor.
Did he say Chiyo...?
It's from my sister...?
You shouldn't be moving yet.
It's not good for you in
your condition.
I'm okay.
I can at least walk...
More importantly, it seems we've
been contacted by Granny Chiyo.
I can't just lie around!
I see... So you've heard, huh?
As it happens, we've learned
something terrible from her message.
Yura was a spy?!
I can't believe it...
A man who served on the council
for four years wouldn't...
But... now it makes sense.
How the enemy broke through
the village defenses that easily.
And I'm sure nobody imagined
a man in charge of security
would be an enemy spy.
Here I thought we had thoroughly
checked everyone out
when Gaara became the Kazekage!
The person in question might've
just been controlled by some kind of jutsu.
More importantly,
it doesn't say anything about
the most crucial thing!
When's the Kazekage coming back?!
Having the Kazekage of one
of the Five Great Shinobi Lands
being kidnapped by rogue ninja sets a
terrible precedent for the other nations!
And it seems one of them
is Sasori of the Red Sand!
It'll be a tremendous disgrace
if this gets out to the other lands!
If it becomes known that
the Kazekage is missing,
who knows when
the neighboring lands will intervene.
Our most pressing need is
to immediately elect a new Kazekage...
and make an effort
to stabilize the village.
Gaara could still very well come back!
Well, the fact is...
it might just be better for the village
if he doesn't come back.
What are you implying?
Gaara is an unstable monster
with the One-Tail inside him.
We thought he would be easier
to control if we made him the Kazekage...
But in the end, there's no telling
when he might go out of control.
There's no mistaking he's trouble.
Gaara originally resonated with
the One-Tail, Shukaku.
But he's an unstable experiment
we can hardly call complete...
He's a failed creation who was even
ordered to be assassinated
by his own father, the Fourth Kazekage.
Right now, some of the younger people
just blindly admire him.
But the fact is most of the people
in this village are just scared of him...
and have no expectations of him!
Say that one more time!
I don't care if you are on the council.
I won't allow it!
Stop, Kankuro!
You're before the statues
of the Kazekage!
This is a holy place!
Kankuro, your anger is understandable.
But there's an element of truth
to what he says.
But the fact is...
this isn't an issue of whether
or not Gaara should be trusted.
Something like this happened
before a long time ago...
The Third Kazekage was kidnapped.
There were all kinds of conjecture
regarding the whereabouts
of the Third Kazekage,
war broke out and the lands
were in chaos...
If only we had focused our attention
on securing the village,
rather than eagerly searching
for the Third Kazekage,
that wouldn't have happened.
Then why didn't you do that...?
The Third Kazekage was
an exceptionally powerful Kazekage
in our history.
And most importantly,
a body was never found.
No one thought someone as powerful as
he could have been killed that easily.
Something like that must
never happen again!
That's why... we must consider
the best interests of the village!
I know... But...
But...
Gaara's...
my little brother.
So this is Kisame's, huh...?
He looks to be worth disposing of...
Then let's get to it.
Right...
Sasori...
Now then...
That should be enough rest...
Break time is over.
We should get going.
Wake up, you two.
We're leaving.
O-Okay.
A little longer...
Let me sleep a little longer.
You're going to save Gaara, aren't you?
Of course, I am!
We'll now be entering
the final stage.
Each team will be deployed
as I just announced.
The absence of Lord Kazekage
is a highly classified matter!
However, operate under the assumption that
the information has already been leaked.
It's conceivable that the nearby lands
will take advantage of this confusion
and execute an attack.
Don't think of this as
just an ordinary border patrol.
The teams that are ready
will depart at once.
What's the matter, Matsuri?
Is this really okay?
Is what okay?
Lord Gaara has been kidnapped.
And yet, here we are guarding
a border
for an enemy who may or may not come
instead of trying to save him.
It's an order from our superiors.
We can only obey.
No way!
Lord Gaara is the Hidden Sand's...
our Kazekage!
I know that!
Gaara's my little brother, you know!
I'm sorry...
This way.
Right!
Naruto, wait up!
Honestly...
Why's that kid trying so hard to
save Gaara who's from a different village?
And what in the world is he?
He's also a Jinchuriki.
He has the Nine-Tails sealed within him.
Indeed, Naruto probably doesn't have
much attachment to the Hidden Sand itself.
But Gaara is a Jinchuriki, just like him.
More than anyone in the Hidden Sand,
Naruto knows how Gaara feels.
After all, the Jinchuriki has been
treated the same way in every village.
That's exactly why he feels
like he has to save Gaara.
It doesn't make any difference to him
if he's from the Leaf or the Sand.
For Naruto, Gaara is a friend
who knows the same pain as he does.
I've seen many things.
And in my own way, I've learned
the nature of things in this world.
Learning that the alliance with
other lands were for show only...
I chose to create a power that could
protect the Hidden Sand.
I'm the one who used the jutsu...
and sealed the Shukaku inside Gaara.
After consulting with his father
the Fourth Kazekage, that is.
What I did to protect the village
ended up just hurting it.
And now a village I avoided
because I couldn't believe in alliances
is trying to help us.
Everything I've done might
have been mistaken.
Now that I'm old, I've learned
to give up too easily.
Kakashi...
Young people have
so much potential within...
I'm so envious.
Oh no, you're just getting started...
You're still very much young.
That's right...
There might still be something
a withered old woman like me can do.
Something only I can do...
It's about finished.
Whose... hand is this?
Oh... it's my hand.
Have I... become someone who is needed?
Huh? What?
Is that me?
That's me... The me who just wanted
to be needed by someone...
Why...? Why did I want
to be like that?
Why... am I...
an existence that desires that?
Those eyes. That nose.
That mouth.
Why?
Why is that Gaara?
I was inside that...
No...
What am I in the first place?
I'm just aware that I'm me.
What am I... in the first place?
I'm just a small... feeling.
It's finished.
Oh man.
In the end, it took three days
and three nights.
It's exhausting every time, isn't it?
Ohhh, my shoulders are all stiff.
Good work, everyone.
Gaara is on the other side of this boulder.
It looks like they put up a barrier.
What's the plan?
Let's bust through!
No!
You're late, Kakashi.
Well, you see...
we got caught up in something
troublesome along the way.
Naruto! Sakura!
Kakashi... By troublesome,
you certainly don't mean me, do you?
Hey!
Naruto...
Now, shall we do this, Kakashi?
Yeah.
Hang on, Gaara.
A barrier, huh...?
It's getting noisy outside.
It appears they've arrived.
Which group? Hmm?
The group Kisame stalled?
Or is it...
It's... both groups...
So they arrived at the same time, huh?
However...
They were just a bit late...
It seems they've got another
Jinchuriki with them...
Don't take it personally, Itachi.
Now then. Shall we get going...?
It's starting to get noisy outside
and we've got our mission
to complete, after all.
Exactly...
What shall we do with
the guys outside?
Well, we don't even know
if they can get in here...
Don't underestimate them.
You should know.
Well... I acknowledge
their brute strength, at least.
Sasori.
Deidara.
You two handle the intruders outside.
I knew it would turn out like this...
But take the Jinchuriki alive.
We know.
Everyone else is dismissed.
Let's go.
Right...
We'll be leaving, too...
Itachi...
What's the Nine-Tails Jinchuriki like?
Tell him.
He'll be the first one to yell
and scream at you.
What does that mean?
Doesn't he have any more
specific characteristics?
Oh my...
Well, that's about it...
You okay with that?
Wasn't he your target?
Let's go.
Okay.
What does it look like to you?
This is... a Five-Seal Barrier.
A Five-Seal Barrier
is created by placing...
paper tags with "Forbidden" written
on them in five locations in the area.
There's the Forbidden tag
here in front of us...
and tags in four other locations...
How can we remove them?
We can't remove the barrier
unless we remove the tags in
all five locations simultaneously.
It must be done simultaneously, huh?
That's right.
The barrier can't be removed unless
the five tags are removed simultaneously.
That's how it's been set up.
Byakugan!
I found them!
Where are they, Neji?!
There's one on a boulder about
500 meters northeast of here...
The... second one...
is on the trunk of a tree growing
along a riverbank
350 meters to the south-southeast...
The third one...
is on a cliff about
650 meters to the northwest...
The last one...
is in a forest a little less than
800 meters to the southwest...
At that distance...
we should be able to use
wireless radios.
We'll remove the tags in
the four surrounding locations.
If this is a competition of speed, our
team will probably be faster, after all.
All right, Lee, you head for
the northwest forest!
Yes, Guy-sensei!
I leave the northeast boulder to you, Neji.
Roger.
And you take the south-southeast, Tenten.
Understood.
I'll head for the northwest cliff.
I'm sure that one will be in
the location most difficult to remove.
What's the frequency?
174.
Roger.
My wireless radio settings are okay.
Mine are okay as well.
All right. Team Guy...
R-Right!
Okay, okay...
With the full power of youth!
- Fight!
- Yeah!
- Fight! Fight!
- Yeah! Yeah!
- And an extra fight!
- Yeah!
Scatter!
So cool! Such youthful enthusiasm!
Hey guys, let's do that, too...!
I'd rather die...
Right...
You fool...!
Well, it's time for me to get going.
There's no reason for me to be here
if I'll just be in the way.
Good work, Pakkun.
Well, I'm outta here.
This is Neji. I'm in position.
I've found mine, too!
I'll be arriving soon.
I've got mine, too!
Neji!
I know!
Byakugan!
A little further south!
A little further...
All right, it's right there!
Okay! I found it!
This is Lee! I'm in position!
Kakashi, how's it going there?
We're ready when you are.
We'll use a buttonhook entry.
Right.
I know!
Yeah!
All right, everyone!
Remove the tags on the count of three!
Here we go!
One... two... three!
Sakura!
Right!
We're too late...
Sasori...
Now... which one's the Jinchuriki?
You... creeps.
I'm going to kill you both!
The first one to start yelling
and screaming...
It's him, huh?
It looks like it.