From here on, we'll be splitting
into two teams: diversion and search.
I'll go over it again.
Diversion will be made up
of Shurado, Chikushodo, and Gakido.
Search will be Tendo,
Ningendo, and Jigokudo.
Konan, you're with the search team.
I know.
The Hidden Leaf Village...
is surrounded by
a spherical barrier that
includes underground
and aerial coverage.
Which means anyone
who enters without permission
is detected immediately.
As planned, we will launch Chikushodo
into the Hidden Leaf's airspace.
We will confuse the enemy
regarding our numbers.
Wait for Chikushodo's summoning.
I was told Itachi and Kisame
infiltrated easily.
Itachi once belonged to
the Leaf's ANBU Black Ops.
He knew the password
to get through the barrier.
I have my own way of doing things.
Starting here,
the world shall know pain...
An intruder!
Single target, west gate, sector I-B
Hurry, hurry!
Yes, I'm coming dear.
Thanks for the food!
Yes, thank you!
Disperse!
What is that?
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
My Fire Style has no effect!
They're everywhere! What's going on?!
I thought there was just one intruder!
I'll confirm with the Byakugan
right away!
This is beyond the scope
of just the Barrier Corps!
Contact other troops and
request backup! Hurry!
Right!
I'll go notify Lady Hokage!
He holds no information
on the Nine-Tails.
Where is Naruto Uzumaki?
He doesn't know either...
The chakra transmission shot up suddenly
and the black rod began warming up,
so I thought it was strange.
These are demodulators for
receiving high frequency chakra waves.
Demodulator?
Which means what?
In other words,
they're chakra receivers!
And, it's receiving
at this very moment!
Receiver? What do you mean?
If this is a receiver...
I don't have time to explain.
I have to notify Lady Tsunade
immediately...
What was that?
What's that?
Let's go!
Found it!
What was that?
Choji! I'll notify the Intel Division.
Right!
I have to get to Pa!
Father! The village is...
Run!
Tami!
Cha!
Are you all right?!
U-Uh-huh.
Th-Thank you so much!
The centipede is down...
Seems that girl did it.
Thank goodness!
Your wound is not too deep.
Thank you...
Sakura!
Are you all right?
Iruka-sensei...
Just what's going on?
I don't know.
But someone is attacking
the Leaf Village!
The situation has been
reported to Lady Tsunade.
The alarm should sound soon.
The village is under direct attack?
Who would do such a thing?
Let's go, Iruka!
Right!
Sakura, hurry to the hospital
and tend to the wounded.
It's full of injured people.
Yes, sir!
Barrier Corps reporting!
An intruder entered Hidden
Leaf Village through our airspace.
Our sensors picked up
a single target.
But shortly after detection,
several attacks were confirmed.
Analysis Corps reporting!
Enemy strength estimated
as three battalions in size!
A foe capable of organizing
this much military power unnoticed...
It must be...
Reporting! I have a witness report
on the intruder!
He wore black with
a red cloud pattern.
The Akatsuki...
So they've finally come.
Sound the state of emergency alarm.
And...
Recall Naruto!
What is all this ruckus?!
The Akatsuki have begun their assault.
Then... their target is...
The Fourth Hokage's legacy...
Naruto Uzumaki!
And yet, despite the danger,
the Fifth Hokage is trying
to summon Naruto back.
Such a thing...
is like pouring oil onto a fire!
Yes... If we keep listening
to the Fifth Hokage...
the Hidden Leaf will be destroyed!
What was that?!
Stop! You mustn't go outside!
Shikamaru! What's going on?!
The Akatsuki has entered our territory.
Kurenai-sensei, can you step back?
All right.
I will return to call Naruto back.
I'm counting on you!
Stop!
Leave Naruto on Mount Myoboku.
What?!
We know that the Akatsuki leader
is the one attacking the village.
How did you find out?
We heard it from Danzo.
Moreover, they are after
Naruto's Jinchuriki power.
So what of it?
The last time, we gave you
the benefit of the doubt.
But not this time.
Naruto is still a child.
This is the assailant who
brought Jiraiya down!
If Naruto is taken and
the Nine-Tails falls into their hands...
Wha—?! What are you doing?!
Until I become Hokage...
I'll...
never die!
I will avenge Pervy Sage!
I can't just sit around doing nothing!
However... I guess I shouldn't
wallow in sadness.
My duty is to be a model
for the next generation
and to help them out.
For that, I'd happily give my life.
I can see that child truly loved
and admired Jiraiya-boy.
Y-You... Unhand us, Tsunade!
How dare you raise your hand
against us counselors...
Who do you think you are?!
How long do you intend to
treat him like a child?
What?!
The will of the Hidden Leaf
has been passed on
and it's growing!
Naruto is striving to surpass
Jiraiya this very minute!
He's not a hidden weapon
to be used by the Hidden Leaf
as a deterrent to war!
He is a ninja who has sworn
to protect the Hidden Leaf...
He is Naruto Uzumaki!
What Sarutobi-sensei and
Lady Chiyo of the Sand had...
and what you two lack... is this!
The power to believe!
In the same way that
my grandfather, the First Hokage,
believed in you and entrusted
the Hidden Leaf to your care...
It is time for you to believe,
and entrust to the next generation!
Do as you please.
Lady Tsunade!
Did you learn anything?
Yes!
This here!
What is it?
It seems to be a receiver
for chakra signals.
Pain's corpse had these inserted
throughout his body.
A receiver?!
According to what
Lord Fukasaku said,
all six Pains had these stuck
in their bodies and faces.
Does this mean that
the six Pains receive
some kind of chakra signal through
their bodies, and then take action?
That part isn't clear yet.
A receiver... Or they use it
to transmit chakra to each other.
Something wireless...
Also, this has definitely been activated.
This must be connected to
the secret of Pain's strength.
Together with the data
the Interrogation Corps gathers,
we'll figure this out.
According to the Intel Division,
the enemy is looking for Naruto.
This enemy, who infiltrated the village,
is undoubtedly Pain.
Messenger frog!
When you go to summon Naruto,
relay this message as well.
Understood!
Shizune, take the data
from the autopsy,
collaborate with Interrogation Corps
and figure out just who Pain is!
Yes, ma'am!
ANBU Team B will provide
Shizune with a protective escort!
Then, guard the Interrogation Corps!
Do not allow the enemy
to get near them!
Yes, ma'am!
I will wait for further news
on the rooftop,
and I will provide treatment for
all the wounded through Katsuyu.
I will use all my power to
protect the village!
Let's go!
Right! I must rush to Lord Fukasaku too!
They are so useless.
All they've done is grow old...
So Tsunade persuaded them
to her side instead...
But now, the Nine-Tails
can be kept caged up.
I'll ask you once more.
Where is Naruto Uzumaki?
Go to hell!
Speak. Is Naruto Uzumaki
in this village or not?
Which is it?
I-I don't know...
This guy... He absorbed the jutsu!
Then we'll have to engage
in direct combat.
Summoning Jutsu!
Starting now, attach yourself
to every ninja and citizen
in the Hidden Leaf Village.
Take in my chakra and use it
to treat all their injuries!
It seems the village is in dire straits.
Never mind, just go.
I understand.
I will protect this village,
no matter what happens!
I swear upon my title of Hokage!
Are you all right?
Tell me where the Jinchuriki
of the Nine-Tails is...
Or else, I'll kill you.
This crest...
I see... So he's from the Akatsuki.
Speak up.
Naruto...
I have no intention of telling
you anything!
I see... Then I have no use for you.
You created a loud diversion,
so that you can investigate
from the shadows...
Kakashi!
Get the wounded to safety.
Leave this scene to me.
Roger!
Good luck, Kakashi!
Now it's just the two of us.
Then I'll ask you.
Where is the Nine-Tails?
What you're doing is totally pointless.
The people of this village are
different from your average village.
Even if it means dying,
there's not a single
one of us who would
sell out a comrade.
Earth Style: Mud Wall!
Lightning Blade!
What was that?!
the Copy Ninja, Kakashi Hatake...
I'm honored to meet you.
Where is the Nine-Tails?
That... is a silly question.
Over there!
Pa!
I'm coming too!
What was that jutsu just now?
It felt different from a shock wave...
Everything around him was blasted
away, with him as the epicenter.
Then...
How will you counter this?
Not just physical attacks...
He can repel ninjutsu as well?!
Impressive.
Now then, how should I...?
Another one?
You're mine!
This guy...
He was facing directly ahead, yet...
Lord Jiraiya took on
six of them at once?!
I must say... That's crazy...
I get it! That's his ability!
Pain...
I have no chance
if I fight them alone.
I must call for reinforcements,
and let them know
what this one's ability is!
I have to do as much as
my body can handle!
A Lightning Style Shadow Clone!
One down...
Kakashi?
Actually, I was all set too.
But this will help me preserve
some chakra.
Thank you.
Are you all right?
Yes... Well... I'll manage.
Do you have enough chakra?
I've already used my Lightning Style
Shadow Clone
and exhausted over
half my chakra.
To be honest, a drawn-out battle against
a formidable opponent like him
is going to be difficult for me.
However, I've figured out
a little of his abilities.
Pa, he's coming!
Almighty Push...
There!
That's...
What did he just do?
He repelled all our attacks.
Using himself as the epicenter,
his jutsu allows him to attract
or repel objects.
Similar to the magnetic laws
of attraction and repulsion...
However, it seems he cannot
utilize that jutsu consecutively.
I know for certain that
there is an interval of time
before he can activate
the next jutsu.
Everyone else has been taken down!
If he can repel all attacks,
how do we defeat him?
The interval between jutsu
seems short too.
We can't get close.
However, that's our only chance.
I have an idea.
And I need your help.
You move quite well...
And you have a wide range of jutsu.
People like you need to be killed,
or you may pose a problem later.
Now!
Double Human...
Boulder!
Too slow...
The other Pain!
He could still move?!
Make it in time!
The damage is devastating...
No...
Everyone, let us hurry!
- Yes!
- Let us hurry. Let us hurry.
Now, hurry.
Your inability to move...
doesn't seem faked.
I didn't make it...
I know that you're not
a Shadow Clone.
I shall make certain of your death...
But just to be safe...
I will not approach you.
Humph... Know pain.
Pa...
Kakashi-sensei!
You tried to protect me...
Save your tears for later... Choji.
If... you are able to move...
report to Lady Tsunade
about Pain's abilities.
A counter strategy is imperative!
K-Kakashi... Sensei?
Reflect later!
You must... hurry!
Run!
But... I... I...
Don't let Choza's sacrifice
be in vain!
Persistent fellows, aren't you?
Damn it... He's still...!
He's after Choji!
Pa... Thank you for everything
you've done.
Just you watch!
Run! Choji!
I daresay with the chakra I have left
it's impossible to destroy
his entire body.
And... if I use it one more time,
I'll exhaust all my stamina
and chakra.
My life will be...
To entrust this intel to the living.
This is the best method I have
right now to save the Hidden Leaf!
I get it...
So... he also... got by...
with that ocular jutsu...
Well... it seems this is it
for me, too.
Obito... Rin...
Whatever the village may say...
You are a great Jonin.
I'm about to die...
But... I'll become your eyes
and see the future for you.
Take care of Rin...
Obito...
It seems this is the end...
of me seeing the future as your eyes.
I wasn't able to protect Rin...
I keep breaking my promises
to you.
Forgive me.
Obito...
Rin... Sensei...
I'll... be joining you now.
Is that you, Kakashi?
So this is where you were...
Will you tell me your story?
Sure... It's a really long story,
so I want to take my time.
Yeah... that's fine.
Well... Father...
Is something wrong?
Lady Tsunade!
U-Um...
Katsuyu has already attached herself
to most of the people
of the village.
Sorry. Let us continue...
Lady Tsunade!
We cracked the ability of
one of our enemies!
Tell me.
He is male.
Between 25-30 years of age.
Distinguishing marks
are piercings,
six in his nose and seven
in his ears.
His ability is a jutsu that simulates
magnetic attraction and repulsion.
He can attract targeted objects
to himself.
And he can repel
every ninjutsu attack.
Repel?! All of them?
Yes! However, once he uses either
jutsu, there is a five-second interval.
Five seconds... That's all?
You did well to report this!
Our casualties will decrease significantly.
Pass on this information to
everyone via Katsuyu!
- Yes, ma'am!
Team Choza provided back-up
for Kakashi-sensei
against two of the enemies...
It is believed everyone
except myself perished.
Go back to Choza!
Take him to the hospital
immediately!
He can still be saved.
Huh?!
Then... Pa is...
Yes...
Thank goodness! I'm so glad!
Kakashi...
What about Kakashi-sensei?!
This spells the end of Tsunade's era.
However, we cannot allow
the Akatsuki to take Nine-Tails.
So I have eliminated that possibility.
We will remain underground
until the chaos subsides.
Shouldn't we be assisting?
Even if you should assume power,
it would be meaningless
if the citizens of
the Hidden Leaf are dead.
The princess is now Hokage.
As long as she can utilize
Katsuyu's jutsu,
the entire village will not perish.
Certainly, there will be lives lost.
But to me, that is a necessary sacrifice.
In order for me to become the Hokage...
I win!
Nothing tastes better than
a drink of sake after work.
It's no use.
Did you find out anything, Tonbo?
Not yet... Nothing promising that
is linked to Pain.
Today's corpse is light.
It's a knack I got
from years of experience.
This one's a woman.
The highest tower in the village
where we always deliver these bodies...
You know what that's for?
In a village like ours, isn't it usually
where the ashes are enshrined?
They were originally built as
a memorial to honor the dead.
If that's the case, why is it off-limits
to the relatives of the dead too?
Like I care.
What? Stop acting arrogant.
Actually... Rumor has it that
Lord Pain lives up there.
Really? That's something.
But there's no way.
It's just a rumor. A rumor...
Never mind that. I'm going to confirm it.
Just like you said. It's a woman.
Good work.
Oh, Lady Angel...
Now quickly, bring the next one.
Inoichi is really amazing!
He scanned half a day's worth of memories
in just 30 seconds...
I can barely keep up!
You fool!
If you have time to talk, find
something that we can link to Pain!
Sorry for interrupting.
It's me, Shizune!
Lady Hokage ordered me
to come here!
Did you learn anything on your side?
Yes! I will explain immediately!
Summoning Jutsu!
Could it be that they use this to
transmit chakra to each other?
It's a similar ability to
our clan's hidden jutsu.
The forefather of all ninja,
the Sage of the Six Paths,
possessed the legendary Rinnegan.
Someone who possesses
the same eye...
If such a person really does exist,
then it wouldn't be a surprise,
no matter what jutsu he uses.
What was that?!
It seems they have
shown up here as well.
We will stop them.
Wind Style: Wind Blade Jutsu!
Lightning Style: Four-Pillar Trap!
Earth Style:
Buta Futa!
Well? Did we do it?
What?!
This beast... is growing more heads!
Looks like a special type
of Summoning.
Rather than fighting the beast,
let's find the one casting the jutsu!
Summoning Jutsu!
Wh-What is that?!
As I thought...
It seems I made it in time.
Lady Katsuyu, thank you so much!
Eek! Forgive me, Lady Katsuyu,
I'm just not used to you yet.
It's quite all right.
They are powerful Summonings.
Everyone, please be careful.
There's no mistake...
When I looked into the mind of
that fellow from the Hidden Rain...
I saw her.
She was a corpse!
And that dead body...
is now using a Summoning Jutsu!
It was thought each
of the six Pains
uses only one type of jutsu.
But something's wrong!
Lord Fukasaku said that
the only one who was able
to use Summoning was the Pain
we did the autopsy on!
What's going on?!
The Pain who was capable
of the Summoning Jutsu
has already been killed
by Lord Jiraiya!
Leave this place to
the ANBU Black Ops and me.
Get to safety!
Ibiki...!
Let's hurry, Inoichi!
We must uncover
Pain's true identity!
We'll head to the Cipher Division
for the time being.
Have Ino accompany us
to assist your jutsu.
Got it...
It's me, Ino. Listen carefully.
We are moving to the Cipher Division.
We shall be your opponents!
That mark...
It's the gang that killed
Uncle Asuma... The Akatsuki!
Is Naruto Uzumaki here in
the village or not? Which is it?
Naruto?!
He's... a member of the village.
We would never sell out a comrade!
The Will of Fire, eh?
What?!
If you do not answer my question,
you die.
I will ask you one more time.
What is this?
Is Naruto Uzumaki here in
the village or not? Which is it?
I know nothing!
So get lost!
We don't know a thing! Let us go!
I see...
Then I shall pass judgment.
It seems you truly did not know.
Wh-What's going on?!
He didn't even touch him,
yet the guy on the left just dropped?!
What did he do?!
Was the Chunin fellow killed without
being able to defend himself at all?
I-I'd better get away from here.
It's too dangerous!
Oh no! Is he on to me?!
It seems you went ahead
to do as you please!
I have no mercy for scum like you!
Now is your chance to
get away, Konohamaru!
It'll take more than that to kill me!
Ebisu-sensei...
Good... He got away.
I messed up...
But I've done what I needed to do.
Is Naruto Uzumaki here
in the village, or not?
If you know, speak up.
N-Naruto?
It seems you do know Naruto Uzumaki.
Then tell me where he is.
I may... not look it...
but I do hold the elite rank
of instructor.
Naruto is my student.
Long ago, I considered him
a nuisance...
Who stood in the way
of Konohamaru's path to Hokage.
That's what I believed...
However, Naruto didn't allow
his cursed fate to discourage him.
With unending optimism and
a never-say-die attitude
he faced one challenge after
another and overcame them.
The important lessons I couldn't teach,
despite being an instructor myself...
Naruto taught them to my students.
You... have rambled on too long.
This is your last chance.
Do you know where Naruto is,
or don't you?
Answer me! Or else I'll kill you.
Naruto... You...
You will overcome the death of
your master and carry on his legacy.
The strong will you possess
will teach Konohamaru...
no, everyone in the village,
many things.
Naruto is a member
of the Hidden Leaf!
I have no intention of telling
you Akatsuki anything!
I see... Then...
Brother Naruto...
When people look at me
or call out to me,
they only see me as the grandson
of the Hokage.
And I'm sick of it!
That's why I want the title
of Hokage right now!
It's not easy, stupid!
You keep harping on about the Hokage.
If you want that title so badly...
you can have it over
my dead body!
Then starting now... we're rivals!
One day, we'll fight over
the name of Hokage.
So look forward to that day,
Konohamaru!
I guess this is the end of the road.
I hope that Konohamaru was
able to escape.
Die...
I'll take you on!
Konohamaru!
Why didn't you run away?!
You have the potential to one day
become a Hokage!
Do not waste your life in
a place like this!
I made a promise long ago.
To fight Brother Naruto over
the title of Hokage...
That's what we promised.
Brother Naruto is my rival!
So I'll never choose to run away!
Because Brother Naruto won't be waiting
at the end of a shortcut!
So fast!
S-Sensei!
Is Naruto Uzumaki here in
the village or not? Which is it?
I get it... So this is what you see
if you get caught.
Now, answer me.
I'm starting to figure out... his ability.
I don't have a clue!
Konohamaru! There's a jutsu
I want to teach you!
It's an A-Rank level jutsu in terms
of difficulty to master.
A Shadow Clone?!
Super advanced ninjutsu that combines
chakra rotation, power,
and contained...
- Rasengan!
Wh-When did he learn... such a...?
I am a Genin of the Sarutobi clan,
honored with the name
of this village!
My surname is Sarutobi!
My given name is Konohamaru!
Remember that!
Fang Over Fang!
He used the corpse as a shield.
I figured as much.
The reports were right.
Physical attacks seem
to be his weakness!
Shino, we're going to exterminate her
with our full power.
Yes.
I'm so hungry!
Let's rest a bit.
We're all tired from the mission.
What's the matter, Guy-sensei?
Have you noticed large numbers
of birds
flying away from the direction
of the village?
As though they were fleeing.
I also have this bad feeling...
We should head straight
for the village.
What?!
Let's go, everyone!
Seriously!
Behind you!
Six piercings in the nose,
seven in the ear... It's him.
It's been a long time, Lady Tsunade.
You are the last remaining
of the Legendary Sannin.
I wish to take a moment
to speak with you.
You are that boy...
... from long ago.
It seems you remember me.
You know him?
A little...
Who is he?
A god who restores order.
It seems he's not in his right mind.
Naruto Uzumaki...
Where is the Nine-Tails?
Who knows...?
The hunt for the Jinchuriki is about over.
The Tailed Beasts are
no longer deterrents
in maintaining the power balance
between the ninja villages.
It's meaningless to protect
the Nine-Tails now.
The war will begin very soon.
Seeds of war exist everywhere,
ready to explode.
And we shall control those wars.
If you cooperate with us,
we would not be averse to helping you.
From the state of this village...
You should know what
we are capable of.
Don't underestimate the Five Kages!
You terrorists seek to destroy
the peace
our predecessors strived
to bring and maintain!
Your words fall on deaf ears!
Such arrogance!
Such chakra...
This is the power of the Rinnegan?
I've never seen anything like it.
Your peace has brought
violence upon us.
I will admit that
some of the past actions of
the Hidden Leaf were not just.
But your actions here
are unforgivable!
Be careful of what you say.
This is your final warning from a god.
Tell me where Naruto is.
Speak!
We will pour every ounce of power
we have into bringing you down!
That is all I have to say!
One other thing...
You have made a huge error!
What you desire, you shall never get!
If you think the Hidden Leaf has what
it takes to protect Naruto, then...
Wrong!
Naruto... is strong.
There are six Pains.
Each one can only use
one type of jutsu.
That woman used Summoning Jutsu.
That means the Pain killed by Lord Jiraiya
was replaced by a different body.
And there's no mistake...
that woman was transported to
Hidden Rain's tower as a corpse.
Did that woman's corpse have
this embedded in her?
No... I'm sure she didn't.
This proves that Lord Fukasaku
was right.
Pain has the power to bring
the dead back to life.
Furthermore, he is able to
substitute bodies as often as he wants,
and controls them by planting
these black chakra receivers.
Then those six Pains are...
It's possible all of them are
actually dead bodies.
And if they have receivers,
they must also have transmitters.
So someone is in the shadows,
sending chakra signals and
manipulating them.
Yes.
The coded message left behind
by Lord Jiraiya,
"The real one's not among them...”
Perhaps it meant that none of
the six Pains is the real Pain.
What?! You mean there are
still others out there?!
Exactly.
I did anticipate that possibility...
But as the worst-case scenario,
I really didn't want it to be true.
And that someone possesses
considerable chakra.
They are able to control this
many bodies remotely, this freely,
using just their chakra.
It's similar to our Yamanaka clan's,
Mind Transfer Jutsu.
But normally you can only
manipulate one person with chakra.
There are six Pains.
Does this mean there are
six others in the shadows?
We don't know that.
In any case, if this is
a Mind Transfer Jutsu,
he has to be pretty close to
the receiver in order to transmit chakra.
Otherwise, it would be impossible to pull
off that magnitude of jutsu and attacks.
He must be hidden somewhere
close to the Leaf Village.
We need to notify
Lady Tsunade immediately,
and organize a search party
to find the hidden Pain.
What?!
How did we not notice him?!
Do not make a move...
or this woman will die.
Damn it!
Mount Myoboku...
The same jutsu that Father uses!
But he was able to search her mind
in seconds without any device?!
It seems Naruto is not here.
Mount Myoboku.
What?!
They retreated?
What's going on?
Mount Myoboku...
That is the hidden village of the toads.
Well then, lingering here is useless.
How did you know?
Why you...
Lady Tsunade...
We should let them go and
in the meantime, fortify the village.
May I ask you one last question?
That chakra in your legs...
Was it to counter my jutsu?
It seems you've realized my ability.
However, all is meaningless
before overwhelming power.
Your great nations proved
that over the years.
You all think that you have
the leading roles in this world,
and do not think twice about death.
Soothed by peace, you become shallow.
If you kill people, you shall be killed.
Hatred brings about
this cause and effect.
Quit babbling such nonsense.
In battle, both sides suffer death,
injury, and pain.
And we of the Great Nations
have had our share of pain!
Stop finding excuses for your actions!
Feel pain.
Contemplate pain.
Accept pain. Know pain!
One who does not know pain cannot
possibly understand true peace!
Bad news! Lord Fukasaku!
What is wrong?
Our messenger, Kosuke,
has been killed.
What?!
His name...
vanished from the register.
Does that mean something has
happened to the Leaf Village?
What?!
Naruto-boy, I have a bad feeling.
Geezer Sage...
Don't tell me the Akatsuki
attacked the village!
Luckily, Ma went to gather provisions
and is near the Leaf Village.
She will be capable of summoning
strong warriors, including us.
Get ready now!
Right!
Damn it...
I won't get to all of them like this!
Lady Shizune!
What?!
They seem to have retreated.
Yes... But it doesn't make sense.
Lady Shizune...
Their scents are completely gone.
They're not around here.
I guess my power scared them off!
That's coming from the Leaf Village.
Oh my goodness...
Lady Shima!
I came through
the distance teleporting pool.
I have a message
from Lord Fukasaku.
To summon them, eh?
Pain! What do you intend to do?!
You can't! That jutsu
will shorten your life!
The power of the six is...
You're really going to do this,
aren't you, Nagato?
I will never forget Yahiko's pain.
And now...
This world shall know pain.
Almighty Push...
Summoning Jutsu!
Wh-What is this?!
How could this hap—
Naruto... Hurry!
Please, Naruto!
Lady Tsunade, are you all right?!
Yes...
You will not get away with this...
You will not get away with this, Pain!
The mark on her forehead is gone!
She has already released
her Mitotic Regeneration Jutsu
and given all her chakra
to Lady Katsuyu.
In order to protect the villagers
from this Pain's jutsu...
She can no longer...
Are you all right, Iruka?!
Forgive me.
It took everything...
just to cover you all.
You are not to blame, Lady Katsuyu.
Damn!
Hang in there, Kiba!
Ow!
This is nothing.
Are you all right, Lady Hinata?
Yes, but Ko, you're injured.
If anything should happen to you during
Lord Hiashi and Lady Hanabi's absence,
I will be dishonored for life.
You need not concern yourself
with me.
But I must!
If everyone is injured while
the head of the family is away,
I will be the one scolded.
Lady Hinata...
Are you all right, Shikamaru?!
Yeah... But what's going on?!
You okay, Shikamaru?!
I made it out, but my leg's broken.
You should consider yourself lucky
if the only thing you suffered in
this attack was a leg injury.
That's...
It's Naruto!
Naruto?!
Where are we anyway?
What's going on, Ma?!
Why didn't you Summon us
to the Leaf Village?
This is the Hidden Leaf Village.
It can't be...!
And it's obvious who did this.
I sense the same energies as when
we rode atop Jiraiya-boy's shoulders.
You saved us the trouble
of looking for you.
Why are you being so reckless?
This is... my justice.
The effectiveness of the jutsu
when all the chakra is concentrated
in Tendo is great,
but it also increases the risks.
Not only that, the other five
are recovering much slower
compared to the last time
this jutsu was used.
From here on out,
I'll be looking after you.
No more Paper Clones.
Summoning Jutsu!
Looks like all six have assembled.
Tsunade?
I am the Fifth Hokage!
Lady Hokage!
You trampled on the jewel,
the dreams of my predecessors.
I will not forgive you!
I will settle this now as the Hokage!
It appears you now understand
a little about pain.
However... my business is not with you.
My business is...
With me!
There's no need for the Leaf's Hokage
to bother herself with the likes of them.
You just sit back and
sip some tea, Granny.
Naruto!
Naruto Uzumaki.
Let's settle this!
Tendo's power won't return
for quite some time.
In which case...
Gamakichi!
Take Granny Tsunade to
someplace safe!
Gotcha!
Granny, I'll take over from here!
Tell everyone in the village
to stay out of the way!
It'll be difficult to fight while trying
to cover for them.
Understood.
But take Katsuyu.
I know she'll be useful to you.
She has intel on them.
Katsuyu... Keep yourself hidden
in Naruto-boy's clothes.
Yes, sir.
Now may not be the right time
to ask a question like this...
But now that I've mastered
Nature Energy...
I'm able to sense everyone's chakra.
Is Kakashi-sensei on a mission
away from the village?
I see...
Master!
Lady Tsunade!
Sakura...
Everything is okay now.
Yes...
Thank you, Lady Tsunade.
Summoning Jutsu!
– Sage Art: Frog Song!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
– Sage Art: Giant Rasengan!
Bunta-boy! Ken-boy! Hiro-boy!
Right on!
Naruto! Ninjutsu won't work
on the Pain standing before you.
He will absorb all your ninjutsu attacks.
Then we'll go with Frog Kumite!
Stay still, you mutt!
I thought we dodged it...
Frog Kumite utilizes
the Nature Energy around you.
The energy became part of
Naruto's body when he attacked Pain!
In Sage Mode, both threat perception
and attack range
are enhanced way
beyond the ordinary.
No time to waste here!
I'll finish this with my new jutsu!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
I see... So you have become a Sage...
mastering the same jutsu
as Jiraiya-sensei.
Jiraiya... Sensei?
I also learned jutsu from Jiraiya.
He was once my master...
Which make us fellow disciples.
Sharing the same master, you and I
should be able to understand one another.
Our master desired peace.
Shut the hell up!
Such massive chakra...
Did you teach him that, Pa?
No... I'm seeing it for
the first time too.
All that...
you've done here...
Where's the "peace" in that?!
You're only looking at the tree,
not the whole forest.
You don't know
the true meaning of peace.
So let yourself be captured.
Your death will lead to peace.
I told you... to shut the hell up!
Summoning Jutsu!
Deidara was right.
He does not listen.
What was that?
What's going on?
Who's fighting them?!
It's Naruto.
Naruto?!
Naruto is back?
Yes.
He has mastered Sage Jutsu
and is now fighting Pain alone.
What?!
Damn this leg!
Please stay here.
Naruto has asked us not to interfere.
He's so full of himself!
Look what they did to this village!
There is no way
he can take them on by himself...
No.
If he's mastered Sage Jutsu,
he's in a class of his own now.
Staying out of the way is
the best teamwork we can offer for him.
Sit tight, Shikamaru.
Please be careful!
The more you strike,
the more it will divide in numbers!
Why didn't you tell me sooner?!
You see... I'm clumsy...
Oww!
So how do we handle this?!
We must clumsily endure it for now...
Chief...
You're slowing down.
It seems your Sage Jutsu power
is decreasing.
Did you use up your Sage Jutsu chakra
with that last jutsu?
Oh no... I'm about to lose Sage Mode!
I have to bring this guy down
before Sage Mode runs out!
Ma, you know what to do!
We're going to break the Rinnegan link!
Got it, Pa!
Bunta-boy!
Boss!
Listen up.
I'm going to hurl you
straight at Naruto-boy!
Hurl... me? But why, Boss?
Listen carefully to
what I'm about to tell you.
Ready, Pa?
Sage Art!
Wind Style: Sand Dust!
Where is he?!
Rasengan Barrage!
Inside its mouth?!
You've exhausted your Sage Jutsu.
Even in Sage Mode,
two Rasen Shuriken are my limit.
Now is my chance.
What?!
You mean we can't merge with him
because of that Nine-Tails?!
It seems that way.
Then what are we to do?!
Naruto-boy came up with
his own unique solution.
That's what he's about to do!
You little scamp!
Why you...
Damn it!
Damn!
This way, Naruto-boy!
Hand it over! I'll do it!
Bring it on!
Stay back, kid! I'll get him!
I'm going to enter Sage Mode!
What?!
Get back, Boss!
I don't want you guys to get caught
in my Rasen Shuriken!
Acting all tough now...
I can replenish Sage chakra
two more times.
That means I have four more tries
with my Rasen Shuriken!
I have to settle this within that time.
Let's do it, Naruto-boy!
Reverse Summoning Jutsu!
What?
Wh-What is this?!
That's right.
This is the one that absorbs ninjutsu.
But I thought we already
took care of him.
What is that?
It seems that Pain
is the key player.
The one Geezer Sage spoke of...
The one who can resurrect the dead?
He must be the Pain
who possesses that power.
That is why when they lined up
in formation...
that Pain stepped back to take
the rearmost position of the troop.
And the most troublesome Pain
is the one on the left.
He hasn't shown his powers yet,
which is suspicious.
Perhaps, for some reason,
he's not able to utilize
his powers yet.
Either way... We have to get rid
of the guy in the back!
Along with some smoke bombs!
All right!
What you absorbed was
a Transformation Jutsu!
Bastard!
You're the original?!
You can't dodge this!
This time, I got you for sure!
My power has finally returned.
It's not over yet!
Sage Jutsu!
Rasengan Barrage!
What?!
Back there...
He had already slipped into
the smoke and jumped up above.
Just barely in time...
Almighty Push!
Are you all right, Naruto-boy?!
Yeah...
Damn it! What was that jutsu just now?!
It seems the core Pain's power
has returned.
You mean, him?
No doubt he used the same jutsu
to blow up the village.
The more power he uses,
the longer the interval before
he can use the next jutsu.
So that's why he couldn't use that
repelling jutsu until just now.
What are my options?
Ninjutsu and taijutsu won't work.
Choji brought us information.
The minimum interval between
Pain's jutsu is about five seconds.
You must target and strike
during that interval.
Only five seconds?
You'll have to trap him with genjutsu.
But how?! I suck at genjutsu!
We'll do it!
Just like before.
Just like before?
Almighty Push...
Damn it!
Naruto...
There's no mistake!
It's definitely Naruto!
He's fighting alone!
No, Lady Hinata!
But Naruto is risking his life
for our village!
If you enter such a battle,
you will only get in his way
and put him at risk!
Hey! We must hurry and
cast the genjutsu.
Performing a duet before everyone
is so embarrassing.
Quit complaining and do it!
I know already!
This genjutsu requires an enormous
amount of Sage Jutsu Chakra.
In other words, it will take a little
time before the jutsu activates.
I'm going to go for that
five-second interval!
As soon as you take in enough
Sage Jutsu Chakra, start the genjutsu!
Remember... You only have
one Shadow Clone left
to take in Sage Jutsu Chakra
for you, Naruto-boy.
Once that's gone,
it'll be impossible to fight
while taking in Sage Jutsu Chakra,
as it requires you not to move.
And your Sage Mode will
run out in five minutes.
Using Shadow Clones to
help you maintain stillness
and take in Sage Jutsu Chakra
was a good idea.
But why didn't you make
more of them?
It's like trying to look to the right
and to the left at the same time.
We've divided the task,
but taking in Sage Jutsu Chakra
is extremely difficult.
At Naruto-boy's current level,
two Shadow Clones were his limit.
On top of that, I can only produce
three Shadow Clones for battle.
Anymore would interfere with
those taking in Sage Jutsu Chakra.
I see... Either way, prolonging things
isn't to our advantage.
You are strong indeed.
This is the farthest Pain
has ever been pushed.
However...
Universal Pull.
That's enough.
Don't worry. I won't kill you.
You are a precious Jinchuriki.
Hah, it doesn't hurt at all!
Don't underestimate
my Sage Mode!
Now it's my turn to...
You are right. That is a problem.
What's happening?
I'm losing power...
I get it! This guy is sucking out
my Sage Jutsu Chakra!
Capture of the Nine-Tails,
accomplished.
You don't have me... yet.
Quite tenacious, aren't you?
So that's how it is.
Well, it's just perfect since
I can't move.
So you've finally resigned yourself.
You know, Nature Energy is
really hard to control.
Sage Jutsu Chakra has its risks,
after all.
Now, it's just you...
Well... not quite.
What do you mean?
These Pains are puppets.
There is another manipulating
these Pains.
The real Pain.
The real Pain?!
All right, we're ready.
Let's do it, Ma!
Gotcha!
Pa!
Geezer Sage!
I've had enough of
that genjutsu.
Pa!
Bastard!
Universal Pull!
Has this tamed you a little,
Nine-Tails?
What are you?!
Just what do you want?!
Why are you doing all of this?!
Why, you ask?
Things always happen
without warning.
And the reason becomes
apparent afterward.
This situation...
Perhaps I will explain to you.
Use Katsuyu as a medium and
gather every piece of data available
from those who have
encountered Pain.
The dead may have left
some information as well.
Even if we have to haul dead bodies,
find out all we can!
Haul dead bodies...
Wait... I think I know where
to find the real Pain!
What do you mean?
Did you figure something out?
Yeah...
Back when I looked into
the mind of the Hidden Rain ninja
who was captured by Lord Jiraiya...
His duty was to deliver bodies
with his partner.
It's a hunch I got from
years of experience.
This one's a woman.
The highest tower in the village
where we always deliver these bodies...
Deliver bodies?
Yes... Your earlier remark
triggered my memory.
Now listen...
First, it's basic knowledge that
one who transmits chakra signals
must be as close to
the receiver as possible.
And...
Of the several towers that exist
in Hidden Rain Village,
this man was delivering bodies
to the tallest tower.
It was rumored in
Hidden Rain Village
that Pain could be found
in the tallest tower.
Actually... Rumor has it
that Lord Pain lives up there.
And the woman who appeared as Pain...
She was the same body as the woman
who was delivered to the tallest tower.
So this tower was the laboratory where
those black rod-like chakra Receivers
were implanted into corpses
to create the Pains.
And how is that connected to
the real Pain's whereabouts?
The best spot to send out
chakra signals...
It had to be the tallest tower
with the widest and farthest reach.
I see... That means...
the real Pain is in the highest spot
close to Leaf Village.
All right! So we'll search every
single spot that is at a high altitude!
You asked me why I am
doing all of this.
Even if I told you why,
I doubt that would change anything.
But what if we tried to have
a discussion once more?
I have nothing to discuss
with you.
My goal is something even
Jiraiya-sensei was unable to achieve.
As I mentioned earlier...
Creating peace,
and bringing about justice.
Peace? Justice?
Yeah, right...
Don't give me that crap!
My master! My sensei!
My friends! My village!
After everything you've done,
don't you dare talk about
peace and justice!
Then tell me what your goal is?
I'm going to kill you!
And bring peace back
to the ninja world!
I see... That is noble of you.
That is justice indeed. However...
My family...
My friends...
My village...
They suffered the same fate
as this village,
by you Hidden Leaf ninja.
How is it fair to only allow you people
to preach about peace and justice?
What are you talking about?!
The Land of Fire and the Hidden Leaf
had grown too big.
To protect its national interests,
it forced feudal clans to wage war
against each other,
and profited from it.
Otherwise, the nation and the people
of the villages would have starved.
However, our small nation and
its villages became the battlefields
for the Great Nations' war.
And each time, our nation was ravaged
and laid to waste.
After all the fighting subsided,
things stabilized in the Great Nation.
And our small nation was left
to suffer the pain and misery.
You and I seek the same thing.
We are trying to establish the peace
that Jiraiya-sensei so desired.
You and I are not different at all.
We each act according to
our own sense of justice.
The justice I delivered
to the Leaf Village
is no different from what
you are trying to do to me.
The pain of losing something dear
to you is the same.
And both of us know
that pain all too well.
You have your justice...
And I have mine.
We are both ordinary men,
driven to seek vengeance
under the banner of justice.
However, if there is justice
in vengeance,
then justice will only breed
more vengeance.
And trigger a cycle of hatred.
We are currently living right
in the middle of that very cycle.
We know what the past has been and
we can predict what the future will be.
That is history as we know it.
So we cannot help
but believe that
human beings are incapable
of understanding each other.
The world of the ninja
is ruled by hatred.
However...
even I can see there's too much
hate in our ninja world.
Hate?
And I've wanted to do
something about this hatred,
yet I'm not sure what must be done.
But I have faith that
there will come a time
when people can truly understand
one another.
It all sounds kinda complicated.
And if I can't find the answer,
perhaps I will entrust you to find it.
You got it! I can't turn you down,
can I, Pervy Sage?
How would you confront this hatred,
in order to create peace?
I want to hear your answer.
I don't have an answer...
to something like that.
I formed the Akatsuki in order
to stop this cycle of hatred.
I can put an end to it.
For that... I need the power
of your Nine-Tails.
I will use the power of every Tailed
Beast to create a Tailed Beast Weapon,
many times more potent than
the power that destroyed this village.
A power enough to wipe out
an entire nation instantly.
A Tailed Beast Weapon?!
The world will know real pain.
The fear instilled by that pain
would prevent wars.
And the world will be on
the road to stability and peace.
But that kind of peace...
It's nothing but a fake!
Humans are not the most intelligent
of creatures.
This is the only way that
peace can be achieved.
And after several decades, that
pain too will eventually fade with time.
It will no longer be a deterrent
and humanity will begin to
battle once more.
This time, they themselves will
use the Tailed Beast Weapon
against one another and
reconfirm what true pain is.
And then peace will be
restored again, for a time.
In the course of
this endless cycle of hatred...
Pain will give rise to
momentary peace.
That is my dream.
Nagato...
Try not to push yourself.
You've already spent
so much chakra.
Peace is right within our grasp.
What's wrong, Neji?
That's Lord Jiraiya's Summoning Frog.
What?!
So the real Pain will be at the highest
spot, somewhere near the Leaf Village.
All right, let's search every single site
that is at high altitude!
Work in teams with
at least two people per cell.
And if you find the real Pain,
do not engage him carelessly.
Try to include Sensory-Type ninja
in the search teams.
It'll be faster.
All right.
Shikamaru, stay here with Shiho
and wait for word from us.
I guess I have no choice
since I can't move.
Okay, Katsuyu.
Get word of this to every
able survivor in the village.
We'll need their help.
Yes, I understand.
You argue that my vision
of peace is a fake.
But in this cursed world,
there is nothing more fictional
than a peace where people can
truly understand one another.
Pervy Sage believed that the day
would come
when people truly understand
one another.
You're wrong!
Empty words...
What can you do when you can't
even back up your answer?
All you are good for...
-... is giving me the power
of the Nine-Tails.
Like I told you earlier...
your death will lead to peace.
I can feel...
Pain's chakra coming inside...
I've avoided any vital spots
and kept them shallow.
But you will no longer be able
to move on your own.
Snap out of it, Lad!
No matter what he says,
you must not listen!
You're the Child of Prophecy!
The savior of this world!
Jiraiya-boy and Pa sacrificed themselves
because they believed that!
So you cannot lose!
If you give up now,
I won't forgive you!
Noisy frog.
Bastard!
I guess I'll be taking you now...
Lady Hinata!
How cruel...
Restricting Naruto's movement
with those poles.
I won't let you hurt Naruto anymore!
Reinforcements?
Why'd you come out here?!
Get away quickly! You're no match...
I know.
I'm just being... selfish.
What are you talking about?!
Don't put yourself in danger like this!
I'm here because I want to be.
This time...
I'm going to save you, Naruto.
I was always crying,
and giving up before even trying.
I made the wrong turns
so many times...
But you helped me find my way
and take the correct path, Naruto.
I always chased after you.
I wanted to catch up to you.
I wanted to walk
beside you all the time.
I want to be at your side, always.
You changed me, Naruto!
Your smile is what saved me!
That's why I'm not afraid to die...
if it means I can protect you!
Because...
I love you, Naruto!
What?
Hinata!
I can't get near Naruto...
I must do something!
I can't let it end like this.
If there's even the slightest chance...
Gentle Step: Twin Lion Fists!
Nagato!
Now's my chance!
One more time!
Hinata!
I want to become a great ninja...
strong like Father and
kind like Mother.
If you're the Hyuga girl,
show us your Byakugan!
If you don't want to,
then don't look our way!
Your eyes are creepy!
I bet you're actually
a monster, right?
Yeah, you Byakugan monster!
Hey! Cut it out!
- Huh?
- Who are you?
I'm Naruto Uzumaki!
The future Hokage!
The future Hokage?
Are you stupid?
Get ready!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Come at me!
Yeah!
Why you!
I knocked him out!
Future Hokage, yeah right!
- Wearing a red scarf...
- Yahoo!
Thinking it makes him look cool!
Hold it, hold it!
This time,
I'll do a super-duper jutsu and—?
Oww...
Are you okay?
It's nothing...
Your scarf...
Those boys...
I'm sorry...
Don't worry about it.
U-Um...
Huh?
Th-Thank you very much.
See ya!
Hinata!
Hey!
Damn it...
Hinata!
Stop...
Don't come, Hinata.
I'm not running away!
It's impossible to change yourself.
Sure she can! Don't go deciding
what a person is like!
Go, Hinata!
I always thought you were
so negative, hesitant, and weird.
But I kind of like people like you.
I don't understand.
Why would someone weak
like you try to resist?
Why fight me?
Knowing... that you'll die?
- I stand by what I say.
Because that's... my Ninja Way...
It was just like this...
My parents were killed
before my very eyes
by ninja from the Hidden Leaf.
Out of love, sacrifice is born...
Hate is born...
and we are able to know pain.
Do you hate me?
It's responding to Naruto's rage.
Do you still think people can
truly understand one another?
Your actions are justified.
But know this...
My pain is far greater than yours!
Let's go!
Is that all you've got?
Not bad.
A Sealing Jutsu?
He broke the Seal...
Here he comes!
He's fast!
Almighty Push!
Impossible...
He withstood my Almighty Push!
Naruto.
Universal Pull!
What was that?!
Oh my god... What is that?
How is Naruto doing?
How can I put it?
Naruto is showing
six tails right now.
At this rate, he may end up
transforming into the Nine-Tails.
Six tails?!
Six... It's much worse
than last time!
Lady Katsuyu. Please tell everyone
to evacuate immediately.
Did you find Kabuto?
Yes.
Good. Don't let him spot you.
Wh-What?!
What is it?
It can't be... He undid
the Sealing Jutsu on his own!
Six Tails?! That's insane!
There's an emergency.
Sorry, but I must return to the village!
H-Hey!
The power of the Nine-Tails...
How magnificent.
I've brought Tendo close enough.
You don't have to go that far.
Your body can't take anymore.
Silence, Konan. I must focus.
Planetary Devastation!
Why did you push yourself
to make it that huge?
My opponent is the Nine-Tails.
I cannot ease up.
The Sage of the Six Paths is
said to have created the moon.
This is nothing compared to that.
Regardless...
I have now captured the Nine-Tails.
Why?
Why did it come to this?
How would you confront this hatred,
in order to create peace?
I want to hear your answer.
How should I know?
It hurts... I hate this.
I don't know...
What am I supposed to do?
I don't know anything anymore!
Someone, help me...
Give me the answer.
Destroy everything.
Erase everything that hurts.
Give me your soul.
I will save you from your suffering.
Yes... You're doing fine.
Eight?! This is bad.
This is really, really bad!
I never imagined it would
be this powerful.
Come over here.
Come...
Rip this Seal off me.
Damn it... It's too late.
How could this happen?
You're...
Fourth... Hokage...
I worked it into the seal spell
so that I would appear within
your psyche,
should the seal be broken to the point
you sprouted the eighth tail.
I really wanted to avoid that...
Since I had no desire to see
you again... Nine-Tails.
Then again...
I did look forward to seeing
my son as a young man.
So I'll call it even.
Fourth Hokage!
Come here!
I'll rip you to shreds!
Well, if that's the case,
I'll stay away.
Right, Naruto?
Naruto... My name...
Hm?
Well... I'm the one who named you.
You are my son, after all.
Son? Then... I'm...
Yes.
You heard me.
You're my son.
Fourth Hokage!
Loud fellow, isn't he?
Let's go somewhere quiet.
Third Hokage didn't tell you much
of anything, did he?
I suppose he wanted to conceal
the truth about the Nine-Tails.
If people had found out you were
my son, you'd have been in danger.
Dad...
Why did you seal the Nine-Tails
inside your own son?!
Do you know what I went
through because of that?!
All the grown-ups looked
at me with contempt...
And I couldn't make any friends.
I wanted people to accept me,
so I trained really hard
to become strong.
Then I met Iruka-sensei, and
Kakashi-sensei, and Pervy Sage...
And I was happy because
they helped make me stronger!
But because of that, a group called
the Akatsuki came after me,
so I trained really hard...
I became even stronger,
but the Akatsuki still killed my friends.
But... huh?
What am I saying?
Damn it, am I supposed
to be happy or mad?!
I don't know anymore!
Naruto... How old are you now?
Sixteen.
Wow... You're already
sixteen years old, huh?
It must have been hard for you...
I'm sorry, Naruto.
I suppose after putting
my own son through so much...
I have no right to act like
a father and apologize.
It's all right... already.
I'm the son... of the Fourth Hokage...
I can handle this.
I sealed half of the Nine-Tails' chakra
inside of you,
because I believed
you could control its power.
Because you are my son.
And there is a reason why I did this.
When the Nine-Tails attacked
the village sixteen years ago,
I learned something.
What?
There was a mastermind who unleashed
the Nine-Tails on the village.
Mastermind?
A powerful ninja at that.
It would require a special kind of power
to go up against such an opponent.
I believe he will attack our village again.
The Leaf Village
has already been destroyed.
Yes... I watched from inside you.
You watched?!
I know about Jiraiya-sensei too.
Then was it Pain who used the Nine-Tails
to attack the village before?
No... It wasn't him.
Then who was it?!
One of the Akatsuki.
The Masked Man.
Back then...
he saw through every move I made.
He's no ordinary ninja.
This man is probably just using Pain.
No! Pain had a grudge
against the Hidden Leaf!
He said, long ago, his own village
was wiped out like ours!
That's right.
Because of that hatred,
he's being used.
Used?! A guy as strong as him?!
And what about
this mastermind masked ninja?
Why is everyone attacking the Leaf?
Perhaps as long as there is
a ninja system in this world,
there can be no peace.
Pain questioned you about peace...
But finding the answer is difficult.
You must find the answer yourself.
I do not have the answer.
If Pervy Sage and you don't know
the answer, how am I to know?!
Everyone expects too much!
I'm not smart!
And I'm not a great ninja!
And...
I know you'll find the answer.
I have faith in you.
Really?
You really believe I can do it?
To be a parent is to have
undying faith in one's child.
Now then... It's time for me to go.
My chakra's fading.
Huh?!
No, wait...
I will rebuild the seal.
However, this will be for the last time.
The Leaf can be rebuilt.
I'm counting on you... Naruto!
Thanks... Dad!
The Nine-Tails... disappeared?!
His doubt is gone...
What happened?
Does he now have control
over the Nine-Tails?
Nagato!
The transformation into the Nine-Tails
disturbed my chakra.
It made me lose my Shadow Clone.
I can only use the Sage Jutsu Chakra
I have left inside of me.
He's already in Sage Mode.
He's tough.
I had to confirm the extent
of the Nine-Tails' power,
but I never imagined he could stop
my Planetary Devastation.
I thought I was going to die!
What the...?
That's where the village is...
What happened?
You did it, Naruto, when you
were in the Nine-Tails state.
She's alive...
I can sense Hinata's chakra.
I was worried,
but no casualties resulted from
your assault
in the Nine-Tails state.
We were lucky.
I see.
It's time to settle this.
Have you come to understand
a little of what pain is?
Unless you know the same pain,
you cannot truly know another.
And even if you get to know others,
there can be no understanding.
That is the truth.
Just like how it's useless
to chase after Sasuke.
Take me to where the real Pain is!
I want to speak to you face-to-face.
Hmm... So you figured that out?
Jiraiya-sensei and now you...
You Leaf ninja are quite impressive.
However, our discussion is over.
Talking with you will change nothing.
Let me talk to him!
Sage Mode...
It seems you can only throw two of
those chakra shuriken. Isn't that so?
After that,
you will run out of Sage Mode!
I guess I have no choice
but to fight you!
If both of your shuriken miss,
you shall lose.
I will give you no more chances.
All that's left is to dodge your attack,
and drag your half-dead body away with me.
Too bad then...
I'll just look for the real Pain myself!
But how?
I have an idea.
Found you!
Bastard!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Now! Smoke bombs!
Right!
Here comes the first shuriken.
Almighty Push!
What?! He had already launched the
second one using Shadow Shuriken Jutsu?!
His jutsu interval is five seconds!
I can do this!
Four seconds to go!
He was already standing by
with a Shadow Clone back then.
Three more seconds
until I can use my next jutsu.
But he missed both shots...
It's over.
What?!
We still have two more seconds! Go!
He had this many Shadow Clones
transformed into rubble?!
One more second!
Zero!
He's now using Shadow Clones
as back up!
Someone like you who has no answer...
should just give up!
But I have faith that
there will come a time when
people can truly understand one another.
And if I can't find the answer,
perhaps I will entrust you to find it.
I know you'll find the answer.
I have faith in you.
Only you can surpass
the Fourth Hokage.
I truly believe that.
He withstood it... Impossible!
That jutsu cannot be thrown.
I have five seconds.
This distance will work for me.
Give up...
... on me giving up!
Rasengan!
Nagato...
The last Pain has been crushed.
Pain operated by receiving
chakra through these sticks.
Once it's taken out,
he shouldn't be able to move anymore.
A cycle of hatred begins.
That is history as we know it.
So we cannot help but believe
that human beings are incapable
of understanding each other.
The world of the ninja
is ruled by hatred.
You're going?
Yeah.
Then this time,
use reinforcements.
No.
I'm going alone!
Lady Hinata!
Everyone...
Thank goodness!
We were so worried.
Are you okay, Lady Hinata?
Thank you, everyone.
Thank you, Sakura.
I'm so relieved.
You overdid yourself this time.
Everyone, Naruto defeated
the sixth Pain.
Way to go Naruto!
How is Naruto? Is he hurt?
He's exhausted, but otherwise okay.
Thank goodness...
Naruto, I'm so glad.
So, where is Naruto?
He's going alone to
where the real Pain is.
Why would he do
something like that?!
Guy-sensei! We must follow!
Yes!
However... Naruto does not
want assistance.
Wh-What?!
No! Naruto's done enough on his own!
He's considerably weakened.
Please lead us to Naruto!
What is it?
It's Naruto...
Naruto!
Guys...
The fact that you're here...
Does it mean that
you've defeated the sixth Pain?
It doesn't matter who won or lost.
What happened?
I can't really put it into words.
What do you mean...
you can't put it into words?
Look, I'm going to see the real Pain.
Please don't follow.
I want to go alone.
I want to talk to the real Pain.
What?! You're talking nonsense!
We're all grateful that
you've defeated Pain.
But it's far too late to
settle things with words!
Then tell me!
If we destroy the real Pain,
and his minions,
and the village and everything else
connected to the enemy,
will that "settle" things?!
What good will talking do?
He is our enemy who
destroyed the Leaf Village!
We cannot forgive him!
I know! I know!
I feel the same way!
How can I forgive
a guy like that
who did this to our village
and its people?!
- Then...
- Inoichi...
Let's do as Naruto says
and let him go alone.
Shikaku...
It is Naruto who stopped Pain.
He has every right to speak to Pain.
Besides, I'm sure he has his reasons.
But...
Just let him go.
Thanks, Mister Shikaku.
Why did you let Naruto
go by himself, Shikaku?
It's my son...
Your son?
Where were you?
Black Ops sent a message for you.
Well... I went to lecture Naruto...
to stop him from acting glum.
It was a pain,
but I couldn't help myself.
He's got something
that we don't have.
"Something"?
Yeah... Someday, he's going to become
a very important ninja to this village.
When I'm with Naruto...
he makes me want to follow him.
Shikamaru, who rarely praises people,
said that to me.
There really must be something
special about Naruto.
I want to believe so.
Let's put our faith in Naruto.
Konan, get back.
But Nagato...
It's all right.
Are you the real Pain?
So, peace has come to me.