Do you hate me?
You're facing the object
of your vendetta...
Do you wish to exact revenge?
A cycle of hatred begins.
I formed the Akatsuki in order
to stop this cycle of hatred.
Nothing in this world will change
even if you kill Pain now
and exact your revenge.
All it will be is self-satisfaction.
If you could not find the answer,
then there is nothing you can do,
but to do the just thing
and sacrifice yourself
for the peace which I am
about to create.
At this close distance,
I can easily control your movements
with my chakra.
Rest assured.
I've avoided hitting your vital spots.
For you are invaluable, Jinchuriki.
What's wrong, Nagato?
He... purposely didn't move.
I came here...
intending to talk to you.
But, I also wanted to
confirm something.
Confirm... something?
I wanted to confirm my feelings.
If I stood before my enemy...
what would I do?
I wasn't sure of myself.
And?
I can't forgive you!
Even now, I want to kill you so badly...
I can't stop shaking!
What? He can resist Nagato's chakra
up close like this?!
I'm glad I made you my student.
Pervy Sage said he believed
that the day would come
when people can truly understand
one another.
I wasn't paying much attention
when he told me that...
Even when he said he'd entrust me
with finding the answer.
I got excited, taking it as a sign
that he acknowledged me
as his student.
Thinking back...
I finally understand what
Pervy Sage meant.
That it's not so simple.
Still, it doesn't change the fact
that you can't forgive me.
Words of forgiveness come easy.
Love does not.
Yeah... You're right about that.
Jiraiya-sensei's words reflect
an idealism from an era long past.
It is far removed from reality.
Didn't you say you would kill me
and bring peace to the ninja world?
Even if you seek vengeance
for your own satisfaction,
if that is your idea of justice,
so be it.
You're not a god.
After witnessing this harsh reality,
do you really still believe
Jiraiya-sensei's silly ramblings?
When I found out you were
Pervy Sage's student,
I wanted to ask you one thing.
What is it?
How could a student of the Pervy Sage
turn out the way you did?
I understand that you're not
like the Akatsuki members
who kill out of sheer enjoyment.
But I don't know a thing
about you guys.
That's why...
I want to hear your stories,
then come up with an answer.
Fine. I will show you our pain.
Nagato! This is a waste of time!
Let's deal with him right now.
Wait, Konan...
I want to hear his answer.
Besides, he won't go down so easily.
He crushed the six Pains
and made it here alone.
Two moments define my greatest pain.
One is the death of my parents.
It was when the Hidden Rain Village
became involved
in the Great Nations' war and
was turned into a battlefield.
Found anything?
Yeah, some canned goods.
Our first meal in four days!
No, three days.
Who cares? Let's eat.
I won't last another minute.
Let's search the other places later.
We might find more stuff.
Now's our chance to
make a run for it.
What if they see us? I'm scared.
Don't worry. Just be very quiet.
Who's there?!
Damn! Enemies?!
Run now!
Nagato, go!
Nagato...
Hurry... Get away...
Run, Nagato!
Run away! Hurry!
Oh no... These people aren't ninja!
What'll we do?!
Why did this happen?!
How could we mistake them
for the enemy?!
Damn it!
W-We didn't know there were still
any civilians in the war zone.
I'm so sorry, kid.
What? What happened?
Dad... Mom?
Goodbye, Mom... Dad...
This is the last that's left.
I'm too hungry to walk.
Thank you... If you didn't wake me up,
I'd probably be dead.
Sorry... Even if you follow me,
I can't feed you.
I don't have a thing to eat.
Excuse me...
Can you spare some food for me?
I...
I haven't eaten in so long.
I'm sorry...
I have nothing to give you.
Times are tough.
We barely have enough for ourselves.
I'm really sorry,
but try somewhere else.
But this was my last stop.
I can't go any further...
Am I going to die here?
Here... Eat this.
Are you sure?
Uh-huh...
Konan, who are those two?
Sorry... They were on the verge of dying.
You even picked up a dog?
Seriously... What's it's name?
Chibi...
You sure have a weird name!
No, I meant the dog.
Wow... So much food...
If you intend to stay here,
I expect you to help find provisions too.
Provisions? How?
- We steal.
- Steal?
But... isn't that a bad thing?
Are you stupid?
We live in hard times when
we have to fend for ourselves.
Pretty words are not enough
to get us by!
Pretty words...
Could you please give us some food?
Just a little will do... please.
I don't have any fish to give out.
Now scram!
You stingy man!
What?! You rotten brat!
Ah! Hey!
You stray dog! Stop!
My goodness! Huh?!
Hey!
Where'd they go?!
Good job, Chibi!
Hey! If you're not going to buy,
go away!
Ow...
Shameless kids!
Next time, you won't get off so easy!
Are you guys okay?
Well, these things happen.
I guess...
Nagato... Do you have a dream?
A dream?
I don't intend to die in a place like this.
I have a huge dream!
World domination!
World domination?
That's right!
If I rise to the top of the world,
I'll never have to go through
this suffering again!
You think so?
Besides, if I were to die now,
I couldn't face Mom and Dad
who brought me into this world.
Right, Konan?
Uh-huh...
If you conquer the world,
you can do whatever you please.
That's just like being a god.
I wonder if you can stop the fighting too.
Are you all right?
Uh-huh...
Damn... What was that?!
Ninja are fighting so close.
It's Hanzo and the Hidden Leaf ninja!
Chibi!
Chibi is...
What'll I do, Yahiko?!
Chibi's not breathing!
Worry about Chibi later!
First, we have to get away from here!
Chibi...
Damn it!
Damn it! Damn it! Damn it!
Why?!
If the fighting doesn't stop...
I'll become the god of this world!
Nagato... Stop your crying!
If all you do is cry after
you get beaten down,
nothing will change!
Just like this nation.
I'm going to change this nation!
And for that, words aren't enough...
You need power!
Power?
We're going to learn ninjutsu!
Ninjutsu? From who?
The Hidden Leaf ninja
who were fighting Hanzo.
I just went to the battle site.
I didn't see their corpses.
They fought with Hanzo,
but they're still alive!
They must be amazingly strong!
But...
I hate Hanzo!
He changed Hidden Rain Village
into a war zone like this.
Anyway, I'm going to become
a student of those strong ninja.
I'm going after them!
What if you go after them and
find out they've been killed?
Then I'll look for whoever killed them.
Goodbye, Chibi.
Teach us ninjutsu.
You're all ninja from
the Hidden Leaf, right?
Thank you. This is for you.
Shall I kill these children?
Wha—?!
I've seen many war orphans.
It's pitiful.
They would be better off if we just
put them out of their misery right now.
Orochimaru, enough!
You go on ahead with Tsunade.
I'll stay here and
look after them for a while.
Huh?!
It is the least I can do.
- Thank you for the food!
Sensei! I'm getting the hang
of fishing!
Oh yeah? You're becoming
more and more promising!
The four of us started living together.
Soon after, a certain incident took place.
Yahiko!
A straggler ninja attacked us
and nearly killed Yahiko.
That is when I struck out and
killed that ninja instead.
As a result, Jiraiya-sensei, who had
been hesitant about training us,
began to teach us ninjutsu.
He said he was teaching us
so we could protect ourselves.
But I think, in my case,
it was so I could control
the power of the Rinnegan.
But I was afraid of my power.
Hate had caused me to go berserk.
I thought what I did was wrong
and was consumed with guilt.
But Sensei pulled me from the depths.
Is it about that incident?
That day...
When that man hurt Yahiko,
I was so mad at him.
Everything went blank in my head.
I didn't know what I was doing.
Before I realized it, the man was dead.
After that, I got so scared.
This hatred made me lose myself...
and I killed someone.
What I did was wrong!
There had to be a better way!
Nagato!
I really don't know if
it was right or wrong.
But thanks to you, Yahiko didn't die.
You protected your friend.
That had to be the right thing to do.
No one can blame you for that.
Before I realized it,
I had already accepted Sensei.
When you are hurt, you learn to hate.
On the other hand, when you hurt someone,
you are resented.
But you start to feel guilty as well.
However, understanding such pain
enables you to be kind to others.
Knowing pain helps us to grow up,
to mature.
And to grow up means
being able to think
and make decisions on their own.
To know and reflect on pain,
and come up with your own answer.
Jiraiya-sensei seemed to be
asking himself the same question.
He hadn't found an answer either.
Just like you haven't.
Back then, I was able to come up
with an answer right away.
I just want to protect those two.
No matter what kind of pain
I have to endure.
I see.
What are you always pondering, Sensei?
There is so much war
in this world.
Only hatred exists.
I want to do something about it.
And to know what the answer
to true peace is.
Three years passed.
I felt that I had grown stronger
physically and mentally through training.
But Jiraiya-sensei's words always
kept coming back to me
from somewhere deep inside.
Sensei had told me that perhaps
the answer rested in my Rinnegan.
Long ago, people constantly fought.
Wars never ended.
It was an age far worse than today.
In such an age, there appeared
a monk who, for the first time,
preached the truth of chakra and
tried to bring peace to the world.
It is said he traveled throughout
the world advocating his teachings,
which he called ninshu.
Time passed and ninshu
became known as ninjutsu.
Ninjutsu isn't about armed power.
It is a teaching that guides
people towards peace.
This monk was known as
the Sage of the Six Paths
and was called the savior of this world.
Like you, he possessed the Rinnegan.
"We are the ones who
create peace and order."
Those are the monk's words.
He must have believed that
the era would come when people
truly understood each other.
Maybe... you are the reincarnation
of that monk.
I have a feeling that those eyes of yours
have been entrusted with the monk's hopes.
Sensei entrusted me with
the quest for peace,
and then left us by ourselves.
Who are you?
I am Madara Uchiha.
Madara?
You're either a criminal or a total
idiot to claim the name Madara Uchiha.
Why'd you approach us?
The Rinnegan...
To guide those who awaken it,
is the mission
our organization has been
entrusted with since ages past.
You know about my eyes?
You are the reincarnation
of the Sage of Six Paths,
who dreamed of world peace
and stability.
Only the villages of large nations
are showered in light.
Leaving your small country's village
in the shadow, dying.
That is why your eye
has awakened here.
Wherever light strikes,
there are always shadows.
So long as there is
a concept of victors...
the vanquished will also similarly exist.
The selfish intent of wanting
to preserve peace initiates wars.
And hatred is born in order
to protect love.
These are all links in a causal
relationship that cannot be separated.
But a world of just victors,
peace and love...
such a world can be created too.
If you allow us to collaborate,
you can learn how.
As soon as you attain
the true power of the Rinnegan...
Your very own world can
be immediately actualized.
Now...
I can't do that.
You're just trying to use us.
Your offer sounds way
too convenient.
One can only reach
the true world
after knowing another's pain
and shedding tears alongside them.
Shedding tears alongside them, huh?
You mean in revenge?
No, that's not what I meant.
I meant in mutual understanding.
Stop talking so idealistically.
No such thing exists
in this world.
Let's go, Konan... Nagato.
We can't trust these guys!
Don't you dare approach us again!
I'll wait here at
the same time every day.
You'll eventually realize it too.
Who the hell are you?!
The guardians of this village.
This is a warning.
Leave this village now!
The hell with them...
Let's kill 'em!
Water Style: Raging Waves!
Wind Style: Gale Palm!
Damn! We can't get near them!
Die!
Take one step and I'll skewer you!
We won't let you take
a single step into this village!
Give up now!
Is it because of the rain?!
Now's my chance!
Sorry! Are you okay?
Damn it! There's no end to this!
I didn't want to use this, but...
Do you belong to Hanzo's gang?!
We're wearing his headband,
but we're not his subordinates.
But some day,
we want to bring peace to
the world just like Hanzo.
In other words,
you're just his copycats.
We're not copycats!
We will keep peace
in this village!
Not through violence,
but through negotiations!
Are you crazy?
This village lies between
two great nations!
As long as they're at war with
each other, the fighting won't end!
The strong will take everything
from the weak!
That's how the world is!
We're fighting to change
that way of thinking!
Each one of you must
secretly wish for peace!
Listen. One piece of straw is weak...
But when you put three together,
it becomes much...
Damn it!
I'm just trying to say,
the more you have,
the stronger it is!
Yahiko...
You're so bad at
making speeches...
Whatever!
Look, we're not going to kill you.
Just get out of here!
I won't guarantee that
we won't attack again!
Fine. We'll do these dozens
of times until you give up...
A hundred times, even.
But just remember,
it'll be more painful the next time!
Retreat!
Earlier, when you tried to attack me,
you protected the kid.
Thank you.
We're war orphans too.
You're such funny kids...
You appear out of nowhere
and ask to protect this village.
It's to change this land.
War will never leave this land.
Nothing will change.
Yahiko...
Seems like things are changing,
little by little.
We're ninja who left the village
because we didn't think
much of Hanzo's ways.
But we were getting sick
of this lifestyle too.
I looked into your eyes
and began to feel like
starting over again...
But I don't feel like
going back to Hanzo.
So take us in as your lackeys!
No!
What?! But earlier, you...!
Not as lackeys, but as comrades.
I'm Yahiko.
This is Nagato and Konan.
I'm Kyusuke the Swift.
If you need to gather intel,
you can leave it to these fast legs.
Then go and find me other villages
that are suffering like this one.
Yahiko...
What?
You should name our group.
There are more of us now.
It's going to be necessary soon.
A name...
How about... the Akatsuki.
This nation weeps from
the sufferings of war.
So we will change this nation...
no, this world,
and welcome a new dawn!
Akatsuki...
That's a great name.
Akatsuki! It's decided!
– Yeah!
Are you the Akatsuki?
Who's that?
The chief of the Hidden Rain,
Hanzo of the Salamander...
Who's the leader?
It's Yahiko!
Yahiko of the Akatsuki!
I shall remember you.
Yahiko?
What does that mean?
Hanzo just acknowledged us.
Our organization is getting larger.
We need to move our hideout.
It's our last day here.
Yes.
This place changed us.
We became strong.
Everything began right here.
We are leaving this place in order
to make our dreams come true!
And...
Where did they go?
To think the secret room would come
in handy at the very last moment.
What a way to set out...
But I guess,
it's appropriate for this country.
Let's go, Nagato! Konan!
It's like...
the Akatsuki suddenly grew.
They all bought into your dream.
Actually, they're all tired of war.
If everyone unites,
I know we can have peace.
Say, where's Konan?
She went out a while ago.
Why?
I dunno...
This is...
Konan's...
"Dear Konan..."
"From the first moment I saw you..."
Is this...?!
It's a love letter.
"I've wanted to ask you
how you feel about me."
"I'll be waiting anxiously
on the back terrace... Kyusuke."
Don't tell me...
Konan's gone over there?!
I dunno...
Yahiko, didn't you have
something to do?
Huh?!
Oh yeah, yeah! I forgot.
I need to go to the john!
I'm going to wet myself!
That guy!
Running's not the only thing
he's fast at!
More friends also mean...
more competition in love!
No kidding...
Hey, Nagato!
Do you like Konan, Yahiko?
Stupid! It's nothing like that!
I think Konan likes you.
Huh?!
Oh, she's coming back.
I know you're there...
Yahiko, Nagato.
Konan...
What did you tell him?
I told him that I don't have time
for a relationship
until we make
the Akatsuki's dream come true.
Isn't that right?
Konan...
Yahiko!
Can you help me out with
some training?
That jutsu... doesn't work...
in the rain!
Oiled paper...
Great idea.
I experimented.
If you hesitate,
I'll leave you behind!
Like I'd let you!
Brother, we have a lot of requests.
I don't know if I can fulfill them all.
We'll do them all.
If there are people in need,
we'll save all of them.
That's the purpose of the Akatsuki.
At this rate, we might become
an organization as big as Hanzo's.
Hanzo is setting an example
for us shinobi
by fighting to bring peace to this world.
We will prove that the Akatsuki
can surpass him one day!
Konan, where's Yahiko?
He went to look for food.
Oh...
What's the matter?
I'm scared... of my power.
Nagato...
Before, I had Jiraiya-sensei.
I'm positive he taught me ninjutsu
so that I could control this power.
But Jiraiya-sensei is no longer here...
Yes, Jiraiya-sensei is gone...
But...
You have us.
We'll control your power.
For as long as it takes...
Konan...
Be careful, Yahiko.
You don't need to see me off!
See to Nagato's wound, will you?
From now on,
save your worrying for him.
Nagato is the keystone of the Akatsuki!
He's the one who will change
this nation... this world.
The same can be said of you...
Everyone respects and admires you.
Nagato is no different.
Nagato is going to be
the bridge to peace.
My role is to be the pillar
that supports that bridge.
Yahiko...
This nation continues to weep.
It continues to endure pain.
I used to hate this land that
cries all the time.
But now, I want to save it.
It's what I want with all my heart.
It reminds me of the crybaby
that I used to be and I can't ignore it.
Yahiko!
Be careful.
He is the bridge to peace...
His will itself is the bridge.
Nagato...
We believe in Yahiko!
Let's go, everyone!
Right!
Everyone is growing weary
of fighting.
Yes...
Even if we win,
the Akatsuki doesn't receive
any rewards...
The only things we have
are our ideals.
In time, pent-up weariness
will erase that ideal.
Are you saying that everyone will
soon forget what they're fighting for?
Nagato...
Will you become the leader
of the Akatsuki?
Huh?
I'm not... cut out to be a leader.
Yahiko...
But you're different.
You have the mark of a hero...
A special symbol known
as the Rinnegan...
that will become
everyone's new ideal.
Yahiko!
Are you going to take advantage
of my Rinnegan?
I'm scared of myself.
I've suffered so long because
of these eyes.
I know...
But you have someone who can
keep that power in check for you.
Konan will always be at your side.
Yahiko...
Hey, Brother! Big news!
What's going on?
A messenger from Hanzo is here.
Are you Yahiko,
the leader of the Akatsuki?
Yes, I am.
I am Kanzo, a trusted subordinate
of Hanzo the Salamander.
I've heard many rumors
about you Akatsuki...
How you seek peace without
relying on military weapons.
That is the Akatsuki's founding principle.
Hanzo asked me to deliver
a confidential letter to you.
Please...
Is he serious?
He would like to
meet you personally.
Hanzo has given the Akatsuki
his seal of approval.
In time...
Hanzo will leave you to lead
the peace negotiations
between the three nations
that surround the Hidden Rain.
Handle the negotiations
between the three nations...?
That's amazing, Brother!
Please relay to Lord Hanzo
that I accept.
That means we can help people
out in the open!
So many gave their lives
for us to get to this point.
Finally, we'll be able to
face them with pride.
Yahiko, your determination to free others
from pain reached Hanzo.
Look...
The Akatsuki's ideals
have been restored.
There was never a need
for a symbol.
We'll all follow your dream,
no matter where that leads us.
Nagato...
We weren't wrong!
Nagato and I will go to
the meeting tomorrow with Lord Hanzo.
Are you sure, Brother?
We'll all go with you...
No, that's not necessary.
Lord Hanzo will be shocked if
too many of us show up.
I know, but...
By the way, where's Konan?
She went to patrol
the Seventh Ward.
She won't be back until
tomorrow morning.
I see... On such a special day too.
Anyway... Today, the Akatsuki took
a giant step forward!
Everyone! Set aside your duties
for today and celebrate!
Who could have...?
This is...!
We finally made it up to this point.
Nagato.
You're—!
Reality is moving ahead quickly.
Cut your ties with Yahiko immediately
and join me.
Otherwise, you will all...
We will what?
What Yahiko speaks of
are just ideals.
He tries to understand others' pain...
but they do not even attempt
to know our pain.
Furthermore, this world has
no desire for that either.
That is reality.
You possess the Rinnegan,
so you should understand.
No matter what you say,
I believe in Yahiko's ideals!
I guess without pain...
you cannot experience reality.
In that respect, even though
you possess the Rinnegan,
you still think like
an average person.
Very well...
Go see reality for yourself,
and experience pain.
There you are, Nagato.
Yahiko...
Was someone just here?
No...
Let's get going.
Or we'll be late for the meeting
with Lord Hanzo.
Right, let's go!
Yahiko...
You are the leader,
so you must die.
If you resist, this woman will die.
You! The red-haired one.
Use that to kill Yahiko.
Then I will spare you and the woman.
Don't, Nagato!
Never mind me!
Both of you escape!
Nagato.
Kill me.
Nagato!
No!
Hurry it up.
Or do you want this woman to die?!
Konan...
Yahi—!
You and Konan must survive...
no matter what it takes.
You are... the savior... of this world.
I know...
you can... do it.
Yahiko!
I have a huge dream!
Kill them!
If the fighting doesn't stop...
I'll become the god of this world!
He repelled it!
How?!
Did we get him?
Nagato...
Konan, hold onto Yahiko and stay still.
Not bad, kid!
You escaped even while being hit
by my Fire Style Jutsu!
You're no ordinary kid.
Those eyes...
Get him!
Summoning:
Gedo Statue!
This is...
What... is that?!
We're dead if that touches us!
So you were the leader behind the scenes.
It's quite a surprise that
you possess the Rinnegan.
Nagato...
Body Flicker Jutsu!
Yahiko died...
And from then on, I took over
as the leader of our organization.
Didn't I say so?
Yeah, I finally understand.
The selfish desire to
preserve peace causes war.
Hatred is born from wanting
to protect love.
There's no such thing as peace
in this accursed world.
Exactly.
You will always be the leader
of the Akatsuki...
Yahiko.
Who could bring me to this point?
Have you forgotten my face?
You are...
Yahiko of Akatsuki!
You are supposed to be dead.
What's going on?!
You teamed up with Danzo
and betrayed us.
You now only think
of self-preservation.
You're trash.
I once respected you.
But, you have changed.
Just who are you?!
How can you be so strong?!
And you don't even understand
why you will lose.
Vanish, Hanzo!
S-Stop...
Since that day, countless comrades
fought and died.
One by one...
One after another...
They continued to die.
The peace-addled citizens
of the Land of Fire...
The meager payments they make to
the Hidden Leaf become war funds.
The Land of Fire is fully aware
of having taken part in war,
yet they falsely proclaim peace.
The peace you great nations enjoy
only exists precariously
atop the sacrifices of
us small nations.
To us, your peace means violence.
Just by living, people hurt others
without even realizing it.
So long as humanity exists,
hate will also exist.
True peace cannot exist in
this cursed world.
Everything Jiraiya-sensei said
is wishful thinking!
I have told you my story.
Now let me hear your answer.
But I have faith that
there will come a time
when people can truly understand
one another.
You may be right.
I also think the same way.
I see...
I get where you're coming
from now.
But I still...
can't forgive you.
I still hate you.
Then you want to settle this?
But...
Pervy Sage believed in me,
and entrusted his dream to me.
So I'm going to believe...
in what Pervy Sage believed in!
That's my answer.
So... I won't kill you guys.
You'll believe in what
Jiraiya-sensei believed?
I see.
So that's your answer?
And do you expect us to wait...
until you make this world
a peaceful place?
Don't play with me!
It's far too late for me to
believe Jiraiya's words!
There's no such thing as true peace!
As long as we live in
this cursed world
peace is impossible!
Then...
Then... I'll break that curse.
If there is such a thing as peace,
I'll seize it!
I'll never give up!
You...
Those... words...
That's right.
They're taken straight from this book.
The first novel written
by Pervy Sage.
Pervy Sage was seriously trying
to change the world with this.
At the end of this book,
he wrote about a student
who inspired him...
It was you, Nagato.
No...
Sensei...
What's the matter?
Is this a good time?
Sure... I was trying to
start on my book,
but I can't come up with any ideas.
I figured I'd take a break
and get a bite to eat.
So? What's going on?
About what you once said to me
about the hatred in this world...
I've been thinking about it.
Oh yeah? Have you figured
anything out?
Peace...
I don't know how to
achieve peace yet.
But...
Some day, I'll break this curse.
If there is such a thing as peace,
I'll seize it!
There's something more important
than the method.
It's the power to believe in it!
I see... That's an excellent thought.
You may very well be correct.
What is it?
Thanks to you, I think I'll be able
to write a fine novel!
Now then...
First, I've got to come up with
a name for the hero.
Nagato...
You three have grown up.
Don't you agree?
Thank you, Sensei.
Come on, stop crying Yahiko.
I'm sure we'll see him again someday.
Sensei...
Why don't you give it up?
This game of tag is getting boring.
A smoke bomb?
Give it up.
Can I say one thing?
I don't care to listen!
Die already!
Give up...
on me giving up!
Even if you bring me down,
another assassin will attack
the village.
As long as we are cursed to
live in the ninja world,
there will be no peace.
Then...
I'll break that curse!
If there is such a thing as peace,
I'll seize it!
I'll never give up!
Wh-Who are you?
My name is...
Naruto!
My name is a precious gift
from Pervy Sage!
I cannot just give up and stain
my master's keepsake!
I will be the Hokage!
And I will bring peace to
the Hidden Rain!
Please believe in me!
How?
How can you say that
you will never change?
That you will not change no
matter how great the pain you face.
Can you continue believing
in yourself?
Can you guarantee it?
Can you have such faith
in yourself?
I've experienced pain too...
And there's a lot of pain nesting
inside of me as well.
There's no telling what kind of pain
will come after me.
If I stop believing because of that...
If the hero should change
it'll turn into another story.
It'll turn into a different story from
the one my master left behind.
Then it won't be Naruto!
I can't write novels like my master did.
That's why... the sequel has to come
from the life I live.
No matter how great the pain,
I'll continue walking.
Because that's who Naruto is!
If the hero changes,
it'll turn into a different story.
You and I are sibling disciples.
As students of the same master, we
ought to be able to understand one another.
That is what I said to you earlier.
I meant it as a joke.
You are a curious fellow.
You remind me of how I once was.
Nagato...
I wasn't able to believe in Jiraiya.
Nor... could I believe in myself.
However...
I have a feeling that, unlike me,
you will walk towards a different future.
I think I shall believe in you...
Naruto Uzumaki.
Gedo Art of Rinne Rebirth.
Nagato don't!
Konan... It's okay.
I am making a new decision.
A decision I had once given up on.
What is it?
What kind of jutsu is that?
Those who possess the Rinnegan
are able to use
the jutsu of all six Pains,
and are said to exist outside
the realm of life and death.
Nagato's ocular power is the jutsu
that controls life and death.
He is the seventh Pain.
Gedo...
If he performs the jutsu at
his current chakra level...
Nagato will not survive.
He is willing to go that far
for this child...
This mysterious child has
changed Nagato.
Who would have thought that
both you and I would die so young?
Although not as early as your mother.
Father, I've always wanted
to ask you something.
Why did someone like you, who was
known as the White Fang of the Leaf
choose to ignore the village code
and abandon a crucial mission
in order to save his comrades?
If you had not done so,
no one would have condemned you and
you wouldn't have become so miserable.
I felt so bitter.
I see...
You took it pretty hard, didn't you?
Yeah.
But you know, Father...
Whatever the outcome,
I know you did your best.
I can see that now
and I understand you.
You broke the code to save everyone.
And I'm proud of you for it.
Thank you.
What is that?!
What is that light?!
Ma? Where am I?
- Whoa!
- What's going on, Guy-sensei?
I see!
Lord Fukasaku was definitely dead!
And yet...
What just happened?!
I-Impossible!
How can such a thing occur?!
What's going on?
Iruka-sensei!
- You're alive!
- You too, Sensei!
Ebisu-sensei, are you hurt?
This is nothing.
Konohamaru saved me.
But never mind my injury.
What is this phenomenon?
Yes...
What? What just happened?!
The villagers are coming back to life,
one after another.
What?! You mean...
I'll stay here and
look after them for a while.
Just until they can take
better care of themselves.
It's the least I can do.
I'm still in time to revive those I've
killed since arriving in the Leaf Village.
It's the least
I can do for them.
What's this?
Seems it was too soon for you
to come here.
There must be something
you're still meant to do.
Father...
I'm glad we got to talk.
Thank you for forgiving me.
Now I can move on in peace.
I'll finally be able to see your mother.
- Pa!
- Yes.
Kakashi too, eh?
What's going on?
Thank goodness!
I'm so glad, Kakashi-sensei!
I will explain everything.
You...
War inflicts death, injury,
and pain to both sides.
The death of someone dear
is hard to accept.
We convince ourselves
there's no way they could die.
It especially can't be helped
with your generation.
You don't know war.
You may try to find meaning in death,
but there is only pain.
An unbearable hatred...
Senseless deaths...
Eternal hatred...
And pain that does not heal.
That's what war is.
Naruto... This is what you
will be facing in time.
Regarding that book, and you...
It feels like someone set it up.
Or... Perhaps this is
the real work of a god.
It seems my work ends here, Naruto.
I believe you can bring true peace.
You're taking this one with you too?
Yes... Tendo Pain was created
from Yahiko's body.
He is very precious to us.
So he was... Yahiko.
So what are you going to do?
I hate to think that
you're returning to the Akatsuki.
I'm leaving the Akatsuki.
Yahiko and Nagato meant
everything to me.
Yahiko's dream...
And Nagato's dream...
If both of their dreams have been
passed on to you,
then you now embody their dreams.
Nagato put his faith in you.
So will I.
We, the Hidden Rain,
will pursue their dreams with you.
The name Naruto, the guts
to never give up, and pain.
That's what I inherited from my teacher
and sibling disciple!
This time...
I pray that you will be the blossom of hope
that never wilts.
Just you watch, Master!
Good job.
Kakashi-sensei...
Just lean on me.
He's gotten heavy.
Hmm?
Welcome back!
We knew you could do it!
They've all been awaiting your return.
My dream is to surpass the Hokage!
And make everyone in
the village acknowledge me!
Naruto... You did well.
Welcome back!
Naruto!
Wh-What's going on?
I relayed every detail of
the events that occurred.
Hey! What was the enemy like?
Are you hurt?
Oww! Don't push!
I'm so glad, Naruto.
Hey! Cut it out!
Sakura...
You're so reckless, you idiot!
Thank you.
Way to go, Naruto.
Yes! That's what youth is!
I can't believe
he pulled it off all by himself.
Uh-huh...
I could almost fall for him.
- Huh?!
Ain't he something, that Naruto?
That's my classmate!
He really outclassed us.
Shut up.
We'll make it up starting now!
Let's join them, Iruka-sensei!
No, I'm fine right here.
- But...
- Now, now...
Naruto is amazing, isn't he?
At first, everyone thought he was
such a nuisance, including myself.
We feared his destiny,
so we kept him at arm's length
and didn't bother with him.
That fox kid shouldn't
become a ninja!
What is the Third Hokage thinking?!
That Team Kakashi...
I heard they defeated
the terrorist Zabuza!
Sounds like the Nine-Tails kid
had a part in it...
No way...
I heard he was a loser.
I bet it was Kakashi's doing.
I hear that Nine-Tails kid made it
to the Finals of the Chunin Exam.
Are you serious?!
He's more skilled than I thought.
Humph! I just hope the fox demon
doesn't go on a rampage.
Oh!
That fox kid?
I can't believe he won against a Hyuga.
That was an awesome match!
I never expected such
a battle from the fox kid.
He's quite a boy.
However, he never ever gave up.
And he stayed true to his Ninja Way.
And slowly, but surely
we couldn't help but acknowledge him.
D-Da...
Damn it!
I heard he protected the village from
the Sand Jinchuriki!
Who did?
Naruto Uzumaki.
You know, the one...
I'm so glad the Fifth Hokage
has been decided!
We can breathe a little easier now.
Thanks to Lord Jiraiya and Naruto!
Is it true they fought Orochimaru?
I heard they couldn't bring
Sasuke Uchiha back.
I hope Naruto isn't too depressed.
A group named the Akatsuki
is after the Jinchuriki.
Which means Naruto will
also be targeted.
Will he be okay?
Lord Jiraiya will look out
for Naruto.
I heard that Naruto rescued
the Sand's Kazekage from the Akatsuki!
Wouldn't it be great if this results
in an alliance between the Leaf and Sand?
The Akatsuki has killed Lord Jiraiya!
Is Naruto all right?!
Naruto has
Lord Jiraiya's determination!
He hasn't lost heart!
He'll keep on going, like always!
Today, everyone trusts Naruto implicitly.
They worry about him, have high hopes
for him and pray for him.
He truly changed the hearts
of many people.
It's because he did his best.
Iruka...
Yes, Lord Hokage?
I agree with you to a point,
but he is just like you.
He never knew parental love
and because of that incident,
people avoided him.
So in order to get attention,
he resorted to mischief.
In whatever shape or form,
he desperately wanted to validate
his existence and his worth.
The Fourth Hokage wanted the villagers
to regard Naruto as a hero.
He placed the seal and
died hoping for that.
Third Hokage... Fourth Hokage...
There is a hero right before our eyes.
Where's Suigetsu?
Suigetsu? Who knows?
He went out two or three days ago
and hasn't come back.
I don't mind if he never comes back.
I can hear you!
The Executioner's Blade...
You still have that?
You left it behind! It was a pain
to go back and retrieve it.
Why should I carry your things
while fighting the Eight-Tails?!
I carried the two of you out of there
when you were dying.
So quit fighting.
Don't act so high and mighty!
Fine. Whatever the case, I got it back.
I don't feel right without this.
We're all here.
We're moving out. Get ready.
Huh? Are your wounds all right?
Yeah.
We're going to the Leaf Village.