I'm just going out for a delivery.
Whoa! Outta the way!
Sorry, mister!
Hey, Naruto!
No, I mean...
Konohamaru!
Hey... Could that be...?
Yeah... No doubt about it.
Hey. Sakura!
Oh, Konohamaru!
Where are you off to?
The main village gate.
I have to pick up the morning gate log
for Lady Tsunade.
You want to come?
It's been about two and a half years.
Yeah, it has...
And then that cat, Tora, suddenly
starts scratching me like crazy!
We had missions like that, too.
It kind of takes me back.
Come to think of it,
have you heard anything
from Naruto?!
Nothing... yet.
I see...
He should be coming back soon, though...
Hello, Izumo, Kotetsu.
Oh, look who's here...
Why don't you head on into town?
You'll see something interesting.
Something interesting...?
Don't tell me!
He's having a ball...
This takes me back!
The village hasn't changed a bit!
Everyone! Naruto Uzumaki's back!
It's all so nostalgic...!
Yup! Yup!
They added Grandma Tsunade
to the Hokage Rock!
Naruto? Is that you, Naruto?
When did you get back, Naruto?!
Just now!
Long time no see, Sakura!
You've gotten taller than me,
haven't you?
Huh...?
Oh! You're right.
He kind of... got
taller since I saw him last...
So? Do you think I seem
a little more feminine?
You're fine!
You haven't changed a bit.
You just don't understand
the heart of a woman...
Naruto!
Sexy Jutsu!
Ohh!
Wha--?!
How about that?!
Check out these curves, right?!
Konohamaru...
I'm not a kid anymore.
And you shouldn't be using jutsu
like that anymore, either.
That's right. It isn't just
your appearance that's matured...
I kind of feel a bit lonesome,
but you've turned out quite admirable,
haven't you, Naruto?
That's such a boring jutsu!
Check out my new and improved Sexy Jutsu!
Right...
The new and improved Sexy Jutsu...
Here we go!
Hey, you idiot!
You haven't changed at all,
have you, you jerk?!
After not seeing you for two and a half years!
You pull this stunt less than two minutes
after we meet!
- That short temper and incredible strength.
- So much for feeling sentimental!
- She's a second-generation Tsunade.
- Huh? Honestly, I'm mad at myself!
It's been a long time, you two.
I'm sure your training produced
good results, right?
Do you think we came back
without making progress?
It went perfectly!
Then show me those
results immediately.
Show you...?
You two will be facing a certain man.
I didn't send him on any missions
for the past several days
and had him on standby for this very purpose.
Hello.
Shikamaru! Temari!
Look who's here!
Naruto.
Hey! That is you isn't it, Naruto!
Shikamaru!
This is... that little shrimp...?
So you're back?
Yeah, I got back this morning.
You don't look as dumb as you used to.
I mean, hey, have you changed?
No, he hasn't.
Oh... I thought so.
Sakura.
Then, does this mean
you're my opponent, Shikamaru?
Opponent? What do you mean?
I just came to deliver
some documents.
Huh? So you're not my opponent?
Then...?
Who are you again?
You don't remember me?
Naruto, that's not your opponent.
He's out there.
You sure got tall... Naruto.
Yo!
Kakashi-sensei!
Sensei, you haven't changed one bit!
Listen, listen...
I've got a present for you, Sensei.
What?!
You got me... Th-This is...
This is the first new book in the
Make-Out series in three years!
I think it's totally boring,
but you like this stuff,
don't you, Sensei?!
That idiot... No way could
a kid understand the appeal.
And on top of that,
it's a very rare item that hasn't
even been released yet...
All right! That's enough fun
for now, Kakashi.
Don't tell me...
Are you my opponent...?
Hmm, not quite...
Naruto... and Sakura,
the both of you!
Kakashi-sensei's our opponent...
I want to see what you
can do against Kakashi...
Your future duties will be determined
by the results.
Future duties...?
Sakura, show me that
you weren't just wasting
your time training under me.
Yes, ma'am!
Then, shall we get right to it?
That's what I'd like to say.
But since you just got back, Naruto,
you must be tired.
I'll give you a short rest.
I'm not particularly tired
or anything!
Let's meet up at
the Third Training Grounds later.
See ya.
Why's he in such a hurry?
I have a pretty good idea...
He's going to read his book.
Oh!
With that look he had,
there's no doubt about it.
That's the obvious reaction
after getting an unreleased copy
of one of my books.
Oh man, I thought you'd be
a little impressed.
Well, my training involved
way more awesome jutsu.
Just as I anticipated from you!
It's all going according to plan!
Plan?
What happened here?!
As you can see, I cleaned
your house until it sparkled.
Konohamaru,
you're such a great guy!
Yup! And I don't even
expect you to teach me
a new jutsu in return either!
I have absolutely
no ulterior motives!
You are so obvious.
All right then. I'm going to
teach you an amazing jutsu.
All right!
First, let me put my things away.
Isn't that the outfit
you used to wear?
Yeah, it doesn't fit anymore.
But I just can't part with it...
What I'm going to teach you
isn't your run-of-the-mill jutsu.
Just what kind of pervy ninjutsu
is it going to be?
Just hurry up and show me!
The first step is rotation.
Whoa! We're going to
add motion, eh?!
Next up is power.
Attack with the risqué, eh?!
And then finally, there's...
There's more!
Containment!
The most points go to
the best-expressed final pose, eh?!
What are you talking about?
I mean,
it's a pervy ninjutsu, right?
It's more awesome than that.
The jutsu I'm about to teach you is A-rank
in its degree of difficulty to master.
An ultimate ninjutsu that hones
chakra rotation,
power and contained...
It's called the Rasengan!
Awesome!
But I don't understand
what's going on at all!
Don't worry about that,
because I'm going to teach you.
Besides, you can do this jutsu
even if you're stupid!
No kidding!
Huh? Stupid?
This training consists
of three steps, total.
First step, the water balloon.
A water balloon?
You have to GAAAH it,
then BAM it, to burst it!
Wow!
So... How did you do that?!
I just explained it.
You have to GAAAH it,
then BAM it, to burst it!
I said...
You have to GAAAH it, then BAM it!
Simple, right?!
Okay, do your best, Konohamaru.
What? That's it?
You're already leaving?!
I have to train with Sakura now.
But!
Don't be a baby, Konohamaru.
In anything you do, you've got to
learn by doing and feeling.
Besides... I have absolute faith...
that you can do it!
Naruto...
All right...
I'm going to do it!
I'm going to surprise you
the next time you see me!
Is Kakashi-sensei
going to make us wait forever?!
Well, he's always been like this.
Honestly... It'd be nice if he'd show
a little improvement.
Oh, sorry about that.
As it happens, I ran into an old woman
in trouble on my way here and...
- Okay! That's a lie!
This place...
kind of takes me back.
Oh, come to think of it,
this was your first Training Ground,
wasn't it?
Team 7...
The three-man cell...?
We had Sasuke with us...
back then, didn't we?
Sasuke's name is
off limits for these guys...
Well... Let's see how much
you've grown.
You haven't given up
on Sasuke, have you?
Absolutely not!
That's why I continued my training!
The rules are the same
as when we first met.
I don't care how you do it.
Just take a bell away from me.
- If you don't...
- "come at me with the intent to kill,"
"we won't be able to get the bells", right?
Exactly.
If you don't come at me with the intent to
kill, you won't be able to get the bells.
You have until sunrise tomorrow.
Now then, shall we begin?
You're not going to do it
while reading your book
this time around, Kakashi-sensei?
Or have you already
finished reading?
Nope... I thought I'd save
the fun for later...
Besides...
Well, I kind of get the feeling...
I may have to...
get a bit serious this time around.
Let's go!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Transform!
His timing for using
the Shadow Clone Jutsu has gotten better.
You've grown, haven't you, Naruto?
However...
Well, it seems you're just
as impatient as ever.
I haven't even said start yet,
have I?
Don't be so hasty.
I haven't even said start yet, have I?
Now then, let's begin.
Ready... start!
Damn it!
I've been had!
Come on, Naruto, you goof!
Right? Above? Left?
Behind?
If he's in none of those places...
He must be below!
Huh?
Wh-What ridiculous strength.
Fifth Hokage...
You didn't just teach Sakura
medical ninjutsu, huh?
Kakashi-sensei.
Huh?
I found you.
I'd... I'd better stop acting like
an idiot in front of Sakura.
I'll get killed...!
She built up her maximum
chakra inside her body at once
and instantly concentrated
all of it into her fist.
That's a feat that can't be done
without considerable chakra control.
Medical ninjutsu along
with superhuman strength...
No. It's more than that.
Sakura's originally a genjutsu-type,
after all.
She might just become
a better kunoichi than the Fifth Hokage.
All right, now I guess
it's my turn, huh?
This is totally different from
back then.
You're wide open!
If I can hit him once...
It won't mean a thing
if you don't hit me.
Phew, that was a close one.
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Here I come!
All right, bring it on.
The bell's mine.
You won't get away!
Dancing Leaf Shadow...?!
Now... where's the real one?
Right here.
Secret Finger Jutsu:
A Thousand Years of Death!
Damn it. I missed!
That was a close one...
In a different sense.
It used to be so easy.
Over there?!
This one is?!
A transformation of one
of Naruto's Shadow Clones, huh?!
I'm finished if it even grazes me...
The speed of his seal forming...
It's way too fast!
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
Where's Kakashi-sensei?
Earth Style: Headhunter Jutsu!
A Shadow Clone, huh?!
Water Style: Water Dragon Missile!
What?!
I always knew, but...
The Sharingan is really
something else, isn't it?
Yeah...
But even more than that,
the speed of his seal formation...
It's so fast it's tough for us
to even get near him...
For the time being, we won't
have a prayer of getting the bells
unless we can do something
about both his hands.
Yeah. That Kakashi-sensei's
incredibly strong for sure.
He's smarter than Shikamaru.
He has a better sense of smell
than Kiba.
His Sharingan is better
than Sasuke's.
His taijutsu is better than
Bushy Brow's.
And he's got way more...
experience than us...
But even Kakashi-sensei must
have a weakness!
If we think hard about it...
Hmm. A weakness, huh...?
Oh! He does...
have a weakness?!
What?!
You should be able to figure it out if
you look back on his actions up until now.
Quit stalling already...
What's his weakness, Naruto?
Well, you see...
I get it!
I never thought he'd have
a weakness like that.
See?! It's clear if you think back
on his actions up until now, right?
Right, right.
In addition to occupying
both his hands,
we might be able to seal off
his Sharingan if things go well.
And then if we seize the opportunity...
Naruto...
Sure enough, you're the number one
unpredictable ninja!
Still, I was so pleased with
how much they've grown
that I ended up getting
kind of carried away...
I guess this time I'll wait and see
what kind of move they'll make.
Now that that's settled,
the first strike will decide this!
We'll make the first move!
Right! Let's go!
They're here.
You're underestimating me.
To think you'd attack me
head-on like that.
Now, Naruto!
Here we go, Kakashi-sensei!
At the end of "Make-Out Tactics...!"
Wh-What?!
As it happens, the main character...!
He's giving away the ending!
N-No!
Oh, no! I still understand
what he's saying.
I can read his lips with my Sharingan.
Oh!
A ninja must see underneath the underneath.
Right, Sensei?!
You got me...
I should've just gone ahead
and finished the book...
But how can you even
read such a boring book?!
Huh?
The Pervy Sage loaned it to me,
but it was so boring
I didn't even make it ten pages.
So of course, I don't know
how the book ends.
Even without Naruto knowing
the ending of the book...
we figured you'd respond
if we mentioned the name,
"Make-Out Tactics."
Pretty good strategy, huh?
You two certainly showed me
some growth.
Master!
Kakashi, do you have
something to say?
Well, they did a great job
taking the bells away from me, so...
Yes.
What are you talking about?
We're talking about
your status for the future.
Our status...?
- Naruto Uzumaki!
- Huh?
Answer me.
Y-Yeah!
Sakura Haruno!
Yes!
The two of you and...
Kakashi Hatake...
The three of you shall
form Team Kakashi!
Team Kakashi...
W-Wait, what does that mean?
The two of you will form a team with
me and we'll carry out missions together.
That's what this means.
It's not like the old days.
We're no longer teacher and students.
We'll work together as fellow Leaf shinobi.
Got it?
Sure! I got it!
Gee, you guys sure got strong.
I never thought you'd really
be able to get the bells...
I just might've surpassed you,
Kakashi-sensei.
Don't get so cocky!
Well, but I'm still pretty young,
you see...
The other day, I developed
an incredible new jutsu...
And it's pretty incredible, you see...
Oh, that's right.
I haven't had any Ichiraku ramen
since I got back!
Oh, I'm also pretty hungry
from all that training exercise
since yesterday.
All right! Let's make a beeline
for Ichiraku Ramen!
Right!
They used to be so cute
and react to everything back in the day...
As promised,
I leave Naruto in your care.
It's my first Ichiraku ramen in ages!
It'll be Kakashi-sensei's treat!
- Treat! Treat!
The actions of the Akatsuki
are gaining momentum...
I'm heading off to gather information.
See you around.
Kakashi-sensei!
Huh?
It's been settled that you're
going to treat us to some ramen!
Hurry up!
Sorry, guys!
I have to go file the formation papers
for our new team!
See you.
I'm off.
Oh! He ran away!
He said something about a unit list...
but he's probably just wondering
what happens next in... his book...
That means...
Then how about we go
on a date, just the two of us?
That's fine. But you're treating.
Oh...
You could at least pay
for half of the ramen...
No way!
Yeah. Ichiraku hasn't changed a bit!
Mm... This aroma...
It's whetting my appetite.
All right!
Hiya!
Welcome!
Old man... Do you remember me?
Naruto...
It's you, isn't it, Naruto?!
No way could I forget you!
Long time no see!
Huh? Naruto?
You sure got big!
Long time no see, miss!
What'll you have?
You're hungry, right?
Yeah, I'm starved!
All right then, today it's on me.
Order whatever you like!
All right!
No...
It's on me today.
I knew you'd be here, Naruto!
Iruka-sensei!
Sakura isn't with you?
If I'd known you were going to treat,
I'd have brought Sakura, too...
Here's an extra-large special serving
of our ramen!
It's the real-deal Ichiraku ramen...
I dreamed about this ramen
so many times during my training...
Now, eat up before it gets cold!
Right.
Thank you!
- Naruto...
- Huh?
You've sure grown
a lot compared to the time
when you wanted this...
Have I?! Have I?!
Do you think so?
This headband you gave me,
it looks perfect on me now, doesn't it?
Don't be getting carried away!
You've still got a long way to go.
You've still got to do better and better!
You've gotten so big...
Man, this is good!
Sure enough, Ichiraku Ramen
is the greatest!
Isn't it, though?
I... thought the next time Iruka-sensei
would treat me to ramen
would be after I'd become a Chunin...
Naruto...
You don't need to worry about
whether you're a Genin or a Chunin.
After all, Master Jiraiya
trained you personally...
I know, but...
But listen, that Pervy Sage
is really merciless!
The cloth on the precious headband
you gave me got all tattered.
The same with my clothes, too.
So I had a new cloth made for it
along with my new clothes!
But thanks to that intense training,
you've gotten quite strong, haven't you?
You should be happy about it.
Yeah. I feel like I've gotten
another step closer
to becoming the Hokage!
Ooh, sounds like you've got
quite the confidence!
That Kakashi-sensei.
Is that stupid book
more important to him
than the results of our training?
So, are you guys on a date?
It's not like that.
Heh! Cut out the jokes.
Why would I be on
a date with this guy?
It's almost time for the Chunin Exam.
I've just been going back and forth
between the Sand and the Leaf
for meetings concerning the Exams.
And although it's a pain,
I've been put in charge
of the Exams...
I've just been told to act as
a guide for the Sand messenger.
Chunin Exam, huh...?
That sure takes me back...
Oh...
So what are you going to do, Naruto?
About what?
About the Chunin Exam.
You're the only one from our class
who hasn't become a Chunin.
What?!
Th-Then, you're a Chunin too, Sakura?
Heh-heh... That's right.
And just for the record,
Kankuro, this person here,
and Neji, who's a year above us,
are all already Jonin.
Huh?!
Then what about Gaara?!
Lord Kazekage...
The meeting is about to begin.
Okay.
What do you think?!
Pretty good, huh...?
It is my finest work.
Over the past several years,
the strength of our village
has stabilized,
and our relations with the Hidden Villages
in our allied nations have prospered.
In particular,
we have achieved good results
in our development of recruits
with the curriculum incorporating...
the training program
from the Leaf Village.
The Chunin Exam is almost here.
I look forward to the results.
However... at this time,
with the Chunin Exam upon us,
there is a nasty rumor
going around...
What is it, Yura?
Have you heard of the organization
called the "Akatsuki"?
Why have they started taking
such dramatic action?
What's their goal?
That's beyond me at this point...
What I do know...
is that they're after what's inside Naruto.
And... that they have something evil
in mind.
I passed on this information
to those in charge of security
for each land.
I sure hope they tighten up
their security immediately.
I see... I'd heard the rumors...
So the organization in question
is finally taking action...
The source of the information
is Lord Jiraiya,
one of the legendary Sannin.
So prior to the meeting,
I took the liberty of issuing an order
to increase Village security.
Elite ANBU Black Ops have already been
stationed at key points around the village.
No matter how powerful
the shinobi may be,
they will not be able
to infiltrate by force.
I hear the members of the Akatsuki
wear black clothing
in addition to capes with
a red cloud pattern on them.
I ordered security to attack
with full force
if they encounter anyone
matching that description.
Now then...
the meeting is adjourned.
Well done, Yura.
I never thought you'd take action
so quickly.
I have served on the council for four years.
It is my intention...
to always make decisions
while considering...
what's in the best interest...
of the... village.
What's the matter?
Nothing... It's nothing at all...
I just haven't slept much...
I see... You need to take care
of yourself.
Thank you for your concern.
I see... That's right...
I see.
So we have to deal with this one, then go
after the guy we sent to Orochimaru, huh?
It seems he turned traitor
and leaked information about us.
It can't be helped.
Even I don't know what happens
after the jutsu is cast.
More importantly,
will just that bag be enough?
Our opponent is the Jinchuriki.
All of my jutsu are works of art.
And I made sure to
bring my specialty.
After all, our opponent
is the One-Tail.
Black clothing and
a red cloud pattern.
Don't tell me...
Is that...?
Contact Captain Yura immediately!
Captain Yura!
Members of that organization have shown up.
I know.
You don't need to worry...
It'll be over soon.
Good work...
Do you remember me?
Of course, I do, Lord Sasori.
Of course, he does.
It wouldn't be much of
a jutsu if he didn't.
They become loyal subordinates
after regaining their memory.
I say it's about ready?
All right, it's done...
My man Sasori, you watch from here.
Okay.
I'll attack the village...
from above.
What do you think of
this artistic form...?
Don't make me wait too long, Deidara!
One.
Two.
Three.
So there are three people
guarding the skies...
Still, this village sure has
quite the artistic design to it.
It's certainly worth destroying, though...
From here on, I'll have to be stealthy.
Wh-What's this strange thing?!
It's not strange, you know.
As expected, philistines just don't
understand art.
I'll show you with your own bodies.
True art... is an explosion!
Infiltration successful.
That's as far as you go.
You're pretty good.
Now that's a handy Jinchuriki.
But... how'd you know
I was the intruder?
There are no birds like that
in this desert.
I see.
What do you mean something strange
got into the village?!
Captain Yura was supposed to have
tightened village security.
Actually... we have been unable to
contact Captain Yura.
Come again?!
So much for the stealthy approach.
But now...
I don't have to bother...
looking for you anymore...!
He's got the advantage,
as expected...
This is a real mess.
Gaara...
He uses strange explosives...
And he's able to guide them, huh?
All right.
They're fast, this time.
Gaara!
It's just like an eggshell
protecting what's inside.
But it's incredible that he was able
to block the explosion completely.
Sand Prison!
This is not good.
This sand's such
a pain in the neck.
Kankuro!
Is Gaara fighting right now?!
Where is he?
Yeah.
He's up there...
Sand Coffin...
Not bad.
I get it.
The sand he used to crush
my hand
is much faster and more powerful
than ordinary sand taken
from the desert...
I remember now!
That's the "Ultimate Defense" sand...
In other words,
the sand from that hole is
what crushed my arm...
I've only got a little bit
of clay left...
I underestimated him...
What you'd call
"not prepared enough."
This is just as my man Sasori said...
I've only enough left for
one more homing-type...
and my specialty as well.
I think...
I'll destroy this village, after all.
Lord Kazekage...
Black clothing and
a red cloud pattern...!
Judging from that appearance,
The Kazekage is likely fighting
a member of the Akatsuki.
I knew it.
Kankuro.
What is it?
For the time being,
we need to consider that
Gaara could lose control.
We need to be ready
in case Shukaku appears.
The villagers will be in danger.
That won't happen anymore.
Gaara will not harm
the people of this village.
Never!
Convene all members
for an emergency meeting!
Yes, sir!
You secure the reservoir.
Take two units with you!
Yes, sir.
Seal off the roads in sector A!
Yes, sir!
We must not assume
there's only one enemy!
No matter what happens,
maintain preparations for battle.
We must be ready to respond!
Medical Team!
Set up a barrier and lead
all villagers inside! Hurry!
There must not be even one casualty!
Is that clear?!
We'll provide full support for Gaara...
No... for Lord Kazekage!
Gaara...
Interference from below really
puts a damper on things...
And besides...
I'm tired of looking at
your expressionless face.
It's a doll molded from
detonating clay that's got chakra
and clay eaten by my palm
mixed together...
This specialty of mine...
It's packed with C3,
my most powerful chakra.
The explosive power is an exquisite
work of art that I'm very proud of!
- What's that? Hey!
- Yeah, what the hell is it?
This is not good! Get back!
You're too late.
Wh-What's this?
It's Lord Kazekage's sand...!
Wow! Look at the size
of the shield he made!
Okay, you're within...
range!
Gaara!
I'd expect no less...
That special sand he carries makes
for a quick defense.
However...
That's just what I want.
My left hand was crushed...
Sand Coffin.
However, I used that opportunity
to eat some of your sand...
and mix it with my bomb clay.
You were doomed the instant you used
that sand to defend yourself.
That being said,
I planned it that way!
Art...
- Oh, no...
- ... is explosive!
Lord Kazekage!
It-It can't be!
Gaara's Ultimate Defense was...
What the hell did he do...?
I guess I'll go retrieve him.
It was harder than
I thought not to kill him...
Mission complete.
Gaara!
Damn you!
Cease fire immediately!
We might hit the Kazekage!
Y-Yes sir!
Cease fire!
Stop the attack!
My man Sasori must be getting tired
of waiting for me.
Is he going to take him
away alive?!
I won't let him get away!
Kankuro!
Don't be running off carelessly!
Wait until we can get
a unit together!
We'll lose him if
we just sit around!
I'll catch up soon!
Don't go after him too far
on your own!
Yeah...! I know!
My mission is accomplished.
You're late...
I told you not to keep me waiting!
Cut me some slack...
This guy was pretty strong.
That's why I told you to make sure
you were prepared.
How about the preparations here?
Things are all ready here.
I had plenty of time, you see...
I was fully prepared unlike you.
Then, let's get out of here.
Wh-What's this...?!
What a mess...
They weren't attacked just now...
It might've been before Gaara
started to fight...
There were even elite ANBU Black Ops
members here...
They must have been attacked at once
by a rather large group?
Or perhaps...
Perhaps...?
No. It's nothing...
From the looks of this,
the guys who took Gaara just
passed straight through here.
Hurry! We're going after them!
- Yes, sir!
There's someone still alive!
Stop! Don't move him carelessly...
A paper bomb?!
Looks like they fell for your trap,
my man Sasori.
Of course. Traps are made
to be fallen into.
I get it.
Deploy a pursuit unit and
have them go after Kankuro immediately!
Yes, sir!
And contact the Hidden Leaf immediately
regarding this situation!
Tell them it's an emergency! Got it?!
Yes, sir!
I have a bad feeling about this...
Something...
Something's about to happen...!
I'm counting on you, Takamaru!
Go!
All right...!
What are you doing up so early...?
Everyone's still sleeping,
you know.
You...?!
I can't leave the village unattended
for too long...
My business here is finished,
so I just thought I'd head back
as soon as possible...
Without even eating breakfast?
I'll just find a teahouse or something
along the way and eat there.
What are you doing here?
It's a pain, but I'm supposed
to be your guide.
I have no choice seeing
as how it's a mission.
Must be quite a hassle...
Here is fine...
The next time we meet will be at
the Chunin Exam?
Yeah... See you around...
It's about time you become
a Jonin.
It'll happen before you know it
if you stop saying everything's a drag
and just do your missions...
What a drag...
What is it, my man Sasori?
I never thought...
someone would be following us.
Hold it!
I found you...!
You will return Gaara to me!
Deidara... You go on ahead...
As I recall...
he was the one who took Gaara
using that strange bird...
Then this must be the guy
who set the trap in the village...
I'll show you... my puppet show!
Crow!
Black Ant!
Salamander!
I'll say it again...
You will give Gaara back to me!
Puppet Master Jutsu, huh...?
Then I'm going on ahead!
You're not going anywhere!
Wha--?!
I don't like waiting for people,
and I don't like
making people wait...
I'll finish this right away.
You're late!
Finally, you're here...
Gee, sorry about that...
This time it took longer
than I thought
to write up the documents
for the new team.
Today's our new team's first mission!
Aren't you fired up?!
You've always been like that,
Kakashi-sensei!
Oh, come on.
You're already annoying!
It can't be helped.
Kakashi-sensei's always had
that look of disinterest!
I'm starting to lose
my dignity here.
If I'm not mistaken,
that's one of the Hidden Sand's...
Where'd this one come from
so early in the morning?
Th-This is Takamaru, the fastest
messenger hawk in the Hidden Sand!
Break!
What's this...?!
It's a level-one emergency message!
Contact the Cipher Corps
immediately!
It's sure been a long time
since I've been on a mission...
I'm so excited!
Naruto, accept the mission
without complaint,
no matter what we're ordered to do.
I know!
I hope so...
Move it, move it!
What was that?
Watch it, you! Be more careful!
So the Cipher Corps
was summoned, huh...?
Then what the bird from earlier
brought must've been...
Whaaat?!
Guarding a gold transport convoy?!
Huh? You got a problem?!
That's totally a C-rank mission!
I'll just have to say no thanks
to a mission like that...
And here I just told him
not to complain.
Please don't act so selfish...
I'm the one she's going to get mad at...
I knew he'd react like this...
Good grief...
Ohh, just as you thought...
Naruto, you haven't matured
mentally at all, have you...?
Naruto...
I gave you an easier mission since
this is more or less a comeback for you...
I didn't ask for this!
I-I'm sorry! I'll give him
a good scolding later...
Y-You moron!
You can talk like that
because you don't know
how frightening she can be... Cha!
The details of the mission
are written here.
Right!
Honestly...
The old man Third Hokage
was much more understanding...
Huh? Did you say something?!
Hey! Knock it off!
Th-There's trouble... Fifth Hokage!
What's all the fuss about?
We've just gotten word that
the Hidden Sand's Kazekage has been
abducted by an organization
known as the Akatsuki.
Gaara was—?!
Team Kakashi,
I'm assigning you a new mission.
You're to go to
the Sand Village at once,
find out what's going on there,
and keep us informed.
You're to remain there
and follow their orders.
Give them any backup they need.
Right!
How...?
How can he read
my hidden weapon attack schemes...?
You've got solid talent...
However, you picked
the wrong opponent.
Your puppets
with the hidden poison weapons...
I can see through them all...
Crow! Black Ant! Salamander!
This is the first time my hidden
weapon attacks have been read like this...
You look puzzled...
You're wondering how
I figured out your attacks, huh?
Of course, I did.
Crow...
Black Ant...
Salamander...
The one who created these
three puppets is none other... than me!
I ended up making
someone wait a bit...
But I never thought my opponent
would be
one of my adorable juniors
using hand-me-downs.
I haven't had such a fun fight
in quite some time.
Then, you're... the renowned master
of the Puppet Brigade,
Sasori of the Red Sand?!
I'm honored that a kid like you
knows my name.
You defected from the Sand over 20 years ago.
What are you doing here?!
What's the point of asking such
a thing before you die?
The poison's circulating, huh...?
You're finished!
You're just going to suffer.
But if you want to live that badly...
I won't finish you off!
However, that poison will kill you
in less than three days.
Gaara...
Damn it...!
There he is! He's over there!
He's collapsed!
And his puppets are smashed...
Okay, we're off now!
We'll be back, Lady Tsunade.
Right...
Naruto, good luck!
Thanks.
Hey!
Are you off on a mission now, Naruto?
That's right!
Oh, more importantly.
Tsunade, I've got some information
for you.
- The Kazekage of the Hidden Sand...
- I know.
I'm just about to send them off
to the Sand now.
Right, right.
You know about the Akatsuki
and Naruto, don't you...?
It's an emergency situation you see...
I just made the best choice I could.
Oh, come on...
Naruto, come here for a second.
Hm?
Listen up, Naruto.
Don't get reckless against the Akatsuki.
They've got business with me.
So this time I'll go to them!
You have indeed gotten stronger...
But if you don't stay calm,
you'll just be asking for trouble.
Losing your cool right away
is a bad habit of yours.
Naruto... I think you know...
But don't use that power.
I know...
Kakashi...
Keep an eye on Naruto and make sure
he doesn't do anything too reckless.
I'm counting on you. Okay?
Okay.
Kakashi-sensei, Sakura,
let's get a move on!
H-Hey, wait up!
We're off.
Oh boy...
Are you worried?
No, I'm not...
He's no longer a weak shinobi
I need to worry about...
And the same goes for Sakura.
Growth is sure a mysterious thing.
Hang on, Gaara!