For the next three days, I'm going to
give it everything I've got...
for Lord Gaara.
Lord Gaara, putting up
your Sand Guard won't help you train!
Sorry... My Sand Guard is
an automatic response
and I'm not conscious of it.
Your Sand is like armor.
Even if your armor is solid,
you'll sustain damage if
your taijutsu is weak.
You must stay on the offensive
and maintain your breathing.
Then your body will move naturally.
Now try defending yourself even
before your Sand Guard activates.
I am impressed, Lord Gaara.
You've progressed so much
in such a short time.
Once you master taijutsu,
you will be able to combine it
with your Sand Guard and
make it even more formidable.
It's only because I have
such a fine teacher.
Shira, are you going to
take the Chunin Exam?
Yes. I'm eternally grateful for
the opportunity you have given me.
It's only natural since
you have the skills.
In time, you will become
a great shinobi of the Sand.
It's finally here! The Chunin Exam!
I'm getting antsy.
It's too soon to get nervous.
Our goal isn't simply to
pass the Chunin Exam...
But to have as many Sand entrants
as possible pass.
It's my way of
repaying Lord Gaara.
I think you're more stressed out
than we are.
I want to live up to
Lord Gaara's expectations.
By the way, this year's second test
is shorter than last time.
It's three days this time
as opposed to five days.
Which simply means this place
is that much more dangerous.
When the sun rises,
the temperatures soar in the desert.
And getting around will
become much more difficult.
I see...
We might have barely
enough time to make it to the goal.
So we can't stop for anything.
Anyway, our priority is
to acquire the other scroll.
To do that, we'll have
to battle a team for it...
But we can't just pick any team.
I came up with something.
When did you...?
Yesterday's brawl in the cafeteria
was a fortunate turn of events.
I was able to get a rough idea
of the other teams' strengths.
The teams to watch are...
the one with Shira,
the guy who stopped your kick, Lee.
And...
The team from the Hidden Waterfall.
With our skills,
we should have no problem
with the rest of the teams.
You're amazing, Neji!
You analyzed all that already?!
So we'll avoid the strong teams
and aim for the weaker ones, right?
I don't like doing things that way...
I figured you'd say that.
But we've waited two and a half years
for this Chunin Exam.
You don't want to fail, do you?
Of course not...
But I...
Determination never betrays you.
I...
I want to fight that guy!
There's the signal to start.
Let's go!
So, what do we do?
We were told not to enter
the Demon Desert...
I have a message
from Lady Tsunade.
What is it?
I'll read it.
"According to intel from agents
who just returned,"
"opposition forces have been
on the move recently"
"in the Land of Wind."
In other words, it's the
anti-Gaara faction.
An assassination attempt
has already occurred.
In spite of this, supervisors from
other villages are prohibited
from entering the Demon Desert...
and Gaara himself intends to supervise
the second test as a proctor.
Needless to say,
the danger is enormous
if Gaara plans to
set himself up as a decoy.
Not only to Gaara,
but to the Hidden Leaf.
If anything happens to Gaara,
our alliance with the Hidden Sand
will be jeopardized.
Guy... Asuma... Kurenai...
Sneak into the Demon Desert
and investigate the Hidden Sand.
"If Gaara's safety is threatened,
protect him!"
Gaara's assassination...?
Gaara himself is the decoy...?
The Hidden Sand must be
at their wit's end...
Whatever happens,
let's protect the Kazekage!
– Right.
– Yes.
Scatter!
Your eyesight is amazing.
Imagine being able to see
what's being reflected
on a water droplet dozens
of kilometers away.
Once she gets a fix
on the relay point,
she can see several
dozen kilometers out.
But when the sun is out,
the water droplets evaporate,
so I can't use it for too long.
Found them!
That's the team from
the Hidden Leaf!
The Hidden Sand is close by too!
Tell them to keep their distance.
Right.
It's a signal from Shira.
Well? Do you see anyone?
Nope, there's no one.
There has to be.
We've run quite far.
What's going on?
Why can't I find anyone
with my Byakugan?
Neji, Tenten... Come here!
What is it, Lee?
I'm positive this is my kunai.
What?!
Just in case we got lost,
I stuck a few kunai into the rocks.
Finding this means...
We've been running
around in circles...
Could this be a genjutsu?
No way! We haven't even
encountered an enemy yet!
– Release!
I knew it...
What's going on?!
There!
I found them!
Let's hurry!
According to Shira,
there are some pesky
Leaf shinobi nearby!
Why should we listen
to a guy like that?!
He's useful to us now.
We can pay him back later...
As much as we want!
Damn... They found us!
We don't need to be nice
to these guys, right?
We'll take their scroll!
– Right!
Here I go!
Leaf...
Whirlwind!
Datsuji! Goji!
You're already within my range.
And I will deal with you swiftly.
Eight Trigrams...
Two Palms!
What?!
4 Palms!
8 Palms!
16 Palms!
32 Palms!
64 Palms!
He blocked every hit?!
Shira!
We'll handle them.
Leave while you can.
I can't believe I get
to fight you so soon!
Hey! What are you
so happy about?!
Lee! Don't take him on carelessly!
Oh, my...
The cactus genjutsu
was broken already?
Cactus genjutsu?
Back then, I did catch
the faint scent of plants...
That was the genjutsu?
We knew the second test
would take place in the Demon Desert.
So we set up several jutsu in advance.
Don't hold it against us...
that we have an advantage.
But not this time!
I don't know about that.
I'm very cautious.
So I wonder what it means...
that I appeared before you?
Huh?!
What?!
I can't move...
Not again?!
This time, I'll release it for you.
Release!
Sorry, but I don't have time
to deal with you guys now.
Please wait!
Shira! Why won't you fight me?
You're strong. I knew that
the moment I took your hit.
That's why I won't fight.
If we fight, one of us will get hurt.
A shinobi fights regardless of the risk!
I have an important goal right now.
That goal is to make sure
Hidden Sand entrants
make it through the test.
You're helping...
... other entrants?
Instead of asking questions,
you should worry about yourselves.
Let's go, Sen, Yome.
Shira!
This sand... is moving!
Help me, Lee!
Wait... I can't get loose...!
Don't struggle!
You'll get buried even deeper!
It seems I miscalculated
our strategy.
What do you mean?
Last night...
He was also analyzing
the Hidden Leaf's strengths.
They've had us under
surveillance from the start!
Not only that,
he took command of the
other Hidden Sand entrants,
and ordered them not
to confront us.
That's why we didn't
come across anyone!
That Shira is not only skilled...
he's smart!
This is not the time
to be impressed!
Can't you hear this noise?
Damn, so this is what
he was talking about!
We're going to fall!
We're going to die!
Eight Inner Gates:
Gate of Rest!
Open!
Is everyone okay?
Yeah, we made it.
But where are we?
There's no way out
of this waterfall.
What?!
So we have to wait until
someone comes to rescue us?!
No way! Does that mean
we're disqualified?!
Is everyone safe?
What about them?
We took care of them.
They fell into the Sand Waterfall Pit.
They won't be able to get out
until after the test is over.
I see. That's a relief.
Now's our chance. Get scrolls
from the other teams.
Yeah, and we're taking
one right now.
What's the big idea?
Like we said.
We're going to get one
from you guys.
Why?!
That's easy to answer, Shira.
Because we don't like you.
What did you want to talk about?
We want to help
and make sure everyone passes.
Your team and ours will
start out close to each other
for the second test.
However, a Hidden Leaf team
that includes a Byakugan user
will also be near.
They are strong.
So what?
The chances are high
that one of our teams
will confront the Hidden Leaf
team in the beginning.
This team is not
to be taken lightly.
We'll impede them.
During this time,
I want you to get as far away
from them as possible.
Oh... In other words,
you're going to order us around?
I just want as many Sand shinobi
as possible to pass. That's all.
That's my way of
repaying Lord Gaara!
Lord Gaara, huh...?
That just doesn't sit well
with us.
That a guy like you
who wasn't a shinobi until just recently...
caught Lord Gaara's eye
and has the nerve
to act all high and mighty
towards us!
Do you realize Shira
saved you earlier?!
Well, we don't owe him...
a damn thing!
Wait!
I have no intention
of fighting you!
Maybe not you... but we sure do!
You're just too good
with the fan...
Using it even in combat to
control your genjutsu powder.
But without it,
you're no match for me.
You squirmy little—!
I learned from Shira too!
I can use this Evasion Jutsu
better than anybody!
I know your moves like
the back of my hand!
However...
Your weakness is...
your eyes that see too well!
I-idiot?
Idiot!
My eyes... My eyes!
Yome!
Sen! Yome!
Don't move!
If you do, we'll shoot!
Shira!
It's over, Shira!
Don't ever show your face again!
Die!
Leaf... Hurricane!
Rotation!
You guys are—!
Shira and his team are useless.
But with the six of us...
Sorry, but we're out of here.
What?!
Let's retreat!
Shira! Are you all right?!
You...
Why...?
I thought you fell into
the Sand Waterfall Pit?
Oh, that was nothing.
Y-You're pretty good.
But why did you save us?
We're not so shameless
as to torment opponents
who have been weakened.
Anyway, thank you.
Can you explain something?
Why would your own comrades
do this to him,
who protected them?
Well... Shira wasn't a shinobi
until just recently.
Wasn't a shinobi?
Someone of his skill?
Perhaps that's due to
his circumstances.
Do you know something, Lee?
Shira has almost no skill
in ninjutsu or genjutsu.
Shira and I are alike...
We're shinobi who can
only perform taijutsu.
So you knew.
I realized it yesterday
when we exchanged punches.
Those who are skilled in ninjutsu
and genjutsu may not notice
that slight, yet unique difference.
I sensed that he was like me.
Since you know that much,
let me explain.
In the Hidden Sand Village,
not even the previous Kazekage
would allow people like Shira
to become shinobi.
But that's—! Even a great taijutsu user
like Shira?!
That's right. That's
why until just recently...
Shira wasn't allowed to attend the Academy
and was treated like an outsider.
Hey! What are you staring at?
You can't even use ninjutsu!
Go away! Your uselessness is contagious!
But Shira refused to give up
and believed in himself.
He kept training all by himself
and honed his taijutsu.
Then, the times changed...
The seat was empty for a while
after the Fourth Kazekage
passed away...
but eventually Lord Gaara
became the Fifth Kazekage.
Those who knew Lord Gaara's past
spread rumors that
our village was doomed,
but that wasn't the case.
Lord Gaara was receptive
to other people's opinions...
and one by one, he did away with
the previous Kazekage's practices
and instituted reforms.
That's Lord Gaara?
Yeah. He's the younger brother
of Temari,
the girl we used to play with
when we were kids.
What happened to the huge boulder
that was used to prevent sand erosion?
Well...
Bring me the one
who destroyed this.
Are you Shira?
You knew that boulder
was placed there
to protect the Hidden Sand Village.
Why did you destroy it?
I am very sorry.
I had no intention of
destroying it.
To me, that boulder was
an invaluable training partner.
Are you saying you destroyed it
during training?
I was told you are not
a student at the Academy.
No.
I don't have any skills in
ninjutsu or genjutsu.
According to the village rules,
someone like me is unfit
to be a shinobi.
So you trained all by yourself?
Interesting...
I want to see which
is more valuable...
That boulder or you!
Your fist is splendid!
Please forgive me!
I can't begin to imagine
the effort it took for you,
banned from the Academy, to hone
your skills to this level.
I hereby abolish the rule established
by my predecessor.
Shira, you will be a shinobi.
I once met someone just like you
in the Hidden Leaf Village.
Through sheer perseverance,
he has become a fine shinobi.
Shira, I predict you will become
as good a shinobi as he.
That's how Shira finally
became a shinobi.
Not only that...
Lord Gaara recognized
Shira's character and
chose him to be
his personal taijutsu coach.
To be named the Kazekage's
taijutsu coach is a huge advancement!
But this displeased many.
When someone who until just recently
was below your rank
attains great success,
people become jealous...
I understand now.
Changing people's perceptions
takes time.
I see, so that's why Shira
said that to me...
I don't know what it is you sensed,
but dwelling on the misfortunes
of birth is meaningless.
Because, for all one's flaws
and suffering, we have just one life.
Shira, you persevered
so much, and yet...
I'll never forgive the ones
who did this to you!
Lee!
That idiot... Don't tell me he's going to...
This is—!
Damn it...
If you guys hadn't run off,
we could've obtained a scroll.
That team with the Byakugan user
is the one Shira warned us about.
Better safe than sorry.
By the way, they're not coming
after us, are they?
I used all those paper bombs,
and that area has a lot
of underground caverns...
The explosions created
a steeper cliff than I expected.
It'll take them a while
to make their way across.
I wouldn't be so sure about that.
Who's there?!
The Beautiful Green Beast of
the Hidden Leaf, Rock Lee!
You're that guy from earlier!
What you did to Shira
is unforgivable!
Please apologize to Shira!
Apologize to Shira?
This guy's from the Hidden Leaf and
he's siding with Shira?!
When you believe
in hard work and perseverance,
it doesn't matter whether
you're a friend or foe!
That's beside the point!
How did you get across that chasm?!
I have invisible wings known
as perseverance!
Until you apologize to Shira,
my rage will not subside!
Like hell, we will!
We know your weakness!
Wind Style:
Sandstorm Hurricane!
This is genjutsu!
Like Shira, you only specialize
in taijutsu.
So we'll just capitalize
on your weaknesses!
That's cowardly!
Please fight me fair and square!
What's cowardly?!
It's your fault for not knowing ninjutsu!
Inside the Sandstorm Hurricane,
countless sand particles
collide against each other
and create powerful
electromagnetic waves.
Because of that,
anyone caught inside it will continue
to experience genjutsu.
It's about time to finish this!
What?!
Neji!
Hey, are you crazy taking
on six of them by yourself?
Tenten! You two made it
across too!
If you made it, isn't it obvious
we would too?!
Damn it...
We're a team!
Don't go off on your own!
I'm sorry! I just couldn't stand it...
Well, we have no choice now.
Let's go, Tenten!
That's more like it!
8 Trigrams... 64 Palms!
What's their deal?
They're ridiculously strong!
I would like some payback as well!
Great Leaf Whirlwind!
Wait, Lee!
Please forgive them.
Shira...!
Why?
Why would you defend them?!
They betrayed you and
put you through hell!
Maybe they did.
But it doesn't matter.
How can you say
it doesn't matter?!
If they won't acknowledge me,
I have only myself to blame.
That's all.
I already told you.
Whatever my flaws
and misfortunes,
this is the life I was born into.
I'm not bitter, and I bear no grudge.
Good or bad, this is my life.
I have only myself to blame
for the bad
because I didn't work hard enough.
I don't want to blame anyone
for the life I have.
Shira...
How can you say
you didn't work hard enough?
Shira! You are a man among men!
The shinobi among shinobi!
I've never been so moved
in my life!
Other than Guy-sensei,
I've never met anyone so amazing!
You get so carried away.
It was really touching,
until you ruined the mood.
Take this.
This way, at least one of
our teams will pass.
Damn it... Must you be so kind?
Put yourself in our shoes, will you?
Sorry.
Why are you apologizing?
You're right.
But if you take this,
what about you guys...?
We'll figure something out.
Why would you go so far?
Is it all for Lord Gaara?
Until recently, he was
a brutal shinobi who'd kill anyone.
People don't change so easily!
I realize that.
But Lord Gaara and I
are the same...
That's what I believe.
I can tell from training with him.
Lord Gaara bitterly regrets
his past actions.
And he knows that atonement
won't come easy.
And yet, Lord Gaara keeps
pushing forward.
Because despite what
people think of him...
he believes that persevering
is the best thing to do right now.
I don't care about
who I am right now...
As long as I'm not ashamed of
the man I am in the future.
Such profound words!
You're absolutely right!
What counts is the man
that you are in the future!
Okay, okay...
We heard you, pipe down!
We... can't accept that.
Hey, give him your scroll.
Why?!
We have our pride too.
We lost this battle.
So we're handing you our scroll.
But we're not about
to give up just yet.
We'll prove it by obtaining the scrolls
from the other teams.
Let's go!
Why did they...?
They realized that they don't want to
be ashamed of the person they'll become.
Shira!
Um...
Thank you.
Thanks to you, it looks like Shira will
have a place in the Hidden Sand.
We didn't do anything.
Shira did it with his own strength and
a little help from our taijutsu fanatic.
He's very earnest...
He might be a little like our Shira.
Uh, I don't think so.
His weird clothes, his hair,
or his eyebrows...
They're not alike at all!
That's true... He's right up there
with Naruto in stupidity.
Naruto?
A shinobi from our village.
He's on a training journey right now.
We've heard of him.
Lord Gaara speaks of a shinobi
who changed him.
I'm sure the name was Naruto.
I wonder what he's up to now?
Neji... Tenten...
This has nothing to do
with the second test...
But I have a favor to ask.
Uh-oh... Here we go...
I never want to go through
something like last time!
Sasuke beat Gaara of the Sand
against whom I was no match...
And Naruto beat Neji
whom I longed to defeat...
Why? Why does it always
turn out like this?
You wouldn't have listened to us
even if we tried to stop you, right?
Right!
Shira! I want to fight you!
Because we both seek
to master taijutsu, please fight me!
If I can face you in battle,
I'll have no regrets about
this Chunin Exam!
Fine with me, Lee.
To be honest, I've wanted to fight you!
Huh?!
I didn't know Lee kept going
with that training.
We're in the middle
of the Chunin Exam!
What is he thinking?
Shira! I will show
you how serious I am!
Let me warn you...
Shira's incredibly strong!
I've become strong too!
This is my last fight.
Last?
Here I come, Lee!
What is this?
Their speed is ridiculous!
A battle of powerful fists...
It's not something
you get to see often.
If I could, I would have liked
to fight him too.
Amazing...
I haven't faced
a taijutsu user this strong
since Guy-sensei and Neji!
He has a fine technique...
I feel his passion in
every punch he throws.
The intensity of his training
comes across clearly.
Lee!
I'm grateful to you.
Perhaps it's all because of you
that I can be a shinobi.
Lord Gaara said
this to me back then...
I once met someone just like you
in Hidden Leaf Village.
Through sheer perseverance,
he has become a fine shinobi.
Shira... I predict you will be
as good a shinobi as he.
It might have been your fists
that changed Lord Gaara.
No, I had nothing to do with that!
It was your perseverance
that moved Lord Gaara.
Lee, I'm going to show you
my gratitude in earnest!
Well said!
That is the creed of those of us
who are dedicated to
the mastery of taijutsu.
They seem to be enjoying this.
Maybe Lee has met someone
he can consider a true rival.
Neither one of them has delivered
a decisive blow yet.
They're just sizing
each other up right now.
What?
They're not fighting at
their full potential?
It's more like 50%.
How much can a body endure?
If they stay evenly matched like this...
No...
They're not quite equal.
Huh? They're not?
They're equal in speed and in
the number of moves they have...
But Shira's physique is
a full size bigger than Lee's.
In boxing, the difference
in body weight
influences the intensity of the blow.
While they may look
evenly matched,
Lee with his smaller build...
Is sustaining more damage?
Lee should be feeling
the effects pretty soon.
Blow for blow, Shira's punches
are harder than mine!
At this rate...
Lee!
That stance!
Don't tell me Lee plans
to use the Lotus!
It's too dangerous!
But he is an opponent
worthy of that risk!
No way!
The First Gate won't open!
Why?!
You hit my chakra points and
stopped the flow of chakra!
As a taijutsu user like you,
I know all your strengths
and weaknesses.
As well as the fact that you are
versed in the secret jutsu,
the Eight Inner Gates!
From now on, I'm serious!
Shira's demeanor has changed.
He's getting serious now!
Here I come, Lee!
What's happening?!
All of a sudden, his attacks
became relentless and accurate!
This is—!
The sound!
Sound?!
His attacks are silent!
We taijutsu users can
counter supersonic moves
because we have honed
our five senses.
One of those senses is hearing.
I remember...
Lee said he once fought a shinobi
from the Hidden Sound
who gave him a hard time!
This time, it's the exact opposite!
Shira is making absolutely no noise!
But how...?
Byakugan!
I see!
It's the theory of the owl.
The owl?
Did you know that owls fly
without making a sound?
Owls have special
comb-like feathers
that muffle the sound
of their flapping wings.
Using chakra that can only
be used with taijutsu,
he's cloaked himself with
the same type of feathers.
To come up with something
like that all by himself...
It's a shame someone like him
is an enemy.
Silent Fist!
See if you can take this, Lee!
How can I...?
There's no point in working hard
if you don't believe in yourself!
Yes! I've trained and worked
just as hard as Shira!
999... 1000!
Now, 1000 sit-ups!
Are you serious?
I am serious!
Wait, wait, wait!
Enough bodybuilding!
You're in far better physical
condition than we are, Lee.
But Guy-sensei, I've never beaten
you or Neji even once!
That's because
you don't use this.
Use my head for taijutsu?
Certainly!
It can be said that
mental visualization
is a fundamental part of taijutsu.
When I weave a sign,
I'm already seeing 100 moves ahead.
What?! Is such a thing possible?!
Yes, it's possible!
Through visualization alone,
if I'm going to fight Kakashi,
I can now see 1000 moves ahead.
Th-That far?
Hey, is that true?
Who knows?
For example, if I attack
with a right seiken fist...
Lee, what would your 50th move be?
Huh?
What technique is your 50th move!
Well...
Let's see...
A right thrust!
Wrong!
Then... A clockwise kick!
Correct!
So what is your 100th move?!
Uh... A left heel kick!
Wrong.
The answer is
a counter-clockwise kick.
What?
I will prove it to you right now!
Ready?
48...
49...
50.
Continue!
Sensei was right!
98... 99...!
100!
Right again!
I see...
He's making that happen!
Huh?
That's amazing, Guy-sensei!
What's your trick?
It's not a trick.
I simply guided your movements.
That's all.
Guided my movements?
Yes!
I used counters that forced you
to react in a certain way.
In battle, there is a sequence
to techniques and jutsu.
When you are in control
of that flow,
predicting what comes next
is not difficult.
Right now, I'm controlling
the flow of battle, and as a result,
you, my opponent who's physically
stronger than me,
have tired out before me!
That's true!
Guy-sensei, you're not
even breathing hard!
By controlling the flow of battle,
I was able to deplete your energy
while preserving my own.
There really aren't many chances to
take down a foe in the midst of battle.
Most attack strategies are just attempts
to create such an opening!
That's what I mean
by using your head!
That's right!
From opponents I've faced before,
I pretty much know Shira's pattern.
All I need to do is control the sequence
of my opponent's moves.
Then, even if his moves are silent,
I can anticipate Shira's fist!
All right!
What?!
Lee's not getting hit anymore!
Finally, Lee...
You remembered that training!
He's countering so fast!
I can't wait to see him go all out!
He missed the chakra point!
What's going on?
Was it by chance?
At this point...
Guy-sensei would be able to activate
the Sixth Gate instantly...
That's impossible for me, however...
Gate of Life! Open!
He went straight to
the Third Gate...
So Lee's trained that far!
So that's the rumored
Eight Inner Gates...
Well then...
Seven Heavenly Breaths:
First Activation!
Second Activation!
Third Activation!
What is that?!
It's a taijutsu breathing method
that Shira came up with.
It's a jutsu whereby inhaling
large amounts of oxygen
invigorates the entire body.
When performing this technique,
Shira's lung capacity increases
nearly fourfold.
So it's his version of
the Eight Inner Gates.
It's amazing that he came up
with that all by himself...
Those two really drive home the fact...
that there is no limit
to perseverance.
No kidding!
Lee! Shira!
Do your best, both of you!
Here I come, Shira!
Anytime!
Not yet!
Fourth Gate of Pain! Open!
Gate of Closing! Open!
So this is what you're like
when you're serious!
My chakra... the sound-muffling
feathers are being blown away!
I'm starting to hear...
the sound of your wings.
Leaf Hurricane!
I'm not done yet...
Shira's wound has opened up!
Shira!
Are you okay, Shira?!
Yeah...
I guess we'll have to
postpone this match.
Lee, I envy you.
I wish I could have trained under
Guy-sensei at least once.
Shira... Why did you release
my chakra points?
So you noticed?
I wanted to fight you
when you could give
a hundred percent.
As I expected, you are strong.
It was a great experience.
What are you saying?
You were too reckless!
Shira, I want you to have this.
Guy-sensei gave it to me.
This is what made me strong.
It is a unique item with
superior breathability
and moisture-wicking qualities
that let you move easily!
You'll see the difference
when you train!
You'll get attached
to it immediately!
Wear this...
and we'll be brothers!
Thanks... I accept it.
Shira... You said earlier
that this would be your last fight...
In the Land of Wind,
there is a battalion that guards
the northern border.
That battalion never leaves
its station.
The environment there
is extremely harsh,
so few candidates
are willing to accept that mission.
I plan to volunteer for it
if I pass this exam.
It's near my hometown.
My parents are sick and
I want to be close to them.
So I probably won't see
any of you again.
I see how it is...
Shira... I had no idea.
I guess that means I won't
be seeing you around either, Yome.
You're probably going
to tag along, right?
I have no regrets about my life.
But I'm sure my life would
have been more interesting
if I had had a friend like you.
I'm going to remember that as
the greatest compliment from you!
And I mean it as such, Lee,
in all sincerity.
Now we have two scrolls!
Then let's head straight
for the goal!
So, when should I break
the news to them...?
According to reports from
the investigative team,
two members of Team Fuu
from the Hidden Waterfall...
Tocchi and Kun...
are actually not Genin.
It is believed they are Jonin
named Kegon and Yoro.
Damn Hidden Waterfall...
What are they scheming?
Wait.
Let me handle this.
This information is not
to go out of this room.
– But!
The second test will
continue uninterrupted.
Understood?!
What is Lord Gaara thinking?!
It will be sundown soon.
Yes.
From here, we'll be able to sense
the enemy's presence right away.
It's the perfect spot to make camp.
So where's Fuu?
Hey! She was over there
just a second ago...
Fuu!
That brat! She's so carefree!
What the—?!
Poke, poke!
Fuu! Don't go off on your own!
Damn it!
What if someone from
another village attacked you?
You are vital to
the Hidden Waterfall...!
Okay, I get it! I'll be right there!
Seriously! If you keep making a scene,
we're going to get spotted!
Fuu...
She's a...
Judging from their headbands,
they belong to the Hidden Rain...
Which scroll do they have?
Heaven or Earth?
All you do is run away!
Just be nice and
hand over your scroll!
That's not happening.
Ajisai...
Fire Style:
Unsealing Jutsu: Confetti Storm!
They ran away?
Our strength scared them off!
Just when we almost had their scroll!
Lady Angel...
Lady Angel,
what is our special mission?
Take advantage of the Chunin Exam
to find a Jinchuriki.
A Jinchuriki?
Suiren, Fuyou...
Use your Sensory Perception skills
and look for a shinobi
who harbors
an enormous amount of chakra.
Is that what a Jinchuriki is?
Even if you don't find a Jinchuriki,
bring back intel of any extraordinary
shinobi from other villages.
– Yes.
You will follow these two, Ajisai.
I understand.
The Hidden Rain is in
the midst of a reformation.
Other villages must not find out.
They must continue to believe
that Hanzo of the Salamander
rules the Hidden Rain.
– Yes!
What is it, Ajisai?
You can so see so many stars
in other villages...
Stars...!
So this is what a starlit sky is like...
Oh... a shooting star!
It's the first time I've seen one...
We'll see them too, someday,
in Hidden Rain Village.
Now then...
There's no other shinobi
in the area.
Okay, we can relax
and have a meal.
We're having okonomiyaki
pancakes for dinner!
Okonomiyaki?
Okonomiyaki in the desert...
Who would have expected that?
We all need to eat well
and maintain our strength.
It's convenient having you around, Tenten.
What do you mean
by "convenient"?
It's so great that
you're so convenient!
Excuse me?
I may have convenient tools,
but that doesn't make me
a convenient tool, got it?
No, no!
You're absolutely convenient!
Come on!
I am not convenient!
You can prepare your own meal.
Hey, Tenten...
Don't follow me!
I wonder what happened?
I don't know either.
What do we do?
Don't look at me.
That was just me venting, wasn't it?
Tenten...
The okonomiyaki pancakes
are done.
Let's eat!
How do they taste?
I'm not too confident
about them, but...
Looks like it's going to
be another hot day.
It's the complete opposite
of Hidden Rain Village.
A little dampness would be nice.
I see a little bit of green over there.
Byakugan!
What do you see, Neji?
There's no one around here.
Let's keep moving.
As we approach the finish line,
others are bound to appear.
You're right.
It's better than lying in wait.
If we're going to wait,
I see a good spot.
Where?
Want to go and check it out?
This place is eerie.
I see caves all around us.
It seems to be a ruin.
A ruin?
Yeah... of the Land of Wind.
Just as I expected.
They're Hidden Leaf shinobi.
They look different from
yesterday's bunch.
Yesterday's trio was
totally unimpressive.
I wonder what these guys are like?
They're heading right for us.
They have
a Sensory Perception type too.
We'll ambush them.
They're lying in wait.
What about their scroll?
We'll fight and snatch it away.
Looks like they plan
to do the same thing.
They're coming straight for us!
Let's not waste time
on senseless fighting.
I'll be blunt.
We have the Heaven scroll.
If this is what you're after, let's fight.
Unsealing Jutsu: Shuriken!
That jutsu...!
Rotation!
Summoning Jutsu:
Gate of Rainwater!
You...!
You're not the only one who
can use Transportation Ninjutsu.
Those guys are pretty good.
Yeah, however...
None of them are overflowing with
large amounts of chakra.
Ajisai...
Unsealing Jutsu: Confetti Storm!
They ran away!
Byakugan!
Let's go after them!
They're coming after us.
They definitely have
a Sensory type with them.
Water Style:
Hidden Drizzle Jutsu!
What happened?
There's little moisture around here.
My Water Style doesn't work well.
We know we're at
a territorial disadvantage.
It's an impossible battle,
but we have no choice but to fight.
Leaf Hurricane!
Above you, Lee!
– Senbon Rainstorm!
You're pretty good!
Gentle Fist!
Leaf Drop!
Tenten!
Ajisai!
I sense their chakra underground...
but it's deep down.
The sand and gravel are in the way.
We can't waste time
fighting senselessly.
We're going to save our teammate,
so we request that you not interfere.
Same here.
Yes, let's call a truce for now.
We're not at war.
This is just the Chunin Exam.
Our teammate's safety is more important
than passing or failing.
We agree to your plan.
But we'll conduct our own search.
This looks like a ruin
of the Land of Wind.
Ajisai and the other shinobi fell
into an underground corridor.
If it's a corridor,
it has to connect from somewhere.
Should we just use brute strength
and dig from above?
There's a risk of collapse.
We should search for
a passageway into the ruin
and follow them underground.
Yikes...
What's wrong?
Burn with the passion of youth!
Let your youthful energy seethe!
Fill up with burning chakra!
But Guy-sensei...
I thought this is
just strength training!
You're too easygoing, Tenten.
Somewhere along this cliff,
your physical strength
will reach its limits.
Then you will fall and die.
Die?
To prevent yourself from dying,
you must overcome the limits
of your physical strength.
Overcoming the limits of
physical strength requires a strong will.
Yes sir!
Hi there.
Are you guys cliff-climbing too?
Hang in there.
Kakashi?!
Why is your arm
behind your back?
It's a little habit of mine.
Well, see you later!
"See you later"?
Wait up! This is a contest!
I'm finishing first!
Don't get so worked up.
This is only training.
What's wrong with
a little rivalry during training!
Hey, please wait, Guy-sensei!
You can take it easy!
Honestly...
Damn, damn it...
Damn it...
Good job, Tenten. You made it.
Well? Did you overcome your limits?
I'm not quite sure...
But I think I overcame something.
Water?
Here you go.
You're convenient, after all.
Please stop saying that already.
I mean, your jutsu is convenient.
Storing items in a scroll,
or using a scroll to pull things
from a distance...
The Transportation Technique,
which is a type of Summoning Jutsu.
You either have the skill
for it or you don't.
You're saying that
I have the skill for it?
Seems that way.
Honing that skill is the path
to gaining the strength
and usefulness you desire.
Hone my skill?
Isn't that only going to increase
my physical strength?
Your spiritual strength too.
You know that chakra
is the combination
of physical energy and
spiritual energy, right?
Of course.
Each individual can increase
chakra simply by training.
Simply put, if you increase
your physical and spiritual power,
your chakra will increase too.
Increasing my chakra
is good for me?
With Summoning Jutsu,
the caster's chakra
is directly proportionate
to the quantity and size
of what is summoned.
This is the amount of water
you just summoned.
By increasing your chakra,
you can summon enough water
to fill a bathtub,
or a lake, or even an ocean.
An ocean...
And that is why we will continue
to train to increase our chakra, Tenten.
Right!
We just climbed up,
so why are we climbing down?!
This is training too!
Burn with the passion of youth!
Let your youthful energy seethe!
Fill up with burning chakra!
Huh?
Where am I?
Hey!
Hey, come on.
Look... I don't think this is
the time to be fighting.
Here.
Let's call a truce
until we get out of here.
What do you say?
That's fine...
But I don't need charity
from one of the Great Nation!
What? "Charity?"
Unsealing Jutsu!
If you had water,
you could have just said so.
The Great Nations...
don't understand pain.
Pain? What are you talking about?
Exactly.
You don't know pain, or the suffering
you inflict upon smaller nations.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
But do you understand
that we need to
help each other
in order to get out of here?
Help each other?
I wonder where we are.
An ancient ruin
of the Land of Wind.
This is probably
some underground structure.
You think so too?
It looks difficult to go up that way.
I agree.
Shall we try?
We don't have a choice.
How are your teammates?
What about them?
My teammates aren't suited for
search and rescue...
So I'm not going to
depend on them to find me...
I plan to get out of here
on my own as well...
Oh!
Did you find anything?
No. I thought this was
the entrance to the ruin,
but it's just a boulder.
I heard it rains all year long in
Hidden Rain Village, is that true?
Yes, it is.
I can't even imagine it.
Probably not.
You've had an attitude
all this time.
But you know, you guys
are also to blame
for why we don't know much
about the Hidden Rain.
We are?
Yes.
I've heard that secrecy is
a doctrine of the Hidden Rain.
So it's no wonder that we don't
know anything about you guys.
The only time we
come into contact with you guys
is through something like
the Chunin Exam.
But because this is a test,
instead of talking with each other,
we have to fight.
That's true.
You guys can come to
Konoha
or Hidden Sand Village...
but if we were to go to
the Hidden Rain,
we wouldn't be allowed to enter.
A small nation like the Hidden Rain
must be extremely careful.
There are other small nations too...
The Hidden Rain is a special case.
You're right...
The Hidden Rain Village is special.
The Hidden Rain will be reborn.
Does that mean you'll be more open?
– That's...
– Wait.
Did you hear something?
Is it your teammates?
I doubt that...
I guess not.
What is it?!
It's an ant.
An ant this huge?!
It's so hard!
They don't call this place
the Demon Desert for nothing...
Unreal things live here.
I wonder if there are others?
I hope not...
But these are ants and...
This place is probably
swarming with them.
Let's capture one.
What?
Capture one for what?
To tame it and make it into
a Summoning Creature.
A summoning...
Besides, their nest could be
connected to other openings.
You know how to Summon right?
Yes.
Is there a trick to it?
I wouldn't know.
I guess it's just sheer talent...
Maybe it's beyond here.
I sense a little chakra...
It seems like she's moving,
but I can't tell for sure.
Found you!
This is the 100th time we've met!
This time, you're going to
hand over your scroll to us!
One of them is missing.
Are they operating separately?
Which means it's three against two...
and we have the advantage.
What's with that beat-up umbrella?
What do you think
you can do with that?
Planning to run away again?!
You won't get away this time!
Who are you guys?
Let's make this clear.
Those guys are our prey.
You won't be attacking
these two right now.
We're in the midst of
helping each other.
Helping? The Hidden Rain?
You mean to tell us that
you're Hidden Leaf like us,
and you're getting in our way?
We're all participants in this exam.
If it comes down to it,
we can come after your scroll too.
What?!
You want to fight us?
Don't underestimate us.
After all,
there's only two of you too.
What shall we do, Neji?
I want to avoid fighting
as much as possible,
but we don't have a choice.
So you're going to come at us,
three against two?
No.
You guys!
We'll assist you.
Wh-What's going on with you guys?
You're kidding, right?
You're going to team up
with the Hidden Rain
to fight fellow
Hidden Leaf shinobi?
According to the second test's rules,
being from the same village
has no bearing whatsoever.
If you possess the Earth scroll,
you're fair game.
Fair game?
Th-That's not fair!
If that's the case...
Retreat!
We'll remember this!
We're going to be Chunin,
no matter what!
Why did you help us?
To save our teammates,
we need to cooperate.
Didn't you come to
the same conclusion?
Yeah...
Then let's all work together
to save Tenten and your friend.
It's the nest...
There's no way we can capture one...
Look.
The ant hole
must lead to the outside.
And... you're suggesting
we go right through this?
It looks difficult, doesn't it?
We should go back
to the original corridor.
You're right.
Not good!
Hurry!
Is that an entrance?
You're probably right.
Okay! Hang in there, Tenten!
Hey, Lee!
I'm coming!
There are ridiculously huge ants!
Lee!
We're prey to them.
I'll distract them.
Neji, you guys go in
and find the two.
Got it!
8 Trigrams: Air Palm!
Hurry!
– Right!
Leaf Hurricane!
You're not getting past me!
I guess...
They wouldn't understand
what I'm saying...
They're chasing us.
No way...
It's caved in...
So we can't pass?
Byakugan!
They're in there.
Yeah, that's Ajisai's chakra.
Everyone step aside.
Stop! An explosion
might trigger a cave in.
8 Trigrams: Open Palm!
I suppressed its power
to try to contain it,
but I guess it wasn't effective.
Not much different
than a paper bomb.
What'll we do?
Hey!
What was... that tremor just now?
It's from the outside.
Someone is trying to
clear this rubble.
Your friends?
Or yours.
I wonder if they can do it.
Seems it will be difficult.
They're coming!
Wait.
Summoning Jutsu!
Ward them off.
What are you going to do?
I'm going to transport the debris
to another dimension
with my Transportation Jutsu.
But you don't even know
how much sand and gravel there is!
This is the only thing left to try.
I'll either remove the rubble,
or I'll run out of chakra.
Enclosing Jutsu!
Please, do it too.
Huh?! But I've never
done anything like this...
It's similar to stowing away
weapons and tools.
You say it's similar but...
Come here!
This is impossible!
Do you remember the last Chunin Exam?
– Yeah.
– Yes.
Uh-huh.
The last time,
the Chunin Exam was cancelled
due to unforeseen circumstances.
On top of not being promoted to Chunin,
I was useless during
the Hidden Leaf's most critical moment.
It couldn't be helped.
You were seriously wounded
and unable to take action.
I'm ashamed that I was
perfectly healthy, but helpless.
Well, that shouldn't
bother you now.
After two years, the Chunin Exam
is being held again.
Is that true?
And so, I must at least ask you...
Will the three of you take
this Chunin Exam as a team?
That goes without saying.
Of course, we will!
Uh-huh.
That's the power of youth!
We've grown much stronger
since then!
What's the matter, Tenten?
Are you unsure?
Sensei, have I gotten
stronger since then?
You... should have.
But I have nothing to show for it.
Without a doubt,
you have persevered
and trained since that time.
Admittedly, we can't see it
as we can Neji's jutsu
or Lee's technique.
But do not forget, Tenten.
Hard work and dedication
will never betray you.
Unsealing Jutsu!
Hey! Are you all right?!
– The rubble...
– But...
it's impossible for me to
remove the rubble like you do.
Hurry!
The ants will dig right through it.
I just have to suck it up
and do it!
If hard work and dedication
never betray you...
Then my chakra has increased!
I almost drowned in the desert.
You did it.
Yeah.
Seawater in the desert!
Tenten, you demonstrated
the fruits of your labor.
I sure did, didn't I?!
As expected!
Now then...
We had a truce. So what now?
If you agree,
can we continue this truce?
It's fine with us.
After what we went through,
I don't feel like fighting.
We're going to head straight
for the finish line.
As for us...
Yes...
We'll detour right
and search for a scroll.
Thank you.
Huh?
I think I've got the hang of it,
thanks to you.
Yeah? I'm glad.
Let's both do our best...
... and meet up in the third test.
Yes.
See you again!
The other villages
are very curious.
Yes... There are so many
different kinds of shinobi.
I wonder if Hidden Rain Village
will go through many changes?
We will change it...
By having faith in Lord Pain
and Lady Angel.
– Yeah.
– Yes.
Let's go.
We must continue our search
for a Jinchuriki.