I was totally useless...
In fact, I was just in the way...
Lee, you're always so positive.
Once you work up a sweat,
you can forget about
all the negative stuff, can't you?
I'm just not like that...
This is not sweat.
These are tears of frustration!
This time, at least, I wanted to be useful
and I had prepared so thoroughly for it!
I-I know how you feel.
I wanted to be useful too...
Kakashi-sensei!
- Na-!
- Where's Naruto?!
That's...
Who's that boy?
Probably... the one who can control
the Three-Tails...
He's the one with that special power.
The Three-Tails has disappeared
into the lake,
but this isn't over by any means.
We'll wait for the Sealing Team
to recover,
and then we'll attempt the
Four-Corner Sealing Barrier again.
However...
we can't move this boy right now.
When he regains consciousness,
we'll move to a safer spot
and make preparations.
Meanwhile, we need to find Naruto.
Naruto...
Don't worry.
Knowing Naruto, he's probably in
the lake doing the breaststroke.
Yamato, Sai, Kiba, Hinata...
And me.
The five of us will search for Naruto.
Shizune, you come with us
just in case Naruto is injured.
Right.
Sakura and Ino will treat the boy.
The rest of you will keep guard.
The enemy is sure to return
to reclaim the boy.
I won't let them!
I will protect the boy, no matter what!
Everyone, stay alert and
carry out your mission!
Byakugan!
Naruto...
What if we can't find Naruto,
even with Hinata and Kiba with us?
Listen. I know we just tried to seal the
Three-Tails and it's totally exhausting,
but we have to be extremely careful
with our chakra control.
I know. I'll redeem myself this time.
I'm absolutely going...
to save this boy.
Well then, the least I can do is make sure
your chakra control goes well,
and do some inspirational squats...!
I can't concentrate!
Okay.
We're supposed to be guarding them.
Th-That's right!
It's not smart to stay clustered together.
Shino is here.
Let's go around the back.
What about... me?!
You keep watch from the roof.
Got it!
The insects are drastically weakened...
Is this also due to
the Three-Tails' chakra?
Where is this...?
I know! I was swallowed by
that Three-Tails!
Which means I'm inside its belly...!
It's so hard!
Seriously, its stomach is awful!
What does it eat anyway?
Oh... me...
You're...!
Why you--!
I won't let you have Yuukimaru!
- Yuukimaru is...!
- Die!
Rinji!
Why you-! What's going on?!
Ditching us in the middle of a fight!
We went through hell thanks to you!
Now, now. I got an urgent summons
from Guren, so I had no choice.
Huh? Wh-What?!
Why you--!
Wh-What?!
It's rude to stare like that!
Humph... Things change every second
on the battlefield.
H-Hey!
Quit complaining.
Where are you going?
Rinji...!
Isn't he... acting strange? That Rinji.
He's lost it. Running away
in the face of the enemy.
Who ran away from the enemy?
Uh... no... Well...
Seriously... Quit staring.
You and Rinji... What's with you?
Have you ever looked at
your eyes in the mirror?
They're not eyes that look at humans.
At this rate, you guys will die.
A-Are we that bad?!
Liar!
No! You're just kidding...
I'm not kidding.
You're not?
The flow of chakra is all over the place...
In your case, I'd say you're heading
straight for self-destruction.
Self-destruction?
My, my.
You fought against a terrifying foe...
You, Kihou... In your case,
I'd say... you have less
than two hours left and then... boom!
Are you serious?!
What about me? Am I...?
Stop! I don't want to know
how I'm going to die!
I-I don't want to die!
Please save me, Kabuto!
M-Me too! Please save me!
I don't want to go! No!
No matter how much you beg,
there are things I can and
can't do with my medical ninjutsu...
Ah...
- Huh?!
No... No, I can't.
I can't do such a thing
to my precious comrades!
"Such a thing"?!
Please do "such a thing" to us!
We'll do anything.
We'll endure anything!
I don't want to go "boom"!
Well, since you insist...
- Huh?
He's being used. He believes
there's someone he can return to...
But he's sure to be betrayed.
When that happens...
He won't have anywhere to go...
If wherever someone thinks of you
is the place you return to...
Then...
I'll keep thinking of him.
So Naruto was talking about this boy...
Huh?
Oh...!
Naruto is okay. I'm sure he's somewhere
thinking about this boy...
Where am I?
It's okay. We're going to protect you
from now on.
Protect...?
It's gone! It's gone!
What's wrong?
Is something missing?
It's gone...!
Gone...!
Gone... Gone...!
This is...
That's...
Yuukimaru...?
Then... Then... you're...
I...
I'm forgiven?
Have you...
You have the gall to ask such a thing
after killing someone...
Forgive you...?
No...!
Absolutely not!
Stop... Please stop...!
I...
My wound...
Did you treat it?
What's the big idea?
What are you scheming?!
Nothing...!
Don't lie!
Your enemy lies unconscious!
Why would you, a ninja,
pass up the chance to...!
I wouldn't do a shameful thing like hurting
someone who's unable to fight!
Where's Yuukimaru?!
He's not close by.
Back then, I think we were the only two
that Three-Tails swallowed.
Then Yuukimaru is still by the lake...
Either your people got him...
or one of my comrades saved him.
Then I have to get out of here
immediately and find out.
So it's imperative that we fight.
I'm going to defeat you
and get out of here.
You won't leave here...
unless you can defeat me.
That's true...
I was just thinking the same thing...
But...
Huh?
Wh-What...?
Huge bugs...?!
They're... miniature Three-Tails!
Argh!
What are you doing?!
I'll use my Crystal Style...!
You can't! Remember?
Not with that injury!
Let go!
I can run by myself!
It's gone...! Gone!
What's the matter?
What are you looking for?
Found it! I found it!
See!
It's a pretty crystal...
It's not even scratched...
I'm so glad. Guren is all right.
Guren...?
Could it be the person Naruto spoke of,
the one this boy thinks of?
Oh...!
Are you all right?!
Guren is all right.
This boy... What's with...
He's being used.
He believes there's someone
he can return to...
But he's sure to be betrayed.
Are you all right?
Why?
Why are you trying to help me?
I don't fight an injured enemy...
You could've left me for
those Three-Tails back there...
That would've been disgusting to watch!
You're... naïve...
Humph!
Had it been me, you'd be dead by now.
And I'd leave this place...
and look for Yuukimaru.
You want Yuukimaru that badly?
For Orochimaru's sake?!
Well, what about you guys?
You discovered Yuukimaru's power
and now you want him for yourselves!
After all, taking the Three-Tails
means that the Hidden Leaf Village
will be in possession of
enormous military power.
We don't need such a thing!
Liar! The Hidden Leaf already
has the Nine-Tails
as well as the Jinchuriki!
People like you with that kind of power
have no right...
to criticize Lord Orochimaru...
or us!
I'm that Jinchuriki!
Wha--?!
But I...
don't use this power.
The Nine-Tails has this incredible power
that I can't control with my own strength.
I've hurt my comrades before
I even realized it happened...
That's why... I don't use its power.
If I hadn't told him such a thing...
The place where someone thinks of you,
that's where home is.
So if someone is thinking about me,
then that's the place I go back to?
You told him?
But no matter how much someone
thinks of him...
If you're going to use Yuukimaru
for Orochimaru's sake...
to make him control the Three-Tails...
That's not right.
I don't want Yuukimaru to get near
a Tailed Beast.
If he becomes like me...
No! I won't let Yuukimaru do
such a thing.
I don't believe you.
He needs a place to return to.
When his mother died,
Yuukimaru lost the place to return to...
So I'm taking her place...!
You should talk!
You're a follower of Orochimaru.
I have to show Yuukimaru that you're not
the person he should to return to!
Then that's fine!
But... for me...
that boy...
Yuukimaru is...
the place for me to return to!
You...
Anyway...
this isn't the place
to argue about that.
While you were unconscious,
I took a look around.
It's really complex in there and
I couldn't find anything like an exit.
But if we split up and search...
Split up?
You and me... The two of us...?
More than that. We need a thousand guys.
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
You three are ordered to take
Yuukimaru away from the Hidden Leaf.
Resort to any means necessary
in order to succeed.
That power...
go and enjoy it
until you're satisfied.
Naruto...!
Naruto...
Here's to the First Naruto Cup Challenge!
The "Let's-Get-Out-of-This-Crazy-Place:
Find-an-Exit" Contest!
Let's do it!
- Yeah!
In your positions!
Ready, set...!
Go!
With this many guys searching,
finding the exit is a cinch!
All right! I'll find it!
No, I will!
Whatever I do, I have to get out...
and find Yuukimaru...
Yahoo!
I know!
I know where Guren is!
Huh?
I'm sure Naruto is with her!
They're in the Three-Tails' tummy!
Huh!
They're so excited...
just like a kid...
I feel so happy.
Yeah, almost like it's not me.
My fatigue's completely gone.
Not only that...
It's as though I'm filled with strength...
Listen, we've got to get
Yuukimaru away from the Leaf,
no matter what it takes.
You worry too much, Four-Eyes.
Right now,
I feel like I can't lose to anyone!
Not even Guren!
Do what you can.
Not that I'm expecting much...
Is that story true?
According to this child, Yuukimaru,
Guren the Crystal Style User is alive...
He says that she and Naruto
were swallowed by the Three-Tails.
The fact that we've searched this much
and still haven't found him means
that story may have
some truth to it...
But how do you know
that Guren is okay?
Guren made this for me.
If something happens to Guren
this will break as well...
I see.
That's proof that Guren is okay,
but it doesn't mean that Naruto is okay.
That's true.
No one knows what the inside
of the Three-Tails' stomach is like.
Even if he is okay, Naruto is
with that Crystal Style user, right?
It's possible that the two
have already fought each other
and settled things.
Then Naruto is...
Right now, those assumptions
are meaningless.
We need to believe he's still alive
and find the Three-Tails first.
I'll... look for it...
Can you find it? The Three-Tails...
Yes... I don't know for sure...
but I sense it...
But what'll we do after
we find the Three-Tails?
I'll seal it once more.
All right. We'll try to rescue Naruto
while you're doing that.
In the event the Three-Tails
becomes violent,
Yamato, bring Shino with you
in case Guren is with Naruto.
Sai, you're on aerial standby.
The rest of you will guard
the surrounding area.
We're up against Kabuto...
no telling what he might do.
Look after Naruto.
Right...
You guys be careful, too.
Shino!
Let's get going.
Understood.
Okay, everyone!
We're the Sealing Team.
Let's move quietly from the very back,
so we don't agitate the Three-Tails, okay?
- Right!
Naruto...
What's the matter?
They've been attacked...
every one of my clones.
What...?
That sound... It's them.
This is bad. We're outnumbered...
What...?
There was one that huge, too?!
No choice but to fight.
Can you fight in your condition?!
Then where's a way to escape?!
You're right, there isn't one.
Crystal Style: Hexagonal Shuriken!
You see! No effect at all.
I'll be the decoy, so run when
you get the chance, okay?!
Here I go!
Take this!
Guren!
Heh! How do you like that?!
- Are you all right?
- Uh... yeah.
Damn...
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Get on my back right now!
I can't do that!
Why not?!
Because... my... pride...
Fool! This is no time for
troublesome talk like that!
Put me down, you idiot!
Stay still!
Hurry up!
Right!
Yes!
I wonder if things are going all right
for Sakura and the others.
That's assuming Naruto is even okay.
Of course, he's okay.
Because he's the person
I want to have an all-out match
with one day.
What is it, Akamaru?
Seems our enemy is
making its appearance.
Good timing.
I was just getting fired up!
I'll express my feelings for Naruto
with my fists!
You people again?!
You knew it was us?
You can hide your shape and smell,
but you can't hide your bloodlust.
I won't lose to an opponent
I've beaten once before!
Don't underestimate us.
We're not the same as we were before!
Dark Smoke Sphere!
We can't get near them... like this.
We won't lose
in the barrage of grenades!
You are so naïve...
My kunai...
Appear!
Smoke Dragon!
What's the matter?
They're here... under us...
Okay. Sealing Team, get ready!
Wait...
There's no way out.
Guren and Naruto are
looking for a way out.
A way out?
If we open up a hole from the outside,
that'll be their way out.
What's going on?
First, we'll have to see what's
at the bottom of the lake.
Camellias...
Bring me a lot of camellia blossoms...
Camellias?
Why did you save me?
That was my line!
Because if you died now,
there was no way I could survive.
What? You're relying on me?
Hey, how is your wound?
Don't touch me!
Once we're out of here,
you and I are enemies!
Suit yourself.
But I'm not handing over Yuukimaru.
Why are you so protective of Yuukimaru?
I told you before.
Regardless of your reasons for
your loyalty to Orochimaru,
he is evil.
He's probably using you.
Like him.
Him?
Either way... a place with you
and Orochimaru,
is not a home Yuukimaru should return to.
I'll go and take a quick look up ahead.
Since my clones can't do surveillance.
Damn... this looks really deep...
Guess we have no choice.
Fog...?
This is bad!
Is it them again?!
What?!
Hey, who's there?!
What are you doing...?
It can't be...
Sasuke! What are you doing here?
Stop it, Sasuke!
I have something to tell you!
Stop it!
Sasuke!
This is the Three-Tails' fog...
I see...
This fog shows illusions of
the weakness in the souls
of the people who stand
within in it...
If I stand inside it,
I will have to face them, as well...
Sasuke, stop it!
You're...!
I've...
I've done something to you
that I can never make amends for...
I want you to forgive me...
Even if it's meaningless now,
I will protect your child to the end,
even if it costs me my life!
Sasuke...
You have a place to return to!
Did you forget about that?!
Listen, Sasuke!
Let go! Let go of me!
Pull yourself together, Naruto!
What you're seeing is an illusion!
What?
You saved me.
You saw Sasuke Uchiha?
Yeah...
You know Sasuke?
I met him at Lord Orochimaru's place.
He's a scary guy.
Is he okay?
Is he doing well?
Uh, yeah... Why do you ask?
Isn't it obvious?!
He's one of us!
I have to bring him back and
tell Sasuke that he has
a place to return to!
You... Are you seriously intending
to bring Sasuke back?
Of course!
That...
Sasuke...?
This guy must be a real fool.
Of all the crazy things,
he wants to save Sasuke...?
What's so funny?
I've never met such a fool!
Where did that come from?
You're splitting my sides! Really...
Hey, are you all right?!
So that's the entrance to
the dimension Yuukimaru mentioned.
If we tear that membrane,
we'd create a way out...
Now!
Lightning Blade!
What? The fog lifted...
Could it be flowing outside?
Wha--?! When did they...?!
Now there's no way to escape.
Damn! Not again...!
They sure are persistent!
One more strike!
Come back, Naruto!
We're ready!
Let's do it now!
Naruto, there's something
I have to tell you.
What is it?
This isn't a good time.
Remember I told you that
Yuukimaru's mother is dead?
Yeah.
I'm the one... who killed her.
What did you just say?
At the time, Lord Orochimaru was
trying to build the Sound Village.
I attacked Yuukimaru's village
on his orders.
But I collapsed there after
exhausting my powers.
That woman...
saved my life,
even though I was her enemy.
Get away...
I'll close my eyes to this if you go now.
Are you planning to betray me, Guren?
But...
I... I...
Out of my desire to be accepted
by Lord Orochimaru...
I killed her...
I had sealed away the memories
and emotions of that moment.
But when I met Yuukimaru,
they all came back to me.
Is that why you protect Yuukimaru...?
As you said...
I hurt Yuukimaru's soul in a way
that I could never make amends.
I have no right to protect him...
Guren...
It's over for me!
But I will protect you
even if it costs me my life!
You must survive!
Please look after Yuukimaru.
It's weird hearing that from you!
Whatever happened in the past,
you're different now!
You...
Camellia?
Yuukimaru...?
He's trying to show us the way out!
Look out!
Okay, now!
I won't let you die in a place like this!
We're going back together!
Still nothing...
Could it have failed?
No, there definitely was an impact.
But nothing's happening...
Hinata, can you see anything?
N-No... Not even with my Byakugan...
Naruto... Naruto won't come back?
Did it reach Naruto?
Furthermore, it seems to have awakened
the Three-Tails.
Shizune!
Sealing team!
Standby for the Three-Tails!
Right!
Sai!
Take Yuukimaru to a safe place.
Right!
- Let's go.
- No!
I'm staying here until Guren returns!
I'm sure she's all right.
Huh?
We're all thinking of Naruto,
that's why he'll return here.
If you think of her, Guren will return too.
No doubt about it.
Now then...
Okay.
Go!
We will begin
the Four-Corner Sealing Jutsu.
Four-Corner Sealing Barrier...
Bind!
The challenge starts now...
Until the Sealing Team
contains the Three-Tails,
it's up to us to suppress it.
Now then, we'll see just how well
my Wood Style works
against the Three-Tails.
All we can do is try...
We'll wait here. All right?
Okay.
Drink... It will ease your fatigue.
You can tell what I'm thinking...
Everyone tells me that
I can't read their moods.
I doubt that. Really...
Dark Smoke Sphere
Stay hidden, okay?
Okay.
Water Shield Shot!
Hide-and-seek, eh?
I've come for you, boy.
I've been able to determine
Yuukimaru's potential
and the limit of his power.
However, the Hidden Leaf are trying
to seal the Three-Tails once again...
If by any chance, they are successful
in sealing the Three-Tails...
When Sasuke achieves
the skills he needs...
The time for my reanimation will be near.
When that happens,
both the Akatsuki and Leaf Village
will be a hindrance.
Our current operation is preparation
for when that happens.
We won't have to worry about
the Akatsuki using
the power of the Three-Tails, but...
It will force a big change
in Lord Orochimaru's future strategy.
We must avoid that...
If I use this, we may lose Yuukimaru...
However, rather than lose
the Three-Tails...
Never mind... if I lose Yuukimaru!
I'll use Yuukimaru's remaining power
to make the Three-Tails go wild,
and destroy the Leaf ninja...!
Where's Kabuto...?
Huh, I heard everything.
So Four-Eyes isn't here?
So there's no one to give us orders...
We're not the same as before.
There's no need to hang
around you anymore...
Well, it looks that way...
You guys are so easygoing.
What...?
You're just cast-offs...
pawns who have outlived their usefulness.
And you don't even know that
I've got you in a vital spot.
Say that again!
You're not one of us anymore!
Want to settle it now?
Settle?
What?! What's so funny?!
It's about time!
What...?! My body feels strange...
I can't stop shaking...
Hey, what's happening?!
Fools!
You should know that
there's a risk to attaining power!
I heard your power has
some side effects!
Side effects...?!
Yeah...
And left alone, it will eat you up
from the inside out.
N-No... I don't want that to happen!
N-No way... I don't want to die!
Unless you get the antidote from Kabuto
before the time runs out,
you'll destroy yourselves
with your own power!
Kabuto entrusted the drug to me.
If you say you won't betray
Lord Orochimaru,
I just may give it to you.
All right. I swear my loyalty.
H-Hurry... give me the antidote.
Know this! No matter how hard you try,
you will never be able to escape
Lord Orochimaru's grasp.
Kabuto said this...
We've stopped
the Three-Tails' movements.
And he wants to see that
power once more.
No!
When I take that medicine,
my head feels like it's going to burst...
Shut up! You will not refuse!
Guren hasn't come back yet!
And maybe, she never will!
Do you want that?!
No... No!
Then stop whining and do as you're told!
O-Okay... One more time.
Just one more time...
Yeah... this is the last time.
Here it comes...
Is that from Sai?
It seems Guren's subordinates have
powered up and attacked Sai.
Huh?!
Any word from Kiba and the rest?
No, not yet.
No way...
Akamaru, you saved me...
If we hadn't hidden underground
due to your quick thinking...
Lee... Tenten...?
They couldn't have...!
Thank you, Akamaru... I'm okay.
You're all okay.
Not at all.
If I didn't summon a protection Wall
from my scroll,
we'd have been goners...
Lee was no help, rushing in like that...
I-I'm mortified...
And after Guy-sensei always warned me that
overconfidence is a ninja's greatest enemy...
I didn't expect it...
That they'd be so strong.
No...
That transformation isn't normal.
We must notify everyone!
Yes...
This fog... We're already in their trap...
Protect the Sealing team!
Right!
Dark Smoke Sphere!
Water Shield Shot!
- Yamato!
- Right!
Wood Style: Giant Forest!
You...! Stop getting in my way!
Wood Style: Giant Forest Jutsu!
Parasitic Insects!
What? Hey, stop!
Nooo!
What's wrong, Akamaru?!
Everyone, stop!
Something's strange here.
The enemy?!
No... This is...
It doesn't look like the enemy at all...
Tenten! You can tell
what Akamaru is feeling?!
Sai!
This is the Three-Tails' fog...
The sealing isn't complete yet.
It's coming...! It's coming!
Gather your chakra!
- Yes!
- Right!
Cha!
Here it comes!
Swallow it, Yuukimaru.
Huh?!
Swallow all of it!
You want Guren to return, don't you?
Okay, I'll do it.
Because my home is wherever Guren is...
I made it back...
Feeling pain means I'm still alive.
Naruto...
Wake up! Naruto!
Yuukimaru... you're okay?
This is no time to be sleep-talking!
We made it back...?
Yeah...
Yuukimaru... Where's Yuukimaru?!
Multi-Smoke Clone.
No... Stop!
It tickles...
What?!
Oh dear... Your cute little bugs
are all crushed now.
Well, time for the main event.
Here I come!
This is interesting...
I'll take that!
Arise Smoke Dragon!
Like Sai reported...
they're completely different from before.
Sh-Shizune-senpai...!
Ino has reached her limit... But...
Ino! Just hang in there!
Shizune...
No way! Not that power again!
Yuukimaru!
Wh-What is this?!
The enemy's jutsu?!
A-A slug...?!
It's Katsuyu,
summoned by Lady Tsunade.
- I'm sorry.
- Forgive me.
Why are you here?
You came to help us, Katsuyu?
Lady Tsunade has
been concerned about
the effectiveness of the Sealing Jutsu
against the Tailed Beast.
She sent me to bring you
the chakra for the Sealing jutsu.
That will be a big help.
Let me distribute it to you.
Please do.
Very well...
That Tsunade!
She sent Katsuyu...
Crap... More!
More power! Yuukimaru!
Naruto!
What is it?
Will I be forgiven...?
I mean... Will he forgive me?
When Yuukimaru finds out that
I'm the one who killed his mother?
Sheesh! Are you still
mulling over that?
I'm prepared to protect Yuukimaru.
If I were you,
I'd keep thinking about him!
Even if I'm despised,
or rejected, or hated!
Whether or not... he thinks of me
as his home...
has nothing to do with it!
I'd keep on thinking about him.
Yeah, you're right!
Then, I'll be a fool too...
just like you, Naruto.
What?!
Let's hurry!
Yuukimaru!
I feel the power of the Three-Tails
beneath the water's surface...
I-It's enormous... I feel like
the chakra will explode any minute.
Th-This much?
Without Katsuyu's chakra,
my power alone wouldn't have been enough...
Listen! If the Three-Tails falls into
the hands of Orochimaru
or the Akatsuki...
It will be disastrous
for the Hidden Leaf...
But the Three-Tails is
in our hands right now...
The only ones who can protect
our comrades in Hidden Leaf Village
from this power are us!!
- Right!
Katsuyu... Can you increase
your chakra even further?
Yes... I will try.
We'll send it to the other dimension
in one go.
R-Right.
Th-They're still trying to
control the Three-Tails.
Yuukimaru, unleash the power
of the Three-Tails! Make it go wild!
Trample the Hidden Leaf!
Sai, did they attack you too?
Yeah...
They got Yuukimaru!
This is...?
No doubt about it! It's them!
Wait!
Wh-What are you doing?!
It's time to get revenge!
If we jump in now, there's a chance
we'll hit each other with friendly fire.
Yeah, even Akamaru's sense of smell
will be useless.
We must wait and see.
Oh man! This is so frustrating!
It seems the enemy is using
Yuukimaru to control the Three-Tails.
At this rate, Shizune's Sealing team
is in danger.
It's a touchy situation...
Countering all these clones
is impossible!
It's no good!
I can't dodge them all!!
It's about time...
Binding Smoke Prison!
To think that I would have the chance
to personally bring down
the renowned Kakashi of the Hidden Leaf.
It was worth surviving just for this...
Wha--?!
Although not to your extent, I use
Shadow Clones too.
Lightning Blade!
This is bad.
They have a saying about smoke
and fools liking high places.
Smoke Dragon!
The Wood Style is useless
against smoke,
since it can change form at will.
Then, I must adapt my style...
Water Style: Hand of Waves!
What?
Smoke is a vapor, so by
liquefying it with water...
it can't be controlled freely.
Not against me and my Water Style.
Your jutsu is meaningless now.
Take this!
Don't forget that I have a third arm.
Playtime is over.
It's useless!
Spindle Formation!
Why... Why?!
Your jutsu was quite effective
against my insects.
However... the cause of your defeat
lies in the fact that you fought with
Hinata of the Hyuga Clan.
To explain...
Hinata, I need to speak with you.
Shino, what's wrong?
Any little thing will do.
Can you tell me anything about
that Crystal Style user?
Unfortunately, her jutsu is flawless.
If I hadn't covered my body with chakra
in time... I would have been...
Speaking of chakra covering
the entire body...!
Shino, watch out for that slimy guy!
He will be a formidable opponent
for you.
Why is that?
His body is his jutsu.
That bodysuit is filled with chakra
and he's able to
change his form at will.
I used my Gentle Fist against him
and he just twisted his body away.
He countered your Gentle Fist...
The problem was the body fluid that
got on my hand when I grazed him.
The enemy's entire body is covered
with a sticky mucus.
I had prior data, so from the start...
I concentrated on scraping that
troublesome mucus from your body.
Since we started...?!
Yes! I focused my attacks on making
that mucous membrane
as thin as possible so that it would
break easily.
That is all.
It's over...?
Yes...
It took some time but...
Kakashi-sensei!
You're all okay...
What about you guys?
Well... we made it somehow.
But what about Naruto?
We haven't found him yet.
I'm sorry about Yuukimaru...
Now then, we'll head out
to assist the Sealing team.
- Yes!
- Right!
We will also recover and protect Yuukimaru!
But first, we'll see how
the Sealing team is doing.
They seem to be in a difficult battle...
This time, for sure...
This time... the Three-Tails...
Ino... you don't need to rush it.
Just focus your mind on
stabilizing your chakra.
Y-Yes...
No good... It's not enough.
Damn it! It's not working!
Is that all there is
to Yuukimaru's power?!
This isn't going to work anymore.
Then I'll have to resort...
to my final measure.
You'll die for Lord Orochimaru's sake.
Here!
Yuukimaru!
Are you all right?
So you guys were alive after all...
Snap out of it! What happened?
Hey Yuukimaru! Wake up!
Yuukimaru!
You came back after all, Guren...
because I was thinking of you.
Wherever someone is thinking of you,
that's the place to return to...
Yes... that's right.
You were thinking of me,
that's why I was able to come back.
Uh-huh...
When I was trapped in
that other dimension
inside the Three-Tails,
all I thought about was you...
That's why you have to
return to me too, Yuukimaru...
I'm so happy.
I'm coming back to you, Guren...
You're the only one I can return to.
Yeah, right.
That's the only place left for you...
Since you can't go running back
to your mother's arms anymore.
Stop! Just shut up.
No, let me just say this...
Listen!! Yuukimaru!
I said to shut up!
It's all right, Naruto...
But...
It's all right! You taught me...
Guren...
So you're prepared...?
How noble. Listen, Yuukimaru!
The one who stole your home from you...
The one who turned the white camellia
red with your mother's blood...
The one who killed your mother
is that woman...
Guren!
Guren is actually an evil demon!
She hid the fact that
she killed your mother,
and got close to you, winning your trust...
just so she could use you.
And she has continued to use you!
Yuukimaru! Don't you hate her?!
Don't you want to kill her?
No one will stop you...
I certainly won't!
Now take your anger out
on the Three-Tails!
And order the Three-Tails
to destroy everything!
Why you...!
Shut up!
Guren...
I'm sorry... Yuukimaru.
What he says is true.
Please listen to me, Yuukimaru.
The Guren of the past committed
many terrible sins
in order to serve Orochimaru.
But Guren is different now!
She regrets all the things in her past.
She's filled with regret!
And no matter what happens,
she will protect you!
No matter how much
you may hate her,
she will keep on thinking about you.
She swore that to me.
I fully realize that no matter
how much I may regret it,
no matter how many times
I say I'm sorry
nothing will ever erase what I did.
If you wish me dead, then kill me.
I won't resist.
But... but if you can forgive me...
I will protect you forever.
Guren...
You're not going to hate me?
You're a nice person Guren...
You are the one
I should return to, after all...
And I'm the one
you should return to, Guren.
I promise you...
I will never leave your side.
I will always think of you.
Uh-huh... And I will
always think of you, Guren.
For now, and forever...
And ever... I love you.
Yeah, me too.
The two of you...
Don't ever be parted again!
What a farce... You weaklings
can lick each other's wounds...
But a bond like that will break easily!
What...?!
Kabuto! You...!
Naruto...
If you get in the way,
I'll kill you too.
Kabuto! You're behind all of this?!
You won't get away with it!
Everyone... The seal will
be complete very shortly.
Maintain your focus until it's over!
- Right!
What is that?!
Tenten! There's a monster behind us!
- Huh?!
What is that?!
Kakashi-senpai! Is that...?
What a persistent bunch.
It's my turn to pay them back for earlier!
Lee, physical attacks
won't work on that slime monster.
Neither will my insects...
Man, what a pain.
Perhaps we should leave this
to the two Jonin.
I wonder if this is
what you'd call "gross".
- We'll torment you...!
Huh?!
They sure are... Gross.
What happened to Rinji?!
Rinji became part of
my collection, long ago.
What?!
He was such a nuisance...
Continue... eh?
I'd be happy to be the one
reporting to Lord Orochimaru...
You?
I've done many things
for you as your spy.
Lord Orochimaru doesn't need
anyone besides me to serve him.
Damn it! So it's all going
as you planned...
Yes... Lord Orochimaru is
an amazing man.
Everything has gone as he predicted.
Guren and Yuukimaru's hearts
have become linked so strongly
that they trust each other
to be the place to return to.
Now, if this close bond is
shattered by their fatal relations
Yuukimaru's anger would
release an explosive force.
That was supposed to be the case...
However, even when he learned that
Guren killed his mother...
Yuukimaru's anger did not explode.
Why...? Why is that?!
The human heart is
such a strange thing, isn't it?
You... are unforgivable!
Toying with Guren and Yuukimaru like that...
You don't play with people's feelings!
Just what are you guys aiming to do?!
It's not only the Hidden Leaf
and the Akatsuki...
but all the Hidden Villages
will soon erupt into a great war.
Lord Orochimaru has his eyes
on that violent future...
That was the reason for
the Three-Tails... for Yuukimaru.
That's all gibberish to me.
Guren!
Go with Yuukimaru!
Show me you can protect him!
I will! I'll protect him with my life!
I won't let you pass.
I'm going to kick your ass!
Dead Soul Jutsu!
Guren...
Rinji!
I promise I'll protect
you. I will not fail.
Guren!
Crystal Style: Crimson Fruit!
Don't worry. I'll be right back,
so you wait here.
Huh?!
Wait here.
I will come back for you no matter what.
Don't go! Guren, you're the only one
I have to return to!
Don't worry. I won't die.
What?!
It's useless.
Crystals are formed when
identical polyhedrons
are aligned in a uniform pattern.
I can stop the crystals from forming
by vibrating the air
with the bats' ultrasonic waves.
Yes... Your Crystal Style
was never a threat to me.
Didn't I tell you it's useless?
You're troublesome
even when you're dead.
After Guren,
it's you... Yuukimaru.
Huh?!
No you don't!
I will protect Yuukimaru with my life!
Guren!
Your Crystal Style...
won't work anymore.
Nothing works against the dead.
Now you can't manipulate
your bats, can you?
Crystal Style...
What--?!
Return to the underworld quietly!
Guren!
No...!
Don't go!
The jutsu is broken!
That... can't be...! You said you'd...
You said you'd protect Yuukimaru...!
Yuukimaru!
The Three-Tails will be
getting tired soon...
Then we'll finish it at once.
What?!
Where is the Three-Tails
getting all this strength?
I'm not sure, but it seems
its chakra suddenly increased.
Yamato, use your Wood Style
to restrain it.
I will deliver the finishing blow.
Right.
Lightning Blade!
Kakashi-senpai.
Yeah.
Find the Sealing Team
and rescue them!
- Right!
Three-Tails!
The moment he lost Guren,
with whom he shared a strong bond...
the latent power in Yuukimaru
was released.
To think that the sadness of losing
the place he should return to
would be this powerful...
Yuukimaru! Stop...!
It's no good!
Huh?! Yuukimaru!
Can you hear me, Yuukimaru?!
It's me! Naruto!
Please snap out of it...
Yuukimaru!
Damn it!
Calm down!
Yuukimaru...
Kill them all! Destroy them!
I'll have to stop it.
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Let's do it!
Damn it! My Rasengan doesn't work!
And yet, I can't use
the Wind Style: Rasen Shuriken.
But what I can do...
Summoning Jutsu!
Bro! That's the Three-Tails, right?
It seems things have
gotten out of hand.
I wouldn't call you guys otherwise.
Gamatatsu, get ready for
the Toad Water Pistol!
Right.
Wait, Gamatatsu!
Huh?
What is it?! We're in a hurry here!
Think hard. The opponent is
a turtle-like beast that lives in the lake.
Even if you increase the power
with the Wind Style,
what will be the effect of using
the Toad Water Pistol,
which is a Water Style Jutsu?
To beat a Water Style,
you need the Earth Style.
If we keep stalling,
the terrain around here will change!
I only have the Wind Style
so we have no choice--!
Wind Style?!
So I'm a good match
with Sasuke, huh?
Yes, only wind can defeat lightning.
No, that's not what I meant.
I mean only the power of wind
can help fire
by making it even more powerful.
Fire Style.
What about the Fire Style?
If we had Fire Style, my wind could...
I can use it.
Huh...?! You can use Fire Style?!
Yeah, I can!
Why didn't you say that sooner?!
You didn't ask!
And? What about the Fire Style?
Oh, Fire Style...
What is it?
Damn it! I thought it was
a good idea...
So just tell me what's going on.
No... I thought we could
help the "Fire"
and make it stronger with my wind.
But fire is weak against water.
I see! If the Water Style is
stronger than the fire,
we'll just create a fire so strong
it evaporates the water.
Huh?!
Hey, Gamatatsu!
What is it, Bro?
Go back to the village and drink
all the Toad oil you can!
Okay? You have one minute!
I will summon you back in one minute.
Gotcha!
I get it! If you use oil instead of
water to fire the Toad Water Pistol,
the oil will spread everywhere...
Then you'll set the oil on fire
with your Fire Style.
That's right.
We can use the same timing
as the Toad Water Pistol
and we won't need to practice first!
All right! This'll work!
Yuukimaru!
Guren... That promise
you couldn't keep...
I swear I'll keep your promise for you!
Naruto! It's been one minute!
Right!
Summoning Jutsu!
Did you have enough time?
Uh-huh.
Just about.
Mmm, we're ready, Naruto!
Yeah!
All right! We'll use
this new collaboration jutsu...
and aim for its face!
Its weak point is the eyes!
All right, are we set?!
It's do-or-die!
Failure is not an option.
Right, Bro.
Let's do it, Gamatatsu!
Okay!
Collaboration Jutsu!
Wind Style: Toad Flame Bombs!
Now!
We did it! It worked, Bro.
Yeah... You did a good job.
Looks like it's over for now.
Well then, we'll be going.
Yeah... Thanks.
See you.
Yuukimaru!
Yuukimaru...
Let's go home together.
Oww!
Try to bear with it.
This should ease the pain a bit.
Thank you, Sakura...
The wound is deep.
I'll do what I can here...
Sakura...
How is Yuukimaru doing?
Shizune-senpai and the others
are tending to him now.
This is terrible. His chakra network is...
Yes, he's suffered a lot of damage...
Even with treatment,
it would be impossible
to restore him completely.
It seems the power to control
the Three-Tails took quite a toll
on Yuukimaru's body.
The jutsu shortened his life...?
Yes.
I can't be certain until we conduct
a thorough examination,
but it's likely that Yuukimaru no longer
has the powers he once had.
We've now lost our only chance
of controlling the Three-Tails...
Perhaps, for this child,
it's better that way...
Shizune, how is Yuukimaru?
He'll live. He's still asleep...
Thank goodness he made it.
Yeah...
But...
I wasn't able to help him
at all in the end...
What?
I foolishly told him
"wherever someone thinks
about you is your home..."
But right before his eyes,
he lost that very home.
That wasn't your fault.
But still...
You are the one I should return to,
after all...
And I'm the one
you should return to, Guren.
I promise you...
I will never leave your side.
I will always think of you.
Uh-huh...
And I will always think of you, Guren.
From now, and forever...
Naruto...
I'm sorry. Yuukimaru...
And that is the situation, Lady Tsunade.
I see... I understand.
Katsuyu, order everyone to return.
Are you sure?
We have no choice.
It would be impossible for them
to continue their mission.
Now that the child has lost his powers,
Orochimaru can no longer
do anything to the Tailed Beast.
We'll pull back for now, regroup,
and come up with a new plan.
But Orochimaru is not the only one
who is after the Three-Tails...
I'm perfectly aware of that.
But the Three-Tails is an adversary
that has given us
a great deal of trouble up to this point.
Even the Akatsuki won't
have an easy time.
I'll send ninja to
replace them immediately.
Once they arrive,
have them tell everyone to withdraw!
Right away.
Those are Lady Tsunade's orders.
Understood.
We'll inform everyone immediately.
We have new orders from Lady Hokage.
We will abort our current mission.
Our orders are to return to
the village immediately.
- What?
- Huh?!
That was sudden.
Hey come on! Is it really okay
to just leave the Three-Tails?
We won't have to worry about that.
They're sending ninja to replace us
and maintain the watch.
But still...!
There's nothing we can do
even if we remain here.
Everyone has suffered too many wounds.
Lady Tsunade has decided that
it would be more effective
if we brought back the information
we've gained this time around
and apply it to our next plan.
We'll move out tomorrow morning.
I want you all to get a good night's rest
before we move out.
Guren...
Gozu?
Why are you...
Why are you saving me...?
Do you remember... that day?
I was placed in solitary after losing
control during Orochimaru's experiment...
I was hardly given any water
or food to speak of.
I was on the verge of dying from thirst.
Then you came and kindly gave me
a ladleful of water.
Because of that, I was able to survive.
Ever since that day, I...
I don't even remember.
I must've been feeling generous.
Even if that were so,
I've always admired you since then...
Guren...
O-Ow...
Huh?!
Yuukimaru?!
Damn!
Senpai.
Damn! Where could he have gone?!
His body's...
in no condition to...!
Yuukimaru!
Where are you, Yuukimaru?!
Damn! It's my fault...!
Yuukimaru...
This is...!
Why would he leave behind something
as important as...?
There isn't even a single crack...
I see. So that's it...
Yuukimaru disappeared?
How could he even move
in his condition?
Hey, Naruto.
You were in the room with him.
Didn't you notice?
No, I guess not.
Huh?! How can you call yourself
a ninja?!
Just what you'd expect from a Genin!
Shut up!
You were asleep, too, you know!
Why you...!
Don't put me in the same league
as a stamina freak like you!
Arguing won't do any good!
But I'm worried about Yuukimaru.
He has nowhere to go, and...
We can't just ignore him!
Let's all look for him!
I agree!
That won't be necessary.
The reason is...
because a child who lost his power
to control the Three-Tails
is no longer a threat to us.
That's not the issue here!
No, Shino is right.
We're under no obligation to look
for a child who ran away.
And besides,
we've been ordered to return.
But that's...!
Are you okay with that, Naruto?!
Yeah, there's nothing to worry about.
He can handle himself.
Naruto...?
We'd better be on our way.
Sorry to keep you waiting Kakashi.
I was hoping we could have caused
some trouble for the Akatsuki...
I'm sorry. I didn't count on
the Leaf ninja interfering.
And so, did that woman...
Guren die?
Regretfully, yes.
She possessed very interesting powers...
As if you mean that...
Maybe you were the one who killed her?
Heaven forbid.
Well, never mind.
We can find any number of replacements
for someone of her ability.
But Yuukimaru...
Leave it.
At this point...
Lord Orochimaru!
I'll bring your medicine right away!
That host body has reached its limit...
At this point, it has lost all meaning...
Because soon,
I will possess his body...
What's the matter, Naruto?
No, it's nothing...
Wow, it feels like I hadn't
been back in ages.
We had one mission after another...
Dinner tonight is at Ichiraku!
Say, Naruto.
Huh?
About Yuukimaru...
Are you sure it was best that way?
You used to worry so much about him.
That's okay.
Besides, even if we went looking for him,
he wouldn't be easy to find anyway.
What do you mean?
The Pervy Sage's words
were true, after all.
He said wherever someone cares
about you is the place you return to.
If you believe, and keep thinking,
about that person...
your feelings will surely
reach them, he said.
What? Is this... what I think it is?
So... we should keep thinking, too.
We need to create a place
that Sasuke can return to.
Right.