I finally caught up.
What should we do,
Lord Momoshiki?
I thought it would just
be a fool's errand...
Well then, why don't we go
greet our visitor?
Kaguya Otsutsuki...
With her warped hunger for power,
she tried to enslave
the entire world.
During the Great Ninja War,
we were able to seal Kaguya away...
after so many sacrificed their lives.
– Six Paths Planetary Devastation!
However, she wasn't acting
merely out of greed for power.
What was the true reason
for her vigilance?
I've been searching for
the answer ever since...
I didn't think that anyone else
could enter this place besides us.
I am Kinshiki Otsutsuki.
Prepare yourself!
A stone statue?
He switched places?!
How careless, Kinshiki.
Oh?
The Rinnegan?
What are you searching for?
Answer me.
Where is Kaguya Otsutsuki?
You don't know?
She's no longer here.
You will tell us everything
you know.
If this drags on,
I'll be at a disadvantage.
You are not getting away!
I've finally found you.
It took quite a while...
Lord Toneri Otsutsuki.
You've finally appeared,
Celestial Being.
Why stand on formality?
We're from the same clan...
I thought that the fate of
the Otsutsuki Clan would end with me.
Quite the contrary...
The main family of the Otsutsuki Clan
doesn't feel that way.
The main family?
If they exist, why did they forsake us
for a thousand years?
We saw it all.
The incident with the woman with
the Byakugan was quite unfortunate.
You endured such humiliation,
and yet, you still risk your life
for that planet...
I must hand it to you.
However, this means that
you're betraying the clan.
You speak as if
you know everything.
But you never made yourself
known until today.
What would you know
about that planet?
Yes... we don't.
Well, let's leave it at that.
I'm up for the fight...
A Time Freeze?!
I'm not authorized to kill
a member of the clan.
Well... don't worry...
Just enjoy the Palace of the Dragon King
for the next 10,000 years.
All right.
Time for me to reel
in a big catch.
Stop!
Don't!
We're done!
They said it was going to be a
bodyguard mission, and what did we get?
Who would have thought
it was for a pet!
It was kind of a surprise,
but now that it's over...
that one was
a piece of cake too!
Well, don't relax yet.
It's not always going to
go this smoothly.
I know that.
Anyway, let's get something to eat!
Sarada, what do you feel like?
Huh? Well...
Mitsuki, is there anywhere
that you want to go?
I'm happy going to
where you want to go, Boruto.
Okay then...
let's do Thunder Burger!
They just came out
with a new thing!
Yuck! Hamburgers again?
Hey, here come
the rookies of Team 7.
They say their mission
success rate is 100%...
And they're younger than us too.
Prodigies sure are different.
Well, it's to be expected, right?
Oh hey, sorry if I hurt your feelings.
We're just jealous.
Forget what we said.
Still, it must be nice.
I wish I was the Hokage's son!
I don't understand them.
You shouldn't let guys
like that get to you.
I'm not.
I just...
Just?
I'm just always being judged by my dad's
standards, and that bugs the hell outta me.
Hey, Boruto!
Weren't we getting hamburgers?
Sorry, I'm not in
the mood anymore.
Who cares about the Hokage?
Even back then...
Come on in.
Thanks for having us!
Happy birthday, Boruto!
Thanks, Aunt Sakura!
You came too?
Disappointed?
Well, I just came
'cuz Mom said to...
Hey!
Looks like you've made yourself
at home.
It's my first time at a birthday party,
but it's really quite fun.
Here's your cake, Big Brother!
Oh thanks, Himawari!
Just as I expected,
that's some cake!
I decorated it!
You did really good, Himawari!
Where's Naruto today?
He said he'd be home soon.
Isn't that good news!
I couldn't care less if that old man
came home or not.
The cake was really delicious!
Thank you!
– Oh, I'm so glad!
– Wasn't it good, Mom?
Your father hasn't returned yet?
Hello?
What? My husband?
Yes...
I understand.
Boruto...
Just like I thought,
that stupid old man!
Well, it's not like I had
my hopes up anyway.
There must have been an emergency
he couldn't put on hold...
Look, he is the Hokage...
Oh yeah, I get it.
I guess it can't be helped
the Lord Hokage would
put off my birthday.
Hey...
Big Brother's late, huh?
You're right...
Sorry, I just got home.
Oh!
Are you all right, Naruto?
Yeah, but...
This is for him.
I really let him down,
so I thought I should
at least get him a present...
I don't know what kind
of games he likes though.
I know deep down they care
so much about each other...
Damn it, it makes me so mad!
You seem to be in a bad mood.
Did something happen
on a mission?
You always come here to clear
your mind when something happens, Young Lord.
It's nothing like that.
Do grown-ups still see me
as a kid?
I don't think that's the case.
I'm a grown up,
and I know just how much skill
you have, Young Lord.
Yeah? I guess so, right?
But...
There are probably others
who don't think that way.
They're jealous of you.
You could also say they fear you...
and your talent.
I make them nervous,
you mean?
That's right!
That's why they can't appreciate
your strength in an honest manner.
And they make excuses like
you're the Hokage's son and such.
It's not like I'm the Hokage's son
because I want to be.
Who needs a stupid dad like that
who forgets his own kid's birthday?
Well, people will understand in time
and see your true power, Young Lord.
And when that time comes...
That time, huh?
Yeah, I wish that time
could be now.
Oh, that's right, Young Master.
Here.
I'm sorry it's late,
but it's a birthday gift.
Naturally, I didn't forget.
Oh... thank you!
What is it?
Another new toy?
This one's very practical.
It may come in handy during
your missions, so please accept this...
the Scientific Ninja Tool.
I'm home!
Welcome back, Big Brother!
What are you doing, Hima?
Well... for my birthday...
Daddy was too busy with work
on your birthday, remember?
So, I thought if I started
doing this now,
Daddy would make sure
to come home!
Hima...
Who cares if that
stupid old man isn't here?
Mom and I'll be here
to celebrate with you.
I can invite
my friends over too, and...
Yeah!
But I want Daddy to be here too.
Hey, Big Brother?
Do you think Daddy will miss
my birthday too?
Will he be too busy
to come home?
No way!
Huh?
I won't let that happen.
Don't worry, Himawari.
I'll absolutely...
absolutely make sure
that Dad comes home
for your birthday!
Really... Big Brother?!
Yeah, don't worry!
Do we really have to meet
this early in the morning?
Okay, everyone's here.
This time, our mission is
to capture thieves
who robbed the Thunder Train.
They suddenly disappeared after
jumping off the Thunder Train?
There's a mining town there,
as well as abandoned mines
that are no longer in use.
So they could be hiding out
in them.
How many are there in the gang?
Ten? Twenty?
Hey, read the report!
It says four, right there.
What? Only four?
Why can't the townspeople just go
and round them up themselves?
That's just not possible.
The mines are arranged
like a maze.
They could easily lie in wait
to attack,
so it's too dangerous
for ordinary people.
And that's where we come in, correct?
And that's why we have to go
all the way out to the sticks?
In any case,
we leave in one hour.
You're dismissed for now!
So another ruin connected to
Kaguya Otsutsuki was discovered?
Yeah, this makes it the third one.
What do you want to do?
I'm going to check it out myself,
of course.
I really don't want to add anymore
to your plate though.
You can't say that.
It was decided at the Five Kage
Conference, remember?
Anything that involves the Otsutsuki Clan
is classified as top secret.
No doubt, if Kaguya had
built living weapons...
like an army of White Zetsu to thwart
anything that posed a threat...
Yeah... It's been ten years
since then.
I fear that something even worse
than the White Zetsu slumbers there.
But...
If we're to protect this peace,
we have to find every ruin
and check it out thoroughly.
I get that.
But haven't you been working
too hard lately?
You've been going home
even less than before.
Well, that's...
I heard about it from Hinata...
You missed Boruto's birthday
the other day, didn't you?
Yeah... I really let him down. But...
But...
I'm the Hokage now.
Everyone in the village is
my family that I have to protect.
Dad...
Boruto...
Sarada, Mitsuki...
Can you go on ahead?
I need to talk to
my stupid old man.
Naruto, I'm going to go on ahead.
Yeah, sorry.
Let's go, Sarada.
Yeah.
Boruto, I didn't apologize
to you properly.
About your birthday,
the other day—
It doesn't matter.
You're super busy with
Hokage business, right?
I never had my hopes up anyway.
Boruto...
Instead...
You'd better be home for Himawari's!
I don't care...
if my stupid old man comes home
for my birthday or not.
But...
But she's still small,
and she wants you there.
So, promise me...
Swear that you'll come
home for that.
Yeah, I got it.
I'll never forgive you
if you break your word.
This is a promise,
man to man, got it?
Humph!
Like I said,
we're really out in the sticks.
There's nothing but mountains.
Hey, can you stop saying
stuff like that?
Are you from the Hidden Leaf?
Yes. We're here to
apprehend the robbers.
About that...
The situation has changed slightly.
Who is he?
He's one of the robbers.
– Huh?!
Did you go into the mine
without waiting for us to capture him?
No, he came running out
of the mine himself.
He was in a panic and
made such a commotion.
We questioned him, but couldn't
make any sense of him.
Hey, what happened to
the rest of your gang?
It's all over!
They're all dead!
They died?
E-Everyone got...
killed by that monster!
Monster?
He's been like that the whole time,
making absolutely no sense at all.
He must've been scared
out of his wits.
Save me.
Please save me!
Where's the mine that
he escaped from?
I posted guards at the entrance.
But as to going inside...
It's not like
we completely believe him,
but his terror made us
scared too.
It's only natural.
Well then, our mission
is to enter the mine
and find out just what
happened inside there.
Hey, what did you see anyway?
H-He's...!
He's coming for us!
The white one!
White?
I guess this is the site
of the incident?
I wonder what
this "white monster" is?
A white monster, huh?
What's wrong?
Oh, it's nothing...!
That would be impossible.
Whatever...
Let's hurry up and deal
with this, guys!
Hey, Boruto!
Don't go taking off
on your own! Hey!
They may be robbers,
but if they're still alive,
rescue is also part of our mission.
This could mean life and death.
I know that!
That's all the more reason
why we can't waste time!
Hey!
Damn it, what is with him?!
It's pretty vast inside.
It looks like this continues
quite deep.
Hey, you're more irritable
than usual today.
What? No, I'm not.
By any chance,
did something happen between
you and Lord Hokage this morning?
It's nothing like that.
Although if my dad
wasn't the way he is,
things would be easier for me.
You two!
We're going to leave you behind!
Okay, coming!
Cut it out and just grow up!
I want to.
But no one treats me like an adult,
and that's what's making me mad.
And it's not like I'm mad
just for my sake.
We've come quite deep
into the mine.
Hey, come here...
What's up, Mitsuki?
Is this—?
Whoa...!
Could it be one of the robbers?
There were more on this side...
Two of them.
So that guy's entire gang was...
Their bodies were cut
with a sharp blade.
The two I discovered
were completely charred,
like they'd been struck
by a jolt of electricity.
You don't think several ninja...?
There's a good chance of that.
Then what was all that talk
about a white monster?
Boruto, it could be this.
Look at these footprints.
They came running from further in.
And...
That one's really huge.
He must've been over
two meters tall...
Then that one killed these men?
If so, they use multiple jutsu.
Anyway, further inside, there's a
monster capable of doing stuff like this.
From this point on,
be prepared for battle.
Do not lose focus,
not even for a second.
The footprints...!
Why did they suddenly stop?!
Was this a trap just to
lure us here?!
Where are they going to come in from?
Above us!
White Zetsu?
Why is he here?
What the hell is that monster?!
White Zetsu?
You mean the things Dad and the
others fought during the Great Ninja War?!
Yeah... They were all supposed to
have been destroyed...
To think that some survived!
Still, I've never seen one
in this form!
Wh-What are you talking about?
They're coming!
Dodge it!
Lightning Style?
Fire Style this time?
Even Wind Style?
How many styles of jutsu
can this guy use?
Whoa!
Boruto!
N-No way!
Big Bro Konohamaru is
being overpowered?
Let's go back him up!
Did it work?
Boruto!
Are you kidding me?!
Oh yeah!
If I remember correctly...
What are you doing?
Big Bro!
He ran away?
No, he let us off the hook
is more like it.
B-Big Bro!
We have to treat your wound now!
What the hell is
that crazy monster?
That's White Zetsu...
a living weapon
created by Kaguya Otsutsuki,
the last enemy we battled
during the Great Ninja War.
But didn't Lord Seventh and
the others annihilate them all?
Then what's something like that
doing here after all this time?
I think the answer to that
lies deeper inside.
Mitsuki?
When did you—?
What is this?
O-Oh...
A relic of the Otsutsuki Clan
in a place like this?
Long ago, Kaguya Otsutsuki
had used the roots
of the Divine Tree just like this
to cultivate countless White Zetsu.
But I've never seen anything
about that form...
in any of the data
about White Zetsu.
Its intellect seemed low.
On the other hand,
its strength is off the charts.
Maybe it underwent a change
while it was left alone?
Wait a minute!
Does that mean there are
lots more like him under us?
Wh-What?
That's really bad!
No, I don't think
there are any more.
Why not, Mitsuki?
It's been nearly ten years
since it lost its master.
That bud is dried up,
and I don't think it's even active.
Without a chakra supply,
they can't stay incubated.
I hope that's the case...
Mitsuki, you seem to know a lot.
My parent taught me.
Okay then, let's go down there.
Boruto?
Well, we can't ignore
that thing just now.
You talk like it's going to be
an easy task...
Besides, if this is the factory
where those monsters are made,
we have to destroy it completely.
That may be true, but...
Hey, Big Bro Konohamaru!
Let's get that thing.
Together, the four of us!
Boruto, that makes a lot of sense.
However, I have to reject it.
Wh-Why?!
This place definitely seems
to be inactive.
But if that's the case,
why is that White Zetsu here?
Huh? That's—
In other words,
we should assume there are others.
And that thing is too much
for you to handle.
Hold on a minute!
Are you saying
we're a burden?!
To put it bluntly, yes.
And I won't let you say that
you aren't already aware of that.
Then, are we going to retreat?
No, I'm going in there alone.
Huh?!
Without a doubt,
we can't leave this place alone.
If anyone is going to deal with it,
it has to be a jonin like myself.
You three go back to the village
and report the situation
in case I don't return.
Konohamaru-sensei!
We can't do that,
Big Bro Konohamaru!
I-It'll be fine.
We can all work together
to beat a thing like that...!
You guys don't know about
the Great Ninja War...
or how terrifying the things
connected to Kaguya Otsutsuki are.
The Otsutsuki are a god-like beings
who gave rise to ninja like us.
Her power is beyond measure.
She's that powerful?
Without a doubt,
you three have grown strong.
But this is on another level.
More strength is required
from here on out.
Don't let this get you down...
Take your time and
build up your strength.
The one thing
we must absolutely avoid,
is for all of us to die here.
So, you need to go back.
That's an order.
Please wait, Konohamaru-sensei!
Sarada?
It's not that I approve of Boruto...
But I also think
we should go in together.
You—!
And why is that?
We don't even know
where the enemy is hiding,
so splitting up at this point
is too dangerous.
It's possible it will target us too.
In fact, I think the chance
of that is stronger.
Even that thing knows enough
to come after the weaker ones.
And if that's the case,
the best strategy is
for us to come along and
provide you with back-up.
Don't you think so, Sensei?
However...
Big Bro!
If the risk is the same,
I don't think we should split up
our fighting strength either.
Damn it, I guess I have no choice.
We'll prove it to you and
make ourselves useful, Big Bro...
I mean, Konohamaru-sensei!
I got it!
But you absolutely must not
overestimate your strength.
Change of orders.
We will proceed together inside...
and we'll take down this White Zetsu.
And we're going to get through
this alive and go home, together!
– Right!
– Yeah!
That's why I want you to listen carefully
to the strategy I'm about to explain.
Strategy?
Yeah, it's a no-fail strategy
to bring him down.
Did we get him?!
No, it's coming!
We'll proceed just as I explained!
Sarada, Sharingan!
Right!
It's going to come at us with Lightning Style,
Wind Style, then Fire Style!
Leave the Lightning Style to me.
Snake Lightning!
All right!
Wind Style: Gale Palm!
Fire Style: Fire Dragon Bomb!
He knows he's getting nowhere
with jutsu-based attacks,
so he's switching to
hand-to-hand combat...
As predicted!
Now, Boruto!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Hey, over here!
No matter how atypical this monster is,
if we keep chipping away at him...
As expected,
Konohamaru-sensei's strategy is brilliant.
At this rate...
That's the way.
Keep baiting it, Boruto!
While you're doing that,
I'll get him with this!
Listen up.
You're going to lure him
with your Shadow Clones.
Don't do anything reckless, got it?
But...
It's weakened.
If I do it now—!
Well, people will understand in time...
and see your true power,
Young Lord.
And when that time comes...
Now's my chance!
I'll settle this right now!
Huh...
Boruto!
It's no good. It's not working.
Try to get away, Boruto!
M-My chakra is—!
Damn it!
At this rate...
I won't let you have Boruto!
All right, now!
I saved the best for last!
Rasengan!
From the Third, known as The Professor...
and the power I inherited from
Big Brother Naruto!
Get a good taste of this!
A-Amazing!
He did it!
Let's proceed inside!
I know!
What are those?!
I knew it.
These are like the cocoons
that nurture White Zetsu.
Don't tell me all of these...
are like that monster?!
No, that doesn't seem
to be the case.
Yes, they're decomposed.
It seems we've come to
the innermost location.
What if there are more
White Zetsu lurking in there?
If so, we'll just have
to fight them off as hard
as we can, using the
same strategy as earlier.
Don't let your guard down.
These are—!
Don't touch that flame.
What's going on with this one?
Who knows?
What's with these black flames?
Everything's burning.
This is Amaterasu!
What's that?
It's Sasuke!
Flames that only he can control,
that can burn anything completely!
I knew it...
Looks like there were
several dozen of them in here.
If Sasuke hadn't been here first,
we'd have been goners.
Are you saying he destroyed
all of them by himself?
Yeah.
The Zetsu we encountered must've
managed to escape and survive.
What's Sarada's dad doing here?
I guess I have no choice,
since you've seen this much...
Sasuke's been on a top-secret mission
all by himself,
tracking the movements of
any remnants of Kaguya Otsutsuki.
A top-secret mission?
He said it's an important duty
that only he can fulfill.
So where is your dad, Sarada?
He can travel through time and space
with the power of his Rinnegan.
He's probably far away by now.
A-Awesome!
You bet he's awesome.
Sasuke is the one and only rival
that Lord Seventh considers his equal.
Dad's—?!
I heard that from my parent too...
That he gets no accolades,
but he is the supreme ninja
who watches over the Hidden Leaf Village
from the shadows.
The supreme ninja?
I guess Sasuke ended up
saving you, Konohamaru.
Yes, but Lord Seventh...
I know you're a clone, but why did you
come all the way out here?
I can't ignore anything
that involves Kaguya.
Still, I can't believe
you found a ruin here too.
Which means there are others?
Yeah.
But judging by that one's appearance...
For her to get these guys ready,
Kaguya must've been expecting
an intense battle
with some formidable enemies...
An enemy that can only be confronted by
creating an army of monsters like these?
I wonder who they could be?
Who knows?
In any case, seems we're going to
have our hands full again...
So, we're being left in the dark,
after all?
It can't be helped.
That's what it's supposed
to be like for genin.
Well, I don't like it!
Even though we...
"Fought too" was that what
you were going to say?
But when it counted most,
we didn't have enough strength.
Neither of us.
Konohamaru-sensei said we're not to
say a word about this to anyone.
It means Lord Seventh and
the higher-ups will deal with the rest.
Sasuke is the one and only rival
that Lord Seventh considers his equal.
Power that the grown-ups...
and everyone...
and Dad will acknowledge...
I still don't have enough.
What are some of your thoughts
when you look back on
the Fourth Great Ninja War?
Yeah... there were a lot of casualties
– It's Lord Hokage!
– in that battle.
I think there are a lot of ninja now
who don't know about that.
Dad?
The most important thing is
to communicate properly
everything that's happened
up to now, you know?
You're right.
As Naruto, Lord Seventh,
just said...
peace was reached after
the many wars of the past.
But we must never forget that
this peace was made possible
through the sacrifice of
many, many shinobi.
We must make sure we teach
this history to the youth,
to the next generation,
in order to preserve peace...
You could say it's our responsibility
to do so.
I get it already.
I've heard this so much,
it's a drag.
It's even in our text books.
Now, turning our attention
to the Chunin Exams,
which for the first time, the five
villages have agreed to sponsor together...
Naruto, do you have any advice
for the genin who will be taking part?
Remember these three things!
Three things?
Teamwork... and perseverance!
And... well...
Good luck to everyone!
That was just two things...
Anyway, thank you for
your inspiring comments.
Thanks for joining us live today.
Thank you very much, Naruto.
Sure!
It seems Lord Hokage is
as busy as ever.
He had his Shadow Clone
do the interview on TV.
Lord Hokage is so amazing!
At this rate...
I won't be able to change a thing.
I never thought I'd become a ninja...
And here I am, a chunin.
Don't get ahead of yourself.
You can celebrate
when you pass.
Oh yeah,
we still have the exams.
Hey Boruto...
Don't do anything stupid until
we get our recommendation letters.
Pranks are off-limits for a while, huh?
About that...
I really couldn't care less about it.
– Huh?
Chunin, jonin...
That's sorta like a license, right?
Why should we get so
hung up on rules
that people from a long time ago
came up with?
Instead, we should just go for it
and become even greater ninja.
What do you mean
by "even greater"?
Well...
Like Sasuke.
Huh?
You mean Sarada's dad?
He doesn't take orders
from anyone,
but he battles powerful enemies
on his own terms.
ninja like that exist.
Rumors say he's mysterious too!
That's what's cool about him.
It's way cooler than going on TV
and rambling on and on.
Why are you making things
complicated at this point?
I'm not.
I got into the Academy and
decided to become a ninja
with all you guys.
That's for real.
And that's why, I'm thinking about
how I can be even cooler.
I'm just doing things
my own way.
You know...
Only guys who want to stand out
say things like that.
That's not it.
Then what is it?
Like I said,
I'll do things my way.
Later!
Damn it.
He's such a drag.
I've brought the applications
for this year's Chunin Exams.
That means we'll get
official recommendations, right?
Well, yeah.
Your work has been recognized,
so I can breathe easy.
Well, there were quite
a few instances of chaos...
Damn it. They sure work us genin
to the bone.
The hell?!
If you don't want it, I can always
take the recommendation back!
No! I never said we weren't going
to take the Exams!
Right, Cho-Cho?
Huh?
Did you say something about being patient
with your triglycerides?
I'm talking about
the Chunin Exams.
Maybe you've got fat stuffed
in your ears?
Mm... Like a sausage pizza, nice.
You're not listening!
Sorry...
You've been sending your clones
out nonstop due to the Zetsu incident.
I'm okay.
The Chunin Exams are coming up.
I have to manage somehow.
Oh, Katasuke.
What's up?
Well, as the head of
the Scientific Ninja Tools department,
I have a request to make,
Lord Seventh.
What is it?
For the upcoming Chunin Exams,
we would like your authorization
to use
the Scientific Ninja Tools
developed by our team!
That's right!
I read the report that they've made
considerable progress recently.
Yes, they are battle-ready now!
That's a Wind Style jutsu.
That's actually pretty interesting.
Isn't it?
You just change the cartridge,
and you can use a jutsu at will.
I see.
Then the genin won't have
to go through harsh training
and they can widen the scope
of their individual ninjutsu!
What do you think?
Their performance will also
be more elaborate.
Thanks, Katasuke.
But I can't approve it.
Huh?
The Chunin Exam is not
a performance.
Its purpose is to nurture shinobi.
All the more reason then!
The Scientific Ninja Tool was invented
for the modern shinobi.
Taking the easy way out on
a test to measure their skills
will only end up
shortchanging them.
That's true...
I understand.
But there's a school of thought that
the masterful use of copied jutsu
like the Sixth Hokage, is also
the mark of an outstanding ninja.
Sure, if that power came
from within himself.
However, the purpose of
the Chunin Exams is to measure
a genin's strength that
they have cultivated to this day.
I see...
Excuse me.
Do you think I was rude to him?
Don't worry about it.
You were absolutely right.
Okay...
Yes!
I stopped the boss attack
with an instant kill!
What?
Your character is
super strong today.
I'm ready.
Just waiting for you, Boruto.
S-Sorry...
Hey, what's up with this level?
You used something,
didn't you, Boruto?
Yeah, so?
If I use this, it makes it easy
to beat the boss.
I'll send you the data too.
Yeah... this is a cheat.
Although your level is impressive.
Yeah but... This is only fun because
I have to sneak away
from my mom to level up.
That's so boring!
Isn't that a drag?
What's the point if you can't win?
So, you're an expert at
video games too?
I brought the applications.
Look, Mitsuki.
I already told you
I'm not going to enter.
Oh, is that right?
I see.
Damn it. Are you still
saying stuff like that?
If that's how you feel,
it doesn't really matter to me anyway...
But are you sure
you're all right with that?
Of course it's not okay!
I was worried, so I came here,
and what do I hear you say?!
I can't rely on Mitsuki!
Listen, Boruto!
My dream is to become Hokage!
I know that!
I can't waste time being
a genin.
I'm going to pass the Exams
as soon as possible.
Like it'll be that easy.
Right?
What is it?
Are you going to get
in my way?
I have no intention of doing that.
You can go ahead and
do whatever you want.
Huh?!
Were you even listening
to the teachers?
A three-man team is required
to take the Exams.
You can find someone else.
It's too late at this point!
There's no way
I can find someone that easily!
She's right.
Our teamwork didn't come
together overnight.
That's true.
I don't care.
You've been acting
so weird lately, Boruto.
Why are you being so stubborn?
Whatever.
Hey, Boruto.
Huh?
You just want to hear
your father say you're great,
more than anything... right?
Oh...
What would you know about me?
I know...
Because you're my sun.
So that's it...
You're acting like a child.
I heard that.
Listen, Boruto.
The way you're acting
is pretty uncool.
Is this the real Boruto Uzumaki?
Come on, Boruto!
Let's show Lord Hokage just how
awesome we are in the upcoming Exams!
Huh?
It's our chance.
You'll be able to show your dad and all of
the spectators just how amazing you are.
And I can pass the exam too!
Me too.
I guess I have no choice!
Okay already... I get it.
Seriously, I guess you guys just can't
do anything without me.
Three-man team or whatever...
just leave it to me.
He's so easy!
You really know how
to manipulate Boruto, Sarada.
I can hear you!
A man doesn't go back
on his word, right?
Well, yeah...
I couldn't care less about
being a chunin.
But I'll just ace the exam
and wow everyone...
and make them see Boruto Uzumaki
is finally here!
Big Brother!
Oh, Hima!
Hey, Himawari!
But before that, there's something
important I have to do...
– Huh?
It's a man-to-man promise.
We're back!
Big Brother is home!
Oh, welcome home.
Daddy!
We're back, we're back...
– So, you remembered.
– we're back!
Welcome home, welcome home,
welcome home!
He remembered.
So, you remembered our promise.
Well, yeah...
Then we're even.
I can put up with it.
I'm a man.
But if you had made Himawari cry,
I was going to let you have it.
So we're even now.
I'll forgive you for today!
Thank you.
As long as you get it.
Daddy!
Dad, everything's ready!
Okay!
All right!
Everything's ready!
Yes!
Here comes the cake!
Whoa!
It's so big!
Himawari's birthday party
is about to start!
Big Brother, I...
That damned...
It's Himawari's birthday!
What the hell does he think this is?!
Boruto!
Let me go, Mom!
I'm going to beat that loser up!
Boruto!
Your father has to work very hard
for the people of the village.
And what about us?!
Aren't we part of the village too?!
So when you're the Hokage,
it's okay to ignore your own family?!
It doesn't mean he's forgotten
about the two of you.
I've heard that so many times
already, ya know!
I'm sick and tired of that excuse!
Boruto...
When Dad was a kid,
Grandpa Hokage wasn't even alive!
Which means
he grew up not knowing
how fun it's supposed to be
with your family, right?
No wonder he doesn't care!
Boruto!
Why did my dad have to
be the Hokage?!
He just sits at his desk
all day and acts bossy!
Anyone can do that!
I understand it's hard not having
your father around on important days.
But it's different with you.
You have a father who's actually here.
Boruto...
Mommy...
I'm sorry, Himawari.
I'm so sorry.
It's so dirty...
and torn up...
But it's different with you.
You have a father
who's actually here.
This is so uncool!
So uncool...
Dad is...
and so am I.
So you've decided to come home...
stupid old man?!
I-I'm sorry,
I thought you were my dad...
You're Naruto's son?
What's your name?
Boruto Uzumaki...
What's the matter, Boruto?
Is that... really you...
Sasuke?
Is Naruto here?
I think he's still at
the Hokage's office.
I see...
Sorry to bother you.
So he's
Sasuke... Uchiha...
H-Hey...
Never mind that now...
I have to go beat up
that stupid old man!
Boruto, please wait!
What the hell are you doing?!
Your mother just said to wait.
Mind your own business!
You said "stupid old man,"
didn't you?
Were you talking about Naruto?
Yeah, I was.
Boruto...
I messed up again...
Dad... What am I supposed to do?
Hey, what happened?!
Well, I just messed up
Himawari's birthday too.
You sent a Shadow Clone
to the house?
Yeah...
You're hopeless!
I told you to go home today.
That just wasn't possible.
The preparations for
the Chunin Exams are late...
And there's the discovery
of White Zetsu's ruins.
It's been ten years already
since the Great Ninja War...
It's troubling.
Yeah...
A gift from Kaguya's Palace.
Sasuke!
I see.
What does it say?
I don't know.
But... I'm getting a bad feeling
about this.
I can't even read it with
my Rinnegan.
Let's hand this over to
the Cipher Corps.
Sasuke, you just said
Kaguya's Palace...
Yeah... I finally found it.
Otsutsuki?
Yeah.
That's what he called himself.
There's no doubt that
he belongs to the same
Otsutsuki Clan as Kaguya.
This is a crisis!
Is this the start of another war?!
We're not sure yet.
But we have to be very careful.
We must never cause
another war like that.
My clothes?
Why do you have that?
I found it on the way here.
Huh?
Near your house.
I see...
And I also met your kid.
Seems just like you
when you were young.
He's nothing like how I was.
He's a lot more like you
when you were young.
No... I take that back.
He's different from you too.
The clothes he wears always
look brand new.
I guess guys like us are
behind the times.
No...
You're wrong.
The soul of a shinobi always
remains the same...
even if times change.
I wonder about that...
Anyway, I think I win
this argument.
You're one to talk, loser.
He disappeared!
You're amazing!
You used to be my dad's rival, right?
I get it now... brand new, huh?
Please make me your student!
There's someone I want
to bring down, no matter what it takes!
Can you do the Rasengan?
If you can't, you can't be
a student of mine.
That's a piece of cake!
Naruto...
That earlier contest
isn't over and decided yet.
Konohamaru-sensei!
What's all this, eh?
Please teach me your Rasengan!
I have to master it right now!
So you want to learn it for the Chunin
Exams and surprise the Seventh Hokage.
Is that it?
Now you're talking like a shinobi!
Well... yeah.
Imagine me, the instructor who gets to
pass on this jutsu to the Hokage's son!
Oh, Lord Fourth, Lord Seventh...!
I swear I will fulfill this
very important duty!
Hey, Boruto!
Get serious, will ya?
Huh?
Was I sleeping?
I heard you were dozing off during
your mission today too.
When you get as good as I am,
you can complete missions half-asleep!
Thank goodness it was
an easy babysitting mission.
Ugh...
Have you been up to something
that's keeping you awake all night?
N-No, not really.
He's being weirdly enthusiastic
all because of my dad...
Coming!
What's the matter?
Sa... Sa...!
I'm home...
Oh, Sasuke!
You don't have to collapse just because
Dad comes home unexpectedly...
So how long can you
stay this time?
Until your Chunin Exams are over.
I just met Naruto's son earlier.
Boruto?
He said he wants to become
my student.
Well, the Exams require
three-man teams...
so it's better if he's at his best.
What happened to
your enthusiasm from earlier?!
Come on, once more.
Watch closely and copy me, like so.
I know, I know!
But it's not working at all...
like so!
Don't copy the way I speak, like so!
No..."Like so" means this!
"Like so" means this in my hand...
Quit saying "like so", "like so"!
Which one is it?!
And why does it have to be
a water balloon?!
Isn't there a better way
to do this?!
It took Lord Fourth three years
to invent this jutsu...
and another six months
to perfect it.
Going by how difficult
it is to master,
this is an A-rank jutsu.
Damn it!
Still no good!
I did it!
Well done!
Okay, on to the next step.
What? A rubber ball this time?!
No! No way... eh!
All right!
That's awfully small...
I'd be hard-pressed to call
that Rasengan.
But the basics are—
Damn it!
You're always so strict, Dad.
Since you probably
don't know Boruto very well,
let me tell you...
Boruto usually isn't like this.
It's a miracle
he even managed this far.
You get it, don't you?
He jumped to
the wrong conclusion.
I didn't say he failed.
I was going to accept him
as my student...
Where did he go anyway?
Is that right? That's terrible!
But if that's the case,
I have something perfect for you.
It's cool...
and smart...
and by expending little effort,
you get exceptionally good results!
And this ought to be what the ninja
of your generation...
should look like!
Wouldn't you agree?
If you have this...
Fire Style, Wind Style, and yes,
the Rasengan is right at your fingertips.
Now...
Let's choose the ultimate technique
that's perfect for you, Young Lord!
I'm managing just fine.
Uh-huh.
I see. That's great to hear.
However, during the Chunin Exams,
you mustn't reveal
your true strength.
If you do, you won't be able
to remain there.
Understand?
Uh-huh. I know.
Rasengan!
Well?
All that from just one day
of training?
I'm not like my dad...
when it comes to talent!
You seem quite different
from Naruto.
Though I'd hoped it
wasn't the case.
Huh?
So? What's your answer?
In terms of me being
your student?
Fine... You can be my student.
Yes!
It's finally time.
Good luck and do your best!
You're awfully cheery first thing
in the morning, Mom.
Does Dad coming home after
a long time make you that happy?
What? No...
It's nothing like that.
– What are you saying!
– I can tell these things about you, Mom.
Anyway, I'm off.
You seem just as happy, Sarada.
It seems you won your bet
with my dad, Boruto.
Huh? Well, yeah.
So?
What are you going to do now
that you're his student?
I'm going to ask him about
my dad's weaknesses.
Look, I'm not criticizing you
or anything, but...
We've got the Chunin Exams
coming up.
Don't you realize that this is
no time for something like that?!
It's all for the Chunin Exams!
I'm going to learn lots of things
from Uncle Sasuke,
and I'll show Dad during the Exams.
And in time,
my power's going to take Dad down!
You mean our power, right?
Just what are you thinking?!
What do you mean by "what"?
It's all about winning
the Chunin Exams with a flair!
Obviously!
I'm not criticizing you
or anything, but...
there are times when
you don't irritate me.
Don't forget about me too.
Mitsuki!
Done already?
This time, Cho-Cho you be
the vanguard,
and Inojin,
you assist from the rear.
Hey, what's up with
all this eagerness lately?
What?
You don't care if you lose
to Boruto's team, then?
I'm not into that.
No one wants to see me lose
my composure, do they?
Then quit complaining and move!
Here it comes!
Ninja Art: Super Beast Scroll!
Partial Expansion Jutsu!
We can do this!
You were so close!
That's it for today.
Damn it!
Honestly!
You should've taken this
seriously earlier.
This time, Gaara's genin
are participating.
You'll have many rivals.
The Kazekage, Lord Gaara, is
your younger brother, right, Aunt Temari?
Yes.
He adopted a son.
I just met him recently,
but I sensed extraordinary chakra
from him.
He was saying he's going to
take part in the Chunin Exams.
At this rate,
you have no chance against him.
Ah... damn it!
The shuriken's not bending at all!
I can't be wasting time with
this kinda training!
Wow!
As expected,
this Scientific Ninja Tool is convenient!
You came here just
to tell me that?
Your subordinate is going
to be under my care.
We will need to submit
a notification.
Thank you very much.
Boruto admires you very much.
It's the exact opposite of how
he feels about his father, Lord Seventh.
He probably feels that Lord Seventh
doesn't acknowledge his worth,
and treats him like a child,
and is rebelling against him.
I've never seen Boruto
determined like that ever.
I leave him in your care!
No...
When it comes to
raising a child,
I have no right to
say anything.
But I'll accept him
as a student.
Is something the matter?
You've been good to Sarada.
I thank you for that.
Hey, tell me everything
about my dad.
When he was a kid,
all he did was talk about
becoming the Hokage,
and he was a total loser.
A total loser?
And damned stubborn.
No, not all that!
What I really want to know about
are his weaknesses.
Weaknesses?
Yeah, isn't there something?
I don't have enough fingers
on my hand to count.
Huh?
He was the stereotypical loser,
full of weaknesses.
But he overcame them with
his own strength, and became the Hokage.
Maybe instead of
the Naruto of today,
you should study who
Naruto was in the past.
What's that supposed to mean?
Is this one bad too?
It seems so.
Not one of Kaguya's scrolls remain.
Momoshiki-senpai...
Are you still here?
How is the search for
the Chakra Fruit going?
We meet after such a long time,
and that's all you're interested in?
Yes, yes...
Of course, I checked into that.
That's the region Kaguya
was in charge of?
I can't wait to get the chakra.
J-Just a minute.
You're going already?!
Hey!
Oh, Momo,
you're as unsociable as ever.
You're saying the chakra of
the Divine Tree was dispersed and
became nine monsters?
Yes.
They call them Tailed Beasts here.
And the ones who took these
Tailed Beasts into their bodies
are known as Jinchuriki.
So "Jinchuriki" possess chakra?
Yes.
And for some reason,
these Jinchuriki have
tremendous chakra.
So, they keep Tailed Beasts inside
their bodies to amass chakra.
The people of this region
do very amusing things.
Right now,
there are two Jinchuriki.
Killer Bee has the Eight-Tails,
and Naruto has the Nine-Tails.
I see.
They may be vulgar creatures,
but I do sense enormous chakra.
At the ruins connected to Kaguya,
we're beginning to see more and
more movement of White Zetsu.
The two that Sasuke
reported about,
who seem to be from
the Otsutsuki Clan...
No matter how you look at it,
they seem to be connected.
So, in order to resist
some kind of threat,
Kaguya had prepared
the White Zetsu.
And now, they've become active.
The time is near.
This one is a Jinchuriki?
He definitely possesses
tremendous chakra.
Like that Rinnegan fellow,
this one has extraordinary strength.
That's right, I'm a Jinchuriki ♪
I have the power of
a hundred men ♪
Killer Bee of the Eight-Tails,
that's me! ♪
Aww, yeaah!
Hey, c'mon.
They seem to be pretty nasty.
Are they ignoring me?
For real?
His words irritate me.
Now then, I shall take you.
So this is the Tailed Beast.
Wha—?
Imagine that...
The Chakra Fruit that we seek is
in the form of an unsightly beast.
Tailed Beast Bomb!
Can you still move?
That guy snatched
the Tailed Beast Bomb so easily!
I was on my way to see Naruto,
but what an obstacle ♪
When it comes to Tailed Beasts
I'm his mentor ♪
This is no time to be rapping!
My, my...
It seems we have no choice
but to collect them one by one.
What is that?!
Magnifying your jutsu
that easily is cheating ♪
Looks like any victory
is fleeting ♪
You could say
this is payback, twofold.
That was easy.
If Kaguya had produced
a Divine Tree in this region,
it would've spared us
all this trouble.
It seems Kaguya developed an attachment
to someone of this planet, and betrayed us.
Furthermore, it seems
she bore his children.
The disgrace of our clan!
That is why the chakra she was supposed
to provide us with never came.
Yes.
Kaguya, betrayed us,
and feared our existence.
It seems she even tried
creating living weapons.
But she was stopped by her own children
and was sealed away.
Hmph.
They saved me the trouble of
having to punish Kaguya myself.
For that, I commend
the vulgar creatures.
For sure.
Is this all?
Now, now...
There's still one more Jinchuriki.
There's considerable
chakra movement
coming from an area
not too far from here.
No doubt this is the massive chakra
we are seeking.
The Chunin Exams are here at last.
Are you all ready?
Yeah!
We will not dishonor
your name, Father.
We three will emerge
victorious without fail.
Don't get too worked up, Shinki.
I'm not the one you should
be focusing on.
It's your rivals from other villages
that you've yet to meet.
Other villages don't matter.
Well, never mind.
In any case, make sure to get
good rest on the Thunder Train.
– Yes!
– Right!
Take care of them.
I'll set out as soon as
I complete my duties here.
I should reach the Hidden Leaf Village
around the time Round Two begins.
Yeah, I know.
I'll visit Temari when I get there.
Yeah.
Gaara!
This voice... Is that you, Shukaku?
It's been a while.
You never initiate contact.
Which means that it's important.
My connection with the Eight-Tails
was suddenly cut off.
Something definitely happened.
Is it only with the Eight-Tails?
Yeah.
I'm still connected with Naruto
and the others.
But I'm getting a bad feeling
about this...
I see.
So anyway, I warned you.
How you deal with this
is up to you.
I'm grateful, my friend.
All right!
You're starting to be able
to bend it a little.
That one's next.
Now go around that one
and hit that target.
No way! It's impossible!
How do you expect me
to do that and hit the target?
No fair!
I mean, if I had that,
even I could have—!
That was just one example.
There are countless other ways.
Use your head a little more
and think.
Don't try to find
an answer instantly.
I know that...
You will definitely win, Young Lord.
Don't worry.
When you're in a bind, the Scientific
Ninja Tool will come to your rescue.
There's no need to worry.
Tomorrow's the Chunin Exams...
I swear I'm not going to lose!
Do your best, Big Brother!
Stay calm while you take the test.
If you haven't forgotten the things
you've learned until today,
you'll definitely pass!
Yeah, I know!
Oh well, just in case...
Okay, I'll be going, ya know!
Bye!
Oh, here they come!
Hey!
You look like you're ready to go.
What happened?
Until recently, you were sounding like
Shikadai, saying how it was going to be drag...
Right?
I don't know what caused
the change of heart.
I told you!
I'll show everyone
the fruits of my training.
Looks like everyone else
is here too.
Hey!
Let's all do our best!
I'm so nervous!
None of them seem like
they're too eager.
You can't really tell
just by looking at them.
Oh, all three of them
have the same face!
They're from the Hidden Mist.
Their names are...
Takanami, Sazanami
and Makinami Senka...
Triplets?
I wonder what kind of
ninja arts they use?
Which team looks
strong to you, Iwabe?
Well...
They look like they've got
some hidden strengths.
They could end up as our rivals.
The Genbu Shinobi Trio
representing the Hidden Stone!
Their background and the ninja arts
they use are a total mystery...
They look super strong!
Do you even think we can win?
Calm down!
Compared to the guys we've had to
fight up to now, they're nothing.
Damn it, he always
gets so carried away!
So, that's Boruto Uzumaki.
The son of the Seventh Hokage, Naruto
Uzumaki, who defeated Father in the past...
What's going on, Shinki?
It's nothing.
Let's go.
The opening ceremony
will begin soon.
Quiet!
Looks like everyone is here.
We will now begin
the first Chunin Exams of
the Five Allied Villages!
As you all know, this is the first
selection exam in history
sponsored by all five villages.
The Hidden Leaf.
The Hidden Cloud.
The Hidden Mist.
The Hidden Stone.
And the Hidden Sand.
At this time, you are all getting
the rare opportunity
to fight against ninja
from other villages.
This is your chance to use
the jutsu that you're proud of!
Good grief...
Are they even motivated
to participate in
this important event?
Everyone, I ask you
to freely demonstrate
the fruits of your training!
– Right!
– All right!
Exam One will begin promptly
at noon in Exam Venue A.
Until then, the time is yours.
Use that time to rest or train!
Dismissed!
Two Chunin Exam
Cheer burger combos, correct?
So? What's going on?
Burgers again? On a day like this?
They say you can't wage war hungry!
Well, there's still time
until the first exam.
This can be our strategy meeting.
Yeah, but Mitsuki is late...
I wonder what he's doing?
These guys were at
the opening ceremony...
Hey, you mind switching with us?
Huh?
There's only two of you.
We've got three.
It's only natural
to seat the larger party
at the booth, right?
We have three too.
One of us isn't here yet.
That's none of our concern.
It's his fault for being slow.
There you have it.
So, if you get it, move.
You can't be ninja
if you're slow like that.
What?!
No, Boruto!
Don't make trouble
before the exams.
Boruto?
Oh, I see...
You're the son of
the Seventh Hokage...
I was curious to see
how good a ninja you were...
Who woulda thought
you'd be such a weakling?
Why you—!
Huh?
That's my seat.
Who the hell are you?!
Why are you
staring at me like that?!
Boruto, how are these guys—?
What's—!!
My body's...
What's going on...
That's enough.
Who are these guys?
What's with that cape?
What's the point of fighting here?
Sorry, our third member's here now.
Could you please
find a seat elsewhere?
Whatever.
We'll see you at the Exams.
Um... Thank you!
You were a big help.
No worries.
Shinki's like that.
Let's go.
Right!
Shinki, huh?
Who is he anyway?
Oh, um...
Ah, it's right here.
Shinki... representing
the Hidden Sand Village.
Oh...
Seems he's the adopted son
of the Fifth Kazekage.
The son of one of the Five Kage.
He's just like you, Boruto.
Kazekage?
It's him, huh—?
Hey, there Tsuchikage!
You're awfully eager
to watch from the first exam.
Same to you guys.
Well, it is history's first
joint exam of the five villages.
I wonder how many genin
will be worth watching this time.
It's nice that we're
at peace these days,
but as a result, the number
of chunin has decreased.
We need new blood from these exams.
By the way, is the Kazekage,
Gaara, not coming?
The exam has already begun.
He should be on his way now.
Oh, we're all here now.
It's about to start.
Okay, I see everyone's here?
I will now announce the outline
of the first round.
The exam for Round One is...
a true or false quiz.
Huh...?
– Huh?!
What is this?
A quiz?
The question will be given
in Exam Venue B
which is 20 km from here.
Any genin who does not
arrive at the venue
within one hour of this stopwatch
will be disqualified.
Furthermore, along the way,
various traps have been laid.
If you get caught up
and can go no further, it means...
– you're disqualified as well.
– Boruto! Look!
Only participants who arrive at
Venue B within the time allotted
– will be allowed to take
– That stopwatch
– the true or false quiz...
– is moving!
– so please pay attention
– Let's run!
to the time.
Any team who is late,
even by a second, will be—
Oh... I wasn't done explaining...
Your explanation itself is a trap.
If they listened until the end,
they wouldn't have made it in time.
At least they can
figure out that much.
This year's participants
are an elite group.
I would hope so.
Oh boy...
It's our first joint exams ever...
But he has no intention of
making this easy for any of them.
This is an exam,
and it's also a serious battle.
I won't be going easy on you, okay?
Traps have been laid!
Be careful as you proceed!
Seems the time's come
to show them what we're made of.
The ultimate technique of us,
the Genbu Trio!
Ninja Art: Genbu Winter Wind
Emperor Formation!
Number 108 – Release!
Respond to my name and manifest!
Jet black—!
We couldn't see
their ultimate technique...
What was he saying at the end?
L-Let's go!
Nothing much we can say to losers...
So uncool.
Those three!
When they get back home
they're going to start training
again from the very beginning.
I'll see to it, personally.
These traps
aren't worth using this...
Oh... Not bad at all.
Then how about this?
Try not to use your jutsu.
No need to show
the enemy our skills.
– Got it.
– Right!
Easy!
And... I still have more
tricks up my sleeve...
Let's go, Sazanami, Makinami.
Yes, Elder Brother.
I'm ready anytime.
We took a lot of time.
We made it with
five minutes to spare.
Damn it!
Look at them with
their unconcerned expressions!
There's more left than I thought.
Still, it's what we speculated.
Well, the real exam starts now.
Each team of three
will stand on the side they believe
is the correct answer.
So, it really is
a true or false quiz!
They sure prepared
some elaborate steps to this...
Those who answer incorrectly,
namely...
those who turn black, will fail.
Turn black?
All right, here's the question.
In the 5th Volume of the Shinobi
Military Strategy Handbook,
the following passwords appear:
Moon is day. Mountain is river.
Flower is nectar.
True or false?
How am I supposed to know that?!
Umm...
What was it?!
I don't remember three passwords...
Sarada, are you familiar
with that book?
I've read it.
But the library only had up to
the 4th Volume of
the Military Strategy Handbook.
Who knew there was a fifth scroll...!
What about you, Mitsuki?
I guess we'll just have to
go by instinct.
I guess this will be of no use
in a quiz.
Damn it! We have to hurry up
and decide or we'll fail!
Boruto, which one do you think
my dad would choose?
Huh? What's up with that question?
Just answer.
False, I think.
Sasuke doesn't seem to be
the straightforward type.
Right? I think so too.
I'm choosing a different path than
Dad and I'll become the Hokage.
Then, we'll choose true?
Yes.
Will you go along with me, guys?
This is fun!
Thinking will get us nowhere.
Let's just take a gamble, Sarada!
Time's up.
The correct answer is...
It's ink! A pool of ink!
Did we fail?
Damn it... here?!
Does it all end here?!
They failed over there too?!
What's the right answer?
Those who turn black, will fail.
Mitsuki!
Boruto!
So that's it!
We barely made it.
I see...
It didn't matter
if we chose true or false.
That quiz was a sham
from the start.
There was never really
a fifth volume at all.
"Those who turn black will fail..."
That's what he said.
You're okay
if you didn't turn black.
You pass if you didn't fall into
the pool of ink.
So that's what he meant.
Man... It's exactly the kinda
crappy test my dad would think up.
Exactly!
Some looked at
the approaching pool of ink
and realized that they made
the wrong choice...
and just chose to let
the ink stain them.
If you're that gutless,
you don't deserve to become chunin.
The real purpose of the first test...
was to see what you
decided to do the instant you
realized you were backed
into a difficult situation.
Do you "give up" or do you
"refuse to give up"?
Those who did not fall into the ink
made the right choice.
The first round of the Chunin Exams
has now ended!
Round Two is in three days.
Let's do our best!
Of course!
We're going to pass the next one,
no matter what!
Right, Boruto?
Huh? Y-Yeah...
For sure!
Hah, you sure can talk big.
You were helpless
without the other two.
What did you say?
Shinki? What's the matter?
No, it's nothing.
Yes, it seems he didn't have
an opportunity to use it this time.
Yes, if he's going to use it,
it should be on a bigger stage...
Looks like Boruto's team
made it through round one.
I see.
Maybe you should say
a few words to him...
Yeah.
Big Brother, dinner's ready!
He's exhausted.
Let's let him sleep.
Uh-huh.
Congratulations on passing
the First Round!
Do your best on the Second Round!
— From Dad.
An email?
He didn't even send a Shadow Clone?
Stupid old man.
You just watch...
I'll show you in the second round,
for sure.
And I'll make you acknowledge me,
no matter what!
You're late.
You were both too early,
that's all.
So? What did you want
to talk about?
I was attacked.
It was on the way to
Hidden Leaf Village.
There should have been
a barrier placed...
Oh, you mean that
thin paper-like thing?
You must be the one...
who attacked the Eight-Tails.
Eight-Tails?
Oh, my superiors did that.
I understand you once
had one inside of you, too.
Wasn't it called the One Tail?
I got you.
Hmm... How very primitive.
What's that called? Willpower?
Honestly, it's not very effective.
Why you...!
Well, no matter.
Lord Kazekage!
What happened?!
Huh?! Who are you?!
Oops.
Oh well, I got what I was fishing for...
So, I'll excuse myself now.
It was probably the Otsutsuki Clan.
The same as Kaguya's clan?
The scroll that I retrieved
from Kaguya's palace
is being deciphered right now.
He was already aware that Shukaku
is no longer inside me...
I see...
I guess there's no choice
but to postpone the Chunin Exams.
But the Feudal Lords, who were
once bitter foes in the past,
are also joint sponsors.
These exams have
important significance.
Yes.
The current climate of uncertainty is
precisely what they're targeting,
so to postpone
the exams now will...
seriously damage the reputation of
the Land of Fire as well as the Hokage's.
And, should that happen,
the hardliners in my village will
also try to exert their power.
I'd like to try and avoid that.
Governing is so annoying.
Then, it's all the more reason
to hurry with the deciphering
of the scroll...
What a headache...
If only we could be
at ground zero like Sasuke.
Perhaps you're right.
How is your injury?
Don't misjudge me, Mizukage.
It takes much more to hurt me.
This is nothing.
I understand...
Everyone knows Shuriken Jutsu
is Sarada's specialty!
I mean... she's your...
She's an Uchiha, after all!
By that logic, Boruto...
This jutsu should be
your specialty too.
I guess so...
This was Dad's specialty, right?
You can't make any more excuses.
Naruto can make over
a thousand Shadow Clones.
I know that!
I'll blow them away
during Round Two!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
I guess four is still my limit.
Round Two consists
of capturing a flag.
Guard the flag in your territory
while you invade enemy territory.
In other words, this is an offensive
and defensive battle!
It's three against three, so
half the teams will be dropped
after this round.
Most of the matches are over.
There's just one set of teams left.
I don't see the enemy,
are we okay?
I'm guarding our flag.
So relax and just attack!
We're counting on you, Boruto!
If we're going to show Lord Seventh
how strong we are,
we have to make it through
this second round.
I don't need you to remind me!
Your surprise attack didn't work.
It's five against three.
You know who has
the advantage, don't you?
Who has the advantage now?
Sarada! Go!
I'll rejoin you soon!
Boruto!
There's no water around, but he can
use a Water Style this powerful?
He even knows...
Lightning Style?
I'm okay now.
Sarada! Go for the flag!
That's what I'm doing...
We did it!
I guess we managed somehow...
Yeah... It was a piece of cake.
As expected, Boruto...
You're a shinobi who's going
to be the Hokage one day.
Excuse me!
But that's going to be me!
He's good.
I couldn't even see him
weaving signs.
Leave it to the son
of Lord Seventh...
Okay, that makes four teams.
This round is over.
Thanks, Shino.
You've been a big help.
He got through the second round too.
It seems he used it
this time around.
I see... Did you get footage of it?
Yes.
Next up is the third test!
Yeah...
Boruto!
This means... finally...
Lord Seventh will get to witness
how strong we are!
Can't you be a little more excited?
I-I know!
I knew it.
Your eyes are bluer than
the Seventh's...
Really?
They are! I'm sure of it!
You pay close attention, don't you?
Ask him to show you next time.
Lord Seventh is nice,
so he won't say no.
Uh, yes?
I'm impressed.
About what?
Boruto's team, of course.
They got through Round Two.
Th-They did, huh?
Well, see you.
You came all the way here
just to tell me that?
Well, it is important news.
By the way, Shikadai's team
made it too.
We just might see a battle
between our sons!
I'm home.
Welcome home!
Congratulations, Big Brother!
I just passed Round Two.
It's no big deal, you know!
Are you hurt?
I'm fine.
But I'm tired, so I'm just
going up to my room.
I don't need any dinner, either.
Sorry you made a wasted trip.
I've ordered a rush on
deciphering the scroll,
but it seems they need more time.
I see... I'll come back later.
Sasuke...
I understand you're training Boruto.
Did Boruto tell you?
No, I heard it from Konohamaru.
I see...
He came to me and asked
to be my student.
So you're... his teacher.
Maybe you were right, after all.
The soul of a shinobi
never changes...
even if the world changes.
That's what I believe.
Sarada passed too.
And, so?
At least look a little happy.
I knew from the start
that she would,
so what's there to celebrate?
This thing really is amazing!
As long as I have this...
H-Hey, I said I don't need dinner.
What is it?
D-Dad!
I...
I heard you passed
the Second Round.
Y-Yeah.
I... um...
What is it?
If that's all, can you go?
You...
You did well.
Well, see you later.
You came up just to say that?
Well, it's important.
It's very important.
Oh, one more thing...
Wh-What?
Don't lose to Shikadai!
L-Like I'd lose!
I'll be watching.
See you later.
If that's all he had to say,
he could've just emailed.
Stupid old man.
Mitsuki, when are you up?
I think I'm up fifth...
I couldn't eat breakfast
this morning.
I know what you mean!
Yet you sure can eat, Chubs.
What? No way!
I didn't realize I was eating!
All right... Everyone's an enemy
from here on out!
Seems like it.
You guys, don't lose until you
get far because I want to fight you!
That goes without saying!
It seems like we won't be
defeating anyone easily.
Let's show them
the Leaf's true strength!
Uh-huh.
Because the winner will be...
– Me!
Ya know!
Round Three consists of
individual matches!
To be held tournament style.
We purposely did not pit teammates
against each other in the first round...
However, if you win,
you may end up facing each other.
Please make sure you verify
what number your match is.
There will be three stages.
The three winners in
Blocks A, B, and C
will square off in the final match.
Are you ready?
Yeah!
Boruto Uzumaki of
the Hidden Leaf...
versus Yurui of
the Hidden Cloud!
Match One! Begin!
I'm gonna "take" you, Boruto.
Huh?
"Take"?
It means I'm gonna take you down
in one fell swoop!
That's so lame.
Quit shortening everything!
Maybe I'll just shorten
this match too!
Like I'm going to get myself caught.
It explodes?
Heh.
Shinki, you were looking forward to
a match with Boruto...
It might not happen.
I'm not interested in
anyone who's weak.
You guys better watch out
for the remaining two...
Especially Mitsuki.
Heh, I don't need your advice.
I'll just crush Mitsuki in my match.
The caliber of students
taking the exam... is sad.
Sneaking around and
playing hide-and-seek?!
Damn it! That gum is in the way!
All right, guess it's time
to grind this...
So that's the gum that uses
chakra as a catalyst?
Isn't it pretty interesting?
Damn it!
I ain't losing here!
It won't reach me
all the way here.
No... way...
Hey, was that for real?
Amazing...
How can he bend it that much?
Sorry...
Looks like I took you down!
What was your name? Charai?
It's Yurui.
The winner is Boruto Uzumaki
of the Hidden Leaf!
He won! He won!
That kid's pretty good.
Damn it, that makes me angry!
Who would have expected
that both of our teams
would be eliminated before
the finals?
It's fine.
Essentially, the Leaf just wanted to
enter their prized offspring...
and let them become chunin,
so it can't be helped.
They can win simply by entering?
Doting parents are annoying,
Mizukage.
I shall take that to heart.
Pretty good!
When did you practicing that?
Yeah, well... It was a breeze!
Which match is up?
Hmm, let's see...
Doesn't this bring back memories
of our Chunin Exams?
That was the first time
we met you, Temari.
That's right!
You had such a bad attitude
back then.
I don't remember.
Let me correct myself.
You still have a bad attitude.
Shikadai's opponent is from
the Hidden Sand?
That's your birthplace,
right, Temari?
You must have mixed feelings.
Shikadai! If you lose,
it's game over!
Go for it!
Don't turn it into a bad match,
Shikadai...
Anyway, please go easy on me.
Match two!
Shikadai Nara of the Hidden Leaf
versus Yodo of the Hidden Sand!
Begin!
Stand ready!
Don't look down on me!
Damn it. You have such
a bad attitude.
Fine. It's going to be a drag,
but I'll attack first!
Like I'd let you get away!
C'mon, what are you doing?!
We're always the ones who create
an opening with a diversion...
At least now,
he can appreciate what we do.
Yeah, see what happens when
you slack off during taijutsu practice?
Still, that one...
She has sharp eyes.
To be able to dodge an attack
like that so easily.
Yeah... There's something about her.
Like what?
Just watch...
I think Shikadai's going to test
something out next.
Damn it.
Acting so calm and cool.
Well then...
How about this?
What?!
That didn't work either, huh?
Watch it, Shikadai!
Aim properly!
That Yodo...
Can she read shadows?
Shikadai, don't waste your chakra!
She's moving around so much.
Are you done?
All right, it's my turn.
This is where it gets serious...
Here I go.
What was that attack just now?
Was it Wind Style? Or not?
One more time!
Those are high frequencies, huh?
If that hits me, I'm out.
But...
I can't afford to lose this early on
in the game!
Oh! That was so close!
Why? Just now, her reaction
was slightly delayed.
Gum? Gross!
Damn it...
Damn that guy!
I get it!
It's sound... right?
At first, I thought you had sharp eyes.
But in that smoke bomb...
and that feint...
You countered easily.
Which means you weren't relying
on your eyes.
When you took your hood off, your
earphones were gone, so it crossed my mind...
but who would've imagined
that you could hear
the slight sound of me shifting
my weight
as I turned to control my shadow!
That explains why your reaction
was a beat delayed
when I stepped on the gum earlier.
Your hearing is frighteningly good.
Perhaps I should commend you
for taking notice...
But shifting one's weight is
a subconscious habit...
Realizing it doesn't mean
you can control it.
You use headphones to keep your
sensitive ears in check, don't you?
Are you nervous?
Huh?
Your quickening heartbeat...
shallow breathing...
It's so obvious.
So what?!
Don't let her manipulate you!
Too late!
Shikadai!
I thought, since you were Lady
Temari's son, you'd have some skill.
But the Hidden Sand
is the best—
You see, when you say stuff
like that,
you're slinging mud at my mom,
who's now a citizen of
the Hidden Leaf.
You... deliberately set off
a paper bomb—!
There was no other way to muffle
the sound of my shoes...
Shall we call it a match?
I give up...
The winner... Shikadai Nara!
Yeah!
All right!
Uh, pardon me!
She gave you a hard time.
So what?
Sarada... Go all out.
Three seconds...
Watch me.
Huh?
I hear you've been dreaming
about becoming the Hokage?
Well, let me give you
a glimpse of reality...
Match Three!
Sarada Uchiha of
the Hidden Leaf
versus Tarui of
the Hidden Rock!
Begin!
One!
Two!
Three!
The winner... Sarada Uchiha!
– Cha!
Amazing!
All right...
We got three straight wins.
Piece of cake!
Good thing your opponent
was weak.
Look, she wasn't weak.
I was just strong!
Okay, I guess I'll make it
four in a row.
Match Four!
Inojin Yamanaka versus Araya
of the Hidden Sand!
Inojin, stay focused!
Oh... That's a long weapon
you have there.
This is my weapon.
Like they say, the pen is mightier
than the sword.
You think that makes you
look cool?
Well, I'll pull that pretentious mask
off your face.
Ninja Art: Super Beast Scroll!
How's that?
Those were specially made with
paper bombs planted inside!
No reaction to the explosions?
No way!
The winner is Araya
of the Hidden Sand!
You were close.
This is my Lightning Style:
Overdrive!
Electrical signals sent from the brain
are what make muscles move.
I'm able to speed up those signals
with Lightning Style, y'see?
Wh-What's that?
This is...
Oops... I'm not supposed
to use this.
Show me what's up next.
What was that just now?!
You trying to scare me?!
Snakes?!
I... give... up!
The winner...
Mitsuki of the Hidden Leaf!
Okay, I'm loaded up with calories.
Nice!
Okay, I'll do this nice and easy.
Do you best, Cho-Cho!
Of course!
Hand!
Huh?
Give me your hand!
Yay!
Do your best, Chubs!
Chubs is off!
So, Cho-Cho's the last one.
It's the last match of
the first elimination round.
That boy's the ace from
your village, isn't he, Gaara?
Is he strong?
You'll soon see.
Would you happen to be
one of those shy boys?
Did you turn away because
you're so enthralled by my charm?
I should apologize in advance.
Wh-What does that mean?
I'm not good...
at holding back...
The final match of
the first round!
Cho-Cho Akimichi of
the Hidden Leaf versus
Shinki of the Hidden Sand...
Go for it, Cho-Cho!
Make sure you finish strong!
Don't you dare do
anything careless—
L-O-V-E!
Fight, Cho-Cho!
If you win, you can eat all
the Thunder burgers you want!
All-you-can-eat burgers with Dad!
Of course, Mom too!
Burgers, huh?
That's not very exciting...
The match has already started!
What are you waiting for?
Stand ready!
Huh?
Oh, okay!
Your parents are quite funny...
I feel kind of bad
they'll be witnessing
their daughter's miserable defeat.
Huh? Just who do you think you are?
You'll soon find out.
Just how skilled is
Cho-Cho anyway?
She's got great talent.
It's just that
she lacks motivation...
Hurry and attack.
Neither you nor those guys from
Round Two are suited to be shinobi.
I'll show you what reality's like.
Huh?
You just ticked me off!
Partial Expansion Jutsu!
Brute strength right
from the start?
Not refined at all.
The way you look down
on people...
makes me really mad!
What is that jutsu?
That's the one Metal and the others
were helpless against, right?
Look down on people?
Well, I don't think
you're wrong about that.
Will she be okay... Mama?
What's the point of you
getting scared?
Cho-Cho is no idiot.
If close combat doesn't work,
she'll switch to long-distance tactics.
You're right!
Distance! Distance!
Move away from him!
You should be grateful that you have
parents who are concerned about you.
Excuse me?
I don't understand
what you're getting at.
Hurry up and give up.
I told you,
I'm not good at holding back...
Ouch!
I just had my nails done too.
How are you going
to make it up to me?
If you're toying with me,
you'll pay big time.
Cho-Cho's eyes
suddenly got intense.
Yes.
Don't try to sneak up close to him!
Partial Expansion Jutsu!
The same tactic won't work!
Hollow...
Boom!
I knew it!
You infused chakra into
the Iron Sand to manipulate it.
Knowing that doesn't change
the situation.
Your boy is pretty skilled.
Where'd you find him?
He was...
I'll teach you
how to use your power.
What's your name?
Shinki...
That's right... Show me more
of your desperation.
Wh-Why you!
Cho-Cho...
You don't have to get up.
You've done more than enough!
You know it's hopeless,
but you still stand?
You know, in the rare edition
series of potato chips,
there's a spicy
codfish roe-flavored one.
That can't possibly
taste good, right?
But, I'll still try it.
Sink or swim,
I have to taste them.
Otherwise, you'll never know
until you try it, right?
That sign!
Dear, she can't do that one yet!
That's not true...
It's just that...
She really hates using it.
With the chakra you have left,
nothing you do will work.
Like I said...
You never know until you try it!
Why are you going this far?
I really hate using this, but...
Human Boulder!
– Go—!
– Go, Cho-Cho!
Roll, roll, roll, roll, roll!
Hey you...
Did your opinion of me change
a little at least?
Well...
Just that I was much better
than you, after all.
I see.
How frustrating!
The winner is Shinki
of the Hidden Sand!
He's strong...
Cho-Cho was using her true power.
And still....
She couldn't put a scratch on him.
It's a jutsu similar to
the Kazekage's,
but the properties and intensity
of his Iron Sand exceeds it.
Damn it.
Boruto and the others don't
have a chance against him.
Cho-Cho!
Get a hold of yourself!
Oh, she seems okay.
Since she's got a silly grin
on her face.
Huh?!
So heavy!
Your name's Mitsuki, right?
You'd better learn
from what you just saw.
What do you mean?
No matter what the reason,
to ease up on an opponent is
to show contempt towards him.
In the next match,
I shall bring you down,
on my father's honor.
You'll be sorry, if you try to pull
what you did in the first round.
On your father's honor, you say?
Don't make me laugh.
In a battle, you fight for yourself.
I'll defeat you in the match
after that.
That's if you're still in the running.
Fine with me.
But you should talk after
you beat Mitsuki!
Cho-Cho!
Cho-Cho...
She just used too much chakra.
I don't think there's anything
to worry about.
I see.
Thank you, Sarada.
Papa... Mama...
Cho-Cho!
What is it? Are you in pain?
That guy...
He's... pretty handsome, isn't he?
He's not bad at all.
Didn't I tell you there's
no need to worry?
Well, I won't allow it!
Papa's handsome too, okay?!
This marks the end of
the elimination matches.
The first match of
the semifinals will be
Boruto Uzumaki against
Shikadai Nara.
The match will begin after
a 30-minute break!
This has turned out to be a drag...
This is the first time we're
fighting all proper like this, huh?
I hear you can produce up to
four Shadow Clones?
Oh, what?
I was planning to shock you
during our match.
Let's do this fair and square
with no hard feelings, okay?
Don't cry after you lose.
Let's do this fair and square
with no hard feelings, okay?
Oh well, I don't need
this thing to win anyway.
You really didn't have
to take time to come.
What kind of remark is that?
So not cute.
Just don't get
your hopes up too high.
Seriously?
Do you have to be
so much like your dad?
Well, being able to relax
is a good thing.
Listen, you have just one chance.
Yeah...
I know.
I don't mean to
pressure you, but...
Don't lose to Boruto.
What's that supposed to mean?
That's putting pressure
on him, though...
Well, I didn't mean it to be.
Anyway, just win!
Yup, just win.
Just leave!
The semi-final match
will begin shortly.
All right...
I guess I'll go win a match.
You're late, Shikamaru.
Oh, sorry.
Where've you been?
Just out.
Boruto Uzumaki of the Leaf,
and Shikadai Nara of the Leaf!
Oh, it's Big Brother!
Match one of the semi-finals... Begin!
Do your best, Big Brother!
They've both improved so much!
It's too bad
this isn't the final match.
They're both doing great!
Well, Shikadai's serious
for a change.
Wind Style: Gale Palm!
Whoa!
That was dangerous.
I wanted to end this before
you used your Shadow Paralysis!
Don't get smart with me!
See?
Your Shadow Paralysis has
gotten much sharper!
Shut up, and let me catch you!
Don't panic, Shikadai...
Show us the fruits
of your training.
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Hey little Shikadai...
Over here!
Where are you looking?!
Hey, hey!
Over here! Over here!
Quit jumping around.
I got his back.
With the clones as my insurance,
I can do it now!
Gotcha!
Yes!
H-Hey! What's that?
How can he spread
his shadow that far?!
It just means Boruto wasn't the only one
getting special training.
No way...
I already figured that
you'd resort to your Shadow Clones...
So, I practiced a counter-strategy
with my dad.
So anyway, I really wish
you'd give up graciously.
Looks like that's the match.
Damn... it...
I heard you passed
the Second Round today...
Oh... yeah.
You did great.
I can't lose!
Wha—?!
Damn it!
Still want to do this?
I lose.
Good grief...
Doesn't this scene
look familiar?
Boruto Uzumaki advances
to the finals!
Big Brother, you looked
so cool out there!
Young Lord!
Congratulations on making it
to the finals!
Oh, it's you, Katasuke.
You are amazing...
It's still in the development stage,
and only one Shadow Clone is possible...
yet you used it so ingeniously.
So marvelous!
This is a supplement.
I look forward to another
impressive showing in the final.
Yeah, I know.
You and I, Young Lord...
Let us breathe new life into
this stuffy old world of shinobi!
Oh, there he is.
There we go.
That was a close one.
Yup. All three of us
were almost there.
I didn't think losing...
would hurt like this.
Yum!
Really?
You should hurt a little more.
Potato chips that have been finished
aren't worth wasting time over.
So that's why
I open up another bag!
Even her brain is greasy!
I really...
did my best.
I thought I could win, you know?
So, let's do our best
in the next one.
Our future's just beginning.
We're like lounge pants with
an elastic waistband.
There's lots and lots of room
for us to grow...
to the max!
I can never get
your questionable metaphors!
What the hell...
Is this your idea of
consoling me?
I guess you're right...
I guess becoming chunin isn't
really our thing.
Yup! Yup!
Besides... first things first...
We should run crying
to Moegi-sensei
and get her to treat us
to barbecue.
– That's right!
Okay, we'll have
a pity party tonight.
Boruto...
Hmm?
You'd better not mess up
in the finals!
Y-Yeah... leave it me!
What? That sounds so unconvincing.
We'll be watching the matches.
Do your best!
Yeah! Thanks!
Oh! I don't think Moegi-sensei is going to
be able to afford BBQ,
with her salary and all...
What? But I'm in the mood
for their extra special kalbi!
Just endure for a bit with the extra
special kalbi-flavored potato chips.
All right!
Sarada!
I'm handing over the role
of heroine to you today!
Thank you!
Sorry for getting into
the finals before you.
It's fine, I'll be right there
with you soon.
Don't get careless
and let him slip you up.
Be extra careful around
that Araya guy!
He doesn't even blink if
an explosion goes off near him.
His composure shows he's gone
through considerable training.
That guy's not normal.
Who do you think
you're talking to here?
I'm going to become the Hokage!
I won't let it end here.
Hey...
Good job, you guys,
you were all so close too!
Well, no use getting depressed
about it.
You guys experienced
the same thing, right?
Let's just cheer for them and
give them our full support.
– Yeah!
– Right.
It's starting!
Match Two of the semi-finals...
Sarada Uchiha of the Hidden Leaf
versus Araya of the Hidden Sand.
Begin!
Go!
You're keeping calm
and just observing?
In that case,
I'll do that too!
I can't keep up with
my Sharingan!
Sarada is amazing!
She's using her Sharingan to
anticipate her opponent's moves!
But that Araya guy is
countering everything!
As expected, the Uchiha's Sharingan
is quite something.
You can talk?
You've been so quiet,
I thought maybe you couldn't!
Nonsense!
Watch out!
It's not over yet.
Sarada!
Did Sarada try to use genjutsu
to stop her foe's moves?
Yeah...
But it seems like
it didn't work out.
That's impossible!
Surprise attacks don't even faze him...
Genjutsu don't even work...
What's going on?!
Is he really human?!
Why won't genjutsu work on him?
My timing was perfect.
But still...
As one would expect
for a Sand shinobi.
Is he just stronger than me?!
No, it can't be!
At the very least, someone who
isn't affected when faced
with a Sharingan-based genjutsu
for the first time would...
Isn't the Hidden Sand Village...?
If this continues,
it's going to be bad...
Sarada!
Move away from him!
Seems you can still move,
even with that wound.
But it's useless.
I've done my research on
the shinobi of the Hidden Leaf.
I know you're really smart too.
It'll be a drag if
this gets drawn out,
so why don't we wrap
this up quickly?
Did you use up
all your strength?
Well then...
Lightning Style: Lightning Ball!
Leaf Hurricane!
Where was she aiming at?
No...
Look.
What the hell?
Thank you, Metal!
That was nothi—!
Everyone!
– Uh... it's not... ah!
– What's going on?
All right.
You can't run away anymore.
There's someone all
the way up there!
Wha—?!
Huh?
What? A twin?
No way!
You're the real one, aren't you?
You Puppet User!
What?!
Did she say puppet?
Wh-When did you f-figure it out?
I sensed something wasn't right
from the very beginning.
No matter how disciplined,
when something suddenly
happens before your eyes,
humans react unconsciously.
But you definitely didn't...
Also, your almost inhuman,
machine-like movements that
my Sharingan couldn't keep up with,
that were unaffected by genjutsu...
That's when I remembered.
That the Sand Village possesses
an outstanding puppet technique.
I-is t-that all?
Oh, and one more thing.
When I was at a disadvantage,
you rushed to finish the fight.
Don't you get it?
If you did research on me,
you should know about
the Sharingan's weakness...
The Sharingan consumes
an enormous amount of chakra.
So Sarada's weakness is...
– Stamina, huh?
– It's stamina.
If you intended to beat me,
the smartest move would've been
to prolong the battle and
force me to run out of chakra.
Instead, you tried to end it all at once.
And that's what convinced me that
you were afraid of a long,
drawn-out battle, weren't you?
Because if I were to
observe you carefully,
you wouldn't be able to
keep your secret hidden.
Those chakra threads you use
to control your puppet!
Hey! If a competitor isn't in the battle
arena, isn't that a disqualification?
Sure, if you leave in the middle
of a match, you're disqualified.
If you weren't there from the very start,
there's no cause for disqualification.
Right, Lord Kazekage?
Do you have a complaint?
We need to amend the rules,
you know.
He hasn't moved for a while.
What's he after this time?
No...
He's... trembling.
Wh-What am I s-supposed to d-do?
I-I... don't like...
being the c-center of attention...
Is he nervous because
we're all looking at him?
He's just like Metal.
A-Am I... like that?
No wonder he uses
a puppet to fight!
There's his bad habit...
Araya...
Shinki...?
I-It's too late!
You can't turn the tide...
in the condition you're in!
I wonder about that.
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
The match ends here!
The winner is Sarada Uchiha!
You didn't do enough research!
We're progressing every day!
Don't you dare underestimate
Leaf shinobi!
You did it, Sarada!
Yeah well...
Those were amazing jutsu!
I haven't mastered it yet,
so I can only use it against
someone coming straight at me.
But never mind me.
Mitsuki, you're up next.
You know, right?
The finals will be between Team 7!
Mitsuki, in the next one,
show 'em how serious you are!
We will now move on
to match three of the semi-finals.
Mitsuki of the Leaf
versus Shinki of the Sand!
Begin!
Amazing...
Wind Style: Breakthrough.
I've got you.
Interesting magic trick.
What will you pull out next?
A pigeon?
I can only produce snakes.
You use unusual jutsu as well.
How do you manipulate
Iron Sand like that anyway?
It's probably the same type of
technique that Uncle Gaara uses.
That's right...
He's the adopted son of
the Kazekage, isn't he?
Well, he may have the Kazekage,
but we have guts!
Mitsuki!
My father personally
taught me this jutsu.
Although you couldn't
possibly understand.
Hmm...
I see... Well, I don't really
care either way.
Wind Style: Wind Scythe.
It's pointless.
Dodge it, Mitsuki!
Snakes again... Was it a clone?
Striking Shadow Snake Assault.
That's what I call
an impenetrable iron wall...
But how about this?
Striking Shadow Snake Burial.
Hey, c'mon...
I know a battle's a battle, but...
he might die.
Yeah, you're right.
I felt no resistance in my hands.
An Iron Sand Clone?!
Damn it...
I thought he had him!
To think that surprise attack
had no effect on him!
I've taught Shinki everything
I know.
His true skills are
much greater than this.
You didn't even take a step until
now, and you resorted to a clone?
So, did I surprise you a little?
Yeah.
But Father taught me to
never let my guard down,
especially in a situation
like this.
He said his former rivals
long ago were like that.
That's what he taught me.
What about you, Mitsuki?
Show me more...
of your strength!
Mitsuki, go for it!
Cheap tricks won't
affect him anymore.
What would Boruto do
in a situation like this?
Lightning Style: Snake Lightning!
Damn it, he got him!
He deliberately let Mitsuki
destroy his Iron Sand wall
and made him think he had
an opening to attack.
Yeah, in that situation,
anyone would have done that.
He's using a considerable amount
of jutsu.
He only has a slight amount
of chakra left!
What are you going to do, Mitsuki?!
Is this it?
I know you have something
more up your sleeve...
I understand where
your complacency comes from.
I'm going to make you show me.
With that attack earlier, I placed
an Iron Sand Marking on you.
I take it that you know about
the properties of the Iron Sand.
Magnetic force.
That's right.
My inescapable spear will
pierce right through you.
It's true, I have no choices
left in this situation.
For me to defeat him,
I'll have to undergo
Sage Transformation...
Now, show me!
That power!
I give up.
Did I hear you correctly?
You heard me correctly.
I just said, "I give up."
Mitsuki, what did you just say?
I submit.
But...!
It's fine... this way.
I understand.
The winner,
Shinki of the Sand!
What?
What happened to Mitsuki?
Did he get injured somewhere?
Don't ask me! I don't know!
Wait!
Damn you, why?
If we had continued any further,
it might inconvenience my parent.
It's because I want
to stay here longer...
Compared to that desire,
I don't really care about
the outcome of this match.
It seems I was
totally wrong about you...
Well...
I still don't know if I would've
won even if I'd gone all out.
What are you doing, Mitsuki?!
Did you get hurt somewhere?
Wh-What is it?
Sorry!
– Huh?
No, that's not right.
It's more like I look forward to working
with you from now on?
Yup. I have a feeling
it's going to be like that.
What happened to him?
The finals will be held tomorrow.
They are... Shinki of the Sand,
Sarada Uchiha of the Leaf,
and also from the Leaf,
Boruto Uzumaki.
Finalists! Please bring
your absolute best to the matches!
– Sir!
What is this?
I brought you here because you
said you were craving barbecue...
Sure, it's too bad that you lost, but...
you guys put your all into it
and I'm sure everyone saw that.
The meat is... so thin.
Huh?
Well, it can't be helped.
Payday hasn't rolled around yet!
Moegi-sensei...
Are we lacking something?
Well...
You know, you don't have to
know the answer to that yet.
Just now, were you thinking
of how to beat Boruto in a rematch?
Okay then.
Your training for the next Chunin Exams
has already begun.
And from tomorrow,
we'll begin special training again!
Right!
Thanks for waiting!
Yay!
Our special combo platter...
– 20 servings!
– The meat's here!
Huh?!
Wh-What's the meaning of this?
I think you have the wrong table!
You guys were deep
in conversation,
so I went ahead and
ordered for us.
Well, we can't let it go to waste.
Let's eat.
Hey Cho-Cho...
Don't you want some?
You guys!
– And here's your bill!
– Cho-cho, give me some meat too.
Don't you want any?
If you don't want any,
– I'll eat it for you!
– Hey, don't eat it!
Are you okay, Sarada?
Yeah, it doesn't hurt anymore.
You were pretty reckless
out there.
Well, I am your daughter,
after all.
Seriously!
So, when did you learn
the Fireball Jutsu?
I asked Dad to teach me.
I can't do it that well yet, though.
Hey, Dad's not coming home
tonight again?
He should just relax
at home since he's back.
It's fine this way for him.
And besides, he comes home
to sleep late at night once in a while...
when you aren't aware.
Your father's been helping
Lord Seventh all this time,
and the work he does
is very difficult.
It's hard, but his work is for
the benefit of this world.
Hmm...
That's very brave of you, Mom.
Hey, don't tease your mother!
Okay!
Chidori!
Amazing!
That's Old Man Kakashi's jutsu, huh?!
Hey, teach me that jutsu!
I can't.
Aw, meanie!
This jutsu is only complete
when you have the visual insight
of the Sharingan.
Then why did
you show it to me?
Your chakra has
a strong Lightning Nature.
Work to improve the precision of
seals that configure the Lightning Style.
In time, you'll be able to
use powerful techniques.
Start off by trying the basics.
Yes sir...
So, you're saying
if I work hard at it,
I'll be able to use techniques
like the Chidori, right?
I got it.
There once was a man who
refused to heed the words of others,
and sought power regardless
of the method...
and tried to change
the world all by himself.
Yeah?
And what happened to him?
He paid for it dearly.
However, in the end,
a friend saved him.
So, in short,
friends are important, right?
I'm all good when it comes to that.
I have great people all around me!
I see.
And now, we'll begin the finals!
You definitely can
win this, Boruto!
Give it everything
you've got, Boruto!
Don't lose to Shinki,
or Sarada either!
You beat me,
so you'd better keep on winning.
And if you don't, you'll be paying
for the pity party, okay?
You guys...
Yeah! Leave it to me!
We will now begin the final round
of the Chunin Exams!
I made it all the way here.
I can't lose.
I definitely can't!
The final match will be held
in battle royale format.
Of these three,
the last one standing
shall be declared the winner!
And now...
Begin!
Ahhh...
He's going to attack two at once?
Is he an idiot?
It's a 3-way battle.
He's only inviting defeat.
Or, it must mean
he's that confident about himself.
My jutsu is good for facing
multiple opponents simultaneously.
I'll easily take you two on
at the same time!
He's really underestimating us.
Hey, Boruto!
He's strong. Do you want to
join forces for this?
And get some payback for Mitsuki?
There's that too...
But for me personally...
This is our home ground.
It would be disgraceful
for two Leaf shinobi to lose.
We can't let
the Five Kage see that!
I could care less about that, but...
I'm with you on that...
I can't lose either!
But we could end up attacking
at the same time.
If there's an opening,
just take it.
So, I guess we have a united front.
Fine with me.
I'll show you that,
you can't destroy my Iron Wall.
Oh yeah?
Then let's just test it and see!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Fire Style! Fireball Jutsu!
Wow!
Those two have some flashy moves!
But they're up against a strong foe
who made it this far without
so much as a scratch.
But those two have teamed up,
so I'm sure they'll manage!
They'd better.
Otherwise, I'd lose face.
What is that?
I already told you...
My Iron Wall is impenetrable.
I see... It's more than I expected...
That absolute defense
reminds me of someone.
The Black Iron Fist...
Shinki's favorite jutsu
that can both attack and defend.
Attack and defend?
Which means—!
What?!
Black Iron Fist...
Eject!
Sarada!
Is she okay?
Of course she is!
The battle's just begun.
It's the two of them,
so they're definitely
trying to think of something!
Damn it!
What's that stringy thing
that's connected to it?
I get it!
An electromagnetic field!
E-Electro what...?
We learned it at the Academy.
About manipulating Iron Sand
in a magnetic field,
and changing its shape
and controlling it.
Where did you find
such a Magnet Style user?
An electromagnetic field?
Then if we hit it with the
Lightning Style, wouldn't it work?
You watched his match
with Mitsuki, didn't you?
Lightning Style: Snake Lightning!
A superficial Lightning Style...
wouldn't even make him blink.
But how about this?
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Lightning Style:
Sarada, you too!
I get it...
Lightning Style:
Lightning Ball!
I'm going to call this...
Improvised Secret Technique!
Lightning Ball Shuriken Jutsu!
With one hand?!
The concept isn't bad.
But one hand is enough
for that level of Lightning Style.
No way?!
Let me show you the difference
in absolute power.
Oh man.
That could be the match!
– No way!
– Fight back, Boruto!
This is bad...
Oh my...
Is this a Sand victory?
And it's two against one?
How pitiful.
As you just saw...
Naruto, I feel bad, but...
I said nothing would
suit me better, didn't I?
The difference in my power
compared to yours is unmistakable,
and I am proving it to
the Five Villages, for all to see.
My father overestimates
the Hidden Leaf.
Because of his respect for
his friend, the Seventh Hokage.
Because of D-Dad?!
I'm just proving it to him...
That more than the Hidden Leaf...
more than the son of the Hokage...
That I, whom my father
passed on all his knowledge to...
am the one who truly excels.
L-Like hell you are!
What are you doing, Young Lord?
Now...
Shadow Clone Jutsu...
Sarada!
Fireball Jutsu!
I see!
If it's now, when the Iron Sand hands
are both occupied...
We're free...
But what do we do next?
My chakra's already...
Don't be such a weakling!
He's in the same situation
as us now.
So one more time, like before...
Is he going to use that?!
Unfortunately...
There won't be another time!
With my father watching,
I will prove that I am superior
to the Hidden Leaf.
First, you...
daughter of Uchiha!
Iron Sand: Black Iron Wings!
Don't underestimate me!
That's—?!
Sarada!
No way...
That can't be true...
Sarada Uchiha is unable to continue!
The Iron Sand I cemented to your body
acts as a homing beacon.
As you can see...
there's no way you can dodge it.
How dare you!
Now it's one on one.
Just as I thought...
the Hidden Leaf is nothing more than
rabble without their Lord Seventh.
What did you say?!
The ones I faced up to the semifinals
were the same.
When you grow up under
the warm protection of the Hokage,
I guess this is what happens.
Shut up! You don't know anything!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Is he going to do his Boruto Stream?!
Th-That's too reckless, Boruto!
He's almost used up his chakra too...
You want to keep struggling
until the end?
Fine with me.
Then I will show you what
devastating defeat is like.
Take this!
Boruto...
Black Iron...
Stream!
Wings!
Boruto!
Boruto...
I'm not going to let you look down...
on us!
With the strength I have now...
this guy is...
More strength is required
from here on out.
Don't let this get you down.
Take your time and
build up your strength.
In time, you'll be able to
use powerful jutsu.
"In time"...
isn't going to work...
Now!
I have to show my dad...
right now!
That I...
can do this!
Purple Lightning!
What?!
Purple Lightning?
The match ends here!
The winner, uh...
the champion is Boruto Uzumaki!
He did it! Boruto won!
way to go!
I had faith that he could do it!
He did it!
Imagine that...
He defeated him, instead of Sarada.
How many tricks does he
have up his sleeve anyway?
But when did he master
Lord Sixth's technique?
Big Brother won! He won!
Yes... he did...
I won?
Huh? What's with the Hokage?
He probably couldn't contain himself
since his son won.
Now there's a doting parent for you.
Dad! Did you see my big win?!
What's the meaning of this?
This is...
He's used a Scientific Ninja Tool,
something that's prohibited
in the Chunin Exams.
Scientific... Ninja Tool?
This shinobi gauntlet
allows one to use ninjutsu
without using one's own chakra,
in addition to other people's jutsu!
It defeats the purpose of showing
your true strength in the Exams.
For that, Boruto Uzumaki is disqualified.
We'll have to deliberate on how
we'll revise the results up to now.
What happened to Big Brother?
Did he do something bad?
Boruto...
I guess it's now or never!
Boruto Uzumaki has been disqualified
for using an illegal ninja tool!
I can't believe
he'd do such a thing...
Talk about the idiot son
who disgraces the Hokage...
Boruto!
Why did you do this?
You didn't...
when we fought, did you?
It's not like that! I—!
Boruto...
Quit! You fraud!
Trying to win by cheating?!
You're a disgrace to the Leaf!
So what will you do now?
You're disqualified as a ninja too.
Let's go. We'll talk later.
We'll talk later?
Do you really have time for that, Dad?
If you'd talked to me before...
I...
I... wouldn't have ended up
in this situation now!
He's right, you know.
Boruto wasn't able to win,
and we're so disappointed...
Lord Seventh.
To be honest, I wanted to make
this announcement after he won.
You guys!
Listen, everyone!
Boruto used
a Scientific Ninja Tool!
It was prohibited here...
But, there is no denying that
this Scientific Ninja Tool
made it possible for him
to reach this point!
Katasuke!
That is why, Five Kage and
everyone from the villages...
This was the perfect venue to demonstrate
this amazing Scientific Ninja Tool and—
Get behind me, quick!
Hey, hey!
What's with you guys?!
Don't approach them!
This arena is where
I demonstrate my...
Our top priority is
to prevent any casualties.
I can see the fox with
my Byakugan.
It's dangerous here,
go to where the others are—!
This child is the last one remaining.
Take care of her.
I'm going to check over there.
Sarada!
Dad?!
You don't look like you're hurt.
This is for last time!
That was close!
Boruto! Are you all right?
Yeah, what about you?
How trivial.
It was sucked in?!
Kinshiki.
Yes!
We can't use our powers here.
We'll end up dragging
everyone into this.
It seems like I'm their target.
I'll lure them.
Looks like it's safe now.
Hurry and go over there.
Uh-huh.
If I use this power here,
I won't be able to stay here
any longer.
But...
At this point,
it doesn't really matter anyway.
I've never seen chakra
used like that.
Otsutsuki!
That's a dangerous power.
I will not let you use it.
Boru... to...
This is amazing.
Our techniques don't possess
this kind of power...
The creatures of this planet
are quite amusing.
Oh, so it's you.
It seems you're good
at surprising people...
but not too good at
being taken by surprise.
Big words coming from you.
How can he see right through
our attacks?
I already know...
You're currently using your weapon,
your sand for search and rescue...
As for you,
you didn't bring your real weapon.
What are you trying to say?
Investigation is my specialty.
If you were at full strength
that's another matter...
But as you are now...!
You see? That happens when
you don't have enough sand.
I don't fall for the same trick twice!
My turn!
This is the Kazekage's—!
You see?
Your real weapon wouldn't break...
but with that sword...
He's certainly underestimated us.
Yes.
What?
You consider power as a mere tool...
You wouldn't understand with
your borrowed weapons...
It's strength honed through
long training.
And it's always dependable,
at any time.
Oh...?
Then I'll just have to teach you,
that your assumptions...
are wrong!
You're so naïve!
I got that jutsu earlier
from that boy.
I can already see through
your moves!
Your jutsu will no longer
work on me!
Didn't I already say
you were naïve?
Are you at your wit's end yet?
Then I'll end this now!
Ameno Subaruboshinomikoto!
Can you guess why I dug into
the earth with my sand?
This is...!
An underground reservoir
of groundwater?!
You can see through all our moves
with your Byakugan.
So, I just turned an act that looked
meaningless to you...
into a saturation attack.
Water Style: Giant Vortex Jutsu!
You were the naïve one, it seems.
Who are you?!
I am Kinshiki Otsutsuki...
This is Lord Momoshiki Otsutsuki.
What do you want with me?
We will turn the scattered chakra
into one fruit,
and finish what Kaguya failed
to do in this seedbed.
According to the scroll...
It was recorded that these guys would
come to steal the fruit of the chakra...
That's why Kaguya was amassing
an army of White Zetsu...
First Kaguya, and now this...
What do they plan to do
with the fruit?
They plan on making pills.
Pills?
Medicine.
Precisely. As long as we have this,
we are eternally young,
immortal, and invincible!
You poor, inferior creatures...
Unless you train and persevere
senselessly, you get nowhere.
Watch me!
With this pill, instantly,
with no effort, and so easily...
I acquire true power.
Quit kidding around!
That's not true power!
Vulgar creatures like you
wouldn't understand...
What will you do?
I didn't want to soil my garments,
but I shall do it anyway.
I'll have to rearrange this seedbed
and make it beautiful anyway.
There's also the jutsu I acquired earlier.
No...
It's meaningless.
What is this?
I didn't know
Dad had power like this...
Here!
If the real you goes down,
it's all over!
Thanks, Sasuke.
Naruto...
It will all be over after this.
But you must not die, Fox.
Sasuke... Take care of them both.
I got it.
– Uncle!
– Dad!
Let's do this, Kurama!
You'd better not be out of shape!
Don't be stupid!
I'm ready to go anytime!
Right!
Listen...
He was full of weaknesses.
He was a good-for-nothing.
But he pulled himself up
with his own strength...
and became the Hokage.
You don't need to understand
who Naruto is now.
You need to know the Naruto
who made it all the way here.
Dad!
You're awake.
Is this the hospital?
Everyone's been
transported here.
Lord Seventh protected us all.
I see.
So everyone's safe?
Mama!
Himawari?!
Hinata!
It's me. Can you hear me?
Mom!
It's all right. She'll be okay.
What happened, Mom?!
She charged after him.
Why'd she do something
crazy like that?!
She tried to get Naruto back...
Dad...
Boruto...
And when Dad was a kid,
Grandpa Hokage wasn't even alive!
So I guess Dad's lucky
he never experienced
the "joy" of having
a parent around!
Why does my dad have
to be the Hokage?!
He just sits at his desk all day
and acts bossy!
Anyone can do that!
This is so uncool!
I'm the one who's... uncool.
You got that right...
Sasuke!
You got caught cheating,
and everyone scorned you.
You had your headband taken away,
and you can't even call yourself
a shinobi right now.
On top of that, your father is gone.
You're in the same situation
your dad used to be in.
But you're lucky.
You have a sister who adores you
and a mother who worries
so much about you.
Maybe instead of the Naruto of today,
you should study
who Naruto was in the past.
So...
what did my dad do
at times like these?
Seems you want to know more
than just his weaknesses now.
Well, ask him yourself.
We're going to rescue him.
My dad is alive?!
I can sense his chakra...
I can't tell if he's hurt or not,
but at the very least, he's not dead.
If you're going to rescue the Hokage...
Let us pitch in and help!
We can't ignore
the Otsutsuki Clan either.
Standing idly by when our sworn friend
has been kidnapped
would disgrace the Five Kage's name.
Let's make them regret ever
making us their enemy.
What was written in the scroll?
It warned of pursuers personally
coming to this land
because Kaguya stopped supplying chakra
to the Otsutsuki Clan.
And Kaguya was in preparations to attack
once they arrived, more or less.
So what they're after is
massive amounts of chakra.
So that's why Eight-Tails was targeted.
It's clear the Hokage was taken
in order to extract the Nine-Tails.
But the timing of their attack...
They ruined the crucial Chunin Exams.
I was attacked by the one
that sucks up that chakra.
That's a dangerous power.
I will not let you use it!
He steals our jutsu with that fishhook.
If the Otsutsuki Clan is our enemy...
Ordinary methods won't work.
We have to be prepared
for the worst.
We must never let something that
takes chakra away from people,
the Divine Tree,
regenerate ever again.
The one called Kinshiki
possesses the ability
to use stolen chakra to forge weapons.
He attacked with ferocious power
and speed.
The other one called Momoshiki...
Not only does he absorb his foe's jutsu
with the Rinnegan in his palm,
he returns it with
an even greater intensity.
Using any jutsu against Momoshiki
will rebound to you.
How troublesome...
We'd better brace ourselves
for this one.
So, where is Naruto?
The scroll revealed their whereabouts.
Naruto is probably there too.
I've already analyzed it
with my Rinnegan.
Then shall we go?
What are you doing, Boruto?
Huh?
Do you intend on bringing him?
Hey, c'mon... you must be kidding!
Even I think it's too dangerous.
Yes, I think he should stay home...
I'm absolutely not joking.
He is none other than his son.
And he's my student.
Maybe...
I—
I'm saying it's okay.
Listen carefully, Boruto.
Those guys are dangerous.
But knowing that,
I'm still taking you for a reason.
Huh?
If several of us should fall,
or in the worst case...
if we're all driven into a corner...
If that time comes,
you must take over.
That's why I'm taking you.
If even you say that...
You're actually a strong shinobi.
I lost to him,
but if you put your mind to it,
you can become the shinobi
who can defeat him.
I can't!
You definitely can.
Huh?
Because you're a bigger loser
than Naruto ever was.
A loser? What does—?
I mean that you hate to lose.
I'm saying you can do it.
Trust my words.
I'll go.
All right.
But before that,
I have something to give you.
Isn't this yours?
I threw it away long ago,
but your father kept it safe
for me all this time.
We made a promise then.
That I would keep it until the day
we could have a real fight.
I'm giving it to you.
All right, let's go!
Dad...
Take me too!
Sarada...
You're the only one in the village
who possesses the Sharingan.
Stay with Kakashi and Shikamaru
and protect this place.
I got it.
Be careful, Dad.
You better come back.
Of course.
Leave everything here to us.
Bring Naruto back home.
Shikadai... I...
You've got something right now
that you need to do.
Explanations are a drag.
Get it done!
I'll listen to what you have to say
when you get back.
Okay!
We'll use this to get to them.
– Boruto!
– Big Brother!
Mom!
Boruto...
Naruto...
I'm going to go now.
I leave your father
in your hands, Boruto!
Yeah!
You're finally acting like a shinobi.
Let's go!
Sarada, Shikadai...
Take care of everyone!
How does it feel to be nourishing
this seedbed that I created?
It's nice, isn't it?
That Divine Tree was created
from one like you,
who harbored a beast.
Old Man Bee...!
In a short while,
you'll become a Divine Tree too....
What a ridiculous amount of chakra.
We've finally just reached
the halfway point.
It's taking too long.
Sorry about that.
You see, we ninja don't like
to make things easy, ya know?
Let's go!
These guys?!
It's the man in the black cape
with the Rinnegan!
Dad!
Don't think that you can escape from us.
Stop babbling, you vulgar creatures!
Let's do this!
Are you okay, Dad?
Boruto!
What are you doing here?
Your clothes...
A lot has happened...
In short, he's become a ninja.
I feel like I'm looking at
my own Shadow Clone.
Do I look at least a little cooler?
Yeah, more than before.
So, you were paying
a little attention to me before?
Boruto... I'm sorry for
everything up until now.
By trying to protect you
and everyone in the village...
I ended up ignoring my family...
And I didn't even try to understand you.
Dad...
When I was a kid...
I wanted attention too,
and kept pulling pranks.
I'm the last guy who has
the right to lecture you.
You used to... pull pranks?
Huh?
Oh yeah...
I also painted words like "stupid" and
"idiot" on the Great Stone Faces...
and Iruka-sensei yelled at me a lot.
No kidding...
Y'know, I don't know anything
about you, Dad.
Boruto...
No, that's not it...
Actually... I wanted to know
all the time.
But my pride held me back...
and I didn't try to see your side...
and kept pushing back at you...
But now... I want to know.
So...
It's fine the way it's been.
Yeah...
It's okay to keep things
just as they were...
Just...
When you have time,
instead of lecturing me...
I want you to tell me
stories from your past.
Okay.
But are you sure about that?
Huh?
It's a really long story!
All right,
if we're going to protect everyone...
We'd better get going.
Protect everyone, huh?
Hmm?
Oh, nothing...
You always say you have to
protect everyone in the village...
You really mean it, don't you?
Of course, ya know!
I never go back on my word.
Because that's my... ninja way!
All right, let's go!
Yeah... Let's do this!
You're quite nimble
and fast for your size.
I'll soon make you regret your insolence,
you inferior creature!
You're wide open!
As are you!
Why you impudent—!
Chidori!
Bloody Mist Sword Art:
Bone Mutilation!
Tsuchikage!
Leave it to me!
Lava Style:
Ash Stone Sealing Jutsu!
Leave this one to us!
You go for the other one!
Attacking when the Five Kage
were all assembled...
You guys have such bad luck...
Sorry we're late!
Dad, wait!
What is it, Boruto?
You can't use ninjutsu on him!
He absorbed every jutsu I threw at him
when I used the Scientific Ninja Tool.
And he magnified the
intensity of those jutsu
many times over and
threw it back at us.
What a pain.
Simply put...
You absorb jutsu, then release it... right?
But once your ammo is used up,
the jutsu is useless.
Just like the Scientific
Ninja Team's toys...
Then that makes things easy.
We'll proceed without jutsu,
and take you down with brute force.
Although that's kinda dull.
Your partner is already done...
Surrender.
Is that your child, Fox?
What a pity, Fox...
That you possess so much power,
yet not the means to pass it down
to the next generation...
You bastard, what the hell
are you talking about?!
Get back, Boruto!
Let me show you...
how my clan does things!
No way!
Now, Lord Momoshiki!
It seems the time has come
for you to consume my chakra...
The same way that my guardian
entrusted me with their power!
Do not waver!
Of course!
Damn it!
This is bad.
It's too late.
Your own brethren...
H-He ate him!
That fiend!
It was Kinshiki's wish to
be useful to me.
The transfer of power...
is the law of our clan!
This playtime has gone on too long.
Well then...
How about we end this now?
You fools who dare defy a god!
Not good!
He's fast!
Humph...
Sand—!
Lord Kazekage!
He knocked out all of the Five Kage,
in that instant?!
This is really bad!
You're next, Fox...
Boruto...
Here you are!
Oh?
Chakra points?
That's not the only thing.
Dad!
I see.
So, you're completely different from
what you were a moment ago.
Nah, rather...
You're just a monster.
Oh please...
We're both monsters.
Dad...
Dad!
This is getting fun.
Let's teach him, Sasuke!
Yeah!
Come!
Why you—!
Here we go, Naruto!
Yeah!
What?!
Planetary Devastation!
Inukai Takeru no Mikoto!
Damn it!
Sasuke!
Die!
Are you okay, Sasuke?
Yeah, I'm fine.
There you are...
Nine-Tailed Fox Demon...
His power...
shall be mine!
I won't let you!
I'll lend you the power
of the Susano'o.
Do it!
I get it...
That's a good idea!
You inferior creatures!
Amazing...
Hey, Hokage...
Did you get him?
No... It's not over yet.
Ugh, he's so stubborn.
Let's finish him with some flashy jutsu
and get it over with.
Please don't say
such reckless things!
If he absorbs our chakra again,
we'll be back to square one.
Yeah, yeah...
Looks like everyone's okay.
All right!
Somehow, we made it in time!
Katasuke!
How did they—?!
They must have snuck in with us!
Make sure you record the power
of this Scientific Ninja Tool!
Yes!
I'll finish you off with
my Scientific Ninja Tool!
You idiot, stop!
Old Man Katasuke!
Don't use that!
Take this!
Damn it, now you've done it,
you bastard.
Did he just absorb the chakra?
I see...
That thing is just like our pills.
Although it's much more crude
and inferior.
Still, you have my gratitude,
you fools!
This is Shikamaru's
Shadow Paralysis!
Isn't this the Nara Clan's?!
I can't move!
Naruto!
This is bad!
I'm putting extra effort into you.
Damn it...
This isn't looking too good.
That's right.
You get it. Now die!
Damn it...
What do I—?!
Boruto...
What's your ninja way?
Ninja way?
I never really thought about it.
It's so old-fashioned,
and I figure it all depends
on your feelings.
I see...
And you're right.
It may be old-fashioned,
but during this battle,
and in the battles to come,
you'll be confronted with it
time and time again.
I don't really understand...
You'll understand
when the time comes.
You'll need to do it, Boruto.
I'm saying you can do it.
Trust my words.
I'll do it...
I can't wimp out now!
I have to trust my teacher... Sasuke...
who believed in me!
Now, Boruto!
I just have to do this!
Rasengan?!
When did he learn that?!
Go!
You should've just stayed
out of sight.
What? It's not going to reach?
What a joke.
It didn't even get close to me!
Well, don't worry.
You are all going
to the same place—
The Shadow Paralysis...
is undone!
Dad!
Boruto! When did you—?
I told him I'd only accept him
as my pupil
if he mastered the Rasengan.
And he managed to do it
in just a few days' time.
He applied his forte,
the Lightning Style,
and unconsciously changed
its chakra nature, creating a new jutsu...
a Vanishing Rasengan.
A Vanishing Rasengan?
A jutsu like that?
I did that? Sasuke?!
You cheeky brat!
I don't even know how I did it, though...
Still, the results were great.
Good job, Boruto.
Wh-What...
As if that will—!
Momoshiki Otsutsuki...
At first, you look invincible...
But it seems that you can't take jutsu
that you can't see.
Don't misunderstand,
you garbage...
So what if I cannot see it?
As long as I have these...
I can continue!
He was hiding more pills!
The bastard intends to finish us
with his next attack.
Boruto, you ready for
another Rasengan?
But Dad, I'm not strong enough to...
It's all right.
It's so heavy!
So, this is Dad's...
This weight...
What did it take to get it this big?
I don't feel like losing today!
I see you.
There won't be a second time.
You probably know this, but...
we've only got one chance.
– Let's go!
– Right!
Such trivial moves!
Damn you!
The rest is up to you now...
Boruto!
Such impudence!
Well, too bad for you!
I don't know about that!
Are you the real one?
I'm...
over here!
Do it, Boruto!
Rasengan!
Yeah, that was very close.
Like I said,
there won't be a second time!
I'm not done yet!
This is nothing!
I am Momoshiki Otsutsuki!
Boruto!
He actually did it!
Magnificent.
O-Oww!
Did I do it?
It ended up like
I told you before, huh?
Even if times change,
the soul of a shinobi never changes.
You're right.
He's just like you.
No kidding!
I told you so, loser.
You don't look so good.
Neither do you.
Don't lump me in with you...
I'm still able to stand
on my own two feet.
I win... this match.
Looks like it.
So counting all the matches until today,
let's call it even.
Yeah, that's right.
I'm the son of Naruto Uzumaki...
Boruto Uzumaki!
Thank goodness!
Yeah.
Thank you, Boruto!
Stop, Mom!
Daddy!
Oh!
– Welcome back, Dad!
– Welcome back.
Are you okay, Big Brother?
Oh, this is nothing!
The attack by the gang calling
themselves the Otsutsuki Clan
caused a lot of damage
in the village...
and resulted in the cancellation
of the Chunin Exams.
It was officially reported that
the Five Kage joined forces
and put an end to the incident,
and things began to return
to normal in the village.
Dad also went back to
his hectic daily schedule.
Being the Hokage is really hard.
And as for me...
– Shikadai—!
– I'm sorry!
Huh?
Why are you apologizing?
I mean...
I told you I'd hear you out,
but I've been so busy
and made you wait.
That doesn't matter
at a time like this.
Sure it does.
I'm the one saying sorry now!
No, I'm apologizing too!
Hey, Shikadai!
Don't laugh at me.
You're so slow.
You only noticed now?
Shut up!
Anyway, in the end,
you had to take on
a lot of stuff all alone...
So, let me apologize for that.
I'm sorry.
I said, don't apologize first.
Oh, right.
Anyway...
I feel bad I cheated...
I'm sorry.
All right!
Well? How was the power
of the Five Kage?
They were strong, like monsters!
Especially my dad!
S-Still, I haven't lost to him yet!
I swear I'm going to become
a greater shinobi than my dad.
Hey, Boruto...
Do you remember
all the faces of the guys
who took part in
the Chunin Exams?
Huh?
You remember what kinda guys
were there?
That's easy.
Shinki used the Iron Sand and...
And the others were...
Hold on...
You weren't watching them
at all!
There were lots of amazing guys,
you know.
If you keep looking up,
they'll end up getting a leg up on you.
What's that supposed to mean?
It means I didn't like losing
to you either.
I've decided to be a shinobi
on my own terms.
What my parents or
the Nara Clan say won't affect me.
I'm the same way.
We said we wouldn't follow
our parents' footsteps...
But we've been following them
without realizing it.
That's why I'm going to go farther
than my dad ever imagined!
There you go talking big again!
But before that,
I'm going to beat you!
Even if you use that
Scientific Ninja Tool again.
I'm never using
that thing again, ya know!
Boruto!
Oh!
Here, I'm returning this.
You hang on to that.
Huh?
It's proof that you're my pupil.
O-Okay!
When you come back to the village,
please train me again!
Sure... only if you've mastered
the basics that I've taught you.
You can count on that!
What were you and Boruto
talking about, Dad?
Nothing much.
Hey, Dad... How long are you
staying in the village?
It will take another day
to analyze the data.
Then keep me company
while you're waiting!
What do you want to do?
I want to perfect
my Fireball Jutsu!
For the future, just in case...
Sounds good.
Yes! Let's go!
Oh yeah!
Tonight, Mom said she'll be waiting
and making something special for dinner!
Let's go, Dad!
I'm home!
Dad!
Hey!
Welcome home!
Your father bought this for us.
Dad did?
Sorry it's late!
Thank you, Daddy!
Dad...
Seems you're not a Shadow Clone.
What's the big idea doing that,
all of a sudden?!
But it's your fault to begin with!
What did you say?!
Daddy, Big Brother... Me too!
Watch out, Himawari!
Hey, cut it out, everybody!
I'm going to put the cake away!
– You can't do that!
– Sorry, Mom!
I'm sorry!
Let's eat the cake now!
Yeah, you're right!
I'm starving.
Me too!
Boruto, go and wash
your hands first.
I know.
Mommy, I'll help you!
All right!
Could you bring out
the plates to the table?
Okay!
I'll help too.
Dad, you just sit down.
You must be tired,
especially at your age.
Don't treat me like an old man,
ya know!
Happy birthday!
– Cheers!
It's rare for you
to come in person.
I understand you almost
used Sage Jutsu
in front of everyone
in the village.
Do you understand what
that would have meant?
That power cannot be used
in front of others.
The average person won't know
what to make of a power
that is beyond their comprehension.
I don't care about that.
What's worse to me is the light
of the sun disappearing.
Is Boruto truly the sun?
In order to ascertain that,
you need to stay and live
among the people.
However, if you are okay
with this,
I have nothing more to say.
I'm sorry I bothered you.
If I stay too long,
who knows what people will say...
So I should be leaving.
Come home once in a while.
Let me see in person,
the changes that occur in you.
It's okay, Mom...
You can leave it.
It looks cool like that.
Mom, my jacket.
I have to go now.
How are you doing on time, Dad?
Oh, yeah.
Papa, your lunch!
Oops.
Thank you, Himawari
Oh no, Boruto forgot too.
I'm off!
I'll be going now!
– Have a good day.
Boruto, are you off on a mission?
Yeah. Do your best at work, Dad!
Got it!
What's important is to study hard
and learn, you know?
So although you're still a genin,
that's how you fought
alongside the Five Kage
and helped save us from danger?
What's the most important thing
for a shinobi?
Teamwork and perseverance!
Oh, how wonderful!
My dad said...
It's not up here that counts...
It's what you know and feel here.
I see.
Finally, any thoughts
on the resumption
of the Chunin Selection Exams?
I'm going to make it this time,
you know!
This has been a live broadcast.
A Shadow Clone?
I hope you're the real one.
Of course!
You've been busy with all
those television interviews.
Even though you cheated.
How many times have I
apologized for that?
Give me a break already!
A panda's escaped from the zoo!
No, that's a bear!
Anyway, it's headed your way.
Roger that!
Not again... eh?
I'll be the decoy,
so you guys capture it.
– Roger!
– Right!
Do it right this time, you two.
Boruto, you're the son of
the Seventh Hokage
and the grandson
of the Fourth Hokage—
Hey, Boruto...
Deep down inside, don't you want
to become the Hokage too?
Me, the Hokage?
I don't want to!
But... when you become
the Hokage,
I'll be your right-hand man.
I'll guard you well!
To me,
the Hokage is just a path.
Just because my grandpa
and dad are Hokage
doesn't mean I have to walk
the same path.
Sarada...
What I'm really aiming for
is to become a shinobi
like your dad.
I'm going to follow
my own ninja way!
All right, here it comes.
Let's do this, Boruto! Mitsuki!
– Right!
– Okay!
Long ago, there was a fox spirit.
This fox had nine tails.
The fox was sealed inside
a shinobi's child
and over time,
they became close friends.
Then a new calamity occurred.
The Ten-Tails was resurrected.
But the child grew up to be a shinobi,
and the fox spirit, the child, and the
clans joined to seal away the Ten-Tails.
This son of the Fourth Hokage
in whom the fox spirit
was sealed, was named...
Naruto Uzumaki.