In the past, the strongest
shinobi was chosen as a leader,
and there were many
who dreamt of becoming a leader.
This is a dream
that is known as the will of fire.
The will of fire is passed on
from generation to generation.
The will of fire is...
– It will be all right!
– We need to cap this night off with...
Naruto's late...
The inauguration ceremony starts
early tomorrow morning.
Oh dear!
– There you go...
Hey, you're home now.
Sorry, Hinata...
He got wasted.
Oh Naruto...
You know you're
not a strong drinker...
At last, tomorrow is the day when
Naruto takes center stage!
All of us, his friends,
will cheer him at full power!
Well, if you ask me,
I gave up the Hokage's seat to him.
You weren't even a candidate,
so to make such a claim
isn't logical, Kiba.
– Besides...
– Shut up, Shino!
Hey, the kids are probably asleep,
so keep it down, guys.
Iruka-sensei...
I'll show you...
I'll definitely become the Hokage...
Can you two go
and wake your father up?
Okay!
What? Is he seriously
still sleeping?
He's so hopeless!
Daddy, wake up!
Wake up!
Wake... up!
"Cutesy coaxing" isn't going to
work on him, Himawari.
This is how you do it.
Get up!
– Thank you for the food!
Thank... you for the food.
Damn it.
Isn't today
the Hokage's Inauguration?
Shouldn't you be getting up
on your own?
You're right, ya know.
Boruto's been
looking forward to it!
He insisted on waiting up
for you yesterday,
and didn't go bed until late.
Oh, that so?
M-Mom!
I can't wait! I can't wait!
I'm going to pick up
your formal attire.
Huh? It isn't ready yet?
Yes, I'm sorry...
The artisan who does the embroidery
is very meticulous about her craft.
This is one job I can't delegate.
This has been my job
for many, many years!
She's done the embroidery
for every Hokage so far
and wants it to be perfect.
So I was told that it isn't going to
be finished until the very last minute.
I see...
That's right...
It wasn't finished in time for
Kakashi-sensei's inauguration...
How old is this lady anyway?
I'll go straight to the venue
after I pick it up.
So please go on ahead
with the kids.
Okay, got it.
– Right!
– Bye-bye!
I'll be finally relieved
of my duties, huh?
I can't wait to spend the rest of
my life relaxing at a hot spring.
Oh, no...
Please don't leave us with a lot of
work that's going to be a drag.
We need you to stay on
as an advisor.
Ahem...
Smoking is not allowed here!
I can't smoke anywhere these days...
Anyways...
he's late.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Hey, Hinata.
Where's Naruto?
It's almost time to start!
What?
My husband isn't here yet?
Please take this...
I'm going to go check on him.
Oh... Wait...
Hey, c'mon you two! Let's go!
What are you guys doing?!
No! I'm bringing it!
Leave it!
It'll only get in the way!
You'll get tired and
I'll end up carrying it anyway!
I'm bringing it!
Everyone's going to be there!
Put yourself in my shoes!
I don't want to be forced to carry
something so embarrassing!
No!
Leave it at home!
Hey, you two!
We have to leave now
or we'll be late!
Uh-oh...
I've really done it....
S-Sorry...
But if you weren't pulling so hard...
Hey! Will you two cut it—!
The same eyes as Mom's!
Oww!
Boruto!
D-Dad! All of a sudden Himawari's
gone crazy and she's super strong!
The Byakugan?!
What the hell is going on?
Here she comes!
Locked on.
This is bad!
What in the world is
holding Naruto up?
He won't make it in time.
Well then, we have no other choice.
Hey, Konohamaru!
Yes?
We will now begin the inauguration
of the Seventh Hokage.
I, Kakashi Hatake,
the Sixth Hokage,
will be the one presiding over
the ceremony today.
And now,
here is the man of the hour.
The hero of the ninja world who
guided us after the Great Ninja War.
The man who will succeed me
as the Seventh Hokage!
The man you all know...
Naruto Uzumaki!
Thank you!
That guy...
Thank you, hey!
Sorry, Big Brother Naruto...
But I'm going to fool everyone with
my Transformation Jutsu, eh!
Naruto?!
Get ahold of yourself, Naruto...
This is... a halted chakra point!
Which means he'll be
unconscious all day...
Who did this?!
Big Brother?
Are you playing hide-and-seek?
I had no idea Himawari was
this dangerous when she's upset!
Are you here?
Big Brother...
I... found... you...
That day, I swore that I'd never
upset Himawari, ever again.
Hamburger steak!
No!
Rice porridge!
I'm telling you! Himawari said
she wanted to eat hamburger steak!
No! Because rice porridge is what
you eat when you're sick!
Hey... hold on...
– Hamburger steak!
– Rice porridge!
Her fever went down.
So what's the harm?
No means no!
Why?
Hamburger steak!
Rice porridge!
Hamburg steak!
You're not the one
who's going to eat it!
I know I'm not going to be eating it!
– Rice porridge!
– Hey... You two.
If you're going to be noisy,
go outside!
See? You made Mom all mad.
She got mad because of you.
Okay, Himawari's seems better,
and I left a pile of
unfinished work, so...
I should be getting back.
Want to go get a bite to eat?
Huh? With you?
You said you had work left...
I haven't eaten yet.
And I can't work when I'm hungry.
You don't want to?
Fine, I'll come along.
So, where are we going?
I've been coming to this shop
since I was a little kid.
It holds a lot of memories for me.
It used to be such a small shop,
but now...
Seriously, ramen?
Mom says you eat hamburgers
every chance you get.
That's a totally unbalanced diet.
Huh?
So is only eating ramen!
You just don't know how good
Ichiraku ramen is.
The nutritional content is
on the same level as Food Pills...
And it's recommended by
the jonin of the village,
starting with the Sixth Hokage.
Seriously?
Welcome...
Oh, it's been a while,
Lord Seventh!
Sorry, I haven't been able to
drop by lately.
Oh, you must be busy.
Oh, you brought your son today?
Hello.
You've grown so much
since I last saw you.
Nah, he's still just a kid.
What will you have?
Two special ramen... and...
Is my wedding gift coupon still good?
Of course!
My father,
the founder of this shop,
gave it to you as a wedding gift!
We'd be so honored.
Besides,
it's all thanks to the patronage of
the ninja world's hero,
that our shop has grown so much.
See?
What...?
Man, this smell
brings back memories...
Everything's shiny and new now,
but this is where your mom and I
went to eat on our first date.
Aren't you supposed to go someplace
fancier for that kind of thing?
No, your mom said,
"I'd love to get some ramen."
Seriously?
I can't picture Mom
loving ramen that much.
I'm telling you, it's true.
And your mom's
loved this place ever since.
Okay, okay.
By the way, how are things
at the Academy?
So-so...
Don't give the teachers
too much trouble...
– Although I...
– This is Kagemasa!
I didn't know they had
stuff like this.
What? You like that stuff?
Not me. My friends do...
Denki and Iwabe...
He's still just a kid when
it comes to this sort of stuff...
Well, it seems he's
steadily making friends too.
So that's good.
Thanks for waiting!
The time-honored Five Kage Summit
is fast approaching.
The Hidden Leaf Village will be
the site of this year's conference,
and the Kage from each village
will be assembling
to discuss many topics.
So are things going to get busy
for you again?
Yeah...
That's fine with me, just...
don't make Mom and Himawari sad.
Yeah...
Hey, you're still a kid, so don't
worry about such things, Boruto.
And whose fault is it that I can't
just be a happy-go-lucky kid?
Welcome!
– Oh?
– Hey, what a coincidence.
H-Hey...
What, Choji? You brought
your daughter here to eat too?
Well, yeah.
Dad and I are going to start having
our monthly ramen-eating contest.
You're battling your daughter?
Don't interfere, Naruto.
This is a serious battle
for us chubby types.
Our pride is on the line!
In this world of extreme calories,
parental ties don't matter!
I-I see...
Do your best...?
I don't quite get it,
but they seem to be having fun.
Why can't our family
be more like that?
That makes it sound like
I want to be closer
to that stupid old man!
What's the matter?
Nothing at all!
Today, I'm definitely going to
break your legendary record...
No, I'm going to break the Legendary
Queen of Gluttony's record!
Legendary Queen of Gluttony?
Who the hell is that?
Hey, enough already.
Let's eat before
the noodles get too soft!
O-Okay.
That hit the spot!
Wasn't it good?
I guess it was okay.
That's good.
I told you I have
lots of memories here.
The appearance may have changed,
but this place holds a lot of
precious memories from the past.
I-It's a tie.
I guess I was
a little short of beating
the Legendary Queen of Gluttony...
bleh.
See you, Choji.
Y-Yeah...
Thank you for coming.
I can't believe those two...
Just who the hell is
this Legendary Queen anyway?
What? You haven't told your son?
Uh, Boruto...
Mom?!
Seriously?
This photo...
It's from after
the Inauguration Ceremony...
Who would have thought Himawari
would awaken her Byakugan?
Still, it's too bad
you couldn't attend
your own inauguration ceremony...
It was your dream for so long.
Yeah, but now...
I have a different dream.
A different dream?
Yeah...
Now that I'm the Hokage,
the entire village is my family.
So... I want to protect and
cherish my huge family.
Naruto...
I probably sound like
Grandpa Third...
But I've realized my dream of
becoming the Hokage...
and so, this is my new dream.
Even if you realize one dream,
it's never over for you...
You're still chasing your dreams,
aren't you, Naruto?
Now you're a bit more handsome.
At least show me the steps.
Idiot.
Figuring out for yourself is
a valuable part of training.
That just makes it more of a drag!
What the hell is he doing?
Ninja Art: Super Beast Scroll!
What is that? Graffiti?
Your sense of style is pretty
old-fashioned, Dad.
Set your heart on fire!
Yes, Dad!
All right then.
Pretty soon now...
Boruto!
Don't get carried away
ridiculing your dad!
You're the ridiculous one!
A Shadow Clone?
Over here!
Stop right there, Boruto!
There's no way I'll let myself
get caught so easily.
Idiots never learn their lesson.
Shh!
Sarada!
Lord Seventh!
Have you seen Boruto?
He went that way.
Thank you!
I should be the one
saying thanks, Sarada.
Damn it.
Getting upset over a little
graffiti on the Great Stone Faces...
Such a petty old man!
You just wanted him to
come after you, right?
You're just upset because he
doesn't pay enough attention to you.
You're wrong!
We haven't played tag in a while...
And I have to break
the record from last time!
Shadow Paralysis Jutsu...
Boruto...
Don't make too much trouble
for Lord Seventh.
The Hokage is under
a lot of pressure...
And that goes for me, his adviser.
Damn it!
Lord Hokage sure has it rough,
having to deal with the likes of you.
That was a Shadow Clone!
The real stupid old man...
went back to work ages ago!
If Lord Seventh used Sage Mode,
he'd find you in a flash!
I know that.
And that's why...
I kept running away
until Dad got serious!
Neither father nor son
knows when to quit.
You and Naruto are so much alike.
Don't lump me in with Dad!
Shikadai, go and get
Lord Seventh's shadow clone.
Huh? Why me?
Then will you take over here?
This is such a drag.
Seems like we're alike too.
It's a drag for me too.
Now, get going!
Yeah... Run with spirit!
Yes!
Next up,
is cliff-climbing!
Yes, Dad!
If you're not going to eat that,
I'm going to take it!
Are you ignoring me?
Adolescent mood swing?
Everyone gets along so well.
Graduation exams aren't even soon.
Are you talking about the tests?
If this test would
change my weight,
I'd consider taking it.
So what's the big deal
about becoming a ninja?
What does everyone want to be?
I mean... doesn't ninja
sound pretty lame?
What's with all this?
Did something happen?
Not really...
Anyway, where are you going
from now?
I have time today,
so I'll go wherever you want!
Actually...
I promised Dad that
I'd train with him later.
I see...
Of course,
to me training is whatever...
I have zero desire to go, but...
You should go.
You don't want to fail
the exam, do you?
What's with that
condescending attitude?
It really gets on my nerves!
You might think you're really special
being from the one and only Uchiha Clan...
so you don't have to worry.
That's got nothing to do with it.
Then what is it?
It's a special chance...
for you and your dad-
Hey!
Cho-Cho!
Over here! Over here!
Damn it! So embarrassing!
Wh-What's wrong with
a grown-up eating potato chips
as he walks around town?
No!
He's such a poser,
he's eating lightly salted chips
just for show!
He usually eats
the consommé-flavored ones!
We really don't see eye to eye,
the two of us!
Oh, that's the problem.
Cho-Cho, over here. Over here!
I'm over here!
So strange.
Don't you think my dad and I
are different in every way?
I wonder about that...
What about your family?
M-My family?
Are you and your dad alike?
I really don't know.
For as long as I can remember...
I've never even met him.
Where are you,
and what are you doing?
I'm home!
I'm so exhausted!
Welcome home!
Is something wrong?
My eyes got blurry.
It happens once in a while.
Let me see!
I-It just got a little blurry.
It's better now.
Maybe my glasses need adjusting.
It might be good to go
get them checked.
Don't make such
a big deal out of it.
You should worry about yourself.
You really work too hard.
So, um...
Yeah?
Did Dad... wear glasses?
What makes you ask
such a question?
You have good eyes,
so I wondered if my needing glasses
comes from Dad.
I don't think so.
Probably.
"Probably"?
You're not sure even
though he's your husband?
What's going on?
You've been acting weird lately.
When is Dad's important mission
supposed to end?
Well... I think it'll end someday.
I guess you wouldn't know.
After all, you don't even know
if he wore glasses.
That was harsh, Sarada.
What's wrong with wanting
to know a little about Dad?
"The Uchiha Clan is among
the most venerable clans
that bore many skilled ninja."
"Their Sharingan is considered
their greatest trait."
"When it awakens,
a special pattern appears in the eye,
enabling one to see through taijutsu,
genjutsu and ninjutsu."
"Even more exceptional is the Mangekyo
Sharingan, which has a different pattern."
The Sharingan, huh?
I wonder if Dad has it...
"The Sharingan awakens when
there is deep emotional trauma."
"Unique chakra emitted inside
the brain by pain and suffering
affects the optic nerves...
transforming the eyes
into the Sharingan."
"The Uchiha Clan,
due to grave misfortune,
nearly lost its entire lineage."
"At the present time,
the only ones known to be living
to carry on the bloodline...
Sasuke Uchiha and his daughter."
Excuse me, I'd like to see
the next set of data
pertaining to Sasuke Uchiha.
Sure! Hold on a minute!
It seems access to data
relating to Sasuke Uchiha is restricted.
Restricted?
Does that mean I can't see them?
Why is that?
Who knows?
I don't make the rules.
But you can submit
a request to view them.
Although the result
will probably be the same.
No, it's all right.
Mom...
Hmm?
Can I ask you something?
Sure.
Why doesn't Dad come home?
You know where he is and
what he's doing, don't you?
That again?
Hmm... I wonder what he's doing.
What's the matter?
Please don't dodge my question.
Every time I ask,
you keep saying you don't know.
How can you call yourself
his wife?
Sarada...
Right now...
Mom...
Are you really Dad's wife?
What's with all this so suddenly?
It's not sudden!
I've been wondering for ages!
Do you really think
you can keep on fooling me?!
You're... acting kinda weird today.
What's weird is
your relationship with Dad.
And it's not just kinda, but a lot!
Sarada!
I'm sorry I raised my voice.
When he's finished with his mission,
Dad will come home.
How do you know that?
You've been apart for so long!
Maybe he's forgotten
all about us!
Your dad and I are connected
through our feelings,
so don't worry!
How can you say that
with such confidence?
No way!
The loan isn't...
She's always been prone
to fainting.
We've been very busy lately,
so her fatigue probably built up.
She'll wake up tomorrow
I said some terrible things to Mom...
The loan...
I'm going to admit her
into the hospital.
Would you like to come too?
I'll come by later.
I want to salvage
some important things...
Found it!
Who's this next to Dad?
The woman with glasses.
I see...
So you were looking
for your dad's photos.
It wasn't that...!
That looks like a pretty old photo.
What's my dad like now?
That's right.
You haven't seen your dad
since you were a baby.
There's something I'd like
to ask you, Ms. Shizune.
Please don't tell my mom...
Of course, Sakura is your mother!
Then please tell me more
about my birth!
Who delivered me?
Who was there when I was born?!
That's...
Your response is the same
as everyone else's, Ms. Shizune.
I checked and I know.
That there's no record of my birth
in any of the hospitals in the Leaf.
That doesn't mean...
Anyway, why are you
so curious about this now?
Because this woman...
has the same glasses as me.
Dad! I said stop it!
Could you not super-size yourself
when you're with your daughter.
Huh?
More importantly,
why would anyone eat something
like that in the morning?
Well, you can be careful, but
when you die, you die. That's life.
Not that I'd ever eat this stuff.
You're still a child, Cho-Cho,
so you need to eat up
in order to grow!
I'm pretty big already,
even among my peers, Dad.
And you, Mom!
Seriously, please quit it with your
condescending and know-it-all attitude!
Now I'm all hungry again
because you made me mad!
I have no choice
but to have seconds!
Sarada!
Oh, hey...
They say food doesn't go down well
when you're troubled.
It's so true.
So even you feel troubled.
Hey, Sarada...
Will you promise not to tell anyone?
Sure... What is it?
I have a feeling I'm not really
Mom and Dad's kid!
I mean...
I don't look like
either of them at all.
Y-You think so?
Once when I was little,
I had a really high fever.
I can't believe
you were able to get this!
I bet it was difficult!
Hurry and give it to her.
Cho-Cho, here's some medicine.
You're going to be okay now!
Feel better soon!
Thank... you.
I can still feel his touch
from that day...
I think that handsome,
manly man is my real dad.
I see...
That's called the
"tragic heroine syndrome."
Huh?
A condition that unconsciously
occurs in girls of a certain age
when attempting
to define who they are.
Who do you think
you are, Mitsuki?
What's with that
condescending attitude?
You wouldn't understand the mind
of a delicate maiden, right, Sarada?
I can tell without looking
at your crest
that you're from
the Akimichi Clan!
So relax!
Get lost, you insensitive jerk!
Damn it!
I'm actually worrying here!
I know that feeling.
Wondering if they're your real
mom and dad...
Seriously?
You are my best friend,
after all.
So anyway, I have a favor
to ask of my best friend.
Will you hear me out?
What is it?
I'm... thinking of going
on a journey.
To find my real mom and dad.
You'll come with me, won't you?
Huh? What's the matter?
Yes... That's it!
Sarada?
Why didn't I think of this before?
I just have to find my dad
and ask him directly!
If you want to know about Sasuke,
maybe you should
ask Lord Seventh?
We'll leave as soon as
we get packed!
Okay?
Got it?!
I'm going to wring it out of him!
Every last detail!
Who...
are you?
Shikamaru, how many headbands
do we need to order again?
I can take care of stuff like that,
so you should...
It's Sasuke's hawk.
That guy's so analog...
80% of Sasuke's missions
take him to places where
he can't charge his devices.
Give him a break.
This is—!
What is it, Naruto?
Didn't I tell you I'd be on leave?
I see...
If this guy really does
have the Sharingan...
It seems impossible
in the first place...
He's either an Uchiha survivor or...
someone connected to him.
So, you've seen him?
And? How was Sasuke Uchiha?
Strong... Really strong.
That's nothing like his true power.
The power of Sasuke Uchiha's
Sharingan, that is...
Sharingan?
He killed Itachi...
He's unforgivable. Must kill...
That's right.
Sasuke... the disgrace of
the proud Uchiha.
He doesn't deserve to
have the Sharingan.
I'll contact you again
if I learn anything new.
I have to get the details
from him personally.
In any case,
I'm going to go meet up
with Sasuke.
I'm leaving a Shadow Clone here
in the village,
and going over there personally.
For such a tiny ember,
it's flared up into something huge.
The quicker you go, the better.
Yeah.
All right!
Take care of things
in the village for me.
Yeah.
Sorry to keep you waiting...
What's going on?
You seem a lot more excited than I am.
Oh, Cho-Cho!
You sure brought a lot of stuff.
Well, it may turn out to
be a long journey.
See...
I'm prepared for anything!
Yeah... that's amazing...
I swear I'm going to
find my real dad.
Feel better soon!
That handsome manly man
who saved my life.
I just know he's my real dad!
All right, I'm going to get going.
Tell Boruto I'm sorry...
That's Lord Seventh...
Wait, he's going out on a trip too?
Wh-What?!
That hurt!
I'm sorry.
Are you all right?!
How come you're the one
taking charge?
Hey, you're angry, aren't you?
You just missed him.
Oh...
I get it, so that's why
he wanted me to tell you sorry.
Let's go, Mitsuki.
Maybe we can still catch up to him.
Boruto!
Do you want me to deliver
that lunch box for you?
Huh?
Sarada...
We're going on a little trip now.
If you like, we can take that
to Lord Seventh.
Cho-Cho, that's okay, right?
I don't mind, but...
Is there enough for me?
No, never mind.
I'm taking it back to Mom and
giving her a piece of my mind.
Always making lunches for him...
She should know better.
She always...
What is it?
I'm saying I'll deliver it to him.
And I'm saying it's okay.
If you don't want it,
I'll eat it for you!
Can you come over here with me?
Are you going to ask me out?
Your condition is pretty advanced.
Just mind your own business!
You know the person
who's going to deliver it.
So, what's the problem?
In this case, I'm qualified to deliver it.
I swear I'll get it to him.
I won't let the lunch your mom
made for the Seventh Hokage...
go to waste.
Why are you so persistent?
A boxed lunch isn't just about the food...
When you know how special
the person who made it for you is.
What's going on with you?
Naruto is heading towards
the Shikoro Pass.
Boruto, let her take it.
Fine...
Here.
I promise to get it to him.
Yeah.
Let's go, Cho-Cho!
'Kay!
I think he's into me.
Seriously though, no thanks!
Finally, I get to meet you...
Dad!
She's so weird.
They're on the move.
I... saw it too.
Let's move on to the next job, Shin.
Bring me his daughter.
The one with the glasses,
who's wearing the Uchiha crest,
just like you.
We'll be able to use that girl
to our advantage in many ways.
The food in the lunch box is going to
get all mixed up
if you keep running like this...
Though the same thing's going to happen
once you eat it...
We have to hurry,
or we won't be able to catch up.
Besides, what's the point of all this
if he doesn't get to eat it?!
I've had it... I can't run anymore.
If you can't run,
I'll roll you if I have to!
Great idea!
Those eyes...
Who are you?
Shin Uchiha.
My dad and I are supposed to be
the only survivors of the Uchiha Clan.
Come with me...
And if I refuse?
My father said... to bring you.
His word... absolute!
I'm taking you away.
What are you going to do with me
after you kidnap me?!
Cho-Cho!
Partial Expansion Jutsu!
You aren't needed.
Isn't this a bit much...
for a kid's fight?
Lord Seventh!
I think my village's kids are
well-behaved but...
Sharingan...
I see, so you're the one...
He treated me so roughly...
Sorry, but I'm going to have to
keep you restrained.
I have some questions for you.
I see...
Mangekyo Sharingan too.
Then I can't go easy on you.
Remote control of weapons...
So that's your power.
Naruto... Are we going to
let loose for once?
Just a little.
S-Sarada...
Is this what they say is inside
Lord Seventh's body?
Yeah... The Tailed Beast...
The Nine-Tails' power...
Go easy, okay?
What a real pain.
Look at all that massive chakra!
And he controls it so accurately!
Nicely countered, kid.
You're well trained.
Wow! I knew that Lord Seventh
was super strong, but...
he's even more amazing when
you see him in actual combat!
His dazzling presence...
Could he be—?
What?
This is the power of the Nine-Tails
of the Seventh Hokage,
known as the greatest shinobi
of his time.
To be able to see
it with these eyes
is an unexpected bonus.
Retreat for now, Shin.
You can't take him on yourself.
He disappeared...
The Transportation Technique?
I guess that's it, huh...
Um...
Could you be my real dad,
Lord Seventh?
Huh? What are you saying
all of a sudden?
It's not quite the same.
What's going on?
Anyways, who was that just now?
This journey was all about
finding my dad, but...
am I like the fair maiden that
everyone's fighting over?!
No.
You're probably
not their target, Cho-Cho.
It's probably Sarada they're after.
Who are they?
They said they were Uchiha...
You don't have to worry
about a thing.
I'll protect you.
Well... As it is, I can't send you
back to the village.
Both of you, come with me!
I think that'll be the safest.
With you?! All right!
Actually, I'm on my way to meet with
Sasuke whom I haven't seen in a while.
I know he'll probably be happy
to see you too!
Oh yeah! I came to deliver this to you.
Oh?
Thanks, sorry for the trouble.
That was delicious.
Thanks for bringing it.
Oh no, please thank Boruto instead.
Okay.
Sarada's dad, huh...
Originally, this was supposed to
be a trip to find my dad.
Did Choji go somewhere?
What's your dad like, Sarada?
I've never met him, even once.
I don't remember him.
That's right...
He's been out traveling
this whole time.
Let's see here...
If I were to describe him...
He was always popular with the kunoichi
at the Academy... just like me.
And he was quite handsome...
just like me.
Plus, he always got the top grade
in ninjutsu... just like me.
Isn't it usually just one top scorer?
Sounds suspect...
But, he was surly, antisocial,
arrogant and rude... totally not like me!
In other words...
He's my rival!
And that stands even now!
Sarada...
Watching you earlier...
reminded me a lot of Sasuke and Sakura
from back in the day.
Oh...
Sasuke doesn't wear glasses,
but your eyes are just like his.
But your presence is a lot
like Sakura.
Like how you might be really scary
when you snap!
Don't worry.
No matter how far apart you are,
or how long you haven't seen him...
it doesn't change the fact
that you're his daughter.
And Cho-Cho...
Your face is a mirror of Karui's,
but your physique is just like
Choji's back then!
Makes me want to eat meat buns.
I wonder why...
– When I'm with Lord Seventh...
– Are you okay?
This is nothing!
... I feel so relaxed!
It's coming into view, ya know!
That tower is where I'm supposed
to meet up with Sasuke.
I can't anymore! Let's take a break!
Guess it can't be helped!
Only for a little bit, okay?
Oh, come on...
The tower is right there in front of us!
It's okay, Sarada.
Put down your backpack too.
Okay.
Um... I need to use the toilet.
Don't stray too far.
All right.
In just a little bit...
I finally get to meet Dad!
Dad!
– Dad—!
– I'm impressed that you found me.
Are you one of them?
Sarada went
after Naruto?!
At least according
to Shikamaru.
Where? Where is she headed?
Who said you can get out of bed?
I think she just wants to ask
Sasuke some questions.
She had an old photo of him
with his ex-partners.
So, she knows...
about that photo.
Can you blame her?
She's old enough to wonder
about her father.
I had a feeling that
if Sasuke was nearby,
she'd get embroiled
in conflicts too.
I mean...
the Sharingan can
also draw in sadness.
Dad!
You're...
Sarada?
Uh-huh.
I see...
I knew right away...
that you were my dad.
There you are!
Sarada, why'd you run off
like that?
Oh!
So handsome!
Sorry I'm a little late, Sasuke.
Naruto, what's going on?
Why did you bring
children with you—?!
This feels right, but maybe
the touch was a bit firmer?
What's going on?
I came...
I came to see you, Dad!
I found out Lord Seventh
was meeting up with you,
so I followed him.
There's something
I really want to ask you.
Something you want to ask me?
Yes.
Um... Well...
Is Mom... my real mom?
I see...
So Sarada's had the Sharingan
for that long?
Emotional trauma triggers
the awakening of the Sharingan.
Perhaps without knowing,
Sasuke's absence affected
her deeply.
Judging by your reaction,
you didn't tell her about the others
in the old photo either?
Sarada is very conscientious.
If she ever found out that
Sasuke was an enemy of
the Hidden Leaf at one time...
But now, he's traveling around
the world for the good of the village.
Even if you kept it secret,
she would find out eventually.
It was the same even
when she was born.
Maybe you should have
more faith in Sarada?
I'm a failure as a mother.
Please answer me.
Is she my real mom?
What happened?
What happened?!
You're never around!
Why won't you stay and
live with Mom?
Do you even care that
you've forgotten your daughter's face?!
Who's this woman next to you
wearing the same kind of glasses as me?!
Do you think this is something
a daughter can ask her mom?
Hey... that photo is—?
I'm really not into situations
like these.
Mom doesn't say anything,
and you're never around.
I can't trust either one of you...
This whole thing is a mess!
Where have you been and exactly what
have you been doing all this time, Dad?!
It has nothing...
to do with you.
Just forget it!
Hey!
That was way too insensitive
of you!
I thought for a moment that
you might be my dad,
but that's impossible!
Don't you think you should
tell Sarada at least?
About why you won't return
to the village.
Are you leaving already?
I'll send word if I find anything.
It wouldn't hurt to stop
by your house, would it?
The existence of a threat
like Kaguya,
who nearly destroyed the world,
could arise again if
we're not diligent.
We can't afford to ignore
any trace of it.
It was a peace that was secured
through huge sacrifices, after all.
This is... also a journey
of atonement for me.
No one has any bitterness
toward you anymore.
Come on, Sasuke,
together we can...
You protect the village as the Hokage.
I'm the only one,
with my Rinnegan,
who can search for traces of Kaguya.
You do what you're meant to do.
And I'll do what I'm meant to.
Isn't this the collaboration
you always wanted?
Listen, treat my movements
as a top secret mission that
only the top brass know about.
Not knowing anything hurts,
you know.
Sarada should, at least...
Knowing will only create
unnecessary anxiety.
She may resent you some day.
Even if she does,
the future ought to stay bright.
Am I wrong?
She has Sakura.
There's nothing to worry about.
I'm really not good...
at dealing with stifling situations
like this.
Okay, after I eat this,
I'm going to really try talking to her.
Sarada, could you
at least believe this?
Your father is
the finest shinobi around.
Sakura, after this test,
the next one will...
That girl!
For the purpose of our goals,
let it begin...
the revival of the Akatsuki.
– Yes.
Here.
What is it?
It's consommé flavor.
You can have it,
so use it to make up with Sarada.
Wait, Sarada!
Please let me go!
If no one will tell me the truth,
I'll go find that woman with
the glasses myself,
and ask her to her face!
Go talk to Sasuke one more time!
Let's go, Shin!
Yes... Father.
I leave it to you... Sasuke!
Dad!
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
Is that his visual prowess?
Dad's amazing!
Yeah... But this is nothing.
Man, if only my real dad
had piercing eyes and
was a "make-the-ladies-swoon" type... yup.
I see... Sasuke Uchiha.
That's something I definitely want
in order to revive the Akatsuki.
Akatsuki?
Who are you?
My name is... Shin Uchiha.
Shin Uchiha? That's...
Those eyes...
Who are you?
Shin Uchiha.
The same name as that boy?!
You can speak the truth at leisure
after we've captured you.
Until then, shut up.
Who told you to rest? Stand up.
Yes... Father.
Are they father and son?
He's using his own son
as a shield?
Naruto, take care of Sarada.
Sure.
As long as she's in here,
they can't touch her.
Be careful and don't
let down your guard.
Wh-What?!
What's going on?!
This is my visual prowess.
Well?
Just as good as yours, huh?
Lord Seventh!
Don't worry, Sarada.
I'm okay.
That guy's able to control
other people's weapons...
with his visual prowess!
That moment...
he marked my sword!
Dad!
Peace keeps humans
from evolving.
Just like it has with you two!
He's inhibiting my movement
with these!
Without evolution,
creatures shall eventually perish!
So, I'm taking... your Sharingan!
Cha, damn it!
Mom?!
What do you think you're doing to
my husband and beloved daughter?!
So... who the hell are these guys?!
We're about to figure it out...
What are you doing here, too?
I'm here too, you know...
What the hell are these people?
Are you okay, Naruto?
Yeah...
I'll heal up soon enough.
Huh? For real?!
So much fuss over
something like this.
Your battle senses have dulled!
How pathetic...
Aw c'mon...
However... it's over.
Thank goodness, you're okay!
Huh?!
I'm sorry, I thought I'd made things
clear to Sarada, but...
No, it's my fault.
You don't need to apologize.
But I've...
Sarada!
What?
I'm taking you along as well.
Wh-What's going on?!
Sarada!
Transportation?
Mom!
Mom...!
Looks like I'm right in the heart
of enemy territory, huh?
It's no use...
They either went really far away,
or escaped inside a barrier...
I can't sense Sakura's chakra at all...
Sarada...
Mom!
Don't take your eyes off of her.
– Yes, Father.
Please behave...
You are not of Uchiha blood,
but we can still use you.
That's the only reason
why I'm letting you live.
You didn't hold back, did you?
It's because you tried to kill
my husband and child!
As well as my dear friend!
That child needs medical attention
immediately, or he'll be in danger.
I'll help.
You don't want to lose
your child, do you?
My child?
Don't misunderstand...
These children are clones, created
by culturing my teeth and nerves.
Clones? That's...
That's just like him...
Yes, that's right...
My master was...
Orochimaru.
What are you—?!
S-Stop it!
Orochimaru?
Yes, Kakashi-sensei
said the same thing.
He felt the enemy this time
could be connected to Orochimaru.
Who's that?
I've heard of him before.
He's a notorious criminal who tried to
destroy Hidden Leaf Village
a long time ago.
He's a tremendously
dangerous individual.
That guy who called himself
Shin Uchiha...
Huh?
His left arm was implanted
with multiple Sharingan.
The only one capable of doing
something like that is Orochimaru.
So then,
Sarada's mom was taken
to this Orochimaru guy's place?
No... that's not possible.
We have Leaf shinobi keeping
strict surveillance on him.
I don't believe he would be
directly involved in this, ya know?
However, in order to
track Shin's whereabouts,
we need to find out all
we can from Orochimaru.
Let's head to his research lab.
Dad!
S-Sarada?
What is it?
How can you be so calm?
Aren't you worried about Mom?
Hey, Sarada, Sasuke is...
Personal feelings only get
in the way of a mission.
If you intend on becoming
a shinobi, remember that.
I only have...
lightly salted chips left, but...
I totally hate intense,
heavy situations like this!
The only thing heavy should
be my weight!
You can do this,
my delicate heart of glass!
Cho-Cho...
All right!
Do the two of you want
to come with us?
Naruto, what are you—?!
They came after Sarada too.
It's safer to stay together.
Do what you want.
Besides, we may be able to see
those people in the photo
at Orochimaru's.
What?!
Okay, it's decided.
We'll set out at daybreak.
How horrible!
Even if they're clones,
didn't you raise them like
they're your sons?
They're just stand-ins
for my organs.
Nothing more, nothing less.
There's no need to grieve.
Living creatures don't truly die.
What do you mean?!
Without a doubt,
the body of every living creature
decomposes in time.
However, genes through
reproductive cells survive forever
without change in
the shape of progeny.
That is the system we call life.
What is that which we call death?
It's merely the expiration of
the disposable corporeal vessel.
You're wrong!
You're wrong in thinking
the body is just a vessel!
That's where one's feelings
and will reside!
What exists between
parent and child
is more than mere gene transmission,
much more!
Genes are the essence of life.
Weak genes perish,
and strong genes hybridize
to create stronger beings.
That is evolution.
You don't understand at all
what should be important
as a parent!
For evolution,
conflict is essential in the further
selection of superior genes.
Through countless battles,
new ninjutsu and other arts
were developed rapidly...
and strong shinobi were selected!
In the past,
the organization known as
the Akatsuki stirred up such conflict!
For the sake of human evolution,
I will revive the Akatsuki...
and carry out the wishes
of Itachi Uchiha!
It's been awhile, Captain Yamato.
Please stop that.
I don't want to be called
"Captain" by the Hokage.
I can't help it...
You'll always be
Captain Yamato to me.
He's definitely not my dad.
So, they're Orochimaru's partners.
But why's Dad in
the photo with them?
I guess, I really don't know
anything about Dad...
Lord Sixth filled me in
for the most part...
But I'm sorry, this is my mission
and can't leave this spot.
I understand.
Sasuke will lead from here.
Follow me.
This way.
H-Hey, Sasuke!
It's not like we're going to
one of your favorite restaurants here.
Be more on guard, will ya?
Damn it! See?!
Been a while, Sasuke.
The guys in the photo!
This isn't the kind of place
you bring kids for a field trip...
The Hokage?
Good timing. Take us to him.
Huh? Hold on.
Are you ordering us around?
Shall I take you to him?
Sasuke, looks like
that won't be necessary.
Oh my... We have an unusual visitor.
Orochimaru.
Orochimaru...
So this is the person...
Hey, you look younger
than before.
You should know me by now.
So don't keep prodding at it,
would you?
H-He's different from
what I imagined.
Hey, so if this person
is my parent...
Would he be my mom or dad?
Which? Which one, Sarada?!
Huh?!
My child's life was
endangered and
my wife was kidnapped by a man
who seemed like an underling of yours.
If you're up to something,
spill it now.
I wonder...
Have I done something suspicious?
What's the watcher outside for?
Then explain the man
who calls himself Shin Uchiha.
Let's go to another room.
Come along.
Shin...
I haven't heard that name
in a while.
He's gone off on his own already,
but he was one of my old experiments.
Danzo Shimura,
the man you all fought...
his right arm came from Shin.
That child possessed
a peculiar trait
where his body wouldn't reject
any kind of tissue transplant.
He was the optimum subject
for cloning experiments.
Cloning?
To put it in simpler terms for you...
He was like a Shadow Clone
that never disappears.
Never disappears?
So once you're done,
what happens to them?
If you want them to disappear...
your only option is to kill them.
Humans aren't simple things like that!
Humans are much simpler
than you think.
Humans are practically slaves
to their genes.
For example, take you, Sasuke.
The reason why your daughter
looks like you
is because your genes
were passed on to her.
Everything about her
is simply data
that was recorded into her genes.
Genes!
Hey, that's not a nice way to put it!
Why does he call himself
an Uchiha?
Oh, that's just him
proclaiming that himself.
Granted, he's a reproduction, but as
someone who possesses the Sharingan,
he was obsessed with
the Uchiha name.
In particular,
with your late brother, Itachi Uchiha.
I see...
I understand Shin's background now.
Do you know his whereabouts?
Oh my, such one-sided questioning!
You've become quite shameless.
Well, anyway...
It would benefit me as well
if the Leaf were to capture
that troublesome Shin.
Besides...
I kind of owe you one, right, Naruto?
How is the child doing?
Well, I hope.
Yeah, the kid seems to be doing well.
Really? That's great.
I'll explain more, come along.
Um...
You're all
my dad's former partners, right?
I guess.
Then...
Can you tell me where
this woman is?
Oh, Karin...
She's at a different hideout.
She's not here.
I see...
Then... could I ask you
one other favor?
No way!
I didn't know Sasuke was that
much of a scummy bastard!
Could Karin actually have...?
Well, right now, it's still only
a possibility!
A genetic test would show
whose child I am, right?
That's funny. I could've sworn
it was around here...
Found it!
All right.
We'll compare the genes
that we harvested from you
with the genes from
Karin's umbilical cord.
Okay, here we go.
Seems your mom is definitely Karin.
Your dad and I are connected
through our feelings,
so don't worry!
Well, you have similar glasses too...
Uh, anyway... I have to go!
I kinda feel like I did something
I shouldn't have...
Since the old days,
you guys have always
messed things up!
You idiot!
Isn't Sasuke the one at fault?
Did you even know about this?
Of course not!
Sasuke, that bastard!
Well, you take it from here!
Hey, Suigetsu!
Wait—!
U-Um... Sarada...
We need to go and rescue
your mom... right?
Liar...
You lied to me, Lord Seventh!
Why do I have to go and rescue
someone who's not even my mom?!
I'm done with people
who've lied to me...
all my life!
At this point, I'd rather not look
like that person at all.
What are you going to do?
This has nothing to do with you,
Lord Seventh.
What is it?!
Nothing to do with me, huh?
Well, it just doesn't work
that way.
I've told Boruto the same thing
time and time again.
To a Hokage,
everyone in the village is family.
So what?!
Isn't that just a convenient excuse?!
Dad's away from the village
so much.
He even forgot
his own daughter's face.
And Mom...
She's been lying
to me this whole time!
Plus...
we're not even related
by blood at all.
I know now that I don't
have a real family.
And... you're not me, Lord Seventh.
So you can't understand
what I feel in my heart.
You and I are not family!
Is that the extent of your bond
with your mom and dad?
Bonds aren't just about
history or blood.
It's something much stronger!
Then tell me! What is it?!
Feelings of love.
That's all you really need.
Nothing more.
So check yourself again
to see if you feel any.
Hey...
When is Dad coming home?
He's out doing really difficult work,
so he can't come home right away.
Doesn't Dad care
about you and me?
What? Don't ever think that!
Then why doesn't he come home?
Sarada...
Dad treasures us both deeply.
That's why he can't come home.
You may not get it right now...
but I know one day
you'll understand.
Mom, you're squishing me!
I-I'm sorry!
I can't help it because
you're so precious!
Mom, have you ever kissed Dad?
Huh?!
What? What's the matter?
Nothing... I was just remembering
something even better...
Mom... that's pervy.
No! Not that!
Then tell me!
What was better than a kiss?!
I'll tell you next time.
I think you'll understand
when you see your dad.
Mom!
I guess I do want to rescue Mom!
Oh yeah?
But... it won't be like before...
What am I supposed to do?
It doesn't matter whether
she's fake or real.
As long as you feel
the desire to save her.
That's what's real!
Let's go rescue your mom.
Yeah!
Oh, there they are!
Sarada!
Where have you two been?
Sasuke!
We have to discuss something later.
What about?
Not now!
First, we're going to rescue Sakura!
She might be dead already,
you know.
My wife's not weak.
But I will thank you for
telling me where he is.
I'll take everyone there.
My visual prowess just came back.
Your visual prowess was diminished?
That explains things...
You have no right to criticize.
Everyone, get on.
In order to revive the Akatsuki,
I will kill Sasuke and take
his Sharingan.
He does not deserve to
carry on the Uchiha name.
The one who does...
is me, Shin Uchiha!
Wait for me, Mom...
I'm coming.
I'm sorry,
I thought I'd made things clear
to Sarada, but...
No, it's my fault.
You don't need to apologize.
My wife's not weak.
How does he really feel about Mom?
I wonder what really went on
between the two of them.
Lord Seventh...
I'm going to save
all this thinking for later.
Right now, I just want to save Mom!
That's all that matters!
We should be close.
Naruto, sense them out.
Right!
I am the only one who deserves
to carry out Itachi's wishes,
and carry on the Uchiha name!
My goal is...
to revive the Akatsuki,
and stir up conflict throughout
the world once more.
"Your" goal... huh.
I guess I don't have to worry.
Since it's apparent
you have no friends.
Friends?
As long as I take you down...
everything will be settled!
I won't let you
continue to go after
my husband and my daughter!
So this is Shin Uchiha's hideout!
They're coming!
What?! Three of them
with the same face?!
These are clones!
Father's orders...
Get rid of the intruders.
Hey, Sarada?!
I'm sorry, Lord Seventh!
I'm going to go rescue Mom!
Damn it.
Sasuke!
Go with her!
Just let me handle these guys!
Huh?
Then what about me?!
Didn't I tell you?
I'll protect you.
First, let's immobilize them...
Creepy!
Just how many of them are there?
Father's orders.
Get rid... of the... intruders.
– Get rid... of the... intruders.
– Damn that Shin...
– What are you doing, Lord Seventh?!
Aren't they the enemy?
We should just take them down!
No, I can't do that.
Be they clones or whatever,
they called Shin, "Father."
A parent should never do
something like this to their child.
Cha!
Mom!
I swear I'll save you!
A trap?!
Dad!
What's the matter?
Let's go.
No one escapes my Sharingan...
Mom!
Mom! You're hurt!
Amaterasu!
You can heal your wounds
yourself, right?
Yes...
Thanks, dear.
With that leg, you shouldn't
be able to move anymore.
We'll be examining you thoroughly
back at the Leaf.
That boy!
Move.
I have no qualms with you.
I will not move.
I will protect Father.
I'm not as soft as Naruto.
Stop it, Dad!
Sasuke!
The tables have turned...
As expected, you are all weak!
It's because worthless parental
feelings have oppressed you...
that's why everything's
turned out this way.
Dear!
Do not move.
You cannot escape my Sharingan.
You are a disgrace to the Uchiha.
I will carry out Itachi's will
and revive the Akatsuki.
It's okay, Sarada.
Something like this
isn't enough to defeat your dad.
Trust us.
Your dad and I will protect you,
no matter what!
It's useless switching places.
I'll impale the three of you,
together as a family!
You said a parent's love
is worthless...
but I don't agree.
Never underestimate a parent.
Mom!
They're calling...
What's going on?
I don't know...
But I think Sasuke and the others
got things under control.
Let's go!
Sarada!
It's over, Shin.
I'll have to use the Shins
as a distraction
and retreat for now.
Not yet.
All of you...
Do it!
What...?
What... are you... doing...?
Enough...
We are to dispose of
old, useless flesh.
That's what you taught us, Father.
You!
I... am... the original!
Your visual prowess
is weak now... Father.
From now on... we will evolve.
That is the most
logical thing to do...
Is this...
the evolution that you hoped for?
Hey, hey!
There's still this many of you?
When did you...
so many...?
We made more of ourselves.
We don't need you anymore, Father.
There are some
pretty chubby ones too!
I guess they couldn't
clone them too well...
Multi-Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Susano'o!
Don't kill 'em, Sasuke!
You're as soft as ever!
Dad... Lord Seventh!
I can't die yet!
You're coming with us,
medical ninja!
Sarada!
I know!
– Mom, I'm going to...
– Don't get in our way!
...protect you!
Cha!
Sarada...
Amazing!
Still going to keep this up?
Calm down.
Kurama...
There's no need to be scared.
If you don't do anymore bad stuff,
we won't do anything either.
You're way too soft...
They're still kids.
We have to teach them
what's right and wrong.
Carrying on Itachi's will, huh?
You really didn't understand
anything about him.
Sarada, way to go!
The Uchiha Clan is amazing!
That was some awesome power!
Huh? Sarada...
Your eyes are just like your dad's!
Sarada...
You had me so worried!
I'm sorry.
I'm so glad you're okay...
You're squishing me, Mom!
Oh, sorry.
Dad!
Are your feelings really
connected with Mom's?
Yeah...
How can you say that for sure?
Because you exist...
Sarada.
You're so lucky, Sarada.
All right! Let's go home!
First of all,
we'll need to give each one of you
a name for convenience...
There are too many of you,
so before that...
You're going to be living
in this facility from today.
In other words,
we're all going to be a family.
My name is Kabuto.
There's no need to be shy, okay?
Aw man!
This was supposed to be
my journey to find my real dad,
but you found your dad instead.
Are you going to keep searching...
for your real dad?
Well...
The one I have now isn't bad...
I guess I'll make do
with him for now.
"Make do"?
Ahh... I wonder where
my real dad is?
Who's that cool guy?
Um... Would you happen to be...
Oh, Cho-Cho!
Did you come to get me?
Thank you!
This touch...
I knew it!
Wh-What's the matter?
Oh, I understand...
I think this is the first time
Cho-Cho is seeing you
with that physique, Choji...
Huh?
Huh?! Is that really you... Dad?!
Yes, I am...
What's with this?!
Is it some secret
Akimichi Clan jutsu?
Well... sort of.
I want to learn it too!
Can you teach me tomorrow, Dad?!
Oh, Choji!
Cho-Cho was searching
for you all this time.
I was on a mission...
Sasuke?!
It's been a while!
Huh?
What?
Huh?!
That's ridiculous!
Sarada is really and truly Sasuke's
and Sakura's daughter!
But what about that umbilical cord?
It's Sarada and Sakura's!
I was the one who delivered Sarada
when Sakura went into labor!
Really?
You used to be so crazy
for Sasuke before...
Idiot!
All I want is for Sasuke
to be happy.
Besides... women can
just be friends too, you know.
Is that so?
Does that mean you've totally
given up on Sasuke?
You really don't get it, do you?
Bonds come in all kinds of shapes.
But never mind that.
Suigetsu, go and apologize
to Sarada!
And bring her some new glasses,
while you're at it!!
I bet she's outgrowing
her current pair.
Right now?!
Seriously...
Cha you guys...
Of course, you are really
and truly my daughter.
You're so silly.
I'm sorry too, Dad.
Don't worry about it.
You probably took after me
in that respect.
When will you be home next?
Dad...
Don't make such a sad face.
Till next time.
Then tell me!
What was better than a kiss?!
I'll tell you... next time.
I think you'll understand
when you see your dad.
Here's your lunch.
Thanks.
See you...
I'm going to get going.
Just a raincheck for me?
Cha...
I've decided...
Thanks.
For what?
Delivering that lunch box
to my dad.
Same here. Because of that,
I've decided what my goal is.
So... I should be thanking you.
Your goal?
I can't very well deliver lunch
to everyone in the village...
So...
I've decided...
I'm going to become the Hokage.
It's been fifteen years
since the Fourth Great Ninja War...
Many children have been
born since that battle.
Not only in the Land of Fire...
but all Five Nations made it
through without great upheaval,
thanks to everyone's perseverance
and hard work.
We, the Five Kage, will remain united
and protect the peace we won.
We'll now have a closed session.
All right...
Shall we get into the real agenda?
I don't see Sasuke.
Wasn't there something urgent to
discuss regarding his mission?
Sasuke's already departed.
It's a situation
which calls for quick action.
What do you mean?
Our shinobi world...
is about to confront
another danger.
You're going to fill us in
on the details, aren't you?
Kaguya, the one Sasuke
and I sealed back then
had a scary, powerful army behind her.
You mean the White Zetsu
that Madara mobilized?
They gave us a ton of trouble.
Kaguya herself was
powerful enough.
But the fact that she had a White
Zetsu army behind her worried us.
Wasn't it because having to face
the Allied Shinobi Forces
would put her at a disadvantage?
Apparently, that wasn't it.
We discovered that the White Zetsu
were created way before
we shinobi were born
into this world.
That's impossible!
If that's true, for what purpose?
Intel we've gathered so far...
hints that in time,
an existence even more frightening
than Kaguya will appear in this world.
What?!
The Hokage, huh?
Someday, the Great Stone Faces
will include mine...
Boruto?!
A foe more powerful than Kaguya...
And the White Zetsu army
is for that purpose?
Is there any other reason?
And you investigated something
so important like this behind our backs?
You're pretty crafty...
It was my plan to keep this quiet
until we obtained concrete proof.
But something like this...
We may be at peace now,
but the ravages of war haven't
been completely erased.
How do we explain this
to our people?
Just thinking about it
makes me feel dull.
I can't believe that
this could be false intel,
a prank intended to fuel unrest.
The future ought to stay bright.
That's what Sasuke said.
How much time do we have until
this new enemy appears?
A few months or years,
maybe more.
We haven't been able
to pin that down.
That's not good.
Yes...
It's bad enough if it's during
our generation.
If it occurs in
the next generation...
What do you mean?
It's hard to say it out loud,
but I'll say it.
The generation below us is...
frankly, not up to par.
The tension-filled past between
the Five Great Nations has changed.
The lack of real skills
among the young
is a deep concern for
every village.
Shin Uchiha's belief that
for evolution,
conflict is essential in
the further selection of superior genes...
I don't want to admit it
but he may have a point...
Our generation united as
the Allied Shinobi Force.
That's why we were able to
emerge victorious in that great war.
But there's no guarantee that
the next generation can win.
And that's why we have
to be the ones
who will destroy this existence
that surpasses Kaguya,
or there will be trouble, right?
Don't you have anything
better to do?
Sarada, damn it.
Gaara, why don't you
say something?
Unreliable compared to
the last generation...
Is there any generation that
hasn't been compared like that?
Isn't that right, Naruto?
Yeah...
I won't let you deface the Hokage!
Why not?!
Hokage are old-fashioned,
disgraceful and useless!
Lord Seventh told me...
that everyone in the entire village
is like his family!
What an exaggeration!
He's all talk!
War isn't the only kind
of conflict there is.
We can battle and compete
with friends and hone our skills.
If you think hard on it,
you can relate, can't you?
It's true, the era in which we
fought is much different from today.
But you know...
I don't believe
that those kids are weak.
They're still buds.
But someday,
they'll surpass us as shinobi...
And they'll fill this village with
fresh, green leaves, ya know.
I have faith in that.
Honestly... I'm shocked.
You want to continue?
Any more than this will kill me.
Let's continue this another time!
Then it's a draw.
Looks like I've won, Sarada!
Lord Seventh!
Bad news!
The Great Stone Faces are...
Th-That kid...
One thing's certain...
He might just become a shinobi
that surpasses us.
You coward!
I'm okay with being a coward,
totally fine with it!
Hey, isn't that a cowardly move?
But you're okay with that... right?
This calls for Sexy Jutsu!
What is that jutsu?!
I'll pulverize whoever
came up with that!
H-Hey, wait!
I still think they make a good couple.
Give me a break! I'm going to die.
Stop it!
Boruto!